Look at him. Breaks my heart.
Poor little guy,
all alone.
I don't see why
his brother can't
sit with him.
Come on, Mary.
When you were in high school,
would you have lunch
with a nine-year-old?
Yes, I would've.
Well, there's something
wrong with you.
I'm gonna keep him company.
Hey, hey, hey, Mary. Mary.
Think this through.
Right now the kids
are just ignoring Sheldon.
What happens if he's
sitting with his mommy?
They could mistake me
for a senior.
Well, I look younger than you.
Just give this time, all right?
It'll work itself out.
(sighs)
ADULT SHELDON:
My mother never understood
that I actually enjoyed
being alone.
Solitude allowed me to think
about important things,
like the effect
of gravitational forces
as you approach
an event horizon,
as opposed
to less important things,
like how many grapes my brother
can fit in his mouth.
(muffled):
14!
Yeah!
(laughter)
ADULT SHELDON:
Jean-Paul Sartre said,
"Hell is other people."
(laughs)
That's humorous
because it's true.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
(sighs)
Something wrong?
How come math is easy
for Sheldon
and hard for me?
I don't know, honey,
but you have your own gifts.
Like what?
Well, like...
...you have very pretty hair.
True.
Georgie.
Would you do me
a little tiny favor?
Like what?
Tomorrow at lunch,
would you mind
sitting with your brother?
Don't do it, Georgie.
You stay out of this.
I ate with him in second grade.
It really hurt my social life.
(sighs)
Sorry, Mom. Can't do it.
Why are you such a brat?
Maybe I'm crying for attention.
This isn't a joke, young lady.
Yes, your brother
may be smart,
but he doesn't have
a friend in the world.
And I am sorry,
but I am very worried about him.
Nice going. You're making Mom
a nervous wreck.
What did I do?
You don't have any friends,
and she is beside herself.
But I'm fine without friends.
I don't know what to
tell you, Sheldon.
She said it's your fault.
I'm going to watch ALF.
ADULT SHELDON:
Science fact:
sisters are the worst.
(door closes)
ADULT SHELDON:
When you're three foot ten
and in high school,
getting from point "A"
to point "B" can be
a harrowing experience.
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ We are the youth gone wild ♪
♪ Whoa ♪
♪ Whoa... ♪
ADULT SHELDON: But it's worth it
when point "B" is...
(exhales)
...the library.
Home to the original
information superhighway,
the Dewey Decimal System.
MS. HUTCHINS:
Hey there, Sheldon.
What can I get for you today?
Chemistry?
Quantum mechanics? Astronomy?
No, nothing fun today.
I need to learn
how to make a friend.
Aw, honey,
you having a hard time
adjusting to high school?
I'm having a hard time
adjusting to Earth.
Yeah. You and me both.
Try this.
It's been around a while,
but it's still quite popular.
Unlike me,
who's just been around a while.
"How to Win Friends
and Influence People."
This might do it.
"Principle one.
Don't criticize,
condemn or complain."
ADULT SHELDON:
The three sharpest arrows
in my quiver.
Thus began
the greatest challenge
of my young life.
Hello, George.
What?
I do admire
your thick head of hair...
George.
Thanks.
What's going on?
Well, I'm practicing
the principles in this book.
Why?
Well, I know Mom is concerned
that I don't have any friends,
so I'm determined
to remedy the situation.
Oh.
George.
Well, good for you.
Do you feel complimented
when I say your name, George?
The book says you should.
George.
I suppose.
Kind of overdoing it a little.
Sheldon.
Well, thank you
for your criticism.
It also says I should praise
any improvements
that you've made.
Okay.
I'll get back to you.
George.
ADULT SHELDON:
On the heels
of that successful beta test,
I decided to practice
the Carnegie principles
on someone my own age.
♪ Hey. ♪
Hello, Billy Sparks.
Hey, Sheldon.
I am genuinely interested
in you
and would like to encourage you
to talk about yourself.
Billy Sparks.
Thank you.
You have the floor.
ADULT SHELDON: Looking back,
I would've had better luck
making friends
with the chickens.
(bell rings)
Go Wolves.
What?
You're a cheerleader,
and by saying
"Go Wolves,"
I'm initiating a conversation
about something
that interests you.
Oh, are you
one of those special ed kids?
My mom says I'm special.
Would you like to be friends?
I don't think so.
Are you sure?
What if I told you
I admired
your boldly-applied makeup?
♪ Oh! ♪
SHELDON:
Greetings from stall number one.
As much as I detest
that odd-smelling cigarette,
I do applaud
your rule-breaking
bravado.
My name is Sheldon.
What's yours?
(door closes)
Hello, gentlemen.
Did you watch any sports
programs over the weekend?
♪ That's what I like about... ♪
Or perhaps did some kissing
with girls?
♪ That's what I like
about you... ♪
Can you hear me?
♪ Hey! Hey! ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
MISSY: 95, 96, 97.
98.
99, 100.
You missed 11 numbers.
I don't need
to be good at math.
I have beautiful hair.
That's the saddest thing
I've ever heard.
Didn't you already
read that book?
I'm reading it again.
How come?
I clearly missed something.
I couldn't find one person
who wanted to be my friend.
Did you look at
the card inside?
Why?
That's just other people
who checked out the book.
It's a list of losers like you
who can't find a friend.
So?
So they're desperate,
and you have their names.
That's brilliant.
Mm.
Now, how is it
that you can't count?
♪ Well, can't you see her
standing there? ♪
So your father tells me
you've been reading a new book?
I am. It's about
how to make friends.
Is that something
you're interested in?
Not really, but Missy told me
it makes you sad
that I don't have any.
Oh.
I got to sew
that girl's mouth shut.
So how's it going?
Well, the principles in the book
didn't work for me at all.
Although Dad does like
being called George
over and over again,
so you might give that a try.
Baby, you don't have
to go to any trouble for me.
But I like
doing things for you.
You're a nice lady.
But if the book's
not working...
It isn't.
But I realized
if I find the other people
who checked out the book, they'd
be looking for friends, too.
That's really smart.
Missy thought of it.
You're kidding.
I'm as surprised
as you are.
♪ Oh, oh-oh, oh. ♪
(distant chatter)
Excuse me, Ms. Ingram?
Sheldon, it's recess.
Go outside, see
what it's like.
Are you
by any chance Evelyn Ingram?
Yes.
The same Evelyn Ingram
who checked out this book?
And why is that
your business?
I just
assumed you were looking
to make a friend.
Oh. (laughs)
Well, that was
a long time ago.
I had just gotten out of a
very difficult relationship.
With a friend?
Friend.
Ha! I gave that man
three years of my life
and my innocence.
I don't know what that means.
It means men are lying dogs
only interested in one thing.
Well, that's not
the dictionary definition.
Mm-hmm.
Always starts the same.
A quick glance across the room,
a casual hand on the shoulder,
lunch at Stuckey's. (laughs)
Oh, yeah, it's
all romance
and flowers in the beginning...
ADULT SHELDON:
The list proved
to be a double-edged sword.
It turns out
self-help books written in 1936
were only of interest
to adults.
You're like,
"I'm here because I care.
And by the way, your phone
could make calls, too."
Then tries to turn
this whole thing around
like it's all
about you being needy,
and you're like,
"Yes, I have needs!
That's what makes me human!"
ADULT SHELDON:
Emotionally troubled adults.
Child, go outside.
Yes, that's my signature.
Why do you ask?
I'm seeking people
who want to make friends.
I wasn't interested in friends.
I took out that book to help
me become school principal.
Did it work?
Are we sitting in
the principal's office?
No.
And you know why?
Because Victoria
MacElroy is not a man!
So to be clear, you're not
interested in making friends?
What I'm interested in
is in living long enough
to see women no longer treated
like second-class citizens.
Well if your goal
is a long life,
that chili cheeseburger is
a step in the wrong direction.
Food is all I have.
ADULT SHELDON:
Like I said,
emotionally troubled adults.
You gonna watch me eat?
Get out of here.
MAN:
Everybody told me,
"Hubert, don't date
someone from work."
But did I listen? No.
Let me tell you something.
She likes to say
I stole her innocence?
Well, what about my innocence?
I was never the same
after we broke up.
ADULT SHELDON:
Two years later,
Mr. Givens became
the high school principal,
which might be why Ms. MacElroy
became morbidly obese.
I had the brains, I had the
charm, and I don't like to brag,
but I was pretty easy
on the eyes back then.
That woman got herself
one heck of a package.
But some people don't
want to be satisfied.
Is that any good?
I'm afraid not.
I failed to make
a single friend.
That sucks. I have a tough time
making friends, too.
The worst part is, it
was important to my mom.
My parents pressure me about
making friends all the time.
So you understand
what I'm going through.
Oh, I read that book.
It's excellent.
Are you into rocketry?
I started with
water propulsion,
worked my way up
to solid fuel,
then went back to water after
I set our garage on fire.
Nice.
I also tried to
get some uranium
and build an atomic engine,
but that stuff's hard to find.
Probably for the best.
Well, good luck on your
quest to find a friend.
You, too.
If you haven't found one
yet, I have good news.
Mom, what do you know
about the drug Prozac?
Not much.
Supposed to make
people happier. Why?
I was just thinking
some of my teachers
might benefit from it.
Speaking of which,
you'll be happy to know
I made a friend today.
Oh.
Well, that's nice.
But, as I said,
this isn't for me.
It's for you.
He made a friend!
He did it!
Our little boy has got a friend.
Who is it?
Who cares?
It's a human being.
It's a warm body.
(knocks)
SHELDON: Mom?
Yes, honey?
Can I come in?
Of course.
Be cool.
What's up, sweetie?
I was wondering
when I could continue
my rocketry hobby.
Uh, Sheldon,
we've been through this.
You can build them.
You just can't launch them.
But launching them
is the fun part.
Tell that to the family
of squirrels
who died in the fire.
Okay.
It was just something I was
hoping to do with my new friend.
Hang on.
Uh, yes.
It's fine.
Ban is lifted.
Mary...
It's for his friend.
He's got a friend.
Besides,
those could have been rats.
Their bodies
were so badly burned.
I thought we were being cool,
but okay.
Hey, here's an idea.
Why don't you invite your
new buddy over for dinner?
Why?
Well, honey,
um, that is what friends do.
My mother asked
me to ask you
if you'd like to
join us for dinner.
Why?
I was hoping you'd know.
MARY:
He's here!
Everybody, stay calm!
Just a normal day,
just a normal dinner.
MISSY:
Can I eat in front of the TV?
MARY: No, you can eat
in front of Sheldon's friend.
MISSY: Aw, fudge.
I know what "fudge" means,
and you are right
on the edge, young lady.
Welcome.
GEORGE SR.:
So, uh...
Tam. What kind of name is that?
Vietnamese. Sir.
Sure. You know, I spent
a little time over there.
Army.
Your mom's name isn't
Kim-Lee, is it?
No. Sir.
Good.
I mean, you know,
it's a small country.
(chuckles):
So...
Mary, how's that food coming?
MARY:
Almost.
So, Vietnam, like in Rambo.
Yes.
That's a cool movie.
Are you in it?
No.
Hmm.
Why would you think
you knew his mom?
MARY:
All right, Tam.
I decided I was gonna make
you a real Texas dinner.
Barbecued chicken and brisket.
Thank you.
Well, I figured
you were probably tired
of stuff wiggling around
on your plate.
Okay, let's say grace.
Now, Tam, when I say "Jesus,"
feel free to say the word
"Buddha" in your head.
I'm actually Catholic.
Oh. Well, that's too bad.
Thank you, God,
for this food,
and bless the hands
that prepared it.
And thank you so much
for Sheldon's new friend.
ALL:
Amen.
So, Tam, tell us
about your family.
What brings y'all to Texas?
Well, after the American War...
You mean the Vietnam War.
We call it the American War.
Hmm.
Anyway,
after the war, my
father was sent
to a reeducation camp
because he fought
on the wrong side.
You mean our side.
I was trying to be nice.
So, for many years,
my mother and my
sisters and I
were very poor
and very often
didn't have much to eat.
Then, when he was released...
What'd they teach him
at the reeducation camp?
How to be a communist.
Cool, like in Rambo.
(chuckles nervously)
When he was released,
we escaped on a small boat
and spent many weeks at sea
dodging Cambodian pirates
until we reached Thailand.
Oh, that's supposed to be
a beautiful country.
Lovely beaches.
TAM:
I wouldn't know.
We were forced to live
in a refugee camp,
where the only thing we had
to eat were pigeons and rats.
Ha! That's a job for hot sauce.
Finally,
we were allowed
to come to United States
and start over in Galveston.
My father saved money
and bought his own shrimp boat.
There's a happy ending. Huh?
See, kids?
When the going gets tough,
America provides.
TAM:
It did.
Until the Ku Klux Klan
burned our boat
and chased us away.
You gonna put a good spin
on that one?
So we came to Medford
and opened up
a convenience store.
My parents work 16 hours a day,
seven days a week
for very little money.
Well, that was depressing.
I don't understand
why it didn't launch.
Me, neither.
Evil Nazi scientists
did it 50 years ago.
How hard could it be?
(doorbell rings)
Can I help you?
Sorry to bother you, ma'am. FBI.
We're looking
for a Sheldon Lee Cooper.
George!
GEORGE SR.:
I'm on the can.
Now!
(door opens)
What?
These gentlemen
are with the FBI.
They want to talk to Sheldon.
What?
We... Uh...
Y-You fellas
must have made a mistake.
Sheldon's nine.
Well, someone living
at this address
recently called a mining
operation in Canada
and tried to buy uranium.
Okay, maybe it's not a mistake.
It's ridiculous.
Let's just go talk to him.
Huh?
He's just a little,
itty-bitty thing.
Really, he's harmless.
SHELDON:
Sorry!
He's in the garage.