(George Michael's "Faith"
playing)
(tape rewinding)
♪ Faith, faith, faith ♪
♪ Baby ♪
♪ I know you're
asking me to stay ♪
♪ Say please, please,
please don't go away ♪
♪ You say I'm giving you
the blues ♪
♪ Maybe ♪
♪ Huh! ♪
♪ You mean ♪
♪ Every word you say ♪
(popping loudly)
♪ Can't help but think ♪
♪ Of yesterday ♪
♪ And another who tied me down ♪
♪ To lover boy rules... ♪
ADULT SHELDON:
My father took pride in saying
that he ran our house
like a tight ship.
The ship got a lot looser when
my meemaw came over
to babysit.
(firecracker pops)
I bet a nickel.
Hang on there a minute,
moon pie.
I want to teach
you somethin'.
Look at your cards,
and then look
in the mirror.
Hey, I'm smiling.
(firecracker pops)
Uh-huh.
And what does that
tell me about your cards?
That I like them?
Attaboy. Now...
look at my face.
(firecracker pops)
Tell me
what you see.
That you're old.
It's a good thing I love you.
(firecracker pops)
I'm gonna look at
my cards again.
You're unhappy.
Which means...?
You don't have good cards.
Mm-hmm.
(firecracker pops)
So...
I'm gonna see
your nickel...
and raise you
a quarter.
Quarter?
You can fold.
No. I have good cards;
you have bad cards.
I'm in.
Nines and fives.
Mm.
That's too bad.
Three queens. You lose!
(laughing)
What?
But you weren't happy.
I made you think
I was unhappy.
But that's lying.
You lied to your moon pie.
I bluffed my moon pie.
Do people know about this?
Sheldon,
what's on a person's face
is not always
what's in their heart.
Well, this changes everything.
How do you know who to trust?
You don't.
That's what makes life
interesting.
ADULT SHELDON:
Meemaw liked to teach me things
that kept me awake at night.
MARY:
Mom, we're home!
In here!
What's he doing up?
Losin'.
(firecracker pops)
Hell is that?
I sent Georgie
on a beer run,
and tipped him
with firecrackers.
Oh, Mom.
(door opens)
Was I supposed to stiff him?
(door closes)
I ate so much candy!
Okay.
They're all yours.
(chuckles)
(firecracker pops)
♪ Faith, faith, faith. ♪
(groans)
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Sometimes people say to me,
"Pastor Jeff,
how do you know there's a God?"
And I say, "It's simple math.
God either exists
or he doesn't."
(chuckles):
So let's be cynical.
Worst-case scenario,
there's a 50-50 chance.
And I like those odds.
That's wrong.
Shelly,
put your hand down.
Sorry. Please continue.
(chuckles)
It's okay, Mary.
I-It's Sheldon, right?
Yes, sir.
Well, Sheldon,
why don't you come on up here
and tell me how I'm wrong.
No.
Okay.
(chuckles) Let's give him
a hand, everybody.
Mm. What's happening?
Shelly's gonna eat him
alive. (chuckles)
PASTOR JEFF:
So...
you were saying?
You've confused possibilities
with probabilities.
According to your analogy,
when I go home
I might find a million dollars
on my bed or I might not.
In what universe
is that 50-50?
(congregation murmuring)
PASTOR JEFF:
So what do you think
the odds are
that God exists?
I think they're zero.
I believe in science.
(congregation ooh'ing,
murmuring)
PASTOR JEFF:
So you don't think
science and religion
can go hand in hand?
Science is facts,
religion is faith.
I prefer facts.
Mm.
I understand that.
Here's a cool fact for ya.
A lot of famous scientists
believed in God.
Isaac Newton.
Albert Einstein.
Even Charles Darwin.
(congregation ah'ing)
So Darwin's right about God
and wrong about evolution?
Now you're gettin' it.
Let's give it up
for Sheldon, everybody.
What a good sport. Oh.
(organ playing)
ADULT SHELDON:
But I wasn't a good sport.
At that moment,
I vowed to come back
the following Sunday
and destroy Pastor Jeff.
(knocking)
Uh, hello, Mr. Cooper.
Is Missy home?
Hello, Billy.
No, she's at church.
I brought her eggs
from my chickens.
I see that.
You can boil them
or scramble them.
Okay.
I like fried.
I don't like poached.
Okay.
Thank you for your time.
MARY: You want me to cook
those eggs for you, baby?
No. They're a gift.
Sorry.
He even wrote me a note.
"Eggs from your
secret admirer. Billy."
GEORGE SR. (calls):
Mary, can you come in here?
I'm cookin'.
I really need you
to come in here.
What on earth?
Uh-oh.
What?
Listen to this.
"French philosopher,
"mathematician and physicist,
Blaise Pascal,
"argued a rational person
should believe God exists
"because you have everything
to gain if you're right,
and nothing to lose
if you're wrong."
Sounds right.
(footsteps approaching)
MARY:
Meemaw is coming over
to watch you-- I gotta go.
Where?
Daddy's not feeling good.
We're gonna go see a doctor.
Is he okay?
He's gonna be fine.
You just sit right there.
Meemaw's on her way over
to cook you dinner.
Can we come with you?
No. Just stay right there,
don't move.
George, let's go.
How long are we
supposed to sit here?
I don't know.
She said don't move.
She was very clear.
Hope I don't have
to go to the bathroom.
(door opens)
Don't worry!
Meemaw's here!
Everything's under control!
Oh.
(chuckles)
We haven't had dinner yet.
Really?
(groans)
I don't feel like cookin'.
I think my husband's having
a heart attack!
NURSE: I need an RRT
and a crash cart.
Over here.
Sir, are you having
chest pains right now?
Yeah, a little bit.
Any numbness
or pain in your arms?
Maybe this one.
Shortness of breath?
Enough questions.
He's a fat, middle-aged man
with chest pains.
Do something!
All right.
Sorry about the fat, honey.
You said you liked me this way.
(grunts)
Is Daddy gonna be okay?
Oh, yeah.
Your Pop-Pop used to have
little chest pains all the time.
Didn't he die of a heart attack?
Well,
for insurance purposes, yes.
(door opens)
Hey. What's goin' on?
Dad's in
the hospital.
What? Why's Dad in the hospital?
He's gonna be fine.
He had chest pains.
What are we doin'? Why
aren't we going to the hospital?
Nobody's goin' nowhere.
We're just
gonna stay calm,
have a nice dinner,
and wait for your mama to call
and tell us what's what.
I'm not hungry.
What did you mean
by "insurance purposes"?
Just eat.
(laughter on TV)
What kind of Texan drinks
pink wine?
(phone rings)
Hello.
Hi, Mom. Kids okay?
Yeah, they're fine.
How's George?
I don't know.
They're running tests.
Well, don't you worry about us.
(chuckles)
Everything's under control here.
Okay.
I'll call you when I know more.
How you holdin' up?
I guess I'm okay.
Well, George is gonna pull
through this, honey.
I guarantee it.
Thanks, Mom.
Thanks for bein' there.
You bet.
I'll call you later.
Okay.
Bye.
What'd she say?
The doctors are doin' some
tests, but, dollars to donuts,
your daddy's just got
a bad case of gas.
Y'all two go
get ready for bed.
I don't want to stay
around here.
I want to go to the hospital
and see Dad.
Well, I want to go to Las Vegas
and see Willie Nelson,
but that ain't gonna happen
either.
This is stupid.
You know
what's stupid?
I got to drink pink wine!
(door slams)
Meemaw?
What?
Is Dad really okay?
Yes.
I hope you're
not bluffing.
You asleep?
No.
Me neither.
Every time the phone rings,
I get scared.
Me, too.
(knocking)
I'm goin' to see Dad.
You guys want to come?
How? Meemaw said
we have to stay here.
You want to go or not?
♪ ♪
Shh.
Who do I shush?
Shh!
(snores softly)
(keys jangle)
(quietly):
What are you doing?
I'm driving
to the hospital.
You can come with me
or stay here-- up to you.
I'm comin'.
Sheldon?
You're 14.
You don't know how to drive.
I drove a tractor at 4-H camp.
It's the same thing.
But you sat on the farmer's lap.
Then stay here.
Come on, Missy.
(snores loudly)
(engine starts)
(click)
♪ And I whine, I'm after you ♪
What are you doin'?
Travelin' music.
SHELDON:
Ugh.
I'm coming with you.
Why are you wearin' my helmet?
I don't expect this to end well.
And the pillows?
Same answer.
Turn it off.
I've got to concentrate.
Aw.
(music stops)
Okay,
seat belts, everybody.
Please drive slowly.
Relax. I know what I'm doin'.
Whoa!
ADULT SHELDON:
I've often been asked
why I never learned
to drive a car.
This night...
is your answer.
Please slow down.
I'm goin' eight
miles an hour.
A cow just passed us.
Do you know
how to get to the hospital?
Yeah.
It's right across the street
from the Dairy Queen.
Which Dairy Queen?
What are you talkin' about?
There's two.
Really?
You're gonna hit it!
Which is the one
Mom takes us to?
You're gonna hit it!
Ooh, you're in trouble now!
(phone ringing)
Yeah?
What took you so long to answer?
Powdering my nose.
What's it to ya?
Sorry I asked. Just wanted
to give you an update.
Y... What's goin' on?
They want to run
some more tests.
They're gonna hold him
overnight.
Oh. Oh, well, that's, that's
nothin' to worry about.
That's just precautionary.
How are the kids?
Oh. (chuckles)
They were a little worried,
but I handled it.
They sleepin'?
Um...
Yeah, yeah.
You bet.
Thanks again for helpin'.
Oh, hey,
these are my grandchildren.
They are my blood.
Okay. I better go.
Okay. We'll talk later.
(exhales)
Son of a bitch.
I hate those kids.
♪ ♪
MISSY:
Just admit it, we're lost.
We're not lost.
Well, I sure don't see
a hospital anywhere.
Why don't we ask somebody
for directions?
Because we're children
in a car, genius.
Dang it!
Are you aiming for them?
Everybody just shut up.
I got this.
(siren wailing)
Oh, no.
We're going to jail.
Georgie's going to jail.
I'm saying I was kidnapped.
SHELDON:
That's a good plan.
You and I were kidnapped.
If I'm going to jail,
we're all going to jail.
Oh, you better pull over.
GEORGE JR.:
Oh, thank God.
Well, don't just sit there--
follow it.
Why?
It's an ambulance--
it's going to the hospital.
Hang on.
MISSY: How about I put
the radio on real low?
GEORGE JR.:
Shut up.
Mary.
Mom!
Where are they?
Where's who?
More importantly...
...how is George?
SHELDON:
Mom!
Ah. There they are!
Hey. Oh.
MEEMAW: Ha! I lost
the little rascals
in the... hall.
I want to see Dad.
Me, too.
The doctors are
with him now.
I'll take you in a bit.
Why are they here?
I think it's obvious.
They love their daddy.
No, I get that.
Why aren't they home in bed?
Well, nobody could sleep.
I thought it was
the right thing.
Good bluff.
Shh.
Okay, thank you.
You all need anything?
You hungry?
No.
No, thank you.
Okay, everybody sit tight.
I'm gonna go check
on your dad.
Georgie.
Give me my damn keys.
Oh, yeah. Here.
Thank you.
How did I beat you here?
We kept hitting
garbage cans.
Oh, God.
I need to wash
my hands.
There are germs here
that can kill you.
Hold up.
Now, y'all like it
when your meemaw babysits.
Poker, candy,
firecrackers.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well, if your mother
ever finds out
what you did tonight,
that is never
gonna happen again.
I can't lie
to my mother.
Sure you can.
Believe in yourself!
(monitor beeping steadily)
(labored breathing)
(amplified heartbeat)
(rapid beeping)
(weak exhale)
(amplified, rapid heartbeat)
(pants quietly)
♪ ♪
ADULT SHELDON:
Despite what it looks like,
I didn't pray to God
that night.
I prayed to Blaise Pascal.
My thinking was,
if he was right
about the existence of God,
then he could pass along
my request
for my dad to get better.
If he was wrong...
well...
in this moment,
I needed him to be right.
What's taking so long?
Shh.
Keep your voice down, car thief.
I didn't steal your car,
I just borrowed it.
You're gonna need
to make bail someday.
Do not come to me.
MARY:
Good news!
Your daddy's gonna be fine.
Should be home
in a day or two.
Oh!
And was it a heart attack?
Minor. No permanent damage.
Oh! That's wonderful!
Our prayers have been answered.
Come on,
everybody,
let's say hello to your old dad.
♪ ♪
Come on.
ADULT SHELDON:
For a brief moment,
I was filled with
the healing power of faith.
Then the next day,
we all got violently ill
from Billy Sparks' eggs,
and I was over it.
Now, everybody knows how,
on the first day of creation,
God said, "Let there be light."
And there was light.
And when God saw that light,
he knew it was good.
(congregation murmuring)
Oh, here we go.
Yes, Sheldon.
You said he didn't create
the sun until day four.
Yeah.
So how could there be light
the first three days?
God is light.
So God's a photon?
God's what made photons
possible.
And what day did he do that?
I would think day one.
If I grab my chest
and keel over, maybe
we can get out of here.
That's a terrible
thing to say.
...because the first day
had just begun.
So, before the Big Bang?
There was no Big Bang.
There was only the Word.
Was the word "kaboom"?
Okay, do it.
(grunts)
We gotta go.
(grunting)
MISSY:
What's happening?
Is it over?
Y-Yes.