I have a special treat
for y'all today.
My dear friend and former
college roommate is here
from the Johnson Space Center
in Houston to talk to us
about our space program.
And yeah, I know
what you're thinking.
These guys were roomies.
How does one go on
to be a....
a fancy scientist at NASA,
and the other's teaching
freshman science
at a public high school?
Yeah, Sheldon.
I was thinking that.
Thank you.
All right, uh, let's
give a warm welcome
to my good buddy,
Dr. Ronald Hodges.
Hey, kids. Hey.
Glad to be here.
And, uh, Hubert, the answer
to your question is, one of
those roomies was busy studying
while the other was out
chasing high school girls.
(forced laugh)
(laughs)
Yeah.
To be clear, they
were all over 18.
(laughing):
Yeah. Well...
Now, what I thought would
be fun to talk about today
is what NASA's planning on doing
beyond the space shuttle.
Things like the first
manned mission to Mars.
Uh, yeah.
Did you see the movie Aliens?
I did.
Did you think it was cool?
Uh...
Sure, I enjoyed it.
Me, too.
Football player, right?
Yes, sir.
(laughing):
Yeah.
Now, of course, before
we can set out
to explore the solar system,
we've got a few minor problems
to overcome.
Not the least of
which is, every time
we launch,
it costs the U.S. taxpayers
hundreds of millions of dollars.
Oh, no, no, no.
Yes.
If you want
to save money,
why don't you land
the booster rockets
instead of letting them drop
in the ocean?
(laughs)
That's a cute idea, but, uh,
it's not technically possible.
Why not?
Well, it's hard to explain.
The math is pretty complicated.
Perhaps
I could help you with it.
(laughing):
Well,
I bet you could.
(laughs)
I'll bet you could.
I'll tell you what.
Here is a NASA patch.
Why don't you have your mom
sew that on your book bag? Now,
who here wants to know how
astronauts go to the bathroom?
BOY:
Me. I do.
Oh, right. See,
now, during liftoff,
all the astronauts
wear diapers.
ADULT SHELDON:
People often wonder why I chose
to pursue a career
in theoretical physics.
I usually respond by saying
I wanted to unravel the
inner workings of the universe.
Yeah, perhaps when
Captain Kirk said,
"To boldly go,"
he meant in one of those, huh?
ADULT SHELDON:
But the real answer was
I wanted
to prove this nincompoop wrong.
Yeah, that's right.
Beam me up, Potty!
(cackling)
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
MEEMAW:
So I saw a lawyer today.
Why?
I'm putting together
my last will and testament.
We're gonna miss ya.
George.
Don't worry.
I ain't leaving him squat.
Are you dyin'?
We're all
dyin', honey.
From the second we're born,
it's just a slip and slide
into the darkness.
Unless you get
bit by a vampire.
Well, now that goes
without saying.
I don't want to die.
I've only kissed
one boy so far.
What?
Relax. It was a
long time ago.
Are you relaxed?
Shelly, you haven't
touched your dinner.
You feel okay?
Oh, yes. I was
just thinking.
About what, baby?
The optimal height-to-width
ratio for a reusable rocket.
MEEMAW:
I was just
thinking the exact same thing.
Really?
Oh, Moonpie, I love you so much.
(laughs)
(sighs)
(sucks air in through teeth)
It's late. What
are you doing up?
I'm working
on the hyperbolic calculations
for a rocket return.
Need any help?
What?
I'm kiddin'. Now, turn out
the light and go to bed.
But...
Now.
(sighs)
Dad, can we afford a computer?
You do my taxes.
What do you think?
Never mind.
Good night.
Meemaw?
Mr. Moonpie,
how might I help you?
How much money are you planning
to leave me when you die?
Nice talkin' to you.
(knocking)
Meemaw?
Want to try that again?
I need to buy a computer
so I can solve
the Navier-Stokes equation.
Uh-huh. How much is a computer?
Apple has a nice one for $2,000,
but the kind I need costs
three million.
Let me see
what I got in the vault.
(murmurs quietly)
Nine bucks and, uh...
Oh, look at that-- a peso.
It's warm.
Hello, First National Bank.
I'd like to speak
with a loan officer.
It's regarding a second mortgage
on my home.
My name is Sheldon Lee Cooper.
Sure, I'll hold.
Oh, I hate hold music.
Hello.
Yes, you can help me,
Dorothy Fitzpatrick.
I'm interested in taking out
a second mortgage.
I'm nine years old.
Why do you ask?
That's called
age discrimination, Dorothy,
but I'm willing to let it slide.
I'm glad you find me cute,
but I'm deadly serious.
I need funds to buy a computer.
No, the house isn't in my name.
I'm nine.
We've established this.
I do prepare the taxes
for my parents,
and if we tighten our belts,
we'll have sufficient equity
for the loan.
Sheldon, who are
you talking to?
Dorothy Fitzpatrick.
Who's Dorothy Fitzpatrick?
Is she a new buddy from school?
She's the loan officer at The
First National Bank of Medford.
Why are you talking to her?
Mom, can this wait?
I'm trying
to negotiate favorable terms.
Hello. Dorothy?
(whirring, beeps)
Hey, how come you
weren't in math class?
That guy from NASA
treated me like a child,
and I need to
prove him wrong.
You are a child.
Tread lightly, my friend.
Was Ms. Ingram upset
I wasn't in class?
(beeps)
TAM: Actually,
she was happy.
She even did a little dance.
Do you know anybody
with a modem?
I think
Radio Shack has one. Why?
I need to access
thrust-to-weight ratios
from the FTP server at
the Johnson Space Center.
Then what?
Then I show that guy
from NASA my work
and laugh as he
begs for mercy.
You know, sometimes
you sound like a super villain.
Silence!
That'll be more effective after
your voice changes.
(sighs)
(in deep voice):
Silence.
(beeps)
Mom, can you take me
to Radio Shack?
Not today, baby.
I have to go food shopping
and get dinner started.
But it's important.
Sorry. Maybe over the weekend.
But it won't take that long.
Sheldon, I said no.
But, Mom...
Not another word.
What?
Can't I just be happy?
Mom, please!
Sheldon Lee,
I said no.
I'm still happy.
Please, Mom!
You're being unfair!
No.
But I really need those
thrust-to-weight ratios.
Do you see I'm cookin'?
Well, take me after dinner.
Enough! I'm not takin' you
anywhere tonight.
(grunts)
ADULT SHELDON:
I'm not proud of it,
but as a child, I was prone...
to the occasional meltdown.
SHELDON:
Cheese and crackers!
ADULT SHELDON:
I'm sorry you had to hear that.
All right,
I finally got him calmed down.
How'd you manage that?
Easy. Gave him a hug
and a little cough syrup.
Mom!
It's not like he's
operating heavy machinery.
We can't keep putting
up with this behavior.
We need to ground him.
How? If you say "No playing
outside," he says, "Thank you."
Well, we need to do something.
It's just a tantrum.
It's what kids do.
You used to punish me
all the time.
That was different.
You were a pain in the ass.
I say no Radio Shack
for at least a month.
Sounds fair.
I'll go tell him.
I'd wait and tell him tomorrow.
He's a little loopy right now.
(laughs)
Good night.
She drugged our son.
ADULT SHELDON:
Thus began the longest month
of my life.
Without the ability to access
the thrust-to-weight ratios,
my well-intended effort
to humiliate a NASA scientist
ground to a halt.
Mom.
Uh... what's going on?
Something's wrong with Sheldon.
(groaning)
What's the matter, baby?
Have a tummy ache?
I think it's an ulcer.
GEORGE SR.:
Don't be silly.
You must have eaten
something.
No.
My symptoms are consistent
with an ulcer.
Shelly, remember
when you thought
you had leprosy, and it was
just a patch of dry skin?
And when you thought you had
gout? Or an enlarged prostate?
Or mad cow?
That was my favorite.
Well, this is different.
Maybe we should take
him to the doctor.
Listen to your wife--
ulcers are serious.
Ow.
Well, I've never seen this
in someone so young,
but, uh, your son has an ulcer.
Thank you.
How could this happen?
Uh, there are
a number of factors.
Has he been under
some unusual stress lately?
Yes. She won't take me
to Radio Shack.
Go wait outside.
I've heard
some interesting research
about treating ulcers
with antimicrobials.
Go.
And you're surprised
I have an ulcer.
I'm surprised
I don't have one.
(clears throat)
Um, Radio Shack?
He's trying to figure out
how to help NASA land rockets.
Oh. Well, that's a nice thing.
He's just doing
it out of spite.
Okay.
Well, keep him
off spicy foods
for the time being,
and I'll write you
a prescription for Zantac.
Does he smoke?
'Course not.
He's nine.
(chuckles):
I started at his age.
Uh, but only when I drank.
(modem dialing up)
(modem whining)
What the...?
Sheldon!
What are you doing?
I just need a minute.
These things are so slow.
Is this your family?
They're lovely.
♪ ♪
Mom.
What?
There's something wrong
with Sheldon again.
SHELDON:
I figured it out!
One night.
I want to sleep one night.
Oh. Hi, Mom.
PETER GABRIEL:
Hi there.
("Big Time" playing)
♪ I'm on my way,
I'm making it... ♪
ADULT SHELDON:
With my research complete
and my ulcer on the mend,
all that was left to do
was send my work to NASA
and wait to become America's
scientific sweetheart.
♪ And I will walk
through the front door ♪
♪ Big time... ♪
ADULT SHELDON:
So I waited...
♪ Make it show, yeah ♪
♪ Big time ♪
...and waited...
♪ Oh, oh, oh... ♪
♪ ♪
(dial tone droning)
(dial tone continues droning)
...and waited.
♪ ♪
♪ Big. ♪
Something's wrong
with Sheldon again.
GEORGE SR.:
Now what?
MARY: Those people at NASA never
responded to his science stuff.
GEORGE SR.: Damn it.
I've had enough of this.
Sheldon, get up.
What's the point?
We're going to Houston.
Really?
Yeah.
You and me are gonna give
those space monkeys
a little talkin' to.
ADULT SHELDON:
I often found my father to be
a strange and puzzling man,
but at that moment,
I never loved him more.
♪ ♪
I don't see why I
couldn't stay home.
'Cause we're having
a fun family outin'.
Can I at least drive?
She said fun, not tragic.
Let's go to the ostrich farm.
GEORGE JR.:
Cool.
We can ride 'em, and
then we can eat 'em.
GEORGE SR.:
We're not stopping anywhere.
We're going to Houston
to straighten this thing out
for your brother,
then we're going home.
Shelly, you doing okay?
Yes. I just hope I
don't get carsick.
You want Daddy to pull over?
I'll be okay.
(vomiting)
MISSY: Oh, God,
it's on my shoes,
it's on my shoes!
MEEMAW:
For Pete's sake,
somebody open a window.
♪ ♪
Yeah, I don't
mean to be rude,
but we've been
waitin' for an hour
to see your boss.
I'm sorry, sir,
but you didn't have
an appointment.
We didn't have
an appointment 'cause every time
I called, you put me on hold.
I'm sure Dr. Hodges'll see you
as soon as he can.
So, what do you
want to do?
I don't know.
I guess we just got
to be patient and wait...
Aw, screw it!
Excuse me, sir,
you can't just...
All right,
here's the deal.
My kid's got
a damn ulcer 'cause of you,
so either you
take him seriously,
or you're gonna be
taking me seriously.
(intercom buzzes)
Yes, sir?
HODGES:
Janice, why don't you
send the little boy in?
(nervous chuckle)
Right away.
He'll see you now.
You're up, Moonpie.
And here...
near apogee,
we gimbal the engine
to exert a torque
that executes
a pitchover maneuver
to flip the rocket
by 180 degrees.
(laughs):
Well, that's very impressive.
Thank you very much
for taking the time...
I'm not done.
Oh.
Uh... sorry.
Needless to say,
we use a P.I.D. controller
to minimize the dispersions
to the landing site.
Anything else?
Yes. I'd like a glass of water.
It's time to take my Zantac.
(mumbles softly):
Oh...
He's been in there
quite a while.
Well, if the topic
is science, he can be
a really Chatty Patty.
I'm bored.
Me, too.
Hey.
Someday somebody's gonna write
a book about Sheldon.
Don't you want there
to be a chapter
about how loving and supportive
you two were?
Doesn't matter.
I ain't reading it.
This is groundbreaking work.
Thank you. And...?
And...?
I thought you might want
to apologize.
Well...
why?
You tried to shut me up
with a patch.
(chuckles nervously):
Well... I-I give those
to everyone.
A-And you have
to understand, Sheldon,
that while your math
is-is theoretically correct,
we don't have the technical
capability to execute it.
So I'm ahead of my time?
Well... it would appear so.
(chuckles)
All right, call me
when you catch up.
W... uh...
We can go now.
♪ ♪
♪ Rocket... ♪
ADULT SHELDON:
I've often contemplated
what might have happened
if my father hadn't stuck up
for me that day.
Would I have gone on to become
a world-class
theoretical physicist,
or just your average Joe
Sixpack theoretical physicist?
Dad?
Yeah?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
We're real proud
of you, honey.
Are you proud
of me and Georgie?
Of course.
You bet.
For what?
Don't go pokin' at it.
♪ ♪
NEWSWOMAN:
For the first time,
SpaceX has successfully landed
its Falcon 9 rocket
on a drone ship
in the Atlantic Ocean.
SpaceX founder Elon Musk
called the event
an "incredible milestone
in the history of space."
(intercom beeps)
Elon, the CNN reporter's
here to talk to you.
Hang on.
Send him in.
(clears throat)