(George Sr. and Mary laughing)
I thought you didn't like
taking the Lord's name in vain?
Oh, shut up.
(chuckles)
It's been a while, huh?
Don't blame me.
You're the one
who had a heart attack.
Mm, the doctor did say
I needed to get more exercise.
I think he meant
walks around the block.
No, he winked at me,
and did this little rotation
with his hips, like...
(laughs)
Mm.
Hmm.
Hey, we got any plans
this weekend?
I thought maybe we could get
started on the vegetable garden,
and then, of course,
church on Sunday.
Yeah, that does sound fun,
but what if, instead,
I was to go up to Bethy Creek
with Georgie
and do some fishing?
How long you been waiting
to spring that on me?
Well, not till I was done
rotating my hips.
You're awful.
(chuckles)
(scoffs)
So what do you say?
What about Sheldon?
What about him?
George.
You can't always leave him out.
I'm not leaving him out.
You know how
he is about fishing.
Get it away, get it away!
Calm down,
it's an itty-bitty thing.
No, I'm an itty-bitty thing!
Who says you have to
take him fishing?
Find something else
to do with him.
Something he'd like.
What are we gonna do?
Spend the weekend
sitting around, thinking?
George.
You have to make an effort.
Young boys who don't spend
time with their daddies
grow up to be oddballs.
Honey, I hate to tell you, but
that ball is already pretty odd.
Please.
Okay, fine.
I'll talk to him.
We'll think of something.
Good.
Thank you.
(grumbles)
(laughs)
What?
I was just remembering
when I took him camping.
SHELDON:
Moth! Moth!
GEORGE SR.:
Sheldon, it's just a butterfly.
How is that any better?
Butterfly, butterfly!
(screams)
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Hey, pal.
Playing with your rockets?
I'm trying to calculate
ballistic coefficients.
Well, that's fun, too.
Listen, I don't have
to work this weekend;
I was wondering if you wanted
to do something together.
Like what?
Whatever you want.
Well, the filter on my air
purifier needs to be changed.
How about a trip to Sears?
Yeah, I was thinking
along the lines of something
a little more active.
Like last year,
we went fishing...
Mom! Dad's trying
to make me go fishing!
No, no, it's okay.
We're not going fishing.
All right, good.
But seriously,
was fishing really that bad?
Mom! Dad's trying to convince me
that fishing wasn't that bad!
Shh. Come on!
Forget I said anything
about fishing.
Just think about it,
and we'll do whatever you want.
Thank you.
There is the launching of
the space shuttle this weekend.
Space shuttle?
Don't they do those
out of Florida?
Yes. Cape Canaveral.
Sheldon, that's-that's like
a 12, 15 hour drive.
I understand. Never mind.
You know what? Let's do it.
It'll be fun.
The three Cooper boys
on a little adventure.
Sound good?
Sounds good.
ADULT SHELDON:
My plan was coming together.
I just needed to get
on the shuttle
so I could finally escape
this ridiculous planet.
Spoiler alert, I'm still here.
So, Sheldon, me and Georgie
are gonna take
a little road trip this weekend,
see the shuttle launch.
Looks like I don't
get a vote in this.
Oh, good, you're catching on.
I wonder if we'll get
to meet an astronaut.
I remember
when I was a teenager,
I had the biggest crush
on John Glenn. (chuckles)
I would've given it up
for him no problem.
Mom.
Given what up?
Her allowance.
Just eat.
So how long
are you gonna be gone?
Oh, we'll leave first thing
Saturday morning,
stay the night in a motel,
and see the launch
bright and early on Sunday.
I can't believe
we're going to see
an actual working spacecraft.
Look how happy he is.
Good job.
How come I don't get to go?
'Cause you, me and Meemaw
are gonna have our own fun.
Could we shoot guns
at the gun range?
Mm, you're too young
to go to the gun range.
Meemaw took me.
We pinky swore.
What are you doing?
Oh, yeah.
Don't listen to me.
I don't know what I'm saying.
I know you like
to just keep driving,
and get where you're going,
but you can't ignore
his bathroom schedule.
I know.
He goes number one
first thing in the morning,
then again in the afternoon,
once more in the late afternoon,
say 4:00, 4:30,
depending on his juice intake,
and then, a quick piddle
before bedtime.
"Piddle." Got it.
Now,
number two's a little trickier.
Mary? Relax.
I can take care of my son.
I know.
Good.
I'm just saying,
if he's upset
or nervous,
he can get all clogged up.
I won't let that happen.
Thank you.
Okay, let's talk about food.
No need to.
He likes his meat cooked
to at least 165 degrees,
except for chicken,
which is 180.
The different foods can't touch
each other on the plate.
Ketchup and mustard
must come out of a packet.
No bottles.
What about his issues
with spaghetti?
That's a trick question.
He likes spaghetti.
All right, I guess you got this.
(door opens)
Georgie.
(knocks on door)
Up and at 'em.
Missy, where's
your brother?
Who cares?
Sheldon, you in there?
GEORGE JR.:
Dad!
Sorry, Georgie.
What's going on?
I can't find Sheldon.
What do you mean,
you can't find him?
I mean I don't know where he is.
Well, he's got to be somewhere.
Maybe he got that time machine
to work.
Where the hell...
George.
MARY:
I think he's ready to go.
(grunts)
MARY:
Wait, Georgie.
Where's your bag?
Don't need one.
Got my toothbrush right here.
What about clothes?
A change of underwear?
Got it.
Georgie, you're gonna
be gone for two days.
I'll turn them inside out.
Shotgun!
No, no.
Let your brother sit
up front for a change.
I actually prefer
sitting in the back.
It's safer.
Oh, come on, sit up front
with your daddy.
He doesn't get to spend
enough time with you.
I called shotgun.
George.
We'll flip a coin.
All right?
Georgie, call it.
Heads.
Tails.
Dang it.
Sheldon, you won.
You get to ride up front.
Can't we do two out of three?
You won. Get in the car.
What's the point
in calling shotgun?
You're a good dad.
If I don't kill one of them
before Sunday, I'm a good dad.
Have fun.
Love you guys.
Bye! Drive safe!
(engine starts)
Oh, this was a good idea,
this was a good idea,
this was a good idea.
This was a good idea.
Isn't this exciting?
It's just us girls,
no boys in the house.
The place already smells better.
(laughs)
So what are we gonna do?
How would you like
to go to the beauty salon
and get all done up?
Can I have orange hair
like Cyndi Lauper?
I don't think so.
Meemaw has friends
with blue hair.
She's right.
I haven't gone there yet,
but after a certain age,
it's mandatory.
(chuckles)
Your hair's not changing color.
Aw.
Sorry, kiddo.
Your mom is no fun.
Excuse me, I'm fun.
So I can color my hair?
Not a chance.
But I'm very much fun.
Whatever you need to believe.
Mein Führer.
(rock music playing)
(music continues faintly
over headphones)
Dad?
Yeah?
Would you like
to have a conversation?
Yeah. Sure.
Absolutely.
All right, what would you
like to talk about?
Um, well, let's see.
Uh... have you given much
thought to what you want to be
when you grow up?
I have.
Great.
And what would that be?
Oh. Most likely a scientist.
Unless I stay in Texas,
then I'm thinking cattle baron.
Cattle baron?
Assuming I don't have
to touch the cows.
Goes without saying.
Did you always want
to be a football coach?
Well, I always
wanted to play.
At least till
I got hurt.
Mm.
Were you a good player?
Eh, not really.
I was just bigger
than the other kids.
So you compensated
for mediocrity
by being large.
I guess.
That works for cattle as well.
Oh, well, thanks for
pointing that out.
You're welcome.
(loudly): You might want to
open a window.
Oh, boy.
(rock music continues playing)
Oh...
♪ Whoa, oh, oh, yeah... ♪
My head is so hot.
(chuckling):
She is such a hoot.
You okay?
Fine.
Okay, don't tell me.
MISSY:
So hot...
I don't like you
making me out
to be the bad guy
just 'cause I won't
let my daughter do
whatever she wants.
I gave you a lot
of freedom,
you turned out okay.
You didn't
give me freedom.
You were never around.
Is that so?
I guarantee I made supper
for Charlene and Edward
more times than you ever did.
I basically raised 'em.
You think I was
out dancing?
I was out working two jobs
so your daddy could
lose all our money on that
damn chain of Fotomats!
It wasn't Daddy's fault that
those little things blew over
every time
there was a storm.
Hmm.
Seriously,
I'm melting.
GEORGE JR.:
Dead armadillo.
That's three for me.
This is a terrible
driving game.
Is it roadkill if
it's still twitchin'?
Huh, both alive and dead,
just like Schrödinger's cat.
I didn't know he had a cat.
You've heard of Schrödinger?
Sure. It's the kid
from Charlie Brown
who plays the piano.
Lucy's got
a crush on him.
(sighs) Schrödinger's cat
is a thought experiment.
A cat in a box is
exposed to poison,
and is both alive and dead
until it is observed.
So the cat's name
is Schrödinger?
No.
Well, what's its name?
Its name doesn't matter.
It does if the cat was dead.
Otherwise, what are you gonna
put on his tombstone?
Not likely the cat's
getting a tombstone.
It would in a pet cemetery.
(Sheldon sighs)
Fine, the cat's name
is Mittens.
Because he has
little white feet?
Sure.
So, in this thought
experiment,
do you think Mittens
is dead or alive?
There's no way of saying
until you open the box.
Oh, come on.
Optimistically, I would choose
to believe he's alive.
Yes!
Oh, thank goodness.
GEORGE JR.:
Oh, dead crow.
There ain't no doubt
about that one.
The toilet was sanitized
for my protection.
I love this place.
Dad, can we go
to Reptile World?
No.
They a got snake
so big it can eat
a whole chicken.
Oh, well, in that case, no.
Aw.
Let's get some sleep.
We got to get up early if we're
gonna get to Cape Canaveral
in time for liftoff.
I'm so excited,
I don't know if I can.
Well, buddy, you're
gonna have to try, all right?
You two share that bed,
I'll take this one.
No.
Nuh-uh.
Come on, fellas,
I'm the biggest.
It makes sense that
I get a bed to myself.
No.
Nuh-uh.
(sighs)
We'll flip for it.
Georgie, call it.
Heads.
(clicks tongue)
Not your day.
Dang it.
That looked like heads.
Go brush your teeth.
This really works?
Your hair will look
just as pretty tomorrow.
Now, come on,
let's tuck you in.
I'm glad I don't have
orange hair.
Me, too, baby.
I want to be
more like Madonna.
Are you trying to kill me?
'Cause if you are, good job.
Why is she only like a virgin?
MARY: Good night!
(door closes)
You ready to finish
our conversation?
There's nothing
to finish.
I raised myself
like a jungle child.
End of story.
Oh, stop being so dramatic.
You think I didn't feel bad
not being around more
than I wanted to be?
Did you?
A little bit.
I'm teasing, come on.
Of course I did.
Why else would I have
begged you and George
to move back to Medford?
So you could be with
your grandchildren.
And you.
Really?
Yeah.
You're the only one of my
children still talking to me.
No surprise there.
Besides, you raised yourself
better than I ever could.
You actually believe that?
No, but it would help
my cause if you did.
(sighs)
Your hair looks pretty.
Enough.
(snickers)
(chuckling)
(snoring softly)
(whispering):
Dad?
Dad.
(snorts)
What?
Georgie keeps kicking me.
Kick him back.
I'd rather not touch him.
You want to sleep with me?
Yes, thank you.
Yeah.
Got enough room?
Yes.
You throw off
a lot of heat.
Sorry.
That's all right.
It's kind of nice.
(thunder rumbles)
Do they launch those shuttles
in the rain?
I think a light rain's okay.
(thunder crashes)
Oh, no.
It'll pass.
Just get some sleep.
(thunder crashes)
It didn't pass.
Sheldon, I'm real sorry.
Can I tell you a secret?
I never understood
how lightning works.
Didn't they teach you
that in high school?
They probably did,
but I got hit in the head
a lot playing football.
Would you explain it
to me?
Well, when positive and negative
charges grow large enough,
a giant spark occurs
in the cloud.
Ah, that-that's pretty cool.
What causes the thunder?
It's a shock wave from particles
heated to 10,000 degrees.
Interesting.
You want to know what's
really interesting?
Hmm?
Aristotle thought that
the sound of thunder
was due to a collision
between two clouds.
He believed the clouds were
expelling air,
in the way a log on
a fire crackles...
ADULT SHELDON: I didn't realize
until years later
that my father was
only asking questions
about lightning and thunder
to cheer me up.
In fact, he would often
pretend to be dumb
just to make me feel better.
Looks like rain.
ADULT SHELDON:
My brother, on the other hand,
didn't have to pretend.
Okay, on the count of three,
we run to the car.
Ready? One, two...
Wait.
I want shotgun going back.
Fine, you get shotgun.
Okay, here we go.
One, two...
I still think
we should wait
till the rain slows down.
GEORGE SR.:
No, we got to get home.
I got work tomorrow,
you guys got school.
You do realize I'll get wet?
It's just water, Sheldon.
All right.
Just making sure you realize.
All right, here we go. Ready?
One, two, three.
(car doors open, close)
(engine starts)
(car door opens, closes)
Buddy, I thought
we had a plan.
You had a plan.
(screaming)
(screaming continues)
♪ ♪
ADULT SHELDON: I never did get
to see a launch in person,
but that was the best trip
I ever had.
I wish I had told my father
while he was alive.