CAPTAIN KIRK:
The Enterprise is preparing
to leave Beta III
in star system C-111.
Sociologist Lindstrom
is remaining behind
with a party of experts
who will help restore
the planet's culture
to a human form.
SPOCK:
The Late Landru, Captain.
A marvelous feat of engineering.
A computer capable
of directing the lives
of millions of human beings.
But only a machine, Mr. Spock.
The original Landru programmed
it with all his knowledge,
but he couldn't give it
his wisdom, his compassion,
his understanding, his soul.
I prefer the concrete,
the graspable, the provable.
You'd make a splendid computer,
Mr. Spock.
That is very kind of you,
Captain.
That's humorous, because Spock
is half human and half Vulcan.
But he's ashamed
of his human side.
That's why I
identify with him.
Good luck.
MEEMAW: I gravitate
a little more towards Kirk.
Why?
(imitating Shatner):
Be-cause... everything
he says...
he makes sound
so im-portant.
I should hope so--
he's the captain.
Sheldon.
Do me a favor.
Go help your brother study
for his math test tomorrow.
Is that really a
good use of my time?
Come on. I'm asking nice.
If he doesn't pass, he
won't be able to play football.
You realize
he's often mean to me.
So? Your mother's mean to me.
I still try to be helpful.
Does she break
wind on your head?
Because that's what
Georgie does to me.
Can you help me out here?
I'll do it if you take
me to the train store.
You got it.
And buy me
whatever I want.
Connie, what are you doing?
(imitating Shatner):
Just providing
my grandson
with financial guidance.
(quietly):
Don't mock the captain.
If Georgie passes his test,
I'll get you whatever you want--
under 20 bucks.
Deal.
Why?
I guess I like him
better than you.
(knocking)
Georgie?
What?
Dad told me
to help you study
for the math test.
I don't need your help.
Get lost.
GEORGE SR.: Georgie,
let him help you!
Fine. Come in!
(rock music playing on stereo)
Oh, dear.
What's your problem?
No problem.
I'll just...
tidy while we talk.
Help yourself.
Before we start, I'd
like to get a sense
of how much algebra
you know.
'Kay.
Do you understand
solving and graphing
linear inequalities?
Sure.
Great. Explain it to me.
Uh...
first you solve 'em...
and then you graph 'em.
And how do you do that?
Uh, you know,
carefully.
Excuse me.
(door closes)
$20 isn't gonna do it.
(chuckles)
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
So you collect all
the terms linear in X.
See? Simple.
Maybe for you.
No, it's simple for everybody.
Now you collect all
the terms linear in Y.
I don't get it.
Try this.
Close your eyes.
'Kay.
Can you see
the slope of the line given
by the coefficients of X and Y?
No.
What do you see?
Darkness.
Try harder.
Wait.
I see Elle Macpherson
in a bikini.
Ooh, it just fell off.
Dad!
I'll make it $40!
Keep going!
Maybe the problem is
you're not a good teacher.
Unlikely. Regardless,
I am your only hope.
What do you see
when you close your eyes?
I see quadrant one as red,
quadrant two is
soft and plush...
(sniffs) quadrant three
smells like lavender,
and quadrant four is overlaid
with a Fibonacci spiral.
That's really weird.
No. What's really weird
is doing simple algebra
and thinking
about a girl in a bikini.
I disagree.
Dad!
GEORGE SR.:
Keep going.
SHELDON:
And when you divide
by a negative number,
you have to reverse the
direction of the inequality.
I'm tired. I'm going to bed.
But we're not done.
You're going to fail.
I get enough of what you said.
I'll be fine.
ADULT SHELDON:
It was at that moment I decided
I was not cut out for teaching.
I consoled myself
with the knowledge
that I was wonderful
at everything else.
♪ ♪
Take one
and pass it back.
Take one and
pass it back.
As you all know,
this test'll count
for 25% of your final grade.
Be sure to show all your work.
If you get stuck on a question,
move on and come back to it
at the end.
And I shouldn't have
to say this,
but if there's any cheating,
I will see it.
I got eyes in the back
of my head.
I got more eyes than a potato.
(chuckles)
Ms. Ingram?
Yeah, Sheldon.
I'm done.
What?
I enjoyed it very much.
I'll take another
if you have one.
No, I don't have
another one.
J-Just read ahead
in the textbook.
Oh, boy.
ADULT SHELDON:
Seeing my brother struggle
was difficult for me.
As his tutor,
I took his failure personally,
almost as if I had failed.
Which was odd,
because I knew how dumb he was.
Georgie, how'd you do
on that math test today?
It was tough.
I don't know.
I'm sorry I wasn't more help.
Me, too.
That's all right, baby,
you tried.
Yeah. It's okay, baby.
I don't understand
what went wrong.
Is there any chance
you drank alcohol
when you were pregnant
with Georgie?
No!
Well, don't be
so high-and-mighty.
I drank when
I was pregnant with you.
You turned out fine.
These days everybody's like,
"Don't drink, don't smoke."
I swear. Texas is
turning into California.
You realize there's nothing
I can do if you fail.
You're off the team.
I know.
Well, I'm gonna ask Jesus
to help you get
a good grade on that test.
Shouldn't you have asked him
before he took it?
The man rose from the dead--
I think he can fix a test
after the fact.
You know, I hear you
say things like that,
and I wonder if maybe I did have
a few too many whiskey sours
when you were in my belly.
(sighs, clicks tongue)
Not me, but not bad.
I would say "A" for effort,
but... that's an "F."
What? How bad is it?
You got a "B."
Are you kidding?
I don't believe it.
Me, neither.
(whistle blows)
So, I guess I have
to rethink my abilities.
Clearly, I'm
a wonderful teacher.
Georgie didn't pass
because of you.
What do you mean?
He cheated.
He had the answers written
on the bottom of his shoe.
He wouldn't do that.
When you cheat in school,
you only cheat yourself.
Where'd you get that?
An inspirational poster
outside the boys' room.
I saw what I saw, Sheldon.
Well, if this is true,
he needs to turn himself in.
That'll never happen.
He'll get kicked off the team.
I'm sorry, I can't
accept this.
There must be
another explanation.
If you don't believe me,
look at his shoes.
I will.
(grunting quietly)
(strained grunt)
This is quite a workout.
♪ ♪
(whispers):
You dirty bird.
What are you doing in here?
You cheated.
No, I didn't.
I'm holding the evidence.
Let me see that.
(spits)
I don't see nothin'.
(gasps):
That's obstruction of justice,
as well as disgusting.
Oh, relax. By passing that test,
I get to play football,
and you get to go
to the train store.
Everybody wins.
But what about the truth?
What about it?
It's supposed to set us free.
Who told you that?
The Bible.
Since when do you care about
what's in the Bible?
When it helps me
win an argument.
The Bible also says honor
thy father and thy mother.
And if you open your mouth,
you're gonna make them sad.
ADULT SHELDON:
He had me.
Somehow, the mullet-headed
simpleton had me.
This isn't over.
Oh, yeah? What are you gonna do?
All right, maybe it's over.
SHELDON:
Meemaw?
I assume you've read the
Surgeon General's report
on the dangers of smoking?
I'm gonna wait
till they turn it into a movie.
Is that your new train?
Yes. It's my reward for helping
Georgie pass the math test.
You don't seem too happy
about it.
I don't feel like I earned it.
Why not?
Can you keep a secret?
Well, at my age, the question
is can I remember one.
Try me.
(whispers):
Georgie cheated on the test.
Oh.
And nothing bad happened.
He gets to stay
on the football team,
Mom and Dad are proud of him;
I even got a train for helping.
So you're feeling guilty.
Very much so.
Well, that's
a real conundrum.
Have you been reading the
Word of the Day calendar
I gave you for
your birthday?
Indubitably.
(chuckles)
So what do you think?
I don't think you should
let it bother you very much.
I mean, there's always gonna be
people in this world
who are playing fast and loose
with the rules.
And your brother's one of them.
That's how Captain Kirk is
on Star Trek.
Well, there you go, and he's,
like, the main guy on that show.
No, Mr. Spock is the main guy.
I stand corrected.
Although Kirk is usually the one
who saves the Enterprise.
Because he doesn't
always follow the rules?
He even cheated on a test
when he was a cadet.
The Kobayashi Maru.
The what?
Kobayashi Maru.
Kirk is a legend because of it.
(chuckles)
Ko-Kobayashi Maru.
Sounds like something
you eat at Benihana's.
Have you ever been
to one of those?
They make you sit
with strangers.
It's crazy.
Do you think a Spock
could become a Kirk?
Well, in my experience,
most people stay
the miserable bastards they are
their whole entire life.
But...
I have seen some folks change.
Hmm.
All right. Well, I'm gonna
go play with this train.
You do that.
(sighs)
(knocking on door)
SHELDON:
Georgie?
Go away.
I need to ask
a favor.
What?
It's private. Can I come in?
(sighs)
Come on.
Ugh.
What do you want?
It occurs to me
you have something in common
with Captain Kirk.
We both have cool hair?
In order to succeed,
you both play fast and loose
with the rules.
Yeah, I suppose we do.
When you cheated on the math
test, what was your strategy?
Well, I guess the most
important part
was not stepping on anything wet
before the test.
And not getting an "A."
Why wouldn't you want an "A"?
'Cause that would
raise suspicions.
Who would believe I got an "A"?
Wow.
Tell me more.
Okay, when you're telling a lie,
it's important to throw in
some details.
Like, when I was wanted to spend
the night at Ricky's house,
and Mom asked me if his mom
and dad were gonna be home,
I said, not only
are they be
gonna be home,
his dad was gonna teach us
how to cook turkey legs
in the smoker.
I like turkey legs.
Were they good?
There weren't any turkey legs,
you dope.
His parents were in Branson.
That's incredible.
I totally believed you.
Details.
Now get out of here,
I got to finish reading this.
Thank you, Georgie,
that was very helpful.
(man speaking on TV)
Did you hear that?
What?
Sounds like Georgie
and Sheldon
are getting along.
Really?
That can't be right.
I just heard it.
Maybe there's hope
for those two after all.
Or it's a sign of
the apocalypse.
Honey, I'm-I'm watching this.
(exhales)
So you'll have to
find someone else
to hold your ankles
in P.E. today.
I'm sorry, what?
I've suffered a terrible injury
and won't be able to attend.
What happened?
See for yourself.
"Dear Coach Wilkins,
please excuse my son, Sheldon,
"from P.E.
"He has experienced
a testicular hernia,
"and needs to rest for the next
six to eight weeks.
Sincerely, Mary Cooper."
Testicular hernia?
That's called details.
Ooh, that's rough.
Hmm.
How'd it happen?
It's hard to say,
but some risk factors include:
heavy lifting, a chronic cough
and repetitive straining
during bowel movements.
I've been there.
Hmm. All right.
Guess I'll see you in...
six to eight weeks.
("Bad to the Bone"
by George Thorogood playing)
ADULT SHELDON: I don't know
if other supervillains
started their careers
by getting out of P.E.,
but that's where I began.
Emboldened by my faux hernia,
I started taking books
out of the library...
without getting
the cards stamped.
You didn't check
out those books.
I know.
Before you judge me
too harshly,
I always brought them back
on time.
I was a rule-breaker,
not a lunatic.
But perhaps my most
satisfying transgression
was duping my sister
into relinquishing control
of the TV.
Hello.
What's that for?
Oh, this? I was just digging
for money in Meemaw's backyard.
There's money there?
Oh, yes. I already
found 75 cents.
Who do you think left it?
If I were to guess,
I'd say pirates
with holes in their pockets.
Can I use your shovel?
Be my guest.
MISSY: Oh, baby,
I'm gonna be rich.
Today, we're going to learn
about Sir Isaac Newton.
Hello, old friend.
...one of the world's
greatest scientists...
(school bell rings)
(grunts)
See you tomorrow, Wayne.
You have a good one, George.
Hey, how's your son doing?
Georgie?
No, the smart one.
He's fine. Why?
What about the hernia?
What hernia?
The one your wife said he had.
Happened to me
while I was in the Army.
I was in a bar in Georgia,
tried to lift up this big gal.
Swear I could hear something
pop down there.
Sheldon gave you this note?
Yeah.
I didn't write this.
You sure?
Looks like your
handwriting.
It's got that little
swoopy thing going on.
I didn't write it.
And I think I'd know
if my son had a hernia.
So what, Sheldon forged a
letter to get out of P.E.?
Looks like it.
How about that.
Don't be proud of him.
Can't help it. First time
he ever seemed like my kid.
Do you have any idea
what's gotten into him?
I might.
Well?
Have you ever heard of...
Mobokachi Kaboom?
Wait.
Koshimaki Magoo.
Wait a minute,
I'm gonna get this.
"Dear Professor Proton,
"I would very much
like to meet you,
"and I only have
three weeks to live.
"Please come visit me here
in Medford, Texas.
"Sincerely, Sheldon Cooper.
P.S. My Meemaw makes
excellent brisket."
MARY:
Sheldon.
Would you like
to explain this note?
Well?
I was trying to be
more like Georgie.
That's a dumb idea.
We don't want Georgie
to be like Georgie.
Well, let me start by saying
how very sorry I am.
ADULT SHELDON:
Despite my explanation
that I was embracing
my inner Kirk,
my mother had me make amends
for all my misdeeds.
Starting in the library,
where I had to reshelve
hundreds of books.
Well, to be honest,
that one was a hoot.
The amends got worse when Coach
Wilkins made me climb the rope.
Lacking any
upper body strength,
I hung there like a salami
in a deli window.
And finally, I had to apologize
to my meemaw,
who was an unfortunate victim
of my sister's treasure hunt.
(shouts)
(thuds)