ADULT SHELDON:
On any given day,
our school gymnasium
presented
a cocktail of horrors.
(screams)
From daily humiliation...
...to school-sanctioned
violence...
BOY:
Oh!
But one day a year,
the gymnasium was transformed
into a haven of learning
thanks to a remarkable
institution
known as the science fair.
A chance for the student body
to come together
in the name of research
and progress.
Uh, while some did
the bare minimum...
(burps)
...and others preferred
razzamatazz over raw data,
I set out to save humanity
from deadly asteroids.
And made it all neatly fit
on three poster boards.
The science fair may be
a competition,
but when the goal is promoting
knowledge, we're all winners.
PETERSEN:
And the winner
of the Medford High School
Science Fair is...
SueAnn Ludlow!
You've got to be kidding me!
Shelly.
(applause)
You people are crazy!
Hey.
All right.
SHELDON:
You're celebrating mediocrity!
(mouths)
Mediocrity!
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
I'll be in my room.
Oh, come on, Shelly.
You still got
an honorable mention.
Stop reminding me.
(sighs)
I hate to see him
so upset.
Well, give him a little
time, he'll calm down.
(door slams)
SHELDON:
Fiddle-faddle!
The F word.
He's real mad.
You don't always win in life,
he needs to learn that.
I know, but these are
big feelings for a little boy.
They're feelings everybody has.
It's part of growing up.
I guess.
SHELDON:
Poodle poop!
MEEMAW:
Okay.
Somebody's got to teach
this kid to swear,
it's embarrassing.
Sheldon, listen,
I know losing
ain't easy.
I deal with it on the
football field all the time.
(chuckles)
It's like that big game we had
last year against Nacogdoches.
We were down 28 points
at the half.
It was raining, it was muddy.
Everybody in the stands
had gone home.
But somehow,
we managed to claw our way back
to a tie with a minute left.
And then, they threw
a Hail Mary,
and the receiver stepped
out of bounds,
but the ref didn't see it.
After all that,
we lose on a bad call.
Believe me, I was furious.
But I sucked it up,
and I walked across that field
and I shook their hands.
I didn't hear a word you said.
Okay.
So while an animal cell
has a membrane,
a plant cell has a membrane
and a cell wall.
SHELDON:
Who cares?
Sheldon,
what are you doing?
Being disrespectful, sir.
Ah. How come?
Because I'm disillusioned
with the school system.
Georgie, do you know
what's going on with him?
Actually, I'm trying
to ignore it.
Well, get your feet
off the desk.
What if I don't?
I was sent to see
Principal Petersen.
What is it this time?
Youthful rebellion.
My voice hasn't changed yet,
but my attitude has.
I'll let him know you're here.
You do that.
Ma'am.
(door closes)
Sheldon Cooper's outside.
Who sent him now?
Givens.
Well, you know what?
Givens needs to man up.
Cooper's
a little boy.
It's not hard to handle him.
I'll send him in.
H-Hold on a minute, just...
Does he know I'm in here?
SHELDON (over P.A.):
Attention, students and faculty.
Oh, no.
This is Sheldon Lee Cooper.
What the hell?
We're taught that hard work
pays off, but that's not true.
I came up with a solution
to save Earth
from killer asteroids,
and lost the science fair
to SueAnn Ludlow,
and her frizzy hair machine.
But it wasn't just me who lost,
we all lost.
Wake up, people.
The system's broken.
Real innovation isn't valued.
Nowadays, it's all about
flash and style.
I blame MTV.
Luckily, my parents
can't afford cable.
We can afford it.
I urge you all to rise up.
(grunts)
They can't send everyone
to the principal's office.
Chew gum in class,
use a number one pencil,
go nuts.
This is Sheldon Lee Cooper
signing off.
Live long and prosper.
You better run, you little punk!
(grunting)
MEEMAW: I can't believe you sent
him to bed without his dinner.
That's right.
On spaghetti and
hot dog night.
That's rough.
He's got to learn.
Let's talk about something else.
Georgie, how was your day?
My brother told the entire
school we can't afford cable.
Oh, right. Missy?
Good, until I learned
we can't afford cable.
(sighs)
I've been thinking, and there's
something I'd like to say.
Unless it's an apology,
I don't want to hear it.
I'm quitting science.
Not an apology.
Spank him, Dad.
I'm really getting
worried about Shelly.
Acting out,
and now quitting science?
Oh, I'm sure he'll get
right back to it.
I've quit smoking and gambling
plenty of times.
Hmm. Look in my purse.
Nothing but cigarettes
and scratchers. (laughs)
(sighs) Maybe he should
talk to somebody.
Not it.
I meant a professional, George.
But way to be a dad.
(door opens)
Hey.
(chuckles)
Welcome back.
Thank you for seeing us
on such short notice, Doctor.
Oh, not a problem.
Sheldon,
I remember you.
Do you remember me?
I remember everything.
Okay.
Uh, you two, make
yourselves comfortable.
Me and my main man Sheldon
are gonna go
have a little chitchat
in my office.
I don't like chitchat,
and I'm not your main man.
Right on.
Have fun.
(door closes)
Now, Sheldon, I understand
you've changed your mind
about being a scientist.
And you're gonna
say I can't?
No. I think that's great.
You do?
Yeah.
I think it's important
to keep your options open.
Let me tell you a little story
about an extremely smart
young boy.
Me?
Me.
For the longest time,
I thought I was gonna be
a professional figure skater.
And then you became disenchanted
with the field like I did?
Exactly.
Someone skated
right over my foot.
And that was that.
I'm not sure
that's the same thing.
I'd say you lost your passion
the way I lost my big toe.
Hmm.
Don't draw in that.
Hey. We're all done.
How'd it go?
Great.
I feel a lot better.
Well, that's
just wonderful.
So, you're going back
to science?
No. In fact, I'm going as far
away from science as possible.
I plan to pursue the arts.
What kind of arts?
I've decided to become an actor.
Of course you have.
Why's he want to study acting?
The doctor encouraged him
to try something different.
Maybe he'll learn
to act normal.
How about you learn
to act nice?
You people don't appreciate
my sense of humor.
(chuckles)
As long as he starts behaving
himself in school,
I don't care what he does.
You know, I actually did
a little community theater
back in my 20s.
Is that so?
I had a good part
in Oklahoma.
♪ I'm just a girl
who can't say no. ♪
Say no to what?
Well...
To, uh, eating
her vegetables.
It was fun.
But I'm pretty sure
doing plays
is just an excuse to change in
front of each other backstage.
Really?
Yeah.
Theater folk just love to
take their clothes off.
How many people
saw you naked?
A lot.
Mom.
Enough.
Y'all don't understand
my sense of humor, either.
(indistinct chatter)
Hello. Are you Mr. Lundy?
My father is Mr. Lundy.
Well, then what should
I call you?
I guess Mr. Lundy.
My father's dead. (laughs)
I was told you're the head
of the drama department.
Mm-hmm, and the girls'
volleyball coach,
which, between us,
is the real drama department.
Was that a joke?
I thought so.
Can I help you?
I'm interested
in becoming an actor.
Well, good for you.
You've come to the right place.
You know, I-I've been
a professional actor
for years and years.
Really? What have you been in?
Well, have you seen
the mattress madness commercials
on channel 68?
I'm soft and firm
in all the right places.
Wow. You're famous.
Well, I...
And I was Carbucketty
in the Dallas-Fort Worth
Players production of Cats.
(purrs)
(laughs) Did you see that?
No, I'm afraid of cats.
Well, you realize the cats
are just the actors.
I still wouldn't risk it.
You're an odd boy,
but you make it work.
(chuckles)
Anyway, uh,
auditions are next week.
You're welcome to come on by.
Excellent.
I checked out a book on acting
so I should have the hang of it
by then.
Well, I like that confidence.
Thank you. Most people
find it off-putting.
I can see that.
ADULT SHELDON: To master acting,
I immersed myself
in all forms of the genre,
from silent films
to modern classics...
...to logic-defying
experimental work.
♪ It's great
to stay up late... ♪
Why are they all singing?
(mouth full):
Because it's a musical.
But why can't
they just say it?
Well, that wouldn't be
very musical, would it?
♪ The stars were shining
bright... ♪
And where is the
music coming from?
You're thinking
about it too much.
♪ So, good morning ♪
♪ Good morning... ♪
And how do they all know
the same dance?
Come on.
Moonpie.
♪ To you and you
and you and you. ♪
ANNOUNCER:
And it is intercepted.
Walking in is Kevin Smith
for the touchdown.
What are you looking for?
A brooch.
What's a brooch?
It's a piece of jewelry.
In my acting book,
there's an exercise
where you look for a missing
brooch in a convincing way.
Why?
According to the story,
it was given to me by a friend
so I could afford to stay in
drama school, but now it's gone.
Well, good luck finding it.
Thanks.
Wait.
You really believed I was
looking for something.
I did it.
I'm an actor.
You're a freak.
Oh, where the heck
is that brooch?
GIRL:
If I can change,
and you can change,
everybody can change.
Thank you, Eva.
That was a-a lovely
reading from Rocky IV.
All right, Mr. Cooper.
The stage is yours.
Thank you.
I'd like to begin with
a monologue from King Lear.
What?
I believe you're supposed to say
"break a leg."
Sorry.
Break a leg.
Poor naked wretches,
whereso'er you are,
that bide the pelting
of this pitiless storm.
How shall your houseless heads
and unfed sides,
your looped and windowed
raggedness defend you
from seasons such as these?
Oh, I've ta'en too little
care of this.
Take physic, pomp.
Expose thyself to feel
what wretches feel,
that thou may shake
the superflux to them
and show the heavens more just.
Holy mackerel.
♪ Don't cry for me, Argentina ♪
♪ The truth is
I never left you ♪
♪ All through my wild days ♪
♪ My mad existence ♪
♪ I kept my promise ♪
♪ Don't keep ♪
♪ Your distance... ♪
("I've Got Rhythm"
playing on piano)
♪ I've got daisies ♪
♪ In green pastures ♪
♪ I've got my girl ♪
♪ Who could ask
for anything more ♪
♪ Old man trouble ♪
♪ I don't mind him ♪
♪ You won't find him ♪
♪ Hanging 'round my door ♪
♪ I've got starlight ♪
♪ I've got sweet dreams ♪
♪ I've got my star ♪
♪ Who could ask
for anything more? ♪
♪ Who could ask for ♪
♪ Anything more? ♪
Ah.
(whoops)
That looked dangerous.
No, that looks dangerous.
We're back.
Hey. How'd the audition go?
Great. I got the lead.
You're kidding.
What's the play?
Annie.
I need to go learn my lines.
Now, I was a little unsure
at first,
but Sandy Duncan does
play Peter Pan,
so when you think about it...
Connie, you're not helping.
Okay.
(sighs)
Hey.
Hello.
(sighs) I want to talk to you
about this play.
I'm excited about it, too.
You know, if you play
the part of a girl,
people might make fun of you.
Mr. Lundy's trying
to push the boundaries
of drama in East Texas.
One way to do that
is cross-gender casting.
Let me rephrase that:
if you play the part of a girl,
people will make fun of you.
In Shakespeare's time, the men
played all the female parts.
No one made fun of it.
If Shakespeare went
to public high school,
it'd be a different story.
You know, Sandy Duncan plays
the part of Peter Pan...
Yeah, yeah, I heard.
(exhales)
I'm trying to protect you, son.
I appreciate that.
Good.
You're a football coach.
Isn't it your responsibility
to put in the best player
for the job?
I guess.
Well, I want to do this,
and Mr. Lundy said
I was the best.
Okay.
Can you at least wear pants
instead of a dress?
I'll give you a definite maybe.
Okay, who's excited?
I don't want to see Sheldon's
stupid play, it's humiliating.
That's why I want to see it.
We're going to support
your brother.
Not another word about it.
Can we at least sit
in the back?
Not a word.
Well, I'm excited.
Okay, everybody,
ten minutes to curtain.
No smiling, girls,
it's a hard knock life.
How you doing,
Mr. Cooper?
You in touch with
your inner Annie?
I believe so.
Good. It's a packed house.
(laughs)
Wha-- oh, what the heck?
Katie? Katie.
You're an orphan,
sweetheart, not a coal miner.
Let's tone that down, hmm?
(indistinct chatter)
(heart beating rapidly)
♪ ♪
Oh, dear.
I can't do this.
What are you talking about?
The play,
I can't do it.
There are
too many people out there.
Oh, that is just stage fright.
That's completely normal.
No, this is a full-blown
panic attack.
All right, listen to me.
You're feeling scared.
I get that,
but what you have to understand
is you're not going out
on that stage alone.
Everybody, gather around, hmm?
Uh, Sheldon,
have you ever been
to the circus?
Yes.
Okay, good.
I had a panic attack there, too.
My point is,
the trapeze artist
always performs with a net
to catch him,
to protect him.
And you are protected
by everyone standing here.
Nothing can happen to
you out on that stage,
because we're a team.
We are your net.
I don't know.
(sighs)
Sheldon, come here.
You...
are a star,
and that audience
deserves to see you shine.
(audience applauds)
ADULT SHELDON: Mr. Lundy gave
a compelling speech.
The audience did deserve
to see what they came for,
an eager boy bravely taking on
the role
of Little Orphan Annie.
You're looking for
a knuckle sandwich.
And in that respect,
they were not disappointed.
Pipe down, all of you.
Go back to sleep.
It's all right, Molly.
Annie's here.
(laughter)
Oh, thank God.
I'd tell you how
an East Texas audience
in 1989 responded
to a grown man playing Annie,
but I think you know.
Mm-hmm.
(whispers):
What's my line?
♪ The sun come out tomorrow ♪
♪ Bet your bottom dollar
that tomorrow ♪
♪ There'll be sun ♪
♪ When I'm stuck with
a day that's gray ♪
♪ And lonely ♪
♪ I just stick out
my chin and grin ♪
♪ And say ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
I think I see his underpants.
I told you.
Theatre folk just love to
show off their business.
♪ Always a day away ♪
♪ Tomorrow, tomorrow ♪
♪ I love you, tomorrow ♪
♪ You're always a day ♪
♪ Away. ♪
(microphone feedback)