Hey, what you reading?
A magazine.
Oh. Making a collage for school?
No, just reading it.
Look at that.
Maybe Sheldon isn't
the only bookworm around here.
Which magazine?
Cosmopolitan.
What?
It's a magazine
for today's woman.
Hey! I was about to find out
what turns a man on.
Where'd you get this?
Heather. I traded
a Fruit Roll-Up for it.
Well, this is going
in the garbage.
You sure?
It's got some great tips on
how to spice up your marriage.
My marriage is fine, thank you.
And you are not to bring filth
like this into our house again.
That's not fair.
Sheldon reads dirty stuff
all the time,
and you don't say anything.
He does not.
Check out the comic book
on his desk.
(sighs)
MARY:
What?
Oh, my goodness.
Oh.
Oh, my.
Hold on. No. No.
Th-This blue man's backside
is all over the place.
On page 112, you get to see
his front side.
(gasps) Oh!
(sighs)
I'll be back.
Where you going?
To give the owner
of that comic book store
a piece of my mind!
Cool.
And then I'm calling
Heather's mom!
Aw.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
♪ Someone told me long ago ♪
♪ There's a calm
before the storm ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ It's been coming
for some time... ♪
Are there any
Vietnamese superheroes?
There's one called
Half-Face.
Why?
The communist government
forced him to build bombs,
and one blew off
half his face.
The left half or the right half?
The bottom half.
That's an important half.
(door bells jingle)
Excuse me.
Did you sell this to my son?
I don't know.
Who's your son?
The little boy in the corner.
Which one?
Sheldon Cooper.
Oh. Yeah.
Look at him!
He is the same size as
one of the dolls you sell here.
Those are action figures.
Where is your sense
of responsibility?
Have you looked
inside this book?
Because I have.
ADULT SHELDON:
At that moment,
I felt a subtle heat
rising through my body.
I was used to being humiliated
by my siblings
on a daily basis,
but from my mother?
This was new territory.
Mom, you're embarrassing me.
Oh, is that right?
Well, guess what.
I don't care.
And if I catch you
doing it again,
I'll be back with my husband;
he is way scarier than me.
I doubt that.
Let's go.
But I came here with Tam.
Tam, you coming or not?
I'm good.
♪ I want to know ♪
♪ Have you ever seen the rain? ♪
♪ Have you ever
seen the rain... ♪
(door closes)
As you can see,
I'm not related to them.
WEATHERMAN (over radio):
And in local weather,
the tornado watch issued Tuesday
is still in effect for the area.
Stay right here for updates
as we get 'em.
I don't understand why
you'd even be interested
in a book like that.
One of the characters
is a scientist
who worked on
the Manhattan Project.
Well, it's filled with
violence and nudity,
and you are done looking at it.
But comics are a form of art.
You wouldn't forbid me
from looking
at Michelangelo's David
just because he's nude.
When a statue
of your naked blue fella
is on display at the Vatican,
we'll talk.
Actually, David is at the
Accademia Gallery in Florence.
Doesn't matter. I don't want you
looking at his bottom either.
Where's Mom?
Chewing out the guy
who runs the comic book store.
Why?
She found
an inappropriate comic
that Sheldon had
and went ballistic.
She also took my Cosmo.
What's a Cosmo?
A magazine for
today's woman.
Sucks for you.
You know, if I had something in
my room she might disapprove of,
I might be looking
for a real good hiding place
right about now.
I think I'm okay.
Your air vent?
(chuckles)
Boys are dumb.
D-U-M-B.
Dumb-a?
What are you doing?
Confiscating your comic books.
You can have them back
when you're 18.
You're taking
Casper the Friendly Ghost?
Ghosts are sacrilegious.
Nothing friendly about that.
Very well.
There's one more book
that belongs in the box,
filled with adultery, genocide,
and even human sacrifice.
You think you're so smart.
I do. And yet you continue
to treat me like a child.
You know what?
You want me to treat you
like an adult, you got it.
From this moment on,
I am done mommy-ing you.
Wonderful. Does that mean
I can have my comic books back?
Comic books are for children.
You're an adult.
ADULT SHELDON:
My new adult responsibilities
began that night.
Luckily, a cookbook
is nothing more
than a set of instructions.
And if there's one thing
I shine at,
it's following instructions.
Aw.
What's Sheldon doing?
(blender whirring in kitchen)
Cooking his own dinner.
Why?
He wants to take care
of himself like an adult.
I plan on putting that off
for as long as possible.
Really? It's a plan?
(clattering in kitchen)
Maybe I should go
keep an eye on him.
No. Let him handle this
on his own.
I wouldn't mind watching.
(sighs)
Let's just say grace.
(loud clattering)
I can't. I got to go in there.
If she's going, I'm going.
No one's going anywhere.
If he needs help,
he can ask.
SHELDON:
I don't need help!
Everything's under control!
(sighs)
You're really holding
the line on this one.
I'm sorry,
but he just pushed my buttons.
Don't be sorry.
I'm diggin' it.
Ew.
Gross.
I agree.
Pretty gross.
Y'all are mean.
How was your chicken?
Not bad. The dish soap
gave it a nice lemony flavor.
All right, bedtime.
Night, Mama.
Night, baby.
Have sweet dreams.
Love you.
Love you, too.
(kisses)
Sheldon, I assume you don't
need to be tucked in?
I can handle it,
thank you.
Okay.
Wow. No good night kiss?
That's up to your brother.
That won't be necessary.
Fine.
(door closes)
(TV playing quietly)
Had enough?
You gonna back down?
No.
He's real smart,
but he needs to learn
he doesn't know everything.
Woman, you are getting sexier
by the second. Whew.
Hey, now that you're
treating him like an adult,
can I have
his allowance?
That allowance is for chores,
which you already don't do.
Come on. We all know
I'm your favorite.
You're not even
his third favorite.
ADULT SHELDON:
Making my school lunch
the next morning
proved no easier than dinner.
(grunting, groaning)
Maybe you're turning it
the wrong way.
(straining): Don't you have
anything better to do?
Not better than this.
This is nothing
a little science can't fix.
All I need to do
is break the pressure seal.
(grunts)
I don't think
that was enough science.
MARY:
Morning, Missy.
Morning, Sheldon.
Morning.
Morning, Mary.
(clears throat)
Mom, you need to sign
this consent form.
What's it for?
Field trip.
Where?
Museum.
Which one?
Does it matter?
It's not like I'm gonna
learn anything, anyway.
It's the planetarium
at the science museum.
And I need you
to sign mine, too.
Oh. It's interesting
that an adult
would need his mother
to sign a consent form.
And here we go.
I don't need you to sign it,
the school does.
So you're saying
even the school doesn't think
that you're mature enough
to make all your own decisions.
ADULT SHELDON:
In that moment,
I was so angry with her,
I almost opened the jar.
(school bell rings)
I'm ready to go to college.
Okay. Where you thinking?
Somewhere with a good science
program, but far enough away
to make my mom cry herself to
sleep every night that I'm gone.
You're applying to
college out of spite?
I see why you're
the guidance counselor.
Okay, let's see.
What about Caltech in Pasadena?
I can't see myself
living in California.
I don't trust
their carefree lifestyle.
Okay. Um...
How about MIT in Boston?
Do they have
a strong physics program?
They're more of
an engineering school.
Next.
There's always Harvard.
Hmm. I don't like cold weather,
but I do look good in maroon.
All right, Harvard it is.
Thank you for your help.
Are you interested in
applying to a safety school
in case you don't get in?
Safety school. You're funny.
So, how was everyone's day?
I cut open a
frog at school.
For science class?
Sure.
We should put a lock
on the knife drawer.
(sighs)
What are you eating?
An English muffin with
ketchup and spray cheese.
No fair.
Lucky.
Sorry I spent an hour
making meatloaf.
MEEMAW:
So, Moonpie,
how's adult life treating you?
Very well, actually.
I'm working on my application
to Harvard.
Is that so?
Yes. And I'm planning
on transferring there
as soon as possible.
You're not going away
to Harvard.
I don't believe
you have a say in this.
Okay, well,
Harvard's real expensive.
How do you plan
on paying for it?
Oh, I'm sure
I'll get a scholarship.
Oh, are you?
Yes, I am.
(chuckles):
Okay. Okay.
Let's just take a deep breath
and talk about something else.
Fine.
I want to hear about that frog.
A different something else.
MARY: I just
realized something.
College applications cost money
just to send in.
They do?
$50, $60 a pop.
I don't believe you have
that kind of money, do you?
Will you excuse me?
I have to go take
a cold shower.
Hello, Randall.
I would like to apply for a job.
You would?
Yes.
I need to earn money
so I can apply to Harvard.
I thought about
going to Harvard,
but then I realized
The Shack is my passion.
So can I work here?
Excuse me. How much RAM
does this computer have?
Um, I can check
on that for you.
It comes with 640 kilobytes,
but it's expandable up to 768.
Well?
Do you even
have a résumé?
No, but I have a report card
that'll knock your socks off.
And what's the processor speed?
It has the Intel 8286,
so ten megahertz.
Sorry, Sheldon.
I think it's against company
policy to hire little kids.
But people say I'm like
an old man all the time.
Hey, I'm one of 'em,
but the answer's still no.
ADULT SHELDON:
When people wonder
why Radio Shack eventually
went out of business,
you can point to this moment.
(electronic door chime sounds)
Meemaw?
Hey! Looking sharp.
You're not gonna try to sell
me a set of knives, are you?
No.
It's a joke.
'Cause of the suit.
Okay.
I need money
for my Harvard application,
and was wondering if there are
any jobs I could do.
Hmm. My yard could
use a little weeding.
I'm not terribly fond
of outdoor work.
Plus, that garden gnome
terrifies me.
Ernesto has that
effect on people.
How much does the job pay?
Well, let me think.
How about a dollar an hour?
How about five dollars an hour?
How about 50 cents an hour?
Wait a minute.
What just happened?
I'll tell you what.
I'll give you a dollar.
Thank you.
(laughs quietly)
(TV playing quietly)
Hey.
You know how you think I
can't do anything for myself?
I do think that, yes.
Well, I have something
I'd like to show you.
You did some chores?
Come see for yourself.
I don't know if I'm ready
for another heart attack,
but here we go.
Feast your eyes.
You did all this?
I did.
You shoved everything in
the closet, didn't you?
Take a look.
I am impressed.
You should be.
There may be hope for you yet.
I thought that showed ingenuity.
Okay, here you go.
(wind rushing)
I got you a shovel
and a bucket and some gloves.
Did you check the gloves
for spiders?
Is this my first
day as Meemaw?
ELMER FUDD (over TV):
It's not?
No. It's duck-hunting season.
That, sir,
is an in-mitigated fabrication!
It's wabbit season!
Duck season.
(alarm blaring over TV)
Not again.
What's wrong, baby?
I'm trying to hear about
duck season and wabbit season,
but they keep talking about
this stupid tornado.
MAN (over TV):
The National Weather Service
has issued a tornado watch
for the following counties:
Angelina...
(wind whistling softly)
Hey, Shelly, how's
it going over there?
I hate everything about this.
(chuckles quietly)
You need to come home
with me.
No. I'm working.
There is a tornado watch.
Let's go!
Oh, come on, Mary.
We've had a watch
every day for two months;
nothing ever happens.
SHELDON: I think
you're just worried
I'm earning the money
to send in
my college application.
I am worried it is not safe
out here. Let's go!
I can worry about my own safety,
thank you.
I don't care
if you think you're an adult.
I'm your mother,
and you will do as I say.
(siren blaring in distance)
Well, that ain't good.
You believe me now?
Mom?
(thunder rumbling)
(glass shatters in distance)
I'm scared!
It's gonna be okay.
GEORGE SR.:
Georgie!
Help me get this
in front of the window.
On it.
Is this my bed?
Yeah.
Aw, it took me an
hour to make it.
(sighs)
You okay, Moonpie?
I'm all right.
I'm not. This is scary.
We're gonna be fine.
This'll blow through
in a few minutes.
(wind howling,
debris clattering outside)
I need to pee.
Can you hold it, baby?
We'll find out.
I'm not all right anymore!
Flashlights, guys!
What if it hits us
and we all die?
It's not gonna hit us!
I might hit you.
(thunder cracks)
But first,
I'm gonna hold you.
(house rumbling, glass shatters)
In the name of Jesus,
I place a hedge of protection
around this house and my family.
I command this storm
to skip over our home
in Jesus' name.
I wish peace
to every single person
in this room
and declare that not one of us
will get hurt
in this storm, in Jesus' name!
(wind howling)
Pray harder!
Okay.
(thunder cracks)
(storm fades)
(birds chirping)
ADULT SHELDON:
The good news was most
of our neighborhood was spared.
MARY:
Oh.
The bad news: my mother thought
she had something
to do with it.
Looks like your house is okay.
You were just worried I might
have to come live with you.
Oh, I think the word you're
looking for is "terrified."
Hmm. Better go check on it.
I'll come with you.
Be careful.
Mom?
Yeah, baby?
(door opens)
You would not believe
the pee I just took.
♪ I see skies of blue ♪
♪ For me and you ♪
♪ And I say to myself ♪
♪ What a wonderful world. ♪