-Ah!
-[woman] She looks excited!
I'm so excited because I love mess.
[man] It's a never ending battle
to fight the clutter.
-[knocking]
-Oh!
I want things to be more simple.
I don't know how to fix it.
With the baby coming,
it's gonna be more chaos.
[gasping, squealing]
[man] Oh, my God! We have too much stuff!
Hello, I'm Marie Kondo.
[in Japanese] My mission is to spark joy
in the world through cleaning.
Ching!
[narrator] Best-selling author
and world-renowned tidying expert
Marie Kondo is dedicated to inspiring
the world to choose joy
with the KonMari Method.
[in Japanese]
A feature of the KonMari Method
is that you clean by item
and not by location.
And we will always clean using
the same categories.
[in English] First, is clothing.
-[Marie grunting]
-[laughter]
I can't reach.
Next, is books.
[Iida] Giving them a little shake
and wake them up.
Then, paper.
[man sighs] I can't do the papers.
[deep groan]
The largest category is komono.
Komono is kitchen, bathroom,
and garage.
Everything miscellaneous.
Finally, sentimental items.
It's kinda hard to let it go,
because I really like this one.
[sniffling] This is kinda hard.
I don't want to just, you know, dump it.
But I wanna be thoughtful about it.
[man 2] From the moment she set foot
in our house,
she had this presence to her.
She wants to see this place turned around.
Marie brought a whole bunch
of joy upon our home.
This is amazing.
[girl] You're so cute! I love you!
You're so cute I love you, too. [laughing]
These are, like, happy, happy tears.
Thank you for what you've brought
to our home, really.
[woman] One, two, three. Jail!
-[boy] Goodbye.
-[laughing]
-One two, three, four, five six...
-Did you just say my name in vain?
...eight, nine, ten, eleven.
No!
[squealing] No!
-I'll cost you 3... 440.
-Four-forty.
We are the Mersiers.
Our nickname is The Fantastic Four.
Indeed.
And our son created that nickname
because all of us are outgoing,
-[Douglas] Mm-hmm.
-all of us are extremely silly...
[Douglas chuckles]
...and we're artsy as a family.
We-- We just go for it.
Whatever we're feeling, we just kinda do.
What do you guys think about making sure
that we can hit the park...
-Yes.
-...before it gets too dark?
Does everybody have clothes for the park?
-Do you know where they are?
-No. You know where they all are.
You know what I did?
I went into my dressers,
I took everything out to put it back in.
To find one pair of pants.
-I cannot find matching socks.
-[Katrina] Okay.
Well, freeze the game, 'cause I don't want
anybody getting extra money.
[Douglas] Do not mess up my board
'cause you know I'm about
to come back and win after--
No, I'm the one who's about to win!
[laughs]
Moving from Michigan, we had to downsize
coming from a four-story,
four-bedroom house,
now reduced down
to a two-bedroom apartment.
[Katrina]
Do you know where your pants are?
-Yeah, I just got some out.
-[Douglas] But I need shorts.
-You only have one pair of shorts?
-I have, like, three!
[Katrina] In L.A. I'm starting
a new adventure with my entire family.
We wanna take advantage
of the opportunities here.
Back in Michigan, it could be
sometimes one note.
-If you're a hair stylist...
-Mm-hmm.
...that work is limited in Michigan.
If you are someone in music,
-the jobs are limited.
-Indeed.
-Did you find your black shorts?
-Um...
We're gonna miss the sunlight
if we can't find 'em.
-[Douglas laughs]
-Real talk.
[Kayci] Mom, do you know
where my matching jacket is?
[Katrina] We've been living here
for a year and a half now.
And I must say...
it hasn't felt like home.
[Douglas] I mean, we're doing
the best we can because,
you know, it's a smaller space
than what we're used to.
But we feel stressed at home
because of the clutter.
[Katrina] It's an unnecessary pressure
and stress for them
to live tight like this.
It's just this one big cycle of...
jumbled scatterbrain.
That's a big red flag.
I don't want to live like that.
So, I need help.
[Douglas] We need help.
[in Japanese] When my family and I moved
from Japan to the United States,
we only brought things
that truly sparked joy for us.
For the Mersier family,
their new challenge is to downsize
the things that they own,
so it will fit in their new home.
[upbeat instrumental music]
[Marie, in Japanese] It's so cute!
Oh, wow!
The look of American apartments
is so cute.
Maybe it's the color.
Hello.
-Hi! Hello!
-Hi, come on in!
-Hi!
-[Marie] Nice to meet you!
-Nice to meet you.
-I am Marie.
-Nice to meet you. Douglas.
-Iida. Nice to meet you.
-Katrina. Nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
-Goodness, it's so good to see you.
-Welcome.
[Marie] Thank you!
[speaking Japanese]
I see a lot
of musical instruments already.
-Do you play--
-[Douglas] I'm a musician.
-[Marie] Oh.
-[Douglas] I play upright, the guitar.
-[Kayci] I play my voice.
-Oh, really?
She's a sing-- She's our singer.
-Wow. Great.
-Yeah.
[speaking Japanese]
So your whole family is in one band or...?
[laughing]
We look like it, huh?
No, I'm not in a band.
I'm the hairstylist and I dress them all.
-[Katrina] Wardrobe.
-Wow.
-She makes sure we eat, you know?
-Yeah.
[laughing]
-Let's start in…
-Yeah. We can go around. All this is...
-...the living room.
-Yeah.
-This is our multipurpose room.
-Yeah yeah yeah.
[Douglas] Mm-hmm.
-This is where we eat...
-Yeah yeah yeah.
...we also watch movies,
and we have a huge DVD collection.
[Marie, in Japanese]
Oh. Is this for your music?
Yeah.
[Katrina chuckles]
-So cool!
-Yeah. It's cool.
So cool.
-This is our tight, tight kitchen.
-Yeah.
[Douglas] It's my favorite room
not to be in.
[Katrina] Ay-ay-ay.
-This is what frustrates me, is...
-[Marie] Yes.
...I will come to get a glass, and it's
like all of the seasoning are in there.
And it just looks cluttered to me,
and it just... I stay out.
-[Marie and Iida speak Japanese]
-[Douglas] And Dad doesn't cook at all.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Did you use to cook?
No. I had one accident
trying to make oatmeal, and I was like...
-[in Japanese] Not since then.
-I order a mean carry out though.
[laughing]
[Douglas] Go into the bedroom.
The bedroom. So he takes this dresser
and I just try to put my life
in these six.
-Your underwear...
-Underwear, socks...
-and swimsuit stuff.
-Yeah yeah yeah.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Are you aware
of where everything is?
-[Katrina] Yes.
-She's the only one
-that's aware of everything.
-[Iida tarnslating]
We-- We ask her,
"Look for a special shirt,"
I'll say "Where is it?"
and she'll tell us.
Ah.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I'm sure it's a lot
when you get asked all the time, right?
Oh, my.
And they don't like my mood
because sometimes I'm like...
[Douglas] Katrina bears
a lot of the weight
of keeping the house organized,
and helping us to keep it organized,
because we don't know where things are.
It's the real daily struggle.
I'll be home alone,
and I'll just say,
"Dang, where is this? I need this now."
And I say,
"Mm, texting Mom. Gotta text Mom."
And it will be to a certain point
where I just spam her phone
until she answers.
That's how much I depend on her.
[Katrina] Have you ever seen such a thing?
[Marie] Every day.
[laughing]
-I love a mess.
-Do you?
-Yes.
-Yeah.
-Oh!
-You know what?
-This is so exciting for me.
-[Katrina] Is it?
-Oh, I'm so glad. I'm so glad.
-Yeah.
[Katrina]
I'll let the kids show you their room.
-[Marie] Oh...
-So!
Okay, let's open these up
to show you how embarrassing
our clothes are up there.
-[Nolan] Terrible.
-Oh, not tall enough.
-[Marie straining]
-I got it.
Oh! Hey!
I'm here for that.
He's good!
[Marie] It's Kayci's and it's Nolan's?
-[Katrina] Yeah.
-[Douglas].
The funny thing with this shelf,
so I bought it and I said,
"You take two shelves,
he takes two shelves,
and this can be
what you guys use during the day.
Keep it neat."
But they can't find anything.
[Douglas] So they'll pull everything down,
it'll be all over...
[Iida translating]
-Wow.
-[Katrina] Yeah.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I think it would be best
if they have a dresser of their own,
too, eventually.
Yes.
The other half of the room,
it is also cluttered.
There's no space.
It's hard for me to feel
like this an actual home.
[somber instrumental music playing]
So they have so much in the room,
because when I organize it,
they don't keep it organized.
It's okay Mom. It's 'cause--
-[Katrina] 'Cause I keep trying.
[Douglas] You're trying hard, I know.
Yeah, like, she organizes our things,
but we don't know how
to keep them organized,
so then when we mess it up
it just hurts her, and it hurts me too,
'cause I feel bad
after I mess it up, so...
[Katrina] I feel like I'm to blame
'cause I'm the mom and Mom is supposed
to create the memories.
Mom is supposed to make home home.
I hold that near and dear and I own it.
It's my responsibility to do the laundry,
go to the grocery store,
wash dishes, cook,
and I've got to clean the kids' room.
But I feel like I'm failing in that area.
Which is not okay with me.
I want to...
create a home
that they will remember, you know?
I want them to remember
where they had peace of mind
and they had a lot of love
-and that's where their support came from.
-Mm-hmm.
-As they were growing up.
-Indeed.
-Sorry.
-We have to help, Mom.
Let's keep showing her the other rooms.
-Yeah. It's okay.
-Mama!
-I'm okay.
-Mama, Mama, Mama.
-Mama, Mama!
[in Japanese] It'll be okay.
It seems like Katrina
manages all the family's belongings.
However,
through the KonMari Method of tidying,
I would like to teach the family
how to be responsible
with their belongings.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida, translating] So, we're gonna begin
the tidying process from here,
but there's something that I like to do
before we begin.
I always like to introduce myself
to the house.
Wow.
[peaceful music playing]
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Okay, great.
[speaking Japanese, laughing]
-[Iida] This is a very nice home.
-[Douglas] Thank you.
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] So, the first step is clothes.
-Okay.
-Alright. Let's do that.
[Katrina laughs]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] First, let's begin
with making a big pile
of all the clothes that you own.
-[Nolan] Snuggy!
-[laughing]
Oh, my--
-Ugh.
-[Marie chuckles]
-[Douglas] You got a lot of clothes.
-Actually...
[Kayci] Yeah, he has way more than me.
[Douglas] No. You always are like,
"I don't have anything to wear."
[Nolan]
That's 'cause they're always dirty.
-[Douglas] All his stuff is out.
-[Nolan] We did it!
[Douglas] Woof!
[Douglas laughing]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida]
How do you feel looking at your piles?
[sentimental music playing]
Seeing that much for her,
I'm definitely not setting her up
to win at life.
He's 12, she's 11.
We could have started this at age five,
just like you.
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Not too late, never too late.
-Mm-hmm.
-That's it.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So from here, we'll be selecting
the clothes that you want to keep
and what you want to let go.
Only keep clothes that sparks joy for you.
-Yes.
-Clothes that you've decided to let go,
thank it for all
that it's been doing for you.
-Gratitude.
-Yeah.
-Gratitude is very important.
-[Kayci] Yeah.
[Nolan] Done so much good for me.
I thank you for that.
You know,
your girl isn't gonna get rid of you.
How have I not worn you before?
You give me so much joy. Oh, my goodness!
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida]
For kids, you guys don't have drawers,
so I have something to recommend to you.
-[Douglas] Alright.
-[Katrina] Okay.
[peaceful music playing]
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] We're gonna create storage
out of these shoe boxes,
but it's only temporary for now.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] In an empty box,
stack them vertically like this.
-[Douglas] Oh.
-[Iida] There we go.
-[Nolan] Wow.
-[Douglas] That's unbelievable.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, you had put clothing racks
in your room, right?
[Douglas] Yes.
-[Iida] You can put the box in there.
-[Nolan] Oh, that's amazing.
[Iida] So then you can go ahead
and buy a dresser or...
you know, you'll know exactly
how much space you need.
With Marie coming to help us,
this is the opportunity
for me to learn how to organize
and to downsize, so that I can finally
make this place a home.
-Bye.
-[Douglas] I'll get that.
-We'll miss you. 'Til the next time.
-[Marie] Yeah.
-[Katrina laughing]
Oh, my gosh.
That was amazing!
-Can she come back, please?
-[Kayci] She blew my mind.
-I know, right?
-[Douglas] My goodness.
Let's get busy with the homework.
Right. We have to--
If you don't get your homework done,
you won't be able to sleep.
-Think about it.
-You'd better finish.
[Douglas laughing]
[Kayci] Are these my goggles?
[Nolan blubbers]
[Kayci humming]
[Nolan] Get out. Swim.
[Katrina]
It sounds like you guys are playing.
Come on now, do the right thing in there.
[Nolan] Oh, gosh, why did I do this
to these shoes, too?
[Kayci] What'd you do?
-This.
-[Kayci] Bro!
Oh, no. But those are such good shoes.
The first Jordans.
[Nolan] No!
[Katrina] How's it coming? Are you done?
-[Nolan] Almost.
-This is my problem.
-[Kayci] You can't--
-[Katrina] Finish.
You owe it to yourselves to finish.
Y'all don't wanna do this tonight, do you?
[Nolan] Nope.
[Katrina]
I get frustrated from the clutter.
I would like for home
to feel like home for them
and I feel like it starts with me. I do.
So I've ended up with doing
their homework for them.
Being a mom is demanding.
I feel accountable for...
downsizing, how things are organized,
so everyone's like,
"Mom, where did you put my this?
Mom, where did you put my that?"
And they know,
I like being able to say "It's here"
because I know
that in their mind it's jumbled,
and I know that the one thing I want
is peace of mind.
I want to give that to them.
But it bothers me slightly
that they come to me...
wondering where is everything.
It's overwhelming.
So I want-- I want them to get that.
[Marie, in Japanese]
We look like we're best friends.
[knocking]
-Marie, hi!
-Hi!
Iida, hi!
-Nice to see you.
-Good to see you.
Welcome, welcome.
I couldn't wait to see you today.
[Iida translating]
[Katrina laughing]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-It's raining so hard today.
-I know. I wish I could control it.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida]
Today's theme is miscellaneous items.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-I'll pull it.
[Iida] This category
of miscellaneous items,
there's a lot of different sub-categories
within this big category.
The trick is to start with something
that's easy for you.
You know, I can actually put this here,
so we can see what we have.
-[Iida] So bed linens for Kayci?
-[Katrina] Yes.
But I wasn't quite sure
if I was folding them properly.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] As long as you're folding it
upright like this, you've got it.
[in Japanese] Folding fitted sheets...
seem to trouble many people.
Fitted sheets contain...
rubber bands inside, so you cannot fold...
the edges together.
But don't worry,
take the sides towards...
the center,
creating a rectangle.
Whichever way you choose
to fold the sheets,
when storing in drawers,
if you store them standing upright,
they will look neat.
So, I kinda wanna set
the family up to win,
so I need your advice on that,
'cause you leave your family, right?
Do they maintain the way you have the home
organized and everything?
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Yes, as a family, each person has
a room that they're responsible for.
-But laundry, that's my forte--
-Right.
-I'm sure that's accumulating as we speak.
-Yes. Oh, my goodness, yes.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So I was wondering,
when I first met you,
I noticed that a lot of the cleaning
and tidying fell to you.
Do you think through this process
that'll change?
I think they'll be more proactive
because they now have some clue
of where their things are.
And instead of me doing it,
I think,
now I'll be able to just guide 'em,
and not just me doing it.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] You know, you're living together,
so it's important for everyone
to maintain their space
and their belongings, but not only that,
but to help each other as well.
[Katrina] Before Marie came,
I wasn't setting
my own self up to win as a mom.
I was doing too much.
Instead of being a homemaker,
I'm a make-it-work-maker.
Do what you gotta do to make it work,
be strong, be tough.
And that love is just
dwindling down because
no one person can do it all.
So, Marie's right.
We all need to work together, as a family.
-I like the idea of assigning everyone.
-[Marie] Yeah.
It gives them a job
that they're responsible for.
But I'm nervous about
the organization of it,
because they sort it
and I helped with the organizing, so...
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] It's perfectly understandable
for you to help and create
their storage spaces,
but I think it's important
is that every time you remind them
where everything is,
so that they start to learn.
To make-- Yes. I agree.
I'm going to adopt that, and...
I'm sure I won't have a problem.
They like teamwork, so, definitely.
[Iida speaks Japanese]
Thanks for sharing.
-[Iida speaks Japanese]
-[laughing]
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Thank you.
[Marie] Thank you.
[sighing]
-[Katrina] I want to load this bucket.
-Yes?
-With everything we can.
-Mm-hmm.
Take it out there,
so we can do it as a family.
Got it.
-I may get serious.
-[Katrina] Nolan! Kayci!
Calm down.
[Katrina] Everybody come
get one thing and we're done.
I got us in this hole,
let me get us out of it.
I feel like this is my chance
to redeem myself and to help the family.
So I'm excited.
-[Nolan] Yay.
-[Douglas] Bathroom's clear.
How are you guys feeling?
Did you know all this was in there?
[Douglas] Yeah.
I know you guys don't know...
where to find half this stuff.
This is the stuff you guys call me about.
-[Douglas] Yeah.
-So now that we can do this,
I'll know exactly where it is,
and more importantly,
you'll know exactly where it is.
Okay.
[Nolan] I want to learn
where I should put things,
but at the same time I kind of,
like my mom,
having to know where everything is,
because I don't have
to think about it as much.
[laughing]
That's the procrastinator
coming out in me.
Listen, you're gonna have
to take care of these things...
and find a home for them.
-Do you even have all the pieces?
-[Kayci] Yes.
-You have a knitting loom in here.
-Yes. Oh, wait, I knew that.
Let me talk about our new lifestyle.
If you opened this and saw this in here,
why not take this out
and go put it in its home?
Well, I didn't know to do that.
-[Katrina] So now--
-Now I do know.
-Let me ask you, does this have a home?
-Yes.
-Where?
-In my drawer.
[Katrina] At the end of this process,
I want my children,
my husband, and myself,
I want our family...
to know how to organize,
for the sake of having a home
and not just a house.
[birds chirping]
-[Kayci] Douglas.
-[Nolan] I'm chilling.
-You can do whatever you want.
-Mm-hmm.
But, just know
we've got some homework to do.
-[Douglas] Hey.
-[Katrina, on FaceTime] Hey!
So, when I came in, I was like,
"What's going on here?"
All this stuff is crazy.
[Katrina] That's trash.
This is all trash.
The box underneath is trash.
You can take out all of that trash,
and the only reason I didn't,
I love you so much,
is because it was raining.
Alright. Okay, thank you.
I'll talk to you later.
Duties in the house. We all do cleaning.
We all try to manage, um...
-Ahem!
-What?
Dad doesn't clean?
Dad doesn't do the bathroom.
Dad doesn't do the kitchen.
Not as much as you.
-Okay, hold on.
-That was-- Yeah, we do it way more.
I'll say this, you guys do do those areas
more than me.
But I do cleaning
when you guys are asleep,
picking up your backpacks,
picking up your socks,
picking up your shoes, sweeping.
I like to think of that
as straightening up.
-Yeah. I hear you.
-[laughing]
Ah!
-You flinched!
-You guys working nicely in there?
[Kayci and Nolan] Yeah.
Let's get to work.
-I have get the mail, take out the trash.
-Write it down.
-Recycling.
-You get the mail?
-Yes, I do get the mail.
-[Kayci laughing]
I'm laughing at you two.
These-- These just...
-Lie, lie, lie, lie, lie!
-[laughing]
-It's a lie.
-[Nolan] Oh, my--
-I'm so excited about you helping.
-[Douglas] Yeah.
You can put these back.
No. I was, uh, putting 'em out for drying.
I'm not gonna dry the clean dishes
with those towels
-'cause those are not clean.
-Got it.
[Douglas] I feel guilty about Katrina
having the majority of the housework.
That's one of the reasons
why I've been trying to be more active,
you know, with the cleaning
and the chores and the duties.
I can organize certain things
that I feel confident in,
but certain things
I just don't feel confident in just yet.
I left you this space.
You can keep sitting 'em right there.
-I didn't wanna do that.
-[Katrina] You can sit that right there.
What did you wanna do, Dad?
Yeah, it doesn't even matter.
How do you want me to grab 'em,
and dry 'em?
No, no, no, that's fine.
[Katrina]
I'm thankful to get help from my family.
Even though they're still, I think,
a long way to go,
I feel like my family is off
to a good start.
-[Marie] Hi, hello.
-[Katrina squeals]
-It's Marie. Hi!
-[Douglas] Hi!
[Katrina] Marie and Marie!
-Hi!
-[Douglas] It's been too long.
-[Katrina] Too long.
-We've missed you.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
We're gonna work together on the--
in the kitchen.
-Together. I'm okay.
-Yes.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Douglas, I'd love for you to work
on sentimental items, the last category.
I know that all the steps
that you've gone through
was very, very difficult.
All throughout, you've sharpened
your decision-making skills,
so you should be confident in your ability
to go through your sentimental items.
Alright, I'll start pulling the things out
to start the process. Thank you.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[laughing]
-Alright.
-Good luck.
Right. Good luck, I need it.
-Good luck to you.
-Wish me luck. Right.
-I'm nervous.
-Good luck. She's scared.
[girls laughing]
So, the items that are sentimental,
we're going to try to categorize those
for each individual.
So if you come across something
that you know that's Mom's,
put it in Mom's sentimental pile.
-[Douglas] Alright?
-[Nolan] Yeah.
[Katrina] No.
Thank you.
[Marie, in Japanese]
Something smells good.
American trash bags are amazing!
It smells so good.
American garbage bags smell nice.
[Katrina laughing]
This cabinet is ridiculous.
It's hard to reach.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Going forward, let's try to keep
things that we don't use as frequently
in hard-to-reach places like that.
[in Japanese]
When using kitchen cabinets,
in the area that is easily accessible,
store items that are used often
such as plates, glasses, and mugs.
On the top shelf,
store items that are used less often,
such as seasonal plates,
and plates for guests.
Paper plates and straws are also items
that are used less often.
These types of items
can become easily accessible
if stored in a box.
-Maybe a little bit more safe.
-[Katrina] Thank you.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] This one?
Yeah, Nolan just decided to keep it.
It was a sippy cup his godmother
bought for him and it's engraved.
-Yeah.
-And we asked him,
"Will you drink out of it?"
He's like "Yes, yes." And we're like--
[Iida translating]
We can put it with your trophies
or in the kitchen.
He said, "Put it in the kitchen.
Put it in the kitchen."
[Iida] Okay, so let's make this
a decoration for the kitchen.
-We'll decide a nice place for it later.
-[Katrina] Okay.
[Katrina] I love the way...
she doesn't make
any of the family members feel bad
about what they wanna keep,
or what they don't.
I mean, I'm learning.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] That's very important when
you're tidying, to respect each other.
Having a family of my own
and being a mother,
and I think that the things in our house
and all the family members in a home
kind of function the same way.
We each play a role and we only have
a limited amount of space
-and we all need each other.
-That's true. It's so true.
I understand. Thank you.
[Douglas] Thank you.
[Douglas] This process that Marie's
helping us with is uncovering layers,
not just to material things,
but, like, the layers between our dynamic
with our family.
Mom, she's been the one that
has been trying to keep us all together
and keep us organized,
and, so, now that we have
this tidying method,
I feel like we really need to keep it up.
-[Kayci] Mm-hmm.
-You know?
Not just for her,
but for ourselves, you know?
Before, I had the wrong mentality
to not want to engage and help,
and even...
not see the value
of learning something like this.
But, now, I realize the responsibility
should not be on Mom.
It should be on the family,
the members of that house.
[Douglas]
I'm gonna be the laundry champion.
[Katrina]
You gonna be able to sort it, too?
I'll assist you with sorting,
so I can learn.
-[Katrina] Mm-hmm?
-Gonna be a laundry champion.
[Katrina] Alright.
Stay on top of it.
[Douglas] I didn't realize the pressure of
having to do everything
until I actually did it.
So now I do want to help
with that a lot more.
I am working on organizing more of
my studio equipment...
that was under the printer area.
[Douglas] So all of your items
pretty much fit in your closet now.
Yeah.
[Douglas] Lot of hard work,
you're doing a great job.
Thank you.
[Douglas] Nolan and Kayci,,
they're doing a terrific job.
[Katrina] I'm literally looking at their
shelves and how they're organizing.
I can't believe
they did it without me.
You just feel so proud.
Our life is finally coming together.
That's how-- That's how I feel.
[Douglas] The kids are doing great.
You're doing great,
I'm trying to keep the energy high.
-We're gonna get through this.
-[Katrina] Awesome.
I'm definitely getting
instant gratification.
For one, I have the entire Fantastic Four
doing it with me.
[Douglas]
This is looking pretty good, guys.
I came around to check on everybody
and I saw the most amazing thing.
-[Douglas] What'd you see, Mom?
-Everybody had everything folded.
-They had it lined up, standing.
-Especially me.
Nice and neat on its own,
socks, underwear,
-shorts, anything that was difficult.
-Especially me.
-They had it all. Dad.
-[Douglas] I had it.
He had it all in a file system.
I could cry.
Like, my family is becoming a family.
My family is growing,
my kids are doing their own thing.
My kids know how to take care
of their resources.
New day, new joy! Whoo-hoo!
[Kayci] Marie brought a whole bunch of joy
upon our home.
I think my mom is way less...
stressed out.
I can see it in her face,
I can see it in her movement.
She lifted the weight
off my mom's shoulders.
A lot of weight.
Because now me and my sister can do things
by ourselves without asking her.
Where you gonna put those to dry?
Uh, I'll lay a towel out,
or I'll just dry 'em.
You know where to get the towels from?
I do know where to get the towels from.
-[chuckles]
-You know where to put the towels back?
-I know where to put the towels back.
-Okay, just checking.
[laughing]
I trust you. I trust you. I trust you.
This method has helped us to grow up.
I know for sure me.
I'm saying us, but I'm saying me.
I'm growing up here.
-You're growing up.
-Yeah.
[Marie, in Japanese]
I'm looking forward to this.
Everyone in the family
has worked very hard.
[Marie] Hello!
-Oh, hi!
-Hi!
-Hi, Kayci.
-Hi, Marie.
-So good to see you!
-Good to see you!
[in Japanese]
This place looks so lovely.
It's so lovely.
-We are so tired.
-[Marie laughing]
But so happy!
-[Douglas] Much different.
-This is amazing.
-It's beautiful.
-That's how we feel.
-Really proud.
-It was because of you.
-[Marie coos]
-[Iida speaking Japanese]
-[in Japanese] May I see the living room?
-Yes.
[Katrina] So, Marie, this room is now
much, much larger right?
[Marie, in Japanese]
It really transformed!
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Oh, the feeling around this TV
is just so different from before.
-[Kayci] It's nice and clean.
-[Katrina] Much different.
[Iida] Oh, and look at those
musical instruments.
-[Douglas] Joy. All around.
-[Iida] Beautiful there.
-[Katrina] You wanna see the kitchen?
-[Douglas] Let's go.
Right this way. Yeah, you can come.
-[Douglas] I'm gonna wash my hands.
-[Kayci] I need a tour.
[Iida] Oh, my God!
-[Katrina laughing]
-[Iida] This is incredible!
-[Katrina] That's how I feel.
I started making my decisions confidently.
Found my joy.
[Douglas] It felt so good in here,
I even came in here
and made a salad for everybody.
-[Iida translating]
-I never come in here.
[Douglas] Mom's been doing a great job.
She's been working really hard.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Phenomenal job, Katrina.
-[Katrina] Thank you.
-It was well worth it.
-[Douglas] A lot more space. Feels great.
[Katrina] My husband picked up
the dry cleaning
and did the laundry and folded it.
-[Marie] Helpful!
-[Katrina] That was so helpful.
Alright, Nolan, Kayci,
come show Miss Marie your room!
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Oh, how lovely!
-[Marie gasps happily]
-[Iida] Well done!
[Douglas] I was really happy
about the dressers
and them being able to utilize them.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] You guys worked so hard, I am so--
-[Katrina] We did.
-[Douglas] We wanted to make you proud.
-[Katrina] It's been a journey.
And I think about
to when you first arrived, and...
not only was the home all over the place,
-our lives were all over the place.
-[Douglas] Yeah.
See, the biggest thing for us was...
that we didn't have the ability to know
how to declutter, how to tidy.
But now, we have the ability
to continue to help the...
the kids to learn it,
and they've learned it at this early age.
And, so, that was very important to me.
This house is finally a home.
I feel joy and I feel peace being here.
[Marie coos]
-Thank you so much.
-[Iida] Amazing job, thank you.
-[Douglas] Thank you.
-Thank you. Mm-hmm.
-[Katrina] I feel proud.
-[Douglas] Yeah.
I thought that moving here
and living in this space
was something I just had to take.
-Something I had to go through.
-Deal with.
Deal with.
-Safe travels to you. Safe travels.
-Alright, take care.
[in Japanese]
See you, thank you very much!
[Katrina] Bye.
You put your mind to it,
something you had no idea how to do,
something that...
-bossed you for so long like it had me.
-Indeed.
And now,
you can move anywhere and make it a home.
You just learned a life skill.
-You-- Your kids know a life skill.
-I can't wait to--
-You're able to pass that on.
-Yeah. Indeed.
[Katrina] It just-- It feels great.
It feels so great.
[pop music playing]
♪ As long as we're together ♪
♪ I know we can do anything ♪
♪ As long as we're together
We can make it through anything ♪
♪ No matter what, you got me ♪
♪ I'm never gonna let you fall ♪