-Ah!
-[woman] She looks excited!
I'm so excited because I love mess.
[man] It's a never ending battle
to fight the clutter.
-[knocking]
-Oh!
I want things to be more simple.
I don't know how to fix it.
With the baby coming,
it's gonna be more chaos.
[gasping, squealing]
[man] Oh, my God! We have too much stuff!
Hello, I'm Marie Kondo.
[in Japanese] My mission
is to spark joy in the world
through cleaning.
Ching!
[narrator] Best-selling author
and world-renowned tidying expert
Marie Kondo is dedicated to inspiring
the world to choose joy
with the KonMari Method.
[in Japanese]
A feature of the KonMari Method
is that you clean by item
and not by location.
And we will always clean using
the same categories.
[in English] First, is clothing.
-[Marie grunting]
-[laughter]
I can't reach.
Next, is books.
[Iida] Giving them a little shake
and wake them up.
Then, paper.
[man sighs] I can't do the papers.
[deep groan]
The largest category is komono.
Komono is kitchen, bathroom,
and garage.
Everything miscellaneous.
Finally, sentimental items.
It's kinda hard to let it go,
'cause I really like this one.
[sniffling] This is kinda hard.
I don't want to just, you know, dump it.
But I want to be thoughtful about it.
[man 2] From the moment she
set foot in our house,
she had this presence to her.
She wants to see this place turned around.
Marie brought a whole bunch
of joy upon our home.
This is amazing.
[girl] You're so cute! I love you!
You're so cute.
I love you, too. [laughing]
These are, like, happy, happy tears.
Thank you for what you've brought
to our home, really.
[gentle guitar music playing]
[crunching]
I am Margie Hodges,
Margaret when my mom is mad at me.
[chuckles]
I live in Culver City, California.
My home has a lot of personal effects,
it has a lot of memories,
it has a lot of photographs, um,
mementos from traveling,
you know, I just like a place that just
anybody can come in,
and feel like they're at home.
I had two little toddlers when we moved
into this particular house,
and then had another child afterwards,
so, yeah, almost 30 years in,
in this house.
[Margie] So, my salt and pepper's here,
cumin,
-put a little coriander, whatever.
-[sizzling]
[woman] Onions are, like...
[Margie] Lu, a little, a little cilantro.
[Lucy] I thought you didn't
even like cilantro.
-[Margie] It's okay.
-It'll shrink down.
-[Margie] Okay.
-[man] Hello.
-[Margie] Hey, Jake man, how was school?
-Good. What's up?
-[Margie sighs] Hi.
-Hi.
-We're gonna make you a healthy dinner.
-[laughing]
-You're not used that that, huh?
-Do you wanna put some of this in?
[Margie] Yeah, that's-- Leave that.
-That one's open, I think it's fine.
-The secret ingredient.
Just shake it up so it's...
I do have a lot of stuff, guys.
You never know what kid's gonna come over
to borrow something.
[laughing]
[Margie] Already.
Oh, I found some stuff.
Let me show you.
I wanted to show you
some pictures I found.
I'm proud of my home.
You know,
it saw us through some good times
and then it saw us through
some really dark times towards the end,
when my husband got sick.
It changed... just everything.
I wish you guys could meet my husband.
He's...
Life of the party, larger than life,
physically, and just his personality.
He just was the guy everybody flocked to.
And he took good care of me
and he taught us all a lot
about life, about what matters in life,
and, you know, how to enjoy...
enjoy yourself.
[Jake] Was this his stuff or...?
This is his stuff. These are--
Some of the stuff is stuff we gave him.
-[Jake] Oh, oh.
-[Margie] Look what I found!
[Chelsea] Oh, my God.
-[Margie laughs]
-[Jake] What?
[Chelsea] I can't...
[laughing]
Who's that?
-Ah, jeez.
-You guys are adorable.
[Margie] Now my husband's gone,
I've got an empty house full of stuff.
Rick has monumental amount of stuff
that has accumulated from prior business
to present business
to inventions.
Any kind of creative ideas
he might have had.
It's so personal to him.
I'm very strong-willed
and have good ideas,
but I don't know that I have
everything it takes, you know, er,
or just the fortitude it takes
to get rid of his belongings.
But I'm alone now.
I lost my husband,
my kids all have moved out,
so, this is the perfect time for me
to make room for,
you know, whatever is next.
So, um, when Marie comes,
she's gonna kinda just get me started,
but she's not gonna be here,
this is gonna be my full-time job,
just cleaning my house.
[Jake] Well, good.
It's a little daunting when you see
how much stuff we've accumulated.
I hope that Marie can help find
the same calmness and coziness
that I like in my house,
but maybe not
with all these things everywhere.
[Chelsea] Mom, are you ready to eat?
-I'll sit here. You sit at the head, Mom.
-[Margie laughs]
[Lucy] Oh, yeah, that's her chair.
It's been so long since a family dinner.
Well, it's kinda-- Yeah.
It is kinda weird
'cause we're missing several, so...
-Okay, guys. [sighs]
-Good luck with your new adventure.
Cheers to new beginnings.
Starting fresh.
Mmm, do I have your support, guys?
I-I-I hope you know
how much this means to me.
[Chelsea] Mm-hmm.
[quavering] You know, it's a lot of--
it's a lot of life in this house,
and I don't wanna just, you know, dump it.
-Yeah.
-I wanna to be thoughtful about it
and I don't want to get rid of...
important things or things that you wish--
oh, man,
we shouldn't have got rid of, so...
kinda, like, I need you to speak up
and kinda be here as I go through this.
-[whimpers] It's kind of emotional.
-Yeah.
I've been so strong, and it's, like,
this is really real now.
It's been a rough year,
but this is gonna be a good cleansing.
Okay, guys, so...
Lu, you do it.
Dear Lord, thank you for this meal
and that we can all be together
and please watch over us, and...
we're here for my mom
on this next chapter
and journey in her life.
In Jesus' name, amen.
-[Jake] Amen.
-Amen.
[in Japanese] By tidying,
you can sometimes ease
the pain of the past.
Or even start thinking about your future
in a more positive way.
Once we are done,
I have every faith that Margie's life
will spark with even more joy.
[birds chirping]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[in Japanese] This house is so cute.
This is the house, right?
[doorbell chiming]
-[Marie] Hi!
-Hello, Marie.
Hello, nice to meet you.
-Nice to meet you.
Thank you for coming all the way
to my house.
Thank you for inviting me.
-I'm so excited for you to be here.
-[Marie] Yeah.
[Marie whispers indistinctly]
So beautiful.
-Thank you. You wanna ride my pony?
-Yeah, yeah.
[Iida translating]
-Can I ride?
-[Margie chuckling]
[laughing]
Wow.
Only because she's little.
[Iida translating]
-This is just decoration?
-[Margie] Yeah, decoration.
-Yeah.
-Okay. Oh, it's so cute.
Yeah.
-[laughing]
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
It's the first time I've seen that.
Wow.
I've got lots of fun things in my house,
lots of special things.
-Wow.
-Yeah, so...
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I'm so happy to be here,
so I'd love it
if you could give me a tour.
-Sure. Not as happy as I am to have you.
-Yeah.
So come on in.
I can take you back into the,
the abandoned bedrooms from my children.
[Marie squeal, laughs]
[laughing]
That, That is the nervous cat.
-I have two, two cats.
-Two cats, okay.
-The other one is okay, this one, nervous.
-Nervous, okay.
I'm sorry. [laughing]
-So...
-Yeah.
My children are big and gone,
but we have lots of stuff left.
-So--
-How many children?
-I have three.
-Three, yeah.
And we keep talking about,
"We need to do this,"
and, "I'm too busy, Mom,"
so, for now, we just put it in here,
and close the door.
This is the dining room.
Yeah, yeah.
It looks so tidy. [chuckles]
My house is clean, it's just every drawer,
every closet is packed.
[Iida translating]
-Oh, what this? How this?
-Well...
-It's a drawer?
-[chuckling]
This is a catchall.
Anything you don't know where to put,
you put it in here.
Ah, okay.
[Margie laughing] She looks excited.
-Yeah, yeah.
-[Iida translating]
I am so excited because I like tidying
and I love mess.
Oh. Well, you came to the right house.
Yeah.
And this is my kitchen,
-[Margie] I live here alone.
-[Marie] Yeah.
[Margie] Look at all my stuff.
-[Marie gasps]
-[Margie laughing]
More stuff!
Oh!
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-I see.
[Margie] My husband loved condiments
and spices and sauces.
And this is what
my husband said to me every morning.
He called me Mag and he would always say,
"Good coffee, Mag!"
Okay, what do you wanna come see?
-Bedroom number two?
-Yes.
I think this is Lucy's stuff.
From when she was little.
-[Marie] Yeah.
-From school.
And then, also I have up here. [laughing]
-I haven't been up there in many years.
-[Marie] Yeah.
-So, I have a very big bedroom.
-Yeah.
This is all my husband's
and then this is all mine.
His things are still in the drawers
and then me.
-[Marie] Oh...
-[Margie laughing]
[Margie] Too much stuff.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
What about these shelves here?
-All kinds-- All kinds of things.
-Clothes, too?
-No, purses.
-[Marie] Ah, purse.
Sometimes I put--
I buy little things, like gifts,
and I just stick it up here. More candy.
[chuckling]
-[Iida] Candy.
-Yeah, but I don't go up here too much.
-Ah.
-This is where he had all his pants,
so I have them,
I have them, um, down there.
Yeah, yeah.
There's the, the jeans.
-[Marie] Yeah, yeah.
-See, see how big?
The pants are so big. This is so many...
so many pairs.
-[Iida translating]
-[Margie]Yeah.
And then we spend a lot of time--
This is our family room.
Oh, wow.
[Iida translating]
-So cool.
-Yeah.
[in Japanese] There's a very good energy.
[in English] This is all of your books?
-Or the--
-I have more. [laughing]
[Iida translating]
-Some of them.
-Yeah, some of them.
Some are my husband's.
My husband saved everything.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida]
So, when did your husband pass away?
-Nine months ago.
-Last summer, last June.
-Yeah.
I have to make room going forward.
-I can't just only live in the past.
-Yeah.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, yes, I think you will find
that this opportunity
for us to work together is really a time
for you to reflect upon your life
and start tidying
and organizing your life.
-I want to keep lots of memories still.
-Yeah, yeah.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] But I would like to value
how you feel
about your past and your memories.
Of course. Thank you, thank you.
[Margie sighs]
Well, I'm thanking you for sitting down
and not running out the front door
going, "Ah! This is too much!"
[speaking Japanese]
So, this is where we begin,
where we start our tidying process.
I'm ready.
I have really kind of stated to everybody,
this year, for me,
is my year to tidy up my whole life.
So, I've been through an awful lot
and I'm...
I've learned a lot, I'm amazed
how strong I have been through it all,
and I, I feel like I've got the energy
and the desire to really
prepare for what's to come next,
whatever that might be.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I feel so fortunate to be able
to go on this journey with you.
Thank you. That makes me...
That makes me very happy.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] After you finish tidying,
do you have an image
of what kind of life
you would like to lead?
Yeah, I-I would like to travel again,
that's really one of the things
on my list, is to travel,
'cause I, I have relatives in fun places
around the world.
Also, I would like to have
a spare room devoted
as a craft room or, you know,
a place for me just to have
all my supplies,
and in one room,
in one spot, organized neatly.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, those images
are very, very important,
but the most important step is to have
an image of your ideal lifestyle
that you want to lead
once you've finished tidying.
Clearer the image, the better.
[Margie] Okay.
[in Japanese]
Before we start tidying...
[in English]
I would like to greet your house.
-Okay. How do you do that?
-[chuckling]
Er, don't worry about me.
-This is just for her.
-Oh, it's-- it's her--
-Yeah, yeah.
-Okay.
I find the best place to...
Okay.
Ah, this is okay.
[peaceful music playing]
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Margie laughs]
[Iida] Thank you so much.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I will tell you,
the feeling in this house is spectacular.
So, what I'd like for you to remember
as you go through this process
is that you're not alone,
the house itself and all your belongings
are there to support you and are with you.
Yes, they are. [laughing]
-[in English] Let's start tidying.
-[laughing]
All of your clothes
and put them in a pile on your bed.
-[Iida] Take out all of your clothes
and make a mountain on your bed.
Okay. This is hard to do.
[Marie] Yeah. Is this yours or...?
-That's Rick's.
-Okay.
-Just yours this time.
-Yeah.
-This end we leave for now.
And this...
[in Japanese]
I always recommend that clients wait
to tidy belongings of a loved one
until the end.
The reason is because
tidying those items is very difficult.
So there is a high chance
that it will stall the tidying process.
[indistinct chatter]
Gonna make a mountain.
[Iida] Thank you.
It looks different when you see it
thrown on your bed like that.
I know.
[Margie laughing]
-Oh, this is mortifying.
-[Marie] Yeah.
Oh, my God.
[Margie] It's gonna be up to the ceiling,
I have a feeling. Oh.
-Wait, [stammers] ...you need to...
-Yeah!
[laughing]
-That was a workout, look at this.
-Yes.
-Look at it, it's just...
-[Iida translating]
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] So, this is the start.
[in English] Hold each item one by one
and choose item that spark a joy for you.
Um...
[laughing] I just...
Oh, my God! That's all I keep saying.
So, you'll be able to be more attuned
to what sparks joy for you
if you start with something
that you obviously like
and you wear all the time,
you're just 100% sure
it sparks joy for you.
My two robes, my three robes.
These couple of things I wear a lot.
This has sparked joy for you.
-Yeah, those are my cozies.
-Okay.
This one, I-I have had this
since I was nursing babies.
My youngest is almost 26.
-[Iida translating]
-[laughing]
But it's okay, I can say goodbye.
[in Japanese] If you are letting go
of an item
that you have a lot of memories of,
that's when you want to say
thank you from your heart.
I know, thank you, thank you. Lots of--
I can't believe how long this lasted,
so many years.
-But...
-[Iida] Yes.
...this is-- this chapter is behind me.
-Yeah.
-So, thank you.
I'm just, um...
[deep sigh] ...feeling a little bit like,
"Wow, this is gonna take me a long time."
I would love to be doing it with Rick,
I mean, there's really nobody else
I could choose to do this with.
He was so capable of so many things,
and now it's kind of like
smacking me in the face with,
"Okay, he's not here.
What are you gonna do now?"
[Marie, in English]
How do you feel now?
It was more than I thought
it was gonna be.
-First of all the amount of stuff.
-Yeah.
But it was easier than I thought
in the sense... [sighs]
I can do without that, you know?
I've-I've been through
some serious battles lately,
so, making decisions
about clothes is very, um...
Well, quite a bit easier than I thought.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Yeah, I was surprised how smoothly
you made the selection,
so I think it's going very well.
Thank you so much.
-Can I give you a hug?
-Yeah. Thank you, thank you so much.
[laughing]
[birds chirping]
[Margie] My life has transformed
just completely, um,
in the last year.
You know, when you choose a person
for 40 years,
you know, you want to be
with that person, and...
it's a big void in the house
and in my life,
and I honestly have never lived alone.
[sighing]
Oh, my God.
I do hope that this will allow me
to have, um,
some thoughts about what can I do,
what do I want to do,
the things that I haven't actually
allowed myself to think.
I want to be able to fantasize about
how do I wanna decorate the bedroom,
for example.
Or how would I redo this
and I have a hard time making decisions.
But, um, it's all on me now,
I don't have to run it by anybody.
And that's an experience, I guess,
I have never had before,
where it's just solely me
making my decisions.
[craw cawing]
[Marie humming]
[doorbell chiming]
-[Marie] Hi!
-Good morning!
-Good morning. Nice to see you.
-Hello.
Hello.
-Welcome back.
-Yeah.
-Come on in. Hi, Iida.
-Good to see you again.
-Thank you.
-Welcome, welcome.
Yeah.
[laughing] Has it been a week?
[Margie] You want to come see
what I've been up to?
[Marie] Yeah.
[Margie] This is what I'm getting rid of.
-[Marie gasps]
-[Iida translating]
Look at all those bags.
Those are all gonna go, yeah.
-And all these purses.
-[Marie] Yeah.
I don't even know
where some of these purses are from,
I don't remember them, they've been
up there so long in my closet.
[Margie] What I'm wondering is,
what do I do now?
This is all I am keeping from my purses.
Do I need to get a container
to put them into, maybe?
-[in Japanese] If you have a container...
-A basket?
[in Japanese]
...or basket, that would be great.
[in Japanese] Many people feel that
there isn't enough space to store bags.
So I suggest the "Bag in Bag" Method.
[speaking Japanese]
Okay, so I just have to basically get
started on getting Rick's items
out of the drawers,
so that I have more room to finish
putting my things away, I suppose.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, what's important
for you to do right now
at this stage is to really
just focus on yourself.
You can set aside Rick's clothes for now,
we'll come back to that.
-Okay.
-We'll take the steps to do that.
I don't want to jump ahead of the process.
I-- I'm learning, so, okay.
I do associate things
with memories for sure.
It's hard to stay on focus 'cause I've got
Rick's items still to be dealt with.
I don't want to constantly
be thinking about that
every time I get dressed in the morning.
I'm definitely anxious,
but I have to trust Marie's process.
[speaking Japanese]
-Okay.
-[Iida] The next on your step is books.
Okay.
[Iida] With books, we follow
the exact same process as clothes.
We will be gathering all the books
in the house,
and going through them one by one.
Ooh!
[Margie] I will literally just
stand up here and climb it.
-Okay.
-[Margie laughing]
-This is all built in.
-Ah, built in.
-[Iida] Okay.
-[Margie] Yeah.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
I think these are, um,
Rick's cowboy books.
When we used to go on vacation,
he'd always read an easy cowboy book.
So, do you like to travel?
Yeah, I used to work for the airlines,
so we did a fair amount of traveling.
[Marie] Yeah, yeah.
That's a keeper.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
How do you feel looking at all these--
all the books?
I feel like I'm in
somebody else's library, [laughs]
...'cause I don't know
what a lot of this stuff is.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So...
So, before I start...
-Gotta wake 'em up?
-Exactly.
-Wake up the piles.
-[Iida] Before I start tidying books,
I like to wake them up a little bit.
It's a little easier to sort through.
[Margie] Um, okay...
[laughing]
How do I decide what I want to keep?
[speaking Japanese]
It's perfectly natural to feel anxious.
Just start with something easy,
you obviously don't want.
Okay. But I'm-I'm wrestling with
not feeling finished up there.
I feel like I'm jumping
into something else and I'm not done.
I was sort of prepared
to pull all of Rick's things out.
Yeah, yeah.
I-- I mean, it's not gonna be
the easiest thing,
but I'm tough and I'm...
I'm not gonna be tough now. [chuckling]
But I really think
I was mentally preparing for that.
So, I... I sort of feel like
I wanna kind of
finish before I jump into the next thing.
[in Japanese] I understand.
Let's shift the rules for you, Margie.
That-That-That I think
that would make me feel comfortable.
[in Japanese] I'm so happy that I was able
to understand you a little bit better.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] You know, I am here to help you,
so whenever you need help or you're stuck,
call on me and I'll come right over.
[Margie] Thank you.
[in Japanese] Normally when we work
on sentimental items too quickly,
we become stuck,
because our ability to determine...
what sparks joy
has not been sufficiently honed yet.
But this was a very special case,
so I allowed Margie to work...
on some sentimental items first.
I offered to help Margie tidy
Rick's clothing with her,
but she expressed her wishes
to tidy his clothes alone,
so I trusted her to do that on her own.
[Margie] Okay. Thank you again.
-Thank you.
-[Iida] Goodbye, see you soon.
-Enjoy the beautiful day.
Okay, bye.
[melancholic music playing]
[Margie sighs]
[sniffling] This is kinda hard.
[crying]
[crying continues]
[Margie sobbing] You know, I looked at
those shirts and I thought
of all the hopes and dreams
he had while he...
you know, was in his Hawaiian shirt phase,
and then it went into the cowboy phase.
And, you know,
it's just kind of a real jolt
to see all this life, you know,
that we've lived,
and the dreams that he had
and, you know, they are now
in a pile on the floor,
and my closet is empty.
And that,
that was a very big jolt for me today.
[gentle piano music playing]
It was-- It was a difficult process
for me, I...
More so than I expected.
And seemingly kind of final.
I've been so good throughout this
and I've been looking at it so long
and just wanting it to go away,
but I guess it's just that final...
final chunk of...
you know, what's so visibly him.
Evidently, there's lots of him
in the house and I've got all his...
papers and belongings otherwise,
but, you know, the clothes are
a very physical thing.
His-His presence was so big,
his clothes are so big,
his shoes are so big,
and it's just very noticeable
he's not there.
[sniffs]
[sighing] Okay.
Ah.
[sniffling]
[car door opens]
[car door shuts]
-[Margie] Hi.
-[woman] Morning. Hi.
[Margie] Hi. I'm Margie.
-I have a big donation for you.
-Margie? Thank you. We love it!
-It's amazing what I'm getting rid of.
-Okay.
Clothing? Oh, you've got a lot of things.
-I do, do you have room?
-Perfect, yes. [laughing]
Absolutely.
[Margie] I did it.
That truck was packed,
and, um, a lot of life,
a lot of memories and...
You know, and my head is full
of 40 years of memories.
[whimpers]
So, I have that, no one can take that.
It's gonna feel good when I drive off,
I'm just... [deep sigh]
...a lot-a lot, a lot!
Getting to this point was a lot of work,
it was a lot of memories,
it was a lot of emotions,
and I want to only remember the good.
[birds chirping]
-Hi, hi, hi. How was your weekend?
-[Lucy] Hey.
[Lucy] Good. I want to see the closet now.
-[Margie] Oh, You haven't seen it. Okay.
-No.
-[Lucy] Whoa, that's creepy.
-Isn't it?
[imitating echo] Hello!
-Aww. That's sad.
-I know.
I know, it's-- it's really impactful
when you see...
-Yeah.
-...all his stuff out of here.
I-I kept one long flannel and his jacket
and I still have some of his boots.
I finally am feeling really different.
I feel proud of myself, you know?
I-I-I always told Rick,
"You're making me lazy,"
because he does things so well,
and does so much that I don't have to.
Not that I couldn't, but I never had to.
And now I enjoy
that I know I can if I need to.
[birds chirping]
[doorbell chiming]
-Hi, hello.
-Hello!
Welcome back, girls!
Hi. Oh, my God! You look so beautiful!
Thank you, thank you.
It's like, you know, the weather change.
Yeah, summer.
Yeah. So how's everything?
-[Iida translating]
-Good.
Well, come on in.
[in Japanese] The next thing I am thinking
about having you tackle is
the room that used to be your kid's room.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
Okay, so this room...
It seems like it's a little more tidy
than the last time I was in here.
Did you go through them all?
Well, I-I have been taking things
and adding things and...
Yeah. I-- Maybe I was trying
to group things, too, maybe a little bit.
Um, just dealing with upstairs
was very emotional for me,
more difficult than I was expecting,
to deal with Rick's stuff.
[Marie, in Japanese]
Regarding the tidying process,
I understand that you've overcome
a very major step.
I'm very proud of Margie
for her accomplishments.
I felt very deeply
what a significant presence
Rick was in Margie's life.
I also felt that she's now ready
to continue tidying,
so I would like to continue
the lesson with her.
[speaking Japanese]
Okay, so we're gonna start looking
at miscellaneous items in this room.
-One by one.
-Okay.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] The things that you want to keep,
like the scrapbooks, the craft equipment,
all those you want to keep,
keep them confidently.
Okay. [takes a deep breath] Alright.
[Margie]
This is a treasure hunt in here, girls.
-Do you want these?
-No, no.
[laughing] I don't know what they are.
You guys have first dibs
on any of my fabulous junk.
[Margie] Well, for $1.89 instead of $19.
-Ah!
-That's where I get myself in trouble.
I'm ready to run away from home!
[laughing]
This is the worst I've experienced so far.
[Margie] I'm a closet stasher.
[laughing] I'm fessing up.
The secret is out and I'm owning it
and I don't want
to feel like this anymore!
-Oh, God. How do I know?
-[Marie, in Japanese] Yes, you will.
Or do I get rid of it now,
and if I need it again,
I go spend 99 cents and buy a new one?
Well...
I don't know, you guys.
Help me out, help me out, I don't know.
[speaking Japanese]
So, if you feel overwhelmed, just...
take a moment to breath in and out.
I know, the decision making is very mental
and it makes you weary.
[speaking Japanese]
Okay. So, if you're unsure,
let's keep it for now.
[Margie] It was a good feeling to know
that Rick's clothes is a closed book now
and I can move forward
with this process, but, um,
I realized soon enough
that I have so much to do,
and to have it all on me
is just-- Aah!
I felt like, "Wow."
It's overwhelming.
There's so much to deal with
and so many decisions
and I don't know how I'll get it done.
I really don't.
I gotta figure out a lot of stuff.
-Uh, and there's so, so many.
-[Iida translating]
[deep sigh]
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, I think going forward, Margie,
your challenge will be
just tackling each item
one by one, calmly,
and you are an expert already
at identifying what sparks joy for you
and what doesn't.
You've already done that so many times.
You've come so far and there's
so much storage space in this house,
so don't try to focus
on what you need to eliminate.
You know, focus on what you wanna keep
and how you want to store them.
-That should be your focus.
-[Margie] Okay.
[Margie] I have a lot of work to do,
but I've gotta try...
things on my own
that I've never done before.
I guess that's what this is all about.
You know, preparing myself
for my next chapter.
It stresses me that there's just so much.
But I am sucking it up,
I'm gonna be tough and get it done.
-Thanks for all your help.
-Thank you!
Okay, you guys.
-I'll see you soon.
-Safe travels.
[Iida] Thank you.
[Margie] Okay, empty shelves.
And I still have some more spices to go,
in addition to all of this
that I already pulled out.
A lot of the stuff that we had here
was for Rick's kind of cooking,
so, I am going to figure out
what sparks joy in my life
at this moment going forward,
and what kind of cooking
am I gonna be doing.
Woo!
[clattering]
Okay, this is a lot of stuff,
I've gotta go get a basket.
Who knows what's in my chemical closet?
This is a couple of years old.
I'm surprisingly feeling perky today
'cause I've had a grueling week,
I have been at it,
cleaning and sorting
and making decisions.
Um, and maybe it's just because
I see such progress, finally.
Oh, here's some towels
I haven't seen in a decade.
Yeah, I'm getting the hang of it,
that's true.
[Lucy] Am I doing up top or down below?
[Margie] Yes, please.
-Which one?
-[chuckling] All, all of it.
I'm enjoying
just not answering to anybody
and not having to consult.
That's kind of exciting.
I'm looking at my house with fresh eyes.
[Margie] So, I have a lot of photographs.
I need some help.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
Absolutely, I'd be delighted to give you
a lesson on photographs today.
-Okay. Okay.
-Yes.
[Margie] So, I have so many
photographs of 4th of July.
Hmm.
I have to look carefully,
like, how old were my kids, you know,
to try to find out the year.
These are all 4th of July.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, there are two ways to do this
and you can use both ways.
You can of course categorize by year,
but you can also categorize by events.
I did the same thing
when I was sorting though my photos.
-Okay, that's probably a lot easier.
-[Iida translating]
And then I have some, you know,
other miscellaneous...
-things that I've been saving.
-Of course.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Are these sentimental
items as well?
-[Margie] Yeah, yeah.
-Sentimental, miscellaneous items.
Yeah, so I, you know,
at least I have 'em in a box, but...
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] You, Margie, you have
so many amazing, cute, craft goods.
-You can make your own box that way.
-Oh, yeah, you know what? I could.
I could-- Or make the labels
to go on them, you're right.
[Iida] Absolutely.
[in Japanese] Store sentimental items
in a way that sparks joy.
For example, store them
in a box that sparks joy.
[speaking Japanese]
[In Japanese] So, separate them
into the 80s, the 90s, the aughts...
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] It's very, very good mix
of everything here.
-[chuckling]
-[Margie] Yeah! Look at my hair!
-[laughing]
-[Iida translating]
-[Iida] 80s? Maybe 80s?
-Oh, 80s, 80s.
You know it's 80s.
Oh, God!
[speaking Japanese]
I think all the baby steps I have taken
has prepared me for this, this section.
It got through to me, as in some way
I learned how easy it was
to discard things, recycle things,
whatever it might be,
but I haven't had as difficult a time
parting with things
as I would have thought.
[Marie, in Japanese]
I can feel that the energy is brighter
and that you are enjoying your life more.
And congratulations on successfully
completing all the categories.
Thank you to my mentor
and mentor extraordinaire assistant.
[Margie] In these last few weeks,
I think I'm getting a better sense
that I am definitely stronger
than I would ever have
admitted to being.
So I-I, you know, that's why,
looking forward to the future,
what is out there for me? I, I don't know.
I know I'm capable of so many things
and things that I have never considered.
So, you know, that makes it fun
to get up each day
and see what's gonna unfold.
[upbeat music playing]
[Marie, in Japanese]
There's a lot of stuff out here.
[Iida, in Japanese]
There must have been a garage sale.
Ah!
[Marie, in Japanese]
This looks really antique.
[Marie] Oh!
[in Japanese]
There's containers over there too.
[doorbell chiming]
-Hi!
-[Marie] Hi!
-Hi.
-It's so nice to meet you!
[laughing]
Hello. This is my baby.
-[Marie] Oh!
-This is Lucy.
[Margie] Well, come on in!
We have a beautiful day here today.
[Iida] Yeah, it is beautiful out.
Where do you want to start?
I'll be happy to show you.
[speaking Japanese]
-Start with that room right there.
-Okay, lead the way.
[Iida] Can I take a peek
at the linen closet?
[Margie] Yes, linen closet.
[Margie] Tah-dah!
[Marie exclaims] Eh!
[Marie, in Japanese]
It looks so neat now!
[Margie] All by myself!
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] The fact that you've mastered
how to store everything
to this level means you can work
with any space going forward.
I'm realizing that through this journey.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Okay, so, on to the next room.
[Margie] Okay.
[Marie gasps happily]
[all laughing]
-[Marie squeals]
-Surprise!
[in Japanese] I am so surprised!
[Iida] My gosh, I'm floored!
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Margie groaning]
[Margie] I've been working so hard!
[Iida] This is a completely
different room!
-[Margie] It is.
-[Iida] Oh, my goodness.
[Margie] I have been working so hard
and I wanted to surprise you!
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I can't believe there's--
I can't believe you can touch the carpet!
-[Margie laughing]
-[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I never thought I'd be able
to do this
and see this whole view of the carpet.
And that's my new hashtag, I wrote it.
"KonMargie."
[Margie] Similar, but different.
[Iida translating]
[laughing]
[speaking Japanese]
I think this will turn into a lovely room
for your hobbies and your passions.
-Well, I did it.
-[in Japanese] This room is complete!
[laughing]
I know. I just haven't slept in two weeks.
This process has been
very therapeutic, I think.
In many ways.
It's sort of a rebirth for me.
This lovely old house
that there's been so many
wonderful memories shared here
and so many more to make.
And to see how it's gonna shift,
um, is anybody's guess at this point.
It is a little harder...
Actually, it was a lot harder
than I thought it would be for myself.
You're saying goodbye to a life
and all his attire was so representative
of our life together for so many years.
It was hard.
But I-I have to think
that he would be proud.
I-I could just visualize him
in the family room,
in his spot, just sitting there,
with me...
spinning circles around him,
'cause that was often the way life was.
I hope he's amused and smiling down
and giving me the thumbs up, saying,
"You're doing the right thing."
Unfortunately, Rick isn't here
to continue on
with the plans that we had made
and the dreams that we had
for our golden years,
but I don't feel despair.
I feel, you know,
very happy for the life we lived,
and going forward,
I'm anxious and excited
for what lies ahead.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So how do you feel, Lucy,
seeing how your mother
progressed through this
and made such huge strides?
[Lu] I am proud of her.
It's gonna be great for her to have a...
You can even feel the air
and the energy in the rooms has changed.
[in Japanese] Tidying Margie's home was
an unforgettable journey for me as well.
I was so moved by "KonMargie's" endeavors.
-Thank you again.
-[Iida] We'll see you soon.
Okay, bye.
-Bye!
-Nice to meet you.
[in Japanese]
I am so happy that I was able to assist
Margie spark joy
in the next chapter of her life.
[Marie, in Japanese]
I was moved deeply by this experience.
It almost made me cry.
[pop music playing]
♪ I wanna be stronger ♪
♪ Let out my roar
And tell the world that I'm wiser ♪
♪ Let go my fears,
You'll hear me scream ♪
♪ Like oh, oh ♪
♪ I'd walk through the fire, fire ♪
♪ You know unbreakable ♪
♪ I'm gonna get stronger ♪
♪ Never gonna stop me ♪
♪ You know I'm unbreakable ♪