-Ah!
-[woman] She looks excited!
I'm so excited because I love mess.
[man] It's a never ending battle
to fight the clutter.
-[knocking]
-Oh!
I want things to be more simple.
I don't know how to fix it.
With the baby coming,
it's gonna be more chaos.
-[clattering]
-[gasping, squealing]
[man] Oh, my God! We have too much stuff!
Hello, I'm Marie Kondo.
[in Japanese] My mission
is to spark joy in the world
through cleaning.
Ching!
[narrator] Best-selling author
and world-renowned tidying expert
Marie Kondo is dedicated to inspiring
the world to choose joy
with the KonMari Method.
[in Japanese]
A feature of the KonMari Method
is that you clean by item
and not by location.
And we will always clean using
the same categories.
[in English] First, is clothing.
-[Marie grunting]
-[laughter]
I can't reach.
Next, is books.
[Iida] Giving them a little shake
and wake them up.
Then, paper.
[man sighs] I can't do the papers.
[deep groan]
The largest category is komono.
Komono is kitchen, bathroom,
and garage.
Everything miscellaneous.
Finally, sentimental items.
It's kinda hard to let it go,
'cause I really like this one.
[sniffling] This is kinda hard.
I don't want to just, you know, dump it.
But I want to be thoughtful about it.
[man 2] From the moment she
set foot in our house,
she had this presence to her.
She wants to see this place turned around.
Marie brought a whole bunch
of joy upon our home.
This is amazing.
[girl] You're so cute! I love you!
You're so cute.
I love you, too. [laughing]
These are, like, happy, happy tears.
Thank you for what you've brought
to our home, really.
[in Japanese] The tidying process
provides a unique opportunity
to understand what is
most important in one's life.
In this episode,
you will meet Aaron and Sehnita.
Join me as I help this family create
an ideal home for their desired future.
[birds chirping]
[boy] Dada, could we go to Toys R Us?
No, Ashton. We're getting rid of things
not going out and getting more.
[woman ] And being happy with
how much we already have.
-[Ashton] Okay.
-[doorbell chiming]
-[man] Hi.
-[Marie] Hi. Nice to meet you.
-I'm Marie.
-Nice to meet you.
Hi, very nice to meet you. Aaron.
I have to try. [speaking Japanese]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
Hi, I'm Iida, Miss Marie's interpreter.
Hi, Iida. Miss Marie's interpreter.
Nice to meet you.
And Natalia is two-and-a-half years old.
She's asleep.
She's taking a nap right now.
-[Iida translating]
-Oh, wow.
-My daughter is same, two years old.
-Oh, really?
And one years old.
-You have a two- and a one-year-old?
-Yes.
And you're organized?
[laughing]
We have no excuse. Alright.
We have no excuse.
I'm Sehnita.
I'm Aaron.
We're the Mattisons.
[Aaron] We've been married 17 years.
We met at the
University of Michigan junior year.
-I think we just--
-End of junior year,
start of senior year.
Started dating senior year,
we basically decided we want
a change of venue,
the weather, time to get
some better weather.
We drove out to Los Angeles
and set up here.
[Aaron] What's going on, guys?
-[Sehnita laughing]
-[Natalia squealing]
We live with our two children.
We have a
seven-and-a-half-year-old boy, Ashton
and an almost three-year-old Natalia.
We're here and we love it,
and we planning on being here
a long time.
[Aaron] There's a thought, though,
as our lives,
we have so much love to give,
we live in a wonderful home, we're part
of a wonderful school district.
We have a lot of opportunity to bring
another baby into this house,
but the clutter, it just feels heavy.
It's just, you know, and overwhelming.
We have a major amount of cleaning
that we need to undertake
before we move forward.
[speaking Japanese]
[Aaron] This, yeah, this is the room
we use the most.
Like, the kitchen, the living room.
Definitely a lot of time spent watching TV
or, you know, playing.
[speaking Japanese]
Okay, so I see part of the problem.
Yeah, you're also seeing
part of the problem. [laughing]
[Sehnita] You know, we've been
in our house for seven years.
[Aaron] But it's a never ending battle
to fight the clutter.
We have things,
and those things end up taking
a space in our house and it's--
They get spread around,
just multiplies, and pretty soon
our house is a chaotic mess.
If we have a space that opens up,
pretty soon it'll get filled up.
[humming playfully]
-You fill up space, too.
-I do, I do.
It's gotta go somewhere.
And, look, there's an open spot!
How about there?
[laughing] Yes.
[Sehnita] I feel like the clutter
is just-- it's like a big block now.
But added to it is
it's so stressful to clean the house.
It's hard to think about
doing anything else
'cause it always feels like,
"No, I gotta go clean."
So even when I'm relaxing,
I should be cleaning.
-We have a fish on our table.
-We have a fish.
I don't why. But there it is.
[chuckling]
This is Natalia.
This is Miss Marie and Miss Iida.
-Can you say hi?
-[Marie] Hi.
Hello. [Marie laughing]
-No. She'll just sit here for a while.
-[Iida] Not yet, not yet.
Well, this is Ashton's room in here.
[Iida] Okay.
[Sehnita] This is his nice, big closet.
-So these are his--
-Clothes. Oh, pajamas?
His pajamas, his, uh, shirts.
Aaron wandered in here and realized that
I have taken over these three drawers.
They're awaiting your magic.
[Marie] What is that?
So, I was born in Pakistan.
So if we have Pakistani occasions,
I have my shawls to take.
When's the last time you wore them?
You know, I feel such a disconnect
to my culture to begin with.
I don't have a big
Indian-Pakistani community
being here in Los Angeles.
So...
you know, that's a little piece of
connection that I would like to hold onto.
[Aaron] This is our master.
We have lots of mess.
[Sehnita] This one is Aaron's closet.
Yeah, these are more like
my dress shirts, I go to work.
-Um...
-[Iida translates]
-[Aaron] Sehnita's clothes.
-[Marie] And some books?
[Sehnita] This might be my little problem.
I have a hard time
letting go of magazines.
This whole pile was in our bathroom.
I'd kind of hidden it from downstairs,
brought it upstairs, hidden it up there.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Do you have any magazines
left in the bathroom right now?
Not in the bathroom.
I might have piles elsewhere.
I do think that Sehnita has a tendency
to hold onto more things.
[Aaron] That's why working with Marie
would be very helpful.
I can't do it by myself.
I can't make her do it.
-Those are mine. Close that door.
-Wait, okay.
-Let me go to--
-Go ahead and close that door.
No. Those aren't-- No.
You can close those.
-Let me try the next one.
-You can't throw those things.
I understand that I either hold onto
things or I'm sentimental about things.
But we're not dying in here, like,
they don't have to, like, airlift me out
of this house 'cause there's no path out.
I'm workable! [laughing]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Oh, my goodness.
Look at this closet. It's huge!
[speaking Japanese]
Okay, so all of your dresses here. I see.
So, half of these dresses
I can't wear right now, but...
I don't want to give up
on getting to my goal weight,
so I don't want to let go of these yet.
These shorts don't fit me,
but I can't get rid of them.
Look at these shoes.
These are another one of those pairs
that I can't get rid of.
I don't think I've ever
seen her wear them.
[laughing] These are maternity clothes.
We were-- part of our goal
of wanting to clear our house is
we would like to add a third baby.
And it feels like
if we can't get our house clean,
you know, maybe we shouldn't
go down that path.
I just know that if we have
this much junk right now,
like, if we were to have a third,
it would only get worse from here.
[upbeat music playing]
-Welcome.
-Here it is.
I think some of the things
that we need a little help with
-in the garage are clothes.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] All these clothes you've kept,
you never let any of them go?
Not any of Ashton's clothes,
not any of Natalia's clothes.
[Aaron] These are just suitcases.
And these suitcases
have suitcases in them.
So I think we need help
minimizing a little.
I feel like-- You know, he's saying
we should get rid of them,
I think we need to take more family trips.
-[Aaron] Not all.
-To make use of them.
Trivial Pursuit.
-Two of two.
-We need them both.
Whole different experience.
We actually have three. One's inside.
And we also have kids toys over there.
[speaking Japanese]
So your kids,
they don't play with those toys?
-[Aaron] No.
-[Sehnita] Not right now.
If we can get
this whole garage organized more,
then they'll be in a place
where they can access them easier.
Once you do your magic. [chuckling]
I want to clean up my stuff,
but I feel like I'm not getting there.
So, for me...
what I've really wrapped
my head around in my life is
if I'm not doing the things
that I need to do,
then, you know, go seek out experts
that can help you make
the change that you need.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] This KonMari Method is not
a simple method to clean your house.
Mm-hmm.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] You mentioned my magic.
I'm sorry to say that
I don't use any magic.
Only you can do that.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] But at the same time, I have seen
many of my clients transform their lives
because in their heart of hearts,
they were ready to prepare
to change their life.
I want to, she wants to,
we want to put in the hard work.
And that's where I think
we're just looking for the guidance.
[in Japanese] Thank you so much.
I'm so honored and thankful
to hear you say that.
We're ready to declutter the home because
we foresee staying here for, you know,
the next 20 years maybe.
So, there's nothing that is going to
force us to go through our stuff,
except for something like this.
[Sehnita] I'm so excited. [laughing]
[doorbell chiming]
-Good morning!
-[Marie] Hi! Good morning!
Good to see you. Good morning.
-Hi. Good morning.
-Hi, good morning.
-[Sehnita] There's Natalia to greet you.
-[speaking Japanese, laughing]
[Sehnita] She had a slight run-in
with the dog this morning
so she's recovering.
-Do you want to go to the other room?
-Yes.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So today, we'll tackle clothes.
[Sehnita] Oh, my gosh.
This mountain of things.
[Iida] So from here, you're gonna be
going through every single piece,
piece by piece.
[Sehnita chuckling]
I feel very overwhelmed.
It does feel overwhelming.
-[speaking Japanese]
-Let's breathe.
Let's take a deep breath of air.
[deep exhale]
-[speaking Japanese]
-Stretch.
[in Japanese]
When you feel stuck while tidying,
try and change the air.
Simply opening the windows
will be effective,
but there are other ways as well.
[high-pitched tone sounding]
Create a sound that has a great vibration.
Light a candle.
Spray an aromatic room spray.
[inhaling]
Lighting some incense...
is also an option.
By creating smoke, it'll purify the room.
Of course, you can do these every day
and not just when tidying.
I use these methods
to purify my home every day.
[speaking Japanese]
So my advice is go with something that's
very easy for you to make a decision on,
something that you'd know right away.
You know, it's like...
it's hard to understand
my feelings because,
you know, there's some things where I'm
like, "No, this doesn't spark joy in me."
It fits me and that's--
and so it's practical,
so I'm glad it fits me.
But, no I'm not happy I have to wear you.
[chuckling]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] But I do understand
because of my height.
You have no idea what a nightmare it is
for me to find clothes that fit me
because I'm so short, in that sense.
And small.
But, in a sense, I will just recommend
picking out clothes that fit you right now
that you're comfortable with
and decide from there.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-This I wear.
[Iida translating]
This I wear.
-[speaking Japanese]
-And it sparks joy for you?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
-[laughing]
-[speaking Japanese]
Instead of just basing it on
whether you wear it or not,
think about,
"Do I really need this piece?"
"Is it necessary for my life?"
[Sehnita] My problem with clothing
and feeling the joy,
it's hard because it's that idea that you
don't let go of things if it's functional.
Like, you don't wear
cocktail dresses all the time,
but if you have a cocktail party,
you don't want to buy
a new one each time either.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-Yes, Aaron, you're doing very well.
-You're doing great.
-[Iida] Very calm.
-Aren't you the best?
[laughing]
-Don't the teachers like you?
-Don't get angry. [laughing]
[Sehnita] Aaron and I are different.
I'm funny, she's not.
-My friends think I'm funny.
-Your friends think you're funny.
Um, yes, maybe Aaron's, like, quick
to want to
you know, be like,
"Okay, I gotta clear my space,"
and maybe I slow him down to be like,
"Wait a minute,
I want you to really think, like,
are you getting rid of anything
that might be important to you?"
And for me, he's going to help me be like,
"Alright, come on, you don't
need to hold onto those things.
That's just more things
we have to clean up."
-Thank you, bye bye.
-Thank you so much.
-Bye.
-Bye!
A lot to do. The homework is now
go through our clothes,
sort through the things we--
that don't spark joy,
move them out.
[Aaron] This is what happens when you
first start going through the process.
[Sehnita] I do still feel stuck in the...
Like having...
Being in the limbo of having clothes
that I need to hold onto.
But when you say, "Have to hold onto,"
what do you mean have to hold?
Why do you have to hold onto 'em?
Like, you can just easily say,
"This sparks joy, this doesn't spark joy."
There's a certain amount of things that
I, yeah, honestly when I take a step back
and I look at some of the stuff I have--
Like, okay, do I want
to hold onto this because--
[Sehnita] You can't let go of that!
See, this is why I can't show you things.
With Sehnita and I, I would love
better communication
dealing with items in our house
because sometimes it feels like
she automatically goes and says,
"No, we should keep it."
[Aaron sighing] That's a lot of stuff.
[Sehnita] We're gonna be here
'til midnight.
-Not me. Nope.
-We are going to be here till midnight.
I was gonna go downstairs
and play video games with Ashton.
[Aaron] Goodbye.
[in Japanese]
Folding clothes is so much fun!
About folding baby clothes,
here's how to fold baby onesies.
First, fold in half vertically,
tuck in the sleeves,
fold it in half,
and then fold into thirds.
Like this, when it is folded
into a square, you are finished.
Next, how to fold socks.
Place one on top of the other
and just fold them in half,
making them very compact.
How to fold underwear.
Fold the bottom up.
Next fold it in half,
and then in half again.
[Aaron] That's my blue jeans here.
This is gonna be my sweaters here.
I think I'm getting close to
getting my stuff gone through.
I feel good, um...
[laughing]
Isn't that great? He feels good.
I am finding it really challenging
to go through my clothes
because even things I like don't fit well,
so I'm not willing to let go
of all those things.
I just realized I'm on camera
and I didn't put on makeup.
Hmm. Alright, so I'm gonna end this video.
[doorbell chiming]
-[Aaron] Hey, Sehnita.
-Yeah?
-[Aaron] Marie's here.
-Oh, okay.
-Hi, good morning.
-Good morning.
-Good to see you again.
-Good to see you.
-Morning, good to see you.
-Sehnita's just upstairs doing some work.
[Aaron] These are all the clothes
we'll be getting rid of.
So this is a mixture
of Sehnita's and mine.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] That's wonderful.
-[Aaron] Yes.
And she's in Ashton's room.
Ooh.
-Good morning, hi!
-Hi, Marie. How are you?
Good to see you.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, how are you?
I'm feverishly trying to
go through these, uh, scarves
and you're here at a perfect time
'cause I was like
I don't know if I know how to fold them.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Oh, but you did it just right.
-Nearly there.
-Okay.
[Iida] Okay, so first...
[speaking Japanese]
I would make sure that
the fringe is rolled inside.
Okay.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] This way you'll protect the fringes
and you'll avoid any unwanted wrinkles.
And then if they're different sizes,
like, I was trying to do this one
and it was a little bit bigger,
so do I try to get it this size?
[Marie speaking Japanese]
So you can just categorize by size
if that's the case.
I'm sure you have other bigger scarves
as well, so just keep those together.
Well I'm-- I like this method
because honestly, um,
it was so hard when I was stacking them
to know what color was in there,
which one to get,
so I probably didn't use them
as much as I wanted to
because I couldn't see them.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] This applies to every
storage space,
but when you open the drawer and
you can immediately see what's inside,
it's really useful.
[Sehnita]
It is so useful. It was a lot of work.
It was a lot of work to go through
all of our clothes,
um, but we're ready
for the next challenge.
[Aaron] We have ten boxes of books,
four or five boxes of magazines.
[Marie  speaking Japanese]
Something that I do
is to wake them up first.
Books that have been stored in boxes
for a long time are sleeping.
They would like some waking up.
-Yes
-[laughing]
They're all sleepy. [chuckling]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] And once we've woken them up
take each book, one by one,
and ask yourself, "Is this something
that I would like to bring with me
into the future?"
[Sehnita] Books are a part of my identity.
I mean, I do really value them
and I value them being in our house.
It will be very hard for me
to get rid of them.
-[Marie] Bye!
-[Iida] Thank you so much.
It just feels like
those are people's works.
Just to, like, kinda just
dump them in a trash heap--
it doesn't feel good to me.
Think you're gonna use this
or you have the internet?
You got the internet.
-Don't you think?
-Can it be in a maybe pile?
Where's your maybe pile?
Here. [laughing]
[Aaron] I definitely understand Sehnita
seeing certain items
and struggling with it as far as looking
and saying, you know,
"Does it bring me joy or does it
bring me guilt for getting rid of it?"
Because even if she said
it's okay to let it go,
she'll have second thoughts.
-Let's get rid of 'em.
-No, I'm going--
[whispering] No, I'm not gonna get rid--
We can't get rid of them.
We're going to give them
for the other baby.
Why are you whispering to me?
[whispering]
Because I'm trying not to yell.
[Sehnita] Because we're definitely
on, uh, different pages about
saving books for a potential third.
I don't want to, at this point,
get rid of everything just...
to have to go buy them again next year.
That doesn't make sense to me.
That doesn't make fiscal sense to me.
Like, with her I'd have to make
her feel okay
that I'm not just going to get rid of
things that she wants
because I know there is
still this fear in her mind that
every stage she's concerned
that I'm going to move things out
that she's going to regret losing.
[Aaron]
Final check for the books, I guess.
Sehnita's just doing a one last review
of the books in here.
Um, I thought they were all boxed.
I said, "Hey I'm gonna
take these to the garage."
She was like, "I want one more look."
So, so close.
I guess this is the final stage.
Uh-oh, she's got a pile
of books she's holding onto.
[Aaron] Oh, Sehni.
Marie's here with boxes.
-[Aaron] Hello.
-Hello!
Can I help?
-[Marie] it's fine.
-[Aaron] You're fine?
Hi, good to see you again.
Hello, how are you?
So good to see you.
[Sehnita] The deeper we get into this,
it's really difficult to do.
But I will say, little by little,
walking into open spaces
has been...
Like, you feel it.
You feel so much better.
And you know who's loving it the most?
Mazzie the cat.
She is loving the open spaces.
She's pouncing here and there
and I want to feel the joy
that cat is feeling.
[speaking Japanese]
-So, books, pretty much done, I see?
-[Sehnita] Yes.
We finished up the books.
It was tough, but like magazines,
she actually got rid of
a lot of magazines.
You might have thought that was a simple
task for me to get my magazines out,
but they were there for... [laughing]
...a few days, weeks.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Well done.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Our focus going forward
is all the miscellaneous items.
The garage and also the children's toys.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
So for toys, gather them
all together at once.
You will be going through them as parents
and deciding how often do they get used,
but I'm sure your kids have a particular
attachment to certain toys,
so this is where you want
to engage the kids
and work together with them as well.
Really encourage them to thank
each item that they're letting go.
[in Japanese] When tidying kids' toys,
take out all the toys first.
If you have more than one child,
create a separate pile for each.
For example, these are brother's,
these are sister's,
and here are shared toys.
Have your children choose
the toys that spark joy.
However, all toys may spark joy for them.
So ask them to rank the toys.
When it comes to storing toys,
it is important to divide
the space clearly.
For example, this box is for him,
these boxes are for both,
and one box is for her.
When you store shared items,
you can keep them according to category.
Here are the toys for physical play.
And here are stuffed animals.
These can be stored like this.
[Aaron] Thank you. Bye.
-Bye!
-Bye, see you later.
See you later!
[Aaron] Okay, let's work.
Toys.
[sighing]
Toys are everywhere.
The toys, we have so many toys.
[Sehnita] Do you like your toys
all piled up, Natalia?
-[Natalia] Yep.
-[Aaron] Happy birthday!
-We got this for you.
-[Sehnita laughing]
[Aaron] I'm ready to get rid
of a lot of it.
For Sehnita, the toys are tied
to emotional sentiment
with people who gave us particular toys,
the toys being attached to memories
from when Ashton and Natalia
played with them.
[Sehnita] Ashton wanted this case.
Like, wanted when he was,
like, four years old?
-[Sehnita] Natalia probably wants it.
-[Aaron] You're killing me.
I would like to keep
the Transformer types.
I think they're kinda neat.
-Um...
-But they don't really play with them.
Yeah, but I do. [laughing]
[Aaron] Hey, Natalia, why's there
a mess on the floor?
I-- 'Cause I wanted to give it away!
-[Aaron] You want to give all that away?
-Yeah.
So you were going through your toys
and making a pile
of things you don't want?
Uh, no, I want it.
[Aaron] Can you pick out one toy
that you don't really play with anymore?
[Natalia] Hmm, ah!
[Aaron] Alright, and that's how you start.
[Aaron] And everyone else is setting up
for a nice, somewhat lazy Sunday,
but Mom and Dad are gonna
get off the couch
and get up to work again.
Not right now!
[Aaron] But, dear!
[Aaron] The garage is a mini version
of our house.
It has anything and everything in it.
What about all these, like, pots?
Some of those pots are gonna go,
some are going to have
our succulents put into it.
Are we doing this right now?
I'm just looking at this beauty.
It is pretty, isn't it?
I was being facetious. Sorry.
I walk into it and I'm like,
"I don't know where to start."
Bikes. We can't really get rid of any
of them because if we do have the third,
they're going to want it.
These two boxes are from the move,
so we've been in this house
for seven years,
we haven't unpacked those.
[Sehnita] But if we have the space for it
why can't we just keep it?
Oh, Natalia's going to be
mad at you about this.
I don't want to get to the point of
throwing my hands up and saying,
"We're just gonna live in a pigsty."
[Aaron] But Sehnita's having a hard time
letting go of a lot of things.
She needs to commit.
From zero to five years old,
it's hard to give... give that up.
What he says is, "We don't need this."
And then I stop, "Well, no, I do,"
or, "I do want it."
This is our garage
and the only thing of tools
is one little shelf.
-There's no garage stuff in here.
-Wait, honestly--
-It's like toys and clothes and--
-Yes, so?
Put it into perspective.
One thing for tools,
the rest is everything else.
You're making me the bad guy
for I don't know what.
I definitely feel like
I'm being guilted into
getting rid of things.
I don't think that's what it's about.
So if I go back to,
"Oh, no, I wanna keep that thing,"
why isn't it a very clear,
like, "Okay, sure."
I'm not gonna feel bad about that.
I'm sorry.
[Sehnita] So when you try to tell me
I don't let go of things,
I don't like that.
[Aaron] You have got to stop,
otherwise we're never gonna
get through this.
I'm at a loss.
The more I think about it, the more...
I just get upset.
I get that I have a strong personality.
I thought the whole process is,
hey, you talk, you share, you share
your thoughts, your feelings...
You-- You lay it all out there.
Well, I feel like...
laying it all out there
only makes it worse.
Maybe it's just a cultural difference.
Maybe it's just different
styles and methods.
And if that's the case,
I can't change someone else either.
I'm looking to change.
I'm open to change.
I wanted to go through this process.
And...
This was my step forward,
and I'm not looking to go backwards.
So...
this place is gonna get into shape...
no matter what.
And that's just how it is.
[gentle guitar music playing]
What's a matter?
Huh?
[Sehnita] This has been a pretty
challenging and nerve-racking process
for us to go through together.
[Natalia whimpering]
But now I realize
Aaron and I do not need
a lot of things to be happy,
and I think that's part of what
has drawn us to each other.
And to be able to come together
in this process
and re-establish that idea,
you know, us in our family, like,
we don't need a lot of things, and...
that's been interesting because of all
of the things that we were surrounded by.
I think we were forgetting that.
[Aaron] You want tea?
[Sehnita] Yes.
[Aaron] What time d'you
go to bed last night?
Four, four-thirty.
So what were you doing?
Like, why am I holding onto
a seven-dollar shirt I got really cheap
that doesn't really fit?
It's kind of putting it in perspective.
I don't need to hold onto this.
Every single one of us should be
examining the things we have and...
deciding if we need it or not.
I really just had this feeling
like I'm ready to let go,
and to take control of the things
that are in my house.
Are these garbage?
Those shoes? Yes.
I guess I'll just get rid of 'em.
You served me well, shoes.
These things that are just
taking up space in your own house,
you gotta give it up.
Does it bring you joy?
-Now, if it's nostalgia, the story--
-Not really.
-Okay, well then--
-[laughing]
I mean, thank you!
[laughing]
[Aaron] It feels good to sort of
move this out of the--
yeah, out of the garage,
sort of move it out of our house
and then to a better home.
It is exhausting.
I really do feel extremely exhausted
and we're not even
at a halfway point yet.
[Sehnita] Very overwhelmed.
So it's Friday.
A couple days since we had
the mass chaos
of dumping out a lot of things.
[Aaron] Yeah!
[Aaron] This, I think we need to get
a vase from outside.
-[Sehnita] I don't-- That can, those--
-[Aaron] It can go?
Then I'll throw this stuff out. Great.
I'll be back.
You got a little excited about that!
She's doing a lot,
she's giving away a lot.
I'm very proud of her, so I just
wanted to give her those kudos.
Good job.
Still cuckoo.
-I mean, kudos. Lots of kudos.
-[laughing]
Now I feel we're on the same level.
Same place.
You'll never be at my level.
-Hi! How are you?
-[laughing]
How are you? It's good to see you.
Good to see you again.
-Hi.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] What's the occasion? So beautiful!
Our last visit. I had to dress up.
[laughing]
[Aaron] We can show you
the guest bedroom.
[Iida] Yes, definitely.
[Aaron] Beforehand I had to put
blinders on to the clutter.
So now, it's just-- it's night and day.
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Oh, my gosh!
-[Sehnita] It's all clear.
-[Iida] Look at this room.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] All those cardboard boxes
are gone?
-[Aaron] Gone.
-[Sehnita] Yes, a lot of moving around.
I love this house. I love being here.
I love spending time here.
[Aaron] This process of looking
at what's in our life
makes it so that we're not gonna
take the items we have for granted,
that we're not going to just bring
more things into the household.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I love this dining room table.
It's beautiful.
-You can see it now!
-[Iida] Yes.
There's some mental space that has
been cleared up through this process
and it was something
that I've needed for a very long time,
so it feels very good.
You go right ahead.
Wow.
[Aaron] The way we approach our house
feels vastly different
and sort of the way we're trying
to live our lives feels vastly different.
-[Marie] Wow!
-[Iida] Amazing.
[Aaron] It's actually a very deep
and meaningful change
that we can carry with us going forward.
[Sehnita] And it felt good to feel like
if it's not bringing joy,
I can just go ahead and let it go,
I don't have to keep putting it back.
Let go. It's easy.
If we have a third, we can do this now,
because before it just felt like,
"I'm gonna put the bassinet on a pile
of, like, junk and papers,
but now I feel very good that
they would be well taken care of.
Like the other two.
You can actually see from one end
to the next. [laughing]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Look at this place!
How everything that was in here!
-Oh, my goodness!
-[Aaron] We can park a car now.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] I am speechless.
[Sehnita] Aww!
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] My method of tidying
really helps you
not just clean the surface of your home,
but to really consider
how you want to live
and what kind of relationship
you want have
with your family, with your friends,
and all the things that surround you.
So I'm really happy and honored
that you really absorbed that.
[Aaron] This process, some ways,
has highlighted our opposite natures.
At the same time, it did sort of help us
better understand each other,
but also to work together
in a meaningful way.
It was kinda nice because this is a great
foundation to launch into the next stage.
-Thank you for bringing your magic to us.
-Thank you!
Thank you so much. Thank you.
-Bye, thank you very much.
-Bye!
-[Aaron] Can you say bye again?
-Goodbye!
Bye!
-[Aaron] Bye.
-[Marie] So cute!
-Say bye.
-Bye, Marie! Bye, Miss Marie Kondo!
[Natalia] Bye, Miss Marie Kondo!
-[Aaron] Yeah, bye-bye.
-[Sehnita laughing]
[pop music playing]
♪ I will always be ♪
♪ A home to come to ♪