-Ah!
-[woman] She looks excited!
I'm so excited because I love mess.
[man] It's a never ending battle
to fight the clutter.
-[knocking]
-Oh!
I want things to be more simple.
I don't know how to fix it.
With the baby coming,
it's gonna be more chaos.
-[clattering]
-[gasping, squealing]
[man] Oh, my God! We have too much stuff!
Hello, I'm Marie Kondo.
[in Japanese] My mission
is to spark joy in the world
through cleaning.
Ching!
[narrator] Best-selling author
and world-renowned tidying expert
Marie Kondo is dedicated to inspiring
the world to choose joy
with the KonMari Method.
[in Japanese]
A feature of the KonMari Method
is that you clean by item
and not by location.
And we will always clean using
the same categories.
[in English] First, is clothing.
-[Marie grunting]
-[laughter]
I can't reach.
Next, is books.
[Iida] Giving them a little shake
and wake them up.
Then, paper.
[man sighs] I can't do the papers.
[deep groan]
The largest category is komono.
Komono is kitchen, bathroom,
and garage.
Everything miscellaneous.
Finally, sentimental items.
It's kinda hard to let it go,
'cause I really like this one.
[sniffling] This is kinda hard.
I don't want to just, you know, dump it.
But I want to be thoughtful about it.
[man 2] From the moment she
set foot in our house,
she had this presence to her.
She wants to see this place turned around.
Marie brought a whole bunch
of joy upon our home.
This is amazing.
[girl] You're so cute! I love you!
You're so cute.
I love you, too. [laughing]
These are, like, happy, happy tears.
Thank you for what you've brought
to our home, really.
[woman] Hello.
[man] What's up, babe?
-Come here. What's up?
-Okay.
-Nothing.
-How are you?
I'm wet now
'cause it's raining a lot outside.
-Was it raining?
-Yes.
[dog barking]
[man] She's home.
[woman] Gus!
-Gus?
-It's okay, I'm watching them.
-There you go.
-Where you going?
Come here, baba. Over here. Okay.
-It's okay.
-It's like I'm not even here.
I'm Clarissa. This is Mario.
I'm Mario. We've been...
together now for going on six years now.
You know, the first time I saw him,
I was like, "Oh!"
-And I was just kinda smitten.
-How was it?
[laughing]
[Clarissa]
This is the trip when we, like,
officially became
boyfriend and girlfriend, went to Cabo.
It started off slow.
I was always here, staying the night.
You know, we just always hung out.
[Mario] Immediately, when I first met her,
I was just captivated by her eyes,
she has beautiful eyes,
and her smile is what won me over.
Immediately, I knew
there was something there.
[Clarissa] I love his personality.
He's always, you know, trying to make
the best out of a situation.
So I just-- I love everything about him.
And he's not bad to look at either.
[laughing]
He used one of my eyeliners to write
"Will you be my girlfriend?"
on the mirror. [laughing]
-With a check box "yes" or "no".
-[woman] Did you say yes?
Of course I said yes. [laughing]
-We've been hanging out ever since.
-Yeah.
God we, uh... I don't know
what I'd do without this girl.
We complement each other so well
in anything and everything that we do.
So we have each other's back.
Through and through.
[in Japanese]
Tidying is not just about cleaning.
It is also about creating a space
that sparks joy.
By doing this, you get
one step closer to your ideal life.
I will be visiting the house
of Mario and Clarissa.
Their biggest challenge is to be able
to let go of their items from the past
and to create a tidy home
for their future.
I'm looking forward to helping
Mario and Clarissa
as they set out on their new journey.
[Clarissa] Yeah, so...
Yeah...
It's getting real.
[Mario] Look at the other picture.
-His flexing?
-Yeah.
[both laughing]
This is your kid.
That's a little dude!
[laughing]
We are expecting a little one
in about six months.
-[chuckling]
-We're expecting our firstborn.
It's a boy.
Uh, and we are stoked.
[Mario] We are so eager to be parents.
Going to, you know, see the sonograms
or to hear the heartbeat...
It melts you.
With the baby coming,
we gotta get our stuff in order,
-otherwise it's gonna be more chaos.
-Yeah.
[Mario] This is ultimately where
I wanna see my kids grow,
but we are slightly overwhelmed
with the amount of stuff
that we keep in certain rooms.
That's where the problem begins.
[Clarissa] We've just accumulated
all of our extra stuff:
clothing, shoes,
just whatever you can think of.
Storage bins full of things
that don't get run through.
We need to get rid of it, move it,
because we do need to make room now.
It's not a matter
of we want to clean up this room
'cause it'd be nicer that way,
now it's like we have to.
I would like to have the house
as complete as possible
and still have some time
before the baby gets here.
I don't want my water to break
in the middle of us painting or something.
[laughing]
Well, Mario painting,
'cause I won't be painting.
[laughing]
It's time.
We're gonna have to part ways
with a lot of things we don't want to.
Yeah.
-But it's all for the better.
-Yeah.
All for the better of our guests,
our family, our friends, and the baby.
[triumphant pop music playing]
[birds chirping]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[in Japanese] Oh, this is it?
[door buzzer sounding]
-Oh.
-Moment of truth.
-Here we go.
-[chuckling]
Oh, Lord, here we are.
-Hi! Hello!
-Hello. Welcome!
Nice to meet you. I'm Marie.
-Nice to meet you.
-Miss Marie, Mario.
Nice to meet you, Miss Marie.
Welcome to our home.
-Thank you for inviting me.
-[Clarissa] No, thank you.
We're excited
that you're coming to help us.
Yes, I'm so excited
about tidying this house.
We're excited, too.
-A little nervous, but excited.
-Yes.
-Don't worry. Have fun.
-[laughing]
Okay. It'll be fun.
-Good, good. We can't wait to get started.
-Yeah.
So this is one of the areas, for example,
that we've put it together,
and eliminated some of the clutter out.
[speaking Japanese]
So, I'm just so excited
to see all the other rooms.
-Are you ready? Okay, let's do this.
-[Clarissa laughing]
[Mario] This is our kitchen.
[Clarissa] So, I mean, trying to keep it
as organized as we can, but...
[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] So do both of you cook?
-[Clarissa and Mario] Yes.
Yes, we do. I specialize in breakfast.
She kinda handles the other two meals.
[chuckling]
-[Mario] Trouble drawers.
-[Clarissa] Just junk.
[Mario] So, this is receipts...
Oh, you can't even open it
because she's stuffed her gum in there.
[Clarissa] We could get rid
of a lot of the stuff that's in here.
[speaking Japanese]
Yes, I agree. I think this place
will change very dramatically.
Oh, man! I can't wait. [laughing]
I can't wait.
The next space that I guess needs help,
-the office.
-[Marie] Ah.
[Clarissa] Um...
Over time,
things have just gotten stored in there.
I hold onto things and throw 'em here,
just so they're out of the way.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, are there any spaces that you
use as an office besides this one spot?
-No.
Because we do most of our--
our tablets and our laptops,
we take with us wherever we go,
into every room.
So doesn't serve us really any purpose.
One thing that we're considering is
it possibly being a nursery,
because we are expecting our first child.
Oh!
-So....
-Oh, you have child?
-We're carrying it right now.
-Congratulations!
-Thank you.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I think this is an excellent
opportunity for you to tidy,
because my clients have told me
that they're so glad that
they got it over with before the baby.
-[Clarissa] Oh, yeah.
-[in English] Because of time.
-Of course.
-Yes.
I can understand,
because I have two babies.
-[Mario] Oh, yeah?
-Yeah!
[in Japanese] You should expect
to have a lot more things.
[laughing]
[in Japanese] When your first child
is born, your world changes completely.
So you get to imagine
what kind of parents you want to be,
or how you want to live as a family.
This is the excitement
that parents get to experience
as they tidy for their first child.
For me, what changed
after my daughters were born,
was that no matter how much I tidied,
my daughters would pull things out.
So keeping a tidy house
became very difficult.
[Clarissa] Okay, so we'll go ahead
and go upstairs.
-[Clarissa] Up here is two bedrooms.
-[Marie] Yeah.
[Clarissa] We both have
a lot of shoes, so...
-[Iida translating]
-[Marie] Oh!
-So should we have shoe racks?
-Yeah.
Call it the clutter room.
-I like it. Yeah, he's so cool.
-[Mario] He's cool, right?
That's what I saw!
[Clarissa] This we use as a guest bedroom.
-These are Mario's shoes. So...
-Ah!
[Mario] Yes.
[Clarissa laughing]
[Mario] That's me.
I've been collecting sneakers now
for over 25 years.
[in Japanese] Oh, 25 years!
And it was a lot worse.
Now it's only about 150, 160.
[laughing]
[Mario] I've been collecting sneakers
since I was 12 years old.
-Put 'em down on the floor, look at 'em?
-Yeah.
[Iida] That way you really know
what you have.
[Mario] I loved sneakers, I loved sports,
I loved athletes.
These are the people I looked up to,
and it sounded so far-fetched
for me back then,
but I think when I became an adult, and...
as I started having an income,
that was a priority,
and I started just kinda buying,
and it got maybe a little out of control.
Ninety-five percent of them
were never used, never unlaced,
let alone ever tried on.
So, more than anything,
I'm ready to get started.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
So first, really look
at all the shoes that you own.
Everything.
Alright, we got some work.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] You'll be able to do it, trust me.
-[Mario] We trust you.
-[Marie] Yes.
Alright.
Let's go.
[laughing]
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, tidying will begin now.
-Yes.
-Okay.
[in English] Before starting,
I would like to greet your house.
-[Mario] Okay.
-[Clarissa] Okay.
Greeting house is very important for me.
[Mario] Okay, good.
Thank you.
[peaceful music playing]
[peaceful music continues]
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Thanks.
-Thank you so much for giving me the time.
-Sure.
-No problem.
[speaking Japanese]
-Okay, so let's begin tidying.
-Okay.
Oh, my. Let's go. Ready. [laughing]
-What's first?
-[in English] The first step is clothing.
-Clothing, ooh.
-Okay.
Put them into a pile.
Okay.
-Okay.
-Down here.
-[Mario] Here?
-Here. All of your clothes.
-Everything?
-All the clothes?
[Marie] All the clothes.
-[Mario, nervously] Okay.
-[laughing]
Oh, my-- That's a lot of clothes, Marie.
-[Marie] I know.
-Yes?
-Yeah.
-Okay.
-[Iida] We begin now.
-Alright.
Okay, let's go.
[Mario] Oh, God.
-Can you take that off, babe?
-[Marie] Yeah.
[Marie struggles, laughs]
I can't reach.
-Yeah.
-Babe, help!
I'm trying, I'm trying. [laughing]
[Marie] I need your help, of course.
[Mario] Oh, God.
[Iida] So this will be
Clarissa's mountain.
[Clarissa laughing] This isn't even..
close to all of it.
'Cause we want everything.
-Like, drawers too?
-[Marie] Yes.
-Wow.
-[Iida] Yes, drawers, everything.
[Mario] This is gonna get in tomorrow.
-[Clarissa laughing]
-[Iida speaking Japanese]
-[Mario] Oh, my.
-[Clarissa] Okay.
-I see a unicorn outfit. What is that?
-It's a onesie.
It's a onesie? That I've never seen?
-This'll be a lot of homework.
-[Clarissa sighs]
[Mario] Dang it.
-This girl is no joke.
-This is giving me anxiety.
-Deep breaths.
-[Clarissa laughing]
-Alright, you still...
-It's still not as bad as--
Are you kidding?
[peaceful music playing]
[Clarissa sighs]
This mess... [laughing]
...makes me...
it's kinda like I need to--
Everything needs to be out of here.
[laughing]
-[Mario] Yeah, this is a lot.
-Yeah.
Yeah.
But this is so important,
to see everything you have.
-See it, right it?
-[Marie] See, yeah.
I knew we had a lot. I didn't...
envision this.
-Yeah.
-[Iida translating]
When you see clothes laid out,
displayed entirely, this is my life.
-[Iida translating]
-[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So from here on out,
you will be selecting things
that sparks joy for you.
Okay.
-[Marie, in English] Spark joy.
-Spark joy.
[Mario] So this is...
Yes.
-Yes.
-[Clarissa] Alright.
[Mario] Yes.
Yes.
Yes. Keep.
[Clarissa] He has a lot of clothes, and...
I think a lot of the stuff
going into the love,
love...
love, and I'm like,
where's the stuff you're getting rid of?
[chuckling]
No.
-No.
-Goodbye, sir.
[Marie] And this is goodbye?
-Not yet.
-Not yet? Alright.
I'm still yes, no. Like...
Touch it. I don't know,
I might need it this summer.
This is hard. This is sentimental.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] What I recommend when that happens
is to start with something
that's really easy to make
a quick decision.
[Mario] There you go.
Oh, yeah, this is not fun. Right now.
But I know, I get it.
-No.
-That's a no?
I'm saying goodbye.
-Thank you.
-Reluctantly, that's a no?
Yeah.
[in Japanese] Many people may feel guilty
when letting go of items.
By expressing gratitude toward
the items you let go,
it will lessen the feeling of guilt.
Thank you very much.
For example, it's important to express
gratitude toward clothes you never wore.
This is because the shirt taught you
that you do not like
to wear shirts like this.
By doing this, it will become clear
what is necessary for you.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida]
So, I think it's going pretty smoothly,
so I was thinking of assigning
all the rest for homework.
Okay, so we're done here, right?
-[Iida translates]
-[Mario] That's it, right? [laughing]
I'm realizing a lot of these clothes
I haven't touched in years.
Okay.
[Mario] I have a lot of stuff, man,
and I don't let go of things,
so it's gonna be hard.
It's gonna be rough.
-Less clutter and more homework, right?
-[Clarissa laughing]
-Alright, thank you.
-Okay, thank you. Bye.
-Have a good night. Bye.
-Bye, guys.
-[Marie] Bye.
-[Clarissa] Bye.
[Clarissa] No.
That's still a lot of shoes.
No.
[Clarissa] Starting to feel good
about the process,
starting to really get rid
of a lot of stuff.
Things that I haven't used,
whether it be clothing, shoes,
you know, some purses
I'm fine with getting rid of, and just...
creating more space. So, I'm not...
someone that's gonna
hold onto something that...
I haven't used in years
just because I want to keep it.
But...
I don't know if that's happened for Mario.
I'm interested to see
how quickly he's willing to actually
get rid of something.
[deep sigh]
Because he's definitely got much more
of an emotional attachment to things.
-[barking]
-[Mario] Come on.
Come on, I'm sorting.
You guys come here,
I'm not gonna be able to do anything.
Oh.
Yeah, this one I don't know
if I can part ways with.
This one means a lot.
'Cause despite whatever struggles
or financial burdens my parents
were going through,
I think actually my Dad might have been
unemployed that Christmas.
And nonetheless,
I remember he took us to go buy.
These were real sacrifices
that my parents were going through,
to sometimes just put a smile on our--
me and my brother's face.
I've kept things
just because I do appreciate
what my family has done.
My first Guatemala soccer jersey.
[Mario] So, it's not as easy
as I thought it was gonna be
to let go of some of this stuff.
[deep sigh]
Yeah. [sniffles]
But, uh, I guess you just sit back
and trust the process.
Granted, I haven't got to my shoes yet,
which I think is gonna be
the hardest part.
But I think that, uh...
I'll take my time with that,
I will say that.
But no, that's staying. That's-- Yeah.
-[dog barking]
-[Marie] Oh!
[Marie speaking Japanese]
Hello.
-[Marie and Iida] Hello.
-[Mario chuckling]
-[Mario] Hi. How are you?
-Hi. Good.
-How are you?
-How's it going? Nice to see you.
-Nice to see you. Hi.
-Hi!
Hi. Good to see you again.
-[Marie speaks Japanese]
-[Iida] How are you guys doing?
-[Mario] We're good.
-[Clarissa] Good.
[speaking Japanese]
-I'd love to see the closets first.
-Okay.
-If that's okay.
-[Clarissa] Closets, alright.
Mine. And then his is over...
-Wow.
-[Clarissa laughing]
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] How did you feel sorting through
your clothes and making selections?
I feel good. It was nice to get rid
of things that I don't use anymore
and things that I know
that I'm not going to use, so...
[speaking Japanese]
How about the clothes that you folded?
May I see those?
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
Okay, so there is my dresser.
So all of this pretty much took up
this whole drawer.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] You are so great at folding!
-[laughing]
-Thank you.
-[Iida] I'm surprised. I'm stunned.
[speaking Japanese]
-The socks, I can recommend another way.
-[Clarissa] Okay.
[Mario] Ooh.
-[speaking Japanese]
-So just stack them together like this.
[in English] Fold in half.
-Oh, okay.
-You see?
And then that way you can stack them all.
And also the band won't stretch out. Yeah.
Yeah, I throw away a lot of socks
'cause that happens.
-[laughing]
-[Iida translating]
Okay, babe, it's your turn.
[Clarissa laughing]
-[Mario] Please.
-Thank you.
-Oh! [speaking Japanese]
-[Clarissa laughing]
-Yes, the same method, I think too.
-[Mario] Socks, I've done the same here.
I have socks, bigger socks obviously.
How would you fold that technique
that you were telling Clarissa
with something like this?
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] For socks of this length,
I would recommend folding it in thirds.
[Mario] Okay.
[Iida] For thicker materials like this...
-[Mario] Okay.
-...thirds work.
[Mario] And just file it as well.
Okay.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I think you guys are on
a very, very good pace.
But what's important is that you guys
are motivated to transform your lives.
-[Mario] We are.
-[Iida] That's what matters the most.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
So after clothes,
the next category is books,
right after that is paper documents.
[in Japanese] Tidying together
is a great way for couples
to see if they share the same values.
From here, I'd like for them to learn
the importance of working together.
[speaking Japanese]
[Clarissa] Okay, so I'm gonna start
moving the papers.
[Mario] Just realized, babe,
this is all your stuff.
-[Clarissa laughing]
-This ain't none of mine.
[Clarissa] The black stuff is yours.
-[Mario] Yeah, that little container.
Oh, jeez. [chuckles]
I hold on to note books.
I'm just like you.
I have stickers.
Why?
My prom... invitation.
-You got stuff I think you can--
-[Mario] That I'm keeping.
Shred.
[paper shuffling]
One thing for me I think
which was so easy for me to kind of...
get rid of things is,
if I'm looking at it and it's not
something I like or not something that
strikes anything in me,
I'm fine with getting rid of it.
An unopened invitation
to my brother's wedding.
I'm keeping that one.
These are from all our holiday parties.
These are keep.
[Clarissa] Argh!
But I don't know
if Mario's fully there yet.
He's still not getting rid of things.
What's this little pile I see here, hmm?
Oh, this is just some...
stuff that needs to kinda find a place
here in the house still.
It's a little frustrating just because
we have a set timeline
where we're gonna be expecting a baby
in, what, five months?
I'm worried because, even though
it's five months away,
like, the days seem slow.
But then all of a sudden, like,
a month goes by
and I'm like, "How did that happen?"
Okay.
I'm working on it, babe.
I'm working on laying on this couch.
Probably shouldn't be
in the living room, but...
[Mario groans]
I definitely hope that Marie really helps
get him in line
with what needs to be done,
because I could tell him
ten times to move something
or put it away,
and he's gonna do it when he wants to.
You still have homework to do.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Just you today?
-[Mario] Yes, just me today.
-[Iida] Yes? Okay.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I think your next assignment
is gonna be miscellaneous items.
Okay.
[in English] Maybe garage.
That'd be great. Yes, I'd love to.
-[Iida] Excuse me.
-[Mario] Alright.
[in Japanese]
The garage seems to be a little neater.
-Wow, very clean.
-We picked up a little bit.
[Mario] Yeah.
Um, our doggies are out here
hanging out for now.
[Iida translating]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Mario, I was wondering.
-Yes?
[Iida] Is there anything in here
that you would let go?
[Mario] Most of the stuff here
still has function.
Like, I have a lot of tile...
-[Iida translating]
-...stored away here.
These are essential electrical supplies
that we're gonna need
once we redo this room,
so, uh, there is a purpose
for all this stuff eventually.
[Marie, in Japanese]
Okay, let's just take everything out.
Okay.
[Iida] Anything you want to keep,
try to keep them in separate categories.
-[Mario] Separate categories? Okay.
-Yeah.
-Uh, and for the doggies.
-[in English] Ah, doggy. Okay.
And this is a vintage clock
that someone gave to me.
This is the alarm clock
that woke me up every day for high school
and I loved it so much.
I'm just that kinda dude
that attaches emotion to things, you know?
[Mario] I might be
what some people call sentimental.
And I guess over the course of time,
I've found it really hard
to part ways with some of this stuff.
As scary as it is for me to admit,
I definitely need just an intervention.
Now, here's a good question for you,
because this does have some type
of sentimental value.
[Marie] Ah.
Because this was the mailbox
that was originally on the home
when I purchased it.
So how do you feel
about something like this?
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, when you hold this
in your hand,
does it still spark joy for you?
[peaceful music playing]
I guess joy wouldn't be
the right word to identify this
as to what it means to me, because...
it's just a reminder of, hey...
You know? For what it's worth,
I never thought that,
you know, to have my parents come
from Guatemala,
and where they came from,
to be here in America now,
and have their home and, you know,
have their son have his home
three doors down from them
is something that I think no way
could they have ever fathomed
or even thought of ever happening.
So, that's why I guess little things
like this mean something to me.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] But this is something
that you'd like to keep
as part of your life going forward?
When you put it that way...
no.
I can comfortably say that
the mailbox I have outside
is more joy than what this is, because...
it's something that we did together.
I can let it go.
[in Japanese] Thank you.
[Mario] Through the Kondo process,
yes, it's changing me as we speak
and it's starting to make sense.
It's time to let go of some of this stuff.
I don't know who the Mario's gonna be
after this process, but...
it's uncharted territory,
and I'm really
kinda anxious to see where it ends.
I mean, I was anxious to get here.
So now that we're here,
I feel like now I'm gonna go through this
as much and as hard as possible.
So next time you're here,
maybe it looks different.
-Thank you.
-Gracias.
[laughing]
[Clarissa] And Mario right now
is going through paperwork.
-Huh, babe?
-Yeah.
-Let the shredding commence.
The wheels are in motion,
and I'm just seeing...
seeing and looking at things completely
from a different perspective.
I'm really second guessing everything
as to why it's here,
why we're keeping things.
I'll keep.
That's it?
[Mario]
We have a lot more real estate here.
-[Clarissa] So here we go.
-Trash.
Mario's about to dump
a whole bunch of stuff in the trash.
[Clarissa] I think Mario's mindset
has definitely changed.
It was a bit hard at first for him
to get rid of things,
but he's much better than before.
And Mario's much...
much more eager to get things done
right then and there.
[Clarissa] So, I've gone ahead
and emptied all of the drawers here.
And got through everything in the kitchen.
And I'm excited, it looks...
completely different than
what it looked like before.
[Mario] I'm more surprised about how Clari
has come along in this whole process.
There's this driving force behind her
and I can't help but to feed off of her.
I got a pregnant girl
that's doing the work here.
The last thing I want her to do
is feel stressed,
especially going through this pregnancy.
I want her to be confident
knowing that I have her back
and I'm supportive with anything
and everything that she might need.
There's our little guy.
Twelve weeks. He's much bigger now.
Teeny tiny.
He's as big as a dollar bill today.
[Mario] Obviously we're transitioning
into parenthood
and to have this kind of approach
of tidying things up
ultimately be part
of our everyday kinda habits,
that's kind of the life I wanna lead,
you know, when my son gets here.
Oh, man. [sighing]
[sighing]
Before the whole process even started,
I knew, I was kinda hesitant to, you know,
get started with what was gonna be
addressing my shoe situation.
Oh, man.
Because those are the ones
that are dear to me,
that obviously has
more sentiment behind...
um, each and every one
of those pairs of shoes.
But I think I'm finally ready.
It's time to part ways
and de-clutter some of these shoes.
The first pair.
You'll stay here.
[Mario] $10,000 worth of credit card debt.
I remember that was the first time
I realized I had a problem.
Debt to tennis shoes.
No, that's not what I want my little man
to think is...
what life is, nah.
I don't ever want him
to glorify anything materialistic.
[groaning]
That hurts.
Never got to wear you guys.
[sentimental music playing]
Well...
Some of these shoes have been with me...
God, over three decades.
These are like childhood sneakers
that I might have preserved because...
even though they weren't my size
as an adult,
I still kept them just
for the sake of what they were
when I first was introduced to them
or laid my eyes on them.
Almost the same exact shoe.
But...
now into my adulthood
and let alone transitioning
into the next chapter of my life,
which is fatherhood,
I realize that certain things have kind
of served their purpose with me,
and I guess maybe that's more
of an invitation now, metaphorically,
to what's to come,
and just open to receiving
whatever it is that comes my way,
that I'm kind of detaching myself from...
what was that kinda like...
that mindset
that I had when I was younger.
Hello.
[Mario] What's up?
[Clarissa gasping]
What are you doing?
Trying.
[chuckling]
Looking at things differently.
[Clarissa] Do we have a...
a, uh, give away or...
-Yeah, those.
-...don't keep? These?
So, you're giving away all the shoes
that I've actually seen you wear.
Yeah, because I intend to wear
the ones that I love now.
[Clarissa] I'm definitely proud of Mario
because he's finally willing
to part with shoes that he has held onto.
And the amount
that he has chosen to get rid of,
to me, was surprising because I didn't--
I'd never seen that before,
so I certainly didn't expect him
to get rid of as much as he did.
So that was-- that was surprising to me.
This has never happened
with this pair of shoes.
-Do they fit?
-Yes.
-[laughing]
-Like a glove.
-You bought those, what, four years ago?
-Yeah.
And if that doesn't tell you something.
I've never even put 'em on.
[Mario] It feels good.
[sighing]
[in Japanese]
There are many people like Mario
who want to display their shoes.
[speaking Japanese]
This arrangement creates
an aesthetic balance to the shoe rack.
[Marie and Iida speaking Japanese]
[door buzzer sounding]
[Mario] Hello, hello.
-Ah, hello!
-[Clarissa] Hi.
Hi!
-[Clarissa] How are you?
-[in Japanese] How are you doing?
I'm doing really well.
-Good, good.
-[Marie gasps]
-The house is yours for you to...
-[Iida translating]
...run through it and see what you think.
And please, we're always ears
to anything that you're gonna
counsel us to do.
[Marie, in Japanese]
I'm most interested in the rooms upstairs.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Clarissa and Mario laughing]
-[Iida] Phenomenal. Wow.
-[Clarissa] Yeah.
I think I took the most from this process,
just because I, uh...
I did have a lot of stuff.
Where I started,
I was over 160 pairs of sneakers,
and that's now chipped away
to probably, like, below 45.
It feels good.
I have an appreciation now
for the things that I did keep
and, most importantly,
it made things easy to part with.
[in Japanese]
Wow, this area changed so much!
[Mario] And so I don't ever see myself
going back to
the way I was before
Marie came into our lives.
[Clarissa] Just the techniques
we've learned, you know,
folding the clothes,
I think it's just gonna make it
a lot easier for us
to continue to keep the house,
you know, clean and in order.
The kitchen is probably
the biggest change.
I'm really happy that
the kitchen looks the way it does now.
The counter tops are as,
you know, empty as they can be.
The cabinets are organized.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] You've worked so hard, you guys!
-[Clarissa] Thank you!
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Oh, Clarissa.
Okay.
[Marie gasping]
-[Clarissa laughing]
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Wow!
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Yes, I think this
is remarkably done.
[Mario] Mm-hmm.
I love walking in here now.
I literally have come here
just to grab a chair,
sit on my phone,
and just hang out in here.
[Iida] So I just want
to commend you, Mario,
because how I remember
this garage was
on the first day, to this dramatic change?
-[Mario] It was bad.
-[Iida] This is very impressive.
[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Great job on the garage.
-Thank you. Thank you.
[Clarissa] He passed, right?
[speaking Japanese]
-He more than passed. Very good.
-[Mario] With flying colors.
I can't believe how much progress
we've made from
what the house looked like to, you know,
once Marie got here,
to what we've been able to do now.
So I'm just completely surprised,
had no idea it would
end up looking like this.
Alright.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I can clearly see
that you guys both
worked so hard in the tidying process.
It was a bit stressful
'cause it was just so much at once,
um, but I'm very happy
with the end result.
[Mario] I feel like 95% of everything
is where it needs to be,
so I don't feel as overwhelmed
with the amount of work
that we need to do
to ultimately, like, clean.
[Clarissa] The office area since that's...
looking like it's gonna be
the final spot for the nursery.
It's, I mean, obviously not ready
for us to do that yet.
The desk is in there, there is stuff
that just needs to not be in there,
but it's very close.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] But I think now,
you said you're 95% there,
but the road to 100%,
I think it's very clear.
-[Clarissa] Yeah.
-I have every faith that you can finish.
[Mario] I know that along this process
we've gotten stronger.
I am so eager and so motivated,
now more than ever, to just...
plow through as much as I possibly can
in terms of addressing things
and projects around the home.
Just to see it just coming to fruition,
it's just, it's so--
Such a good feeling
and I'm hooked on that feeling right now.
-We'll be done before the baby's here.
-Yes.
And much before the baby gets here
because we do wanna enjoy
this free time that we now have.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, is it okay if I ask
when the baby is due?
In August. So do you wanna go grab
the new pictures?
[Mario] Would you like to see him?
Yes, I'll get 'em.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] This is a great timing
that you finished this.
[Clarissa]
Yeah, that's what we're thinking.
That's why, you know,
we're kind of putting...
deadlines on all the other things
we wanna get done to just...
-Please.
-...enjoy.
Here, let's put 'em down there.
-[speaking Japanese]
-Put 'em on the table.
[in Japanese] I can see the face!
[squealing]
-[laughing]
-[in Japanese] Oh, my gosh! It's a person!
[laughing]
-[Iida] Oh, there he is.
-[Clarissa] So, yeah, he is a boy.
[all laughing]
[in English] Oh, I can see.
[in Japanese]
What an amazing thing to look forward to.
-[in Japanese] Thank you.
-[Iida] Thank you so much. I'm honored.
-[Mario] So, gracias.
-Gracias.
-[laughing]
-Muchas gracias.
Muchas gracias.
Yes, to you. Thank you.
[speaking Japanese]
Do you know how to say
"spark joy" in Spanish?
Te, T. E.
-Te.
-Trae.
-Alegria.
Te trae alegria.
-That's lovely.
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] I love the sound of that.
-[laughing]
[Marie, in Japanese]
Mario and Clarissa learned
the tools to create their ideal life,
through this tidying process.
Even though they are still
not completely finished,
I'm sure by the time their son arrives,
their home will be ready.
I hope Mario, Clarissa, and their son
will continue to spark
a lot of joy in their future.
[pop music playing]
♪ Take me away ♪
♪ Don't be afraid ♪
♪ 'Cause they always say ♪
♪ Let go of your fears ♪
♪ 'Cause we all make mistakes in life ♪
♪ But if we're ever gonna get it right ♪
♪ We're gonna give it all another try ♪
♪ That's what I'm dreaming of ♪
♪ Follow all the things you love ♪
♪ Love, love ♪