-Ah!
-[woman] She looks excited!
I'm so excited because I love mess.
[man] It's a never ending battle
to fight the clutter.
-[knocking]
-Oh!
I want things to be more simple.
I don't know how to fix it.
With the baby coming,
it's gonna be more chaos.
[gasping, squealing]
[man] Oh, my God! We have too much stuff!
Hello, I'm Marie Kondo.
[in Japanese] My mission
is to spark joy in the world
through cleaning.
Ching!
[narrator] Best-selling author
and world-renowned tidying expert
Marie Kondo is dedicated to inspiring
the world to choose joy
with the KonMari Method.
[in Japanese]
A feature of the KonMari Method
is that you clean by item
and not by location.
And we will always clean using
the same categories.
[in English] First, it's clothing.
-[Marie grunting]
-[laughter]
I can't reach.
Next, is books.
[Iida] Giving them a little shake
and wake them up.
Then, paper.
[man sighs] I can't do the papers.
[deep groan]
The largest category is komono.
Komono is kitchen, bathroom,
and garage.
Everything miscellaneous.
Finally, sentimental items.
It's kinda hard to let it go,
'cause I really like this one.
[sniffling] This is kinda hard.
I don't want to just, you know, dump it.
But I want to be thoughtful about it.
[man 2] From the moment she
set foot in our house,
she had this presence to her.
She wants to see this place turned around.
Marie brought a whole bunch
of joy upon our home.
This is amazing.
[girl] You're so cute! I love you!
You're so cute.
I love you, too. [laughing]
These are, like, happy, happy tears.
Thank you for what you've brought
to our home, really.
[in Japanese] The KonMari Method
is a means to realize your ideal life.
My clients this time, Angela and Alishia,
are newlyweds.
They recently purchased a condo
for their new home.
They are a lovely couple,
but they are having trouble figuring out
how they can turn their new home
into a comfortable space for both of them.
Through tidying, I'm looking forward to
helping them create a comfortable home.
[upbeat music playing]
-Hi!
-Hi.
-Hello, I'm Marie.
-Angela.
-Nice to meet you.
-Hi, I'm Iida, Miss Marie's interpreter.
-Hi Iida. Nice to meet you. Angela.
-We're very excited to have you here.
-Yes!
-Alright, come on in.
-Thank you.
[Angela] We do have a kitty cat.
-[Angela laughing]
-[Iida translating]
-Hi.
-Hi. [laughing]
[in Japanese] Hi, Kitty!
-Nice to meet you. I'm Marie.
-[chuckles] Alishia.
Pleased to meet you.
-Hi, I'm Iida, Miss Marie's interpreter.
-Nice to meet you, Iida. Alishia.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Oh, you have two dogs!
-Our puppies out there.
[Angela] So the big one is London
and the little one is Teddy,
and you've met kitten, Earl.
I'm Angela, I'm a veterinarian.
I'm Alishia, I'm a flight attendant.
I was working a flight from...
Vegas to Atlanta,
and she was my passenger and she was all
like, "Hey, cute stuff."
-I was like, "Hey, girl."
-That's not how I remember it.
Oh, my gosh, really?
I mean, it's close enough.
-That was, what, five years ago?
-Mm-hmm.
[Alishia] Prior to Angela
I was considered a nomad.
I feel like I literally grabbed her
out of the sky and...
brought her down to earth.
Oh, yes.
[Angela]
We recently just got married last June.
-We've literally married...
-[Alishia] Married our lives together.
So, we are new homeowners.
About a month ago,
we've closed escrow on our new place.
So, this is that first step
into adulthood that we're--
we've heard so much about. [laughing]
[Angela]
Just in these last couple of weeks,
we've been moving
and things are everywhere.
[Alishia]
The transition has been semi-stressful.
-You know, it's--
-Very stressful.
Okay. Very stressful.
[Alishia] That's why it's critical
for us to get our space
organized and live-in ready,
because it's a new chapter.
You don't want to start
the new chapter...
-disorganized or chaotic.
-With old stuff.
We want that easy breezy.
We want to be able to come into our space
and definitely feel...
relaxed, you know?
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So how long has it been
since you moved here?
Uh, It's only been three weeks.
-We just moved here.
-Three weeks?
[Angela] Yes.
[speaking Japanese]
-Gosh, so you just moved in.
-Yes.
-[Iida] Wow.
-[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, as soon as I entered this room,
it seems perfectly organized and tidy.
Is, is--
Do you really have a problem with tidying?
-Oh, you'll see.
-Should we give you a little tour?
[in Japanese] Yes, please.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-♪ The struggle ♪
We call this the struggle room.
-[Iida] I see. I'm starting to see now.
-[Alishia] The good stuff. Yeah.
Ninety percent of those are mine.
[Iida translating]
[Alishia] Those are mostly mine.
[in Japanese] Here are the shoes.
-Clothes.
-[Marie, in English] Clothes.
-Mostly mine. Well...
-[Iida translating]
Mine. Mine, mine.
Ours, more winter stuff.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-So how do you use this room right now?
-We don't.
-[Angela laughing]
We want this room to be
kinda like the office
slash guest space, slash closet.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Yes, there's a lot of cloudiness
here in this room.
So we'll figure that out.
-[Alishia] Don't fall on anything.
-[all laughing]
[Angela] We tried to organize
this space a little bit.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So how do you use this space?
My pants and then...
-Those are my jeans on that side.
-Yeah.
[Alishia] Usually, we find ourselves
in a closet battle.
For instance, we share belts, like belts
and socks and accessories and things.
I'll ask her where the belts are,
'cause my belts that she doesn't wear
are in a spot,
so we have, like, separate belts
and we have belts together.
-[Alishis chuckles]
-The belts together get lost.
[Alishia] Although we've been together
for so many years,
we never got to organize.
We're gonna have clothes in both rooms.
You wanna put your shirt on over there,
pants over here.
How do you want this to work?
I've kinda just been grabbing
the outfit together.
Like, I grab a shirt, come in here
and grab some pants,
and get dressed in the room.
-I'm just saying, you don't want...
-Some cohesiveness?
-Yeah.
-I do, but I just...
I just want everything put away right now.
[both laughing]
-It causes tension.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So the general impression
that I got from your closet is that
a lot of your things are mixed together
and it's a little difficult
to determine, oh, what's inside.
-Yeah.
-Yes.
Yes.
[in Japanese] A tip on sharing
closet space with a partner
is to designate areas for each person.
For example,
in this closet...
[grunting]
I can't reach the top rack,
so I will choose to use the bottom rack.
By doing this,
it is easy to see
how much clothing you have.
[Marie] Aw.
[Angela] This is kind of
our stress-free area.
We wanted to ensure we had
a place in the house
to kinda get away from all of the moving,
and so we put this together first.
[Alishia] Okay. [grunting]
You got it?
So this is the only part
where it's kind of like hers and mine.
[Alishia] Yeah, clothes are mine.
I feel like we organize things
a little differently,
like, she will put things
in a different spot than me,
and I think that's how we get
kind of our wires crossed.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I would recommend making
this particular closet
all of Alishia's clothes.
[Alishia] And then that way Angela
could have the guest bedroom space.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Ultimately, that would be
the simplest solution.
-[tsks] Goody.
-Okay.
[in Japanese] When tidying,
each individual should be responsible
for their own space.
This lessens the tension
and increases their sense of trust
and bonding.
[Angela] The kitchen. It could be better.
[Iida] This has room
for improvement definitely.
[Angela] That's actually a problem area.
[Iida] So do these items belong
to the both of you,
or does one person
have more than the other?
I would say maybe both.
The kitchen was kinda split.
-Yeah.
-Half is mine, half is hers.
We're definitely complete opposites
when it comes to, like, organizing.
[Angela] And it's frustrating.
We need help categorizing what stuff
needs to go with what stuff.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I really feel that the presence
of this home is so important.
You mentioned that this is your first home
that you've purchased,
so this is a very significant space.
So I would like to take this time
to formally introduce myself to your home.
-Okay.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] It's only been three weeks, right?
-Yup.
-Yes.
[speaking Japanese]
If that's the case,
I think it would be much better
if you do this with me.
-Okay.
-Okay, let's do it.
[Iida] Let's gather here in the middle.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Just tell your home
your intention for it
and your hopes for it.
[peaceful music playing]
[playful music playing]
She'll meditate for a while.
[Angela chuckling]
You guys left me.
[laughing]
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] How did you feel?
-Inspired.
-[Iida translating]
Excited.
-[Alishia] Yeah.
-[Angela] I just saw order.
-Yeah.
Relaxed.
[Iida] I hope you'll keep
all the feelings that you felt
in your heart
as we go through the tidying,
because tidying isn't just about
organizing your home.
It's about creating a welcoming, inviting,
positive environment into your home.
Yay!
[Iida] Take out every single,
last piece of clothes.
Oh, lordy, help me!
[chuckling]
-What's your anxiety level right now?
-[laughing]
[Angela]
We're gonna lose Marie in the pile.
[Alishia] Holy macaroni.
[Angela] I told you you have
more clothes than me.
[Alishia]
I know I have more clothes than you.
[Angela] I think we have it all.
[Iida] We're gonna be going through
these clothes piece be piece.
When you hold each item in your hands,
ask if it sparks joy for you.
Okay. I can do that.
We can just start right from the top.
Yes.
Yes, yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
And all of these yeses. [laughing]
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Angela, let's get started
with your pile, then.
-Okay.
-Oh, Okay.
[Angela] Clothes for me
are just functional
because I'm not very attached
to material things.
So I don't have very
many clothes in general
just because I'm wearing scrubs
four days out of the week.
I don't have dresses and shirts
and pants and stuff like that.
I don't like to get dressed up too much.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Ask if it sparks joy for you.
I like it, but I really--
I don't wear it as often.
I can let you go.
You can be happy for somebody else.
-[Marie] Thank you.
-[Angela] Thank you.
She let the Redskins go?
Get out of my space!
-[laughing]
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
Goodness.
[Alishia] I pride myself
on my eclecticness
because I do wear a uniform,
and so, I don't really get to wear
my clothes too much,
and I feel like
even though I'm not wearing
the clothes all the time
it's still, like, an expression
of my personality.
Right, how are we doing?
[Alishia] Question: there's some things
that I'm holding onto.
There's one dress in particular
I wanted to show you.
This is actually the little dress.
My grandmother bought me this.
Ah! I love.
[Iida translating]
Isn't it so cute?
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] I love it, it's lovely.
But it's also too small, so...
[Iida translating]
I just remember...
wanting it really bad,
and she kinda gave me that look.
She was like, "Go try it on."
So I go try it on and she goes,
"Okay, you can have it."
[Iida] Are you very close
to your grandmother?
I was, she passed away in 2006.
This is probably, like...
close to the oldest thing in my closet.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] The point of this process isn't
to force yourself to eliminate things.
It's really to confirm how you feel about
each and every item that you possess.
[inhaling sharply]
I'm just gonna look at you
a little longer.
Just a little longer.
Marie helping us tackle the biggest
challenge, which is our closet space
and the actual organization
is so refreshing.
I'm excited to put everything
where it needs to be.
-Bye, see you soon.
-See you soon. Bye.
Okay, you ready to get this homework done?
Where do I put my keep stuff?
[Alishia] I love my clothes.
I know when it touches my body,
I'm like, "Ooh!" I get it.
I get it. So that, that feeling
that she said that you should feel,
that is-- that's joy.
I feel that with a lot of my items.
For instance, this particular dress,
I was probably 16 or 17
when my grandmother purchased it.
But it was just that memory
of being with her.
And my grandmother loved clothes,
so we have that in common.
So...
[sharp inhale and exhale]
It's kinda hard to let it go,
'cause I really like this one.
And I wear it all the time.
That's probably why it's faded, too.
But...
[pats and tsks]
This just takes me back
to a time with her and
not really-- I mean I spent
a lot of time with her,
but I just want it--
just I always remember--
[softly] I think I might cry now.
[gentle piano music playing]
[crying, sniffles]
[sniffling]
[Angela] You okay?
So you didn't just--
You okay?
-Aww...
-[Alishia sniffling]
It's okay.
[seagulls squawking]
-[doorbell chiming]
-[dogs barking]
-[Alishia] Hi!
-[Marie] Hi!
-How are you? Hi.
-Oh my goodness gracious.
[Angela] London, come on, let's go.
Let's go outside, honey.
Teddy, London, outside, let's go.
Go. Git.
There you go.
[Marie laughing]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] How's it going?
How was the homework?
[Angela] Um...
-Well...
-[both laughing]
First things first,
these items are the things
that we've touched on
and loved on and thanked,
but they no longer serve
a purpose for us, so we're actually...
in the process of donating.
-[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] That's great.
Okay.
-[in Japanese] I'd love to see the rest.
-Great. Okay.
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] I was wondering,
what did you do with the dress
that your grandmother gave you?
I still have it.
It's just next to the bed.
I knew I was gonna go through...
the changes in my mind and in my body,
especially with my clothes, because I do--
I love my clothes.
But I have to learn to extract
the memory from an item.
That dress brings up my grandmother,
and I guess it's just more of a sad place
because she's no longer here.
I am gonna donate or give away or...
if anyone wants it. [laughing]
It's healthy to revisit and to remember,
and obviously I want a part
of my grandmother to be in my home,
but there are a lot of different things
that could remind me of her.
A question I had,
what is the best way to fold
the hoodies,
because they get so bulky
and I feel like it doesn't remain folded.
[speaking Japanese]
So there are two ways to store hoodies.
You can store them in drawers
or you can pile them together.
If you were storing them in drawers,
aim for that rectangle in the middle,
fold towards the center...
[speaking Japanese]
...tuck the hood in...
...and roll into thirds,
so you can file them vertically
-in the drawer if you like.
-[Alishia] Okay.
And then,
what is the best way
to fold undergarments?
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I consider bras
very important for women,
so I like to file them in a way
that really, truly sparks joy.
[in Japanese]
Bras are special items for women.
So let's store them with VIP treatment.
When storing bras,
arrange them in a way where
you don't smoosh the cups.
It'll spark joy if you arrange them
in a way that creates a color gradient.
Let's fold the cupless bras.
Fold it in half...
and tuck in the straps.
They can be stored in this way.
For soft cup bras.
Fold it in half,
tuck in the straps,
then roll it up
for a refreshing way to store it.
[in Japanese] When storing bras,
if you put them in boxes,
it'll look more organized.
Okay. Just a little quick peek.
[laughing]
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] And most importantly, shoes.
What happened to those?
[Alishia] The shoes are still mixed.
What we are trying to figure out
is if it'll be easier to leave
in the shoe box
or to take the shoes out.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
I will make this my homework
and think about it.
-[speaking Japanese]
-So okay, leave that up to me.
Don't worry too much
about the storage solution.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So today I'd like to move
onto the miscellaneous items
and I recommend tackling the kitchen.
Okay.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Just take everything out,
even the tupperwares, everything out,
and just go through them and ask yourself
if you see any items
that don't belong to your life ahead,
that you don't necessarily feel
like it should be
a part of your life going forward.
Okay. Now...
Some spices.
Um, we have some pantry items.
[Marie] Oh, I see.
If there are any expired items,
this is a great opportunity
to toss them.
[Angela] Oh, for sure.
[in Japanese] The main tip on organizing
the pantry is to categorize food items.
For example, the drinks category
such as coffee and tea.
Cereals and snacks.
Pasta, flour, and other carbohydrates.
And finally canned foods.
For small items such as snacks,
if you put them in boxes
it'll be easier to access
and it'll look more organized.
By storing your food like this,
it will make it easy to keep track
of the quantity of food you have.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Next time I'm here, I will have
solutions for you in terms of storage
for all your miscellaneous items.
-See you next week.
-Next time.
Thank you guys. Bye bye.
-[Marie] Bye!
-[Alishia] Bye-bye.
Okay.
-We have more homework to do.
-More homework.
[Alishia] Oh, goodness. [sighs]
It's about to go down. [groans]
-Soy sauce.
-Soy.
This is disgusting. Throw it away.
[Angela] Why?
-Oh!
-Why, Alishia?
Don't why me.
We don't eat ketchup.
Is there ketchup in the refrigerator?
[Alishia chuckles]
Yes, there is.
You know what, ketchup?
You don't bring me joy anymore.
Oh, my gosh.
Uh-oh.
Don't even look.
[Alishia] What is that? Gravy?
[Angela] Turkey gravy, slow cooker.
There you go.
You've got turkey gravy from 2015!
[laughing]
[Angela laughing]
I feel like you've been holding onto
that turkey gravy just to be spiteful.
-We need to figure out...
-[Angela] Stop sliding that.
-Ugh...
-[Angela] Pick it up. Put it in the back.
I don't reach.
Oh, my goodness. Short people.
Angela and I have a disconnect
on where do we put these items.
Her access is different from my access.
Basic access is height.
[Angela] We have a lot of cabinet space
where I can put stuff higher
and reach things,
but she does more of the cooking,
so it needs to be where she can reach it.
Unless she doesn't want me to touch it.
And then I just put it really high.
Like my things.
[laughing]
"Don't touch my stuff, Alishia."
[Alishia]
Have you gone through these glasses?
[Angela] Yeah.
They don't look like you went through 'em.
Don't sort my things,
sort your things, 'kay?
Oh, those are fighting words!
"Don't sort my things, hmm hmm hmm."
Meow!
-[Angela] We disagree on
-[Alishia] Organization.
-...where things should go
and how things should be done.
If I had to give you an example of
what type of person I think Angela is,
she will put a blender...
in the linen closet.
Why is this here?
"Well, all the electronics are in there."
So in her mind it makes sense.
And then in mine I'm like, "No."
It made sense at the time and so I did it.
[sighs]
[Angela] You can get rid of those
pink ones.
[Alishia] What about these dirty
yellow ones?
You're sorting my stuff again.
Jesus, let go of it. Let go.
-[Angela] You are real judgy today.
-Well.
These are actually, like, seeing glasses.
These are not for style.
Why don't you just put them all in there?
You have a problem with wanting
to put things in different places.
One of the things that Marie
made very clear is that
even though you have different ideas,
like items need to be together here.
So once we sift through that
a little more,
with time, I think we'll be good.
[doorbell chiming]
-[Marie] Hi!
-[Alishia] Hello!
-Hi.
-Come on in.
-Come on in, welcome, welcome, welcome.
-Hi.
-Come on in.
-Nice to see you. Wow.
You guys brought gifts.
-[Iida translates]
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
Yes, many of them.
-[Alishia] Let's get right into it.
-Yeah.
-[Alishia] What's our next dilemma?
-[Angela] Shoes.
[Iida] When storing all these shoes,
try to imagine
what a store display would look like.
So just keep the similar colors together,
same types of shoes together.
-[Angela] So the shoe boxes.
-[Alishia] Can we keep the shoe boxes?
-Yeah. So like that, right?
-Right.
[Alishia] So we could just put the shoe
box here and then the shoes on top.
The only thing about this shelf...
are the heels.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I actually have the same rack
in my closet, too
and that's always been my
problem that I have.
[Alishia] Oh, snap! Look at that!
[Iida] Even these you can fit
and it won't fall through.
Okay.
-Wow.
-[Iida laughing]
You solved that problem so fast.
[Iida] For me in my house,
I tend to use pretty postcards
or things that spark joy for me.
Oh, nice, okay.
I can do that.
-[Angela] What should we move onto now?
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] I'd like to continue
with the lesson on komono.
Yes.
[Alishia] So...
I don't know what to do
with our dog items
'cause they are in multiple places.
[Iida] Let's take a look.
Oh, they're getting excited.
[Alishia] "That's my stuff!"
So we have three fur babies.
-Welcome to our family.
-Right.
[Angela] Um, untraditional,
but traditional at the same time.
We're like the Brady Bunch.
It was really important finding a space
that they could--
we could all co-habitate together.
Um, so the balconies are really nice
'cause they can go outside
on the balconies
and kinda get that airspace.
It's important that we get the space
together for them, too.
Oh, yes.
'Cause as you can see,
they're up in everything.
Oh, yes.
[Iida] So what's in here?
What's in this basket?
So, they have a lot of toys
and I want them to be able to get them.
But I also want the toys out the way.
I don't know how
she found all these balls.
Well, granted at our last place,
we lived next to a tennis court.
Can you select how many
tennis balls you need?
-One.
-Just one?
[dogs whimpering]
-[Angela] She wants her tennis balls.
-[all laughing]
I would say more than that because
sometimes at the park they get nasty
and we don't want to bring it home.
-[Iida] Two?
-[Alishia] Three. Mhm.
-[Angela] Three tennis balls.
-Three, okay.
[speaking Japanese]
You definitely use these for walks, right?
-The leashes.
-Yes. And so we have--
we just need to put it somewhere.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So for the kitten
and doggie supplies,
I think using this whole section
for their items would be best.
Just hanging them right here
and putting the leash
will help identify this section.
[in Japanese] When tidying pet supplies,
it's important to create
a space for them.
Here's a tip for storing pet items.
For example,
you can put toys here.
This is a toy.
Leashes go here.
Grooming and food supplies here.
If you divide the space,
it'll look more tidy.
For dogs, you take them
on a walk every day
so you can put leashes on a hook
and put them on the wall.
I never got a chance
to use a leash like this
because I only had eel-like fish
as pets when I was little.
[Angela] You want to go
to the master bath?
-[Iida] Let's take a look.
-[Angela] Sure.
[Alishia] The bathroom is kind of
a mixed-use space.
Angela is a groomaholic.
So...
for instance, hairbrushes,
shampoos, conditioners...
The woman is insane.
[Angela] My bathroom
needs to be organized.
-I need to be an arm reach away from...
-She uses so many products.
...my brush and my gel
and my hair lotion.
"I need contact solution, I need this,
I need that, I need--" I'm like, "Oh."
I don't want anything
on the bathroom counter.
I like cohesiveness
and she just likes accessibility.
So these items here,
Angela uses these daily.
-Hmm.
-Along with...
[Iida translating]
...these, daily.
And then we have the makeup brushes
and lipsticks.
Oh, more hair stuff.
[Iida translating]
Oh, that's like my hair stuff.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] So, the point here
for storage in the bathroom
is to section it off with smaller boxes
and utilize the space that way.
-Game changer!
-[Angela] We need a lot of those.
[Marie] Yes.
-[Iida] Let's stack them.
-Game changer!
-I'm never gonna throw away a box again.
-[Alishia] Yeah, it makes sense now.
As soon as she put
that little box in there,
it all just came full circle.
I was like, "Ah!"
-I like that.
-Yeah.
Okay. We're moving on.
[Alishia] Now with the bathroom,
even though we're in the same drawer
we're still separated.
That way, it's not messy. You know, it's--
You still have your little bit of space.
-You want me to take something for you?
-[Iida translating]
[Marie] Thank you.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
The cool part
has definitely been organizing,
um, as opposed to kinda
letting go of things.
[Angela] Since all of our stuff
was together,
I think, you know, we blended,
but now that we have our designated spaces
but we still have our communal things,
everything else is just gonna
fall into place.
So we are going all drinkware here,
all food items here,
-and dishes are staying there.
-Yeah.
We work well together...
when we have a clear path.
Let's get to it, let's chop chop.
[Angela] Big, big.
Small, small.
The common goal was this is our home,
and we want it to be ease for both of us.
-[Angela] We like straws.
-[Alishia] Boxes. Bam.
High five. Mm.
We want to be able to move-- maneuver
without, you know, restrictions.
Now it's like all the things
that we love sparks that ding!
-The what?
-Ding!
[Angela laughing]
That's like my favorite thing, like...
Ding!
[Angela] It's all Alishia's stuff
that has to move.
You just seem so excited about that.
I want a little corner,
that's all, to call my own.
-[Alishia] This is your corner.
-Yeah, it's my corner now.
Our biggest headache was her getting
her closet in order and then
me getting my closet in order.
And so once we got things separated
we can kind of do our own thing.
[Alishia] I've taken my things
out of the dresser,
so this is gonna be all Angela's items.
Aren't you happy? You get your own space.
[whispering]
I'm so excited to have some space.
Things had to get worse first...
before we started to really understand
what the process was about,
knowing that, you know,
we are doing this journey together,
but we do have an individual journey
that we need to take
before we kinda get together
and tackle the things that we...
co-own.
[Angela] I am exhausted
from a hard day's work.
Alishia, she's determined
to get this shelf in order.
[Angela] The bickering is...
-It's slowly on the decline.
-[laughing]
I love her more.
-Do ya?
-I do.
I didn't think that was possible. [laughs]
You'd be surprised
what a little organization could do.
So obviously our wedding book,
wedding gift book, remember?
I think we kind of actually started
organizing in the same...
-you know, the same fashion now as well.
-Mm-hmm.
[Angela] Marie is gonna be so excited.
[Alishia] I hope she likes it.
[Angela] Everybody's knocked out.
[birds tweeting]
[doorbell chiming]
[Angela] Marie's here.
-[Marie] Hi!
-[Alishia] Hi, Marie!
How are you? Good to see you. Welcome.
Hi!
Good to see you.
-How are you?
-Good, how are you?
-Good, good.
-Good.
-More boxes.
-[Iida] I know!
-We ran out.
-[laughing]
Ready to see what we've done?
-[speaking Japanese]
-Yes, absolutely. Let's go.
-[Alishia] Our space now...
-[Angela] It's like a welcome home.
-[Alishia] Oh yeah.
-[Angela] Like, you did it.
[Angela] There's no roadblocks,
I know where everything is, it's perfect.
[Alishia] Mhm.
[Angela] Things you eat with.
[Iida] Oh, look how neat it looks.
[Angela] I remember at first, the biggest
task was, I don't organize like she does.
-[Alishia] Right.
-[Angela] And vice versa.
And now we kinda see eye to eye on...
Everything is right here.
[chuckles] Right, and it makes sense
to be right there.
-Yeah, common ground on organization.
-Yeah.
-[Alishia] Ready to move on?
-[Angela] Yeah.
[Angela] That second room,
we kept the door shut
because we didn't want to see
all that stuff.
-[Angela] Goodness gracious.
-[Marie gasping]
-[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] This is amazing.
[Angela] Now we can actually...
-[Alishia] Walk in there.
[Angela] I leave the door open now
'cause I like looking at the space.
[speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Look how well
you've used the space.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] Now you know where everything is.
-[Alishia] Oh, yeah.
-[iida] It's easy to find.
I'm excited for people to come
and see this. "Look what I did."
[laughing]
We did a good job, Honey.
-[Angela] Yeah.
-Yeah.
We're a couple, we're together,
we share a lot of things together,
but everything got a lot better
when we designated our own spaces.
[Marie speaking Japanese]
[Iida] Look how neat and simple it looks
when you open the closet.
-[Alishia] I love it.
-[Iida] It's amazing.
[Alishia] We don't really have to struggle
through the other person's things
to get to our own.
[Angela] To just kinda have that...
individuality has kinda
made a world of difference.
That was the biggest transformation,
I think.
So going through the process took care
of a lot of those little blips
and stresses.
[Alishia] It's also, like, soothing
to open the drawer
because you know it's in order.
[Angela] We've gained a deeper respect
for each other's belongings
and we really got to learn a lot
about each other in that process as well,
and see why that item brings them joy.
So, it was really therapeutic
in our relationship as far as just
getting to know each other
a little bit better.
We're so grateful for you to come in
and just show us something
we thought we possessed within ourselves,
but we just didn't know how to exert it.
[Angela]] You gave us the tools
that we needed to really
put things together.
I think when we first came in
and we welcomed the home
and we really wanted to
envision the space,
I think
we're coming to that point where...
-this is how we wanted the space to be.
-Oh, yeah.
[speaking Japanese]
-[Iida] You guys get an A+.
-Nice.
[Iida] Congratulations, you've graduated
the KonMari Method of tidying! [chuckles]
-[laughing, speaking Japanese]
-Thank you. Congratulations.
Thank you, thank you.
-[Angela] My gosh.
-[Alishia] It's so exciting!
-[Angela] I know!
-High five.
Yes. We did it.
We are ambassadors
of Marie Kondo. Like look,
this'll change your life.
-Seriously.
-And it's not just about organization,
-it's really a lifestyle change.
-Oh, yeah.
Um, and it really is therapeutic
-and it'll change things in your life.
-Oh, yeah.
-Thank you!
-Thank you so much.
Much!
-Thank you.
Have a good day, guys.
-Bye!
-[Alishia] We'll keep you posted.
She didn't just come by, she came in
and she, like, left her stamp.
-Her aura's around the house.
-Definitely.
-We really appreciate you.
-We appreciate-- Yeah.
Thank you so much for just...
changing how we view our items,
how we view our clothes,
how we view our animals.
Like, there's just a different level
of appreciation that we have for...
-everything in the home now.
-Everything.
[bottles clinking]
[pop music playing]
♪ This is home ♪
♪ When I'm with you ♪
♪ As long as we're together ♪
♪ This is home ♪
♪ When I'm with you ♪
♪ As long as we're together ♪
♪ This is home ♪