[ominous tone plays]
[automated voice] You must convince
another player to pick up this call.
If you fail to convince
another player to take the phone,
you will be eliminated.
[dramatic music plays]
Your time starts now.
[ticking]
[Husnain] Why did I answer the phone?
Now I'm, like, properly under pressure.
But I want to eliminate 432.
Do you want food?
[Bryton] Wait. Why can't you have it?
[Husnain] No, they said convince someone
to pick the phone up
if they want a chocolate muffin.
[Bryton] I don't want that phone, dawg.
[woman 1] He's been on the phone
for quite a while now.
[man 1] Something ain't right here.
[Bryton] I mean,
I had issues with player 198,
so there's no chance
that I'm grabbing
that phone out of his hand.
[suspenseful music plays]
Do you want food? Do you want food?
[Husnain] What do I do? What do I do?
Normally, I can blag something,
but, like, when it's the pressure
of "you're gonna get eliminated,"
and the chance of like four million,
everything just gets blank.
-Chocolate muffin if you want it.
-Chocolate muffin? Why not?
Do you--
No, you can get the phone if you want.
If it's not an elimination,
I will. [chuckles]
Go for it.
[suspenseful music intensifies]
I can see the fear in his eyes.
If you want food-- If you want food,
you have to pick it up within two minutes.
[Favour] I know something's not right.
Someone has to pick the phone up.
It's a chocolate muffin.
Chocolate muffin, whoever wants it.
Two minutes, that's what they said.
I just thought, "These scavengers
love chips and burgers."
"Why would they not love muffins?"
[man 176] What did they say?
[Husnain] Yeah,
you got two minutes to do it.
-Are you sure?
-[Husnain] Yeah.
-No!
-[Husnain] Two minutes.
[Bryton] You gonna trust him?!
-Of all people, you gonna trust him?
-[Husnain] It's a chocolate muffin.
[Jada] Answer it, answer it, answer it!
Pick it up, pick it up!
-[man 202] Seb, don't!
-Why?
Seb, come with me.
Seb, Seb, just trust me.
-[Jada] We only have two minutes!
-You got two minutes to pick it up.
Pick up the phone. I'm not picking it up,
but someone pick it up.
[Husnain] Whoever wants to get it, get it.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah, just pick it up.
-Darius, no!
-[Husnain] Just pick it up.
-[man 375] Darius, no.
-Don't, Darius.
-No!
-[all chattering]
-[players screams]
-[woman 033] No.
-Mate, it's not that deep.
-No? Okay--
All right. I'm-- I'm gone. I'm gone.
[Husnain] Pick it up in two minutes,
or no one gets it.
[woman] No. No!
He's way too desperate
to have somebody pick it up.
[Husnain] My mind's going 100 miles
an hour right now.
I don't have time to think though.
Does no one want it?
-[beep plays on speaker]
-[automated voice] Player 198.
Answer the phone.
Two minutes are up.
[automated voice]
You have failed the test.
[door clangs and whirs]
[man] He was like-- Yo.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo, yo!
Look who's here.
[ominous music plays]
[Husnain] I just lost $4 million.
[woman] He's gone, he's gone!
[ominous music swells and continues]
Oh my God.
[automated voice] Player 198…
eliminated.
[players gasp and exclaim]
[automated voice] The current prize fund
now stands at $3,380,000.
[choral theme music playing]
[Bryton] Look, hey, hey.
I told y'all about that damn phone.
-Everybody wants to pick up that phone.
-Exactly.
[Bryton] He got greedy.
He has friends here.
-Yes.
-He didn't go to any of his friends.
He went to somebody
he just met today for his first option.
Like, that shit makes no sense.
Like, if it was me,
I woulda been like, "Bruh."
"We got pizza
on the other side of this door."
"Like, I need you over here."
Like, he was bad at it.
This is really getting cutthroat now.
Now that he's gone, nobody has a target,
which means
everyone's going for everyone now.
-[Rick] Can you believe that?
-[Stephen] It was unreal, dude.
[Rick] I can't believe it.
If you go, dude,
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
[chuckles] You're gonna carry on.
That's your job.
Dude, you're the brightest light in here.
I'm so serious.
You're the brightest light. I don't care
if you're the oldest one here.
-We sticking together.
-We are a good team.
Yeah, we really are.
I honestly feel like the gganbu gang
is doing a-- a really good job
being low-key,
being cool with everybody else.
I don't feel like we have any enemies,
by any means,
and I feel like we're
all really good people. I feel…
comfortable, oddly enough.
[Rick] Pretty much my goal to come here
is-- is to make a contribution.
You know, not really planning on winning,
with the talent here,
but I was always hoping
if I could help one person win that,
it's, like-- it's a win for me.
-Wouldn't that be incredible?
-M-Maybe something like that will happen.
If you win,
it would be like I was part of that.
[ominous music plays]
I'm-- I'm not a leader… directly,
but I like to enable the leader.
I like to help.
I work hard.
My work had always
taken up a lot of my time.
I have more free time now,
and… over the years,
I've added a lot of hobbies to my life.
Everything I love
and everything I do in a big way.
I don't do anything in a small way.
My wife thinks that's one of my faults.
Um, I'm a beekeeper.
Uh, I have such passion for-- for my bees.
I think about my bees every day.
I just wonder if they think about me.
[ominous tone plays]
[man 1] Whoa!
[man 2] Nice.
[man 107] Two, that's two.
I-- I think tug-of-war is next.
Expect the unexpected.
We don't know, we just have to--
Every day we're here,
we gotta wake up and be ready to adapt.
-Yep.
-And do anything we can to survive.
-Yeah.
-So…
[Trey] I feel like I trust 0-3-3, Figgy.
She and I have been having
good conversations,
and she feels very open and candid with me
in a way
that I don't think other people are.
Listen, if I go,
can you take care of my mom,
please? [chuckles]
-If something happens, you want--
-Yeah.
To you? You're asking me
to take care of your mom?
[Trey] Yes. Just make sure she's okay.
-Are you kidding me? No questions asked.
-[laughs]
-I got you two. 100%.
-Okay.
-100%
[musical swell plays]
[ominous tone plays]
This experience,
you're just ripped away from so much
and everything you know.
And you really have
to rely on the people around you.
And I wanna be, like,
a warm presence for people,
where, like, maybe they feel like
they're talking to somebody back home.
Um, to give them that safe space.
In a game where people are fighting
for $4.56 million,
um, people are gonna be
incredibly ruthless.
Um, people are going
to lose their minds in this game,
but I wanna be a safe base
for people in this game,
to where they're like, "I can go to Figgy,
and Figgy's gonna, like,
bring me back down."
"She's gonna calm me down,
gonna make me feel better."
Like, I wanna be that for people, um,
and in return, like,
I will also have a safe base with them.
I think that's so important in this game.
[musical swell plays and rises]
[ominous tone plays]
[gentle classical music plays]
[automated voice] Attention, players.
The lights in the dorm
will be switched off in five minutes.
So, you all think for sure
it's gonna be tug-of-war tomorrow?
[man] If it's following the wall map,
that's next.
I would definitely like to have
at least one strong guy.
In Big Chad, of course.
But I think everybody here wants Big Chad.
He's the biggest, baddest,
grizzly bear-looking dude here.
[clock chimes on speakers]
[automated voice] Attention, all players.
This is your wake-up call.
Oh my God.
[yawning]
-[man 218] Ready for some oats?
-[man] No.
[laughs]
Lorenzo is so not happy with his hairline.
He wants it to pop out. [laughs]
I could tell.
All the sensations
that are in your body right now,
your heartbeat, your breath, feel.
[Stephen] Where's all the gang?
-Everyone's brushing their teeth probably.
-[Stephen] Oh, yeah.
How'd you sleep?
Really good. Today's a win-win tug-of-war.
I need to stretch.
Everybody knows
that tug-of-war is coming up next.
[Bryton grunts gently]
[tense music plays]
[man] There we go.
[Bryton grunts]
I know that my team
are very strong, very athletic,
and there's not really
anything to worry about.
Looking in the showers and stuff
and seeing the guys'
like, shredded, six-packs and like…
That, like-- That scares me.
Well, tug-of-war
is about more than just strength.
If we can stick together,
we're sticking together.
[Bryton] I'm prepared, I'm ready.
Being strong is my greatest attribute
in this whole entire game.
I really, really like my odds.
[buzzer plays on speaker]
Heyo.
[doors clang and whir]
[creepy choral music plays]
Something's happening.
[square guard] Attention, all players.
The third game will begin shortly.
[tense ethereal music plays]
Players, please make your way
to the game hall.
-[Trey] I feel nervous. You feel nervous?
-Really? Nah. [chuckles]
[Trey] I think a lot of people
have started becoming
really good friends with each other,
and every time there's a game,
it's kind of gonna be
a random slot of luck
if your friend
that you were just talking to
is gonna stay in the game
or not the next day.
It's gonna be a bloodbath.
["The Blue Danube Waltz"
by Johann Strauss plays]
[door creaks]
[dark, pulsing music plays]
[man 1] Oh my God.
[Bryton] Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Perfect, perfect, perfect, perfect…
I told you, I told you.
[Trey groans]
[Bryton] I don't think I want
any other number except one.
-[Stephen] Here we go again.
-[258] How's it feel? How's it feel?
Crazy.
Ooh, eight lines.
[automated voice] Attention, players.
For the next game,
teams will play head-to-head.
[suspenseful music plays]
Please divide yourselves
into eight equal lines.
You have five minutes.
[chimes and ticks]
-All right, let's get a team.
-Copy. No, come with us.
-[man 1] Can I join up with you, guys?
-[Rick] Oh gosh, where am I?
[man 2] You're in, you're in.
[Rick] I have no idea where Steve is.
What are you thinking, bro?
Do you wanna get a squad?
Rick?
[Rick] Where am I?
Hey, he's right here. Right here.
-God bless them.
-[Stephen] Don't worry, Rick. We got you.
[Stephen] My first instinct,
we're about to line up
and play tug-of-war, so the gganbu gang
needs to stick together.
It's all good. We got Rick.
[Rick] I'm glad I'm on your team.
[Bryton] …nine, ten, eleven, twelve,
thirteen, fourteen, fifteen.
-[man] Good.
-It's 15.
[Bryton] This is tug-of-war.
Nobody's worried, nobody's stressed
because there are some large men
and strong men on our team,
but I see the other lines
and groups running around
like chickens with their head cut off.
But my line, we're chilling.
If y'all have a line, put your hand up.
We need three more.
They need help. Don't leave them hanging.
Y'all don't wanna be eliminated, agree!
Hey, when you have your team, sit down.
[Figgy] We have two extra.
If you are at the end of the line,
please go. Just go.
[Figgy] We have too many people
in our line.
If we do not get a team
by the time clock runs out,
we all might get eliminated.
Raise your hand
if you want 186 to get out of the line.
[man 182] Be together.
Be together with this.
This doesn't change anything.
I still don't have to go.
-Go, please!
-[woman] Back of the line!
-Please, go!
-[man 182] Hey, hey!
Okay, okay. Calm.
Y'all don't wanna go home.
Just think about each other.
Don't think about y'all selves. Come on.
I will go, I will go. Okay, I--
I will go. Don't worry, it's fine.
Sit down. Hey, everybody sit down.
[Dash] Bro, we got this. We got this.
-You think so, yeah?
-Yeah.
Facing forward, facing forward.
[musical swell plays and intensifies]
[beeps]
[Bryton] Oh my God.
She's out there bawling, crying.
For what?
Control your emotions.
This is not a game of sympathy at all.
-Hey. You gotta breathe.
-It's all right.
-It's just, like, really stressing me out.
-Take a breath. It's okay.
-[453] I don't know why I'm crying.
-[182] It's okay. We're here together.
We here now. Even though we maybe
go against each other, we're here.
We are here.
Right?
-[exhales slowly]
-We got this.
Right.
[ominous tone plays]
When I retired from basketball,
I was making a very good, like,
very good check week-to-week.
Um, and my wife Sam is our saving grace
'cause, you know,
she had a hold of my money,
and I was like,
"Yo, just do what you gotta do."
And-- And when I fully retired,
I understood the troubles
and the daily worries about money,
and she humbled me a lot about that.
We do have money trouble sometimes,
and our time will come
when we will be financially rich.
Yet you have to be morally rich first
to truly appreciate the financially rich,
and Sam taught me that.
[automated voice] We will now draw numbers
to decide which two teams will play first.
[suspenseful percussive music plays]
[man] Here we go.
[automated voice] Team three.
And team one.
-[players applaud]
-[man 337] Oh.
Let's go.
-[Bryton] I like it. I like it.
-[man 068] I like that.
[Bryton] I see line three, and I see Brad.
His line is bad.
They look weaker and smaller.
Line one is the strongest line.
We have a clear advantage.
[Brad] I'm looking over
at team number one,
and I'm like,
"Man, all the big guys, man."
They have an upper hand.
[ominous tone plays]
Holy shit.
[man 447] Oh, man.
[automated voice] Attention, players.
-[man] What is this?
-[Brad] Damn.
[automated voice]
Welcome to the third game.
Warships.
[woman] No!
[Bryton] This is not tug-of-war at all.
H-Holy sh--
This is a completely new game.
[Brad] Damn.
The team we're going up against
was thinking
that brawn was gonna win this?
Oh, no. This was gonna win it
all day, baby.
[automated voice] Attention, players.
To begin, both teams must pick a captain.
Bro, I choose Brad
to be the captain of this ship any day.
-[woman] He knows what he's doing.
-Absolutely.
-He plays it all the time.
-All the time.
Me and my brothers grew up
playing this since I was, like, ten.
I played this a few months ago.
[woman] It's meant for you today.
I put my hand in the air immediately
because all I can do
is try to save myself.
These guys are no longer
my complete teammates.
I have to leave them in the dust
if I'm gonna make it another day.
So the first thought I have is,
"I do not wanna be
in a sinking ship. I'm captain."
[automated voice] Captain,
you must pick a lieutenant.
352.
-Yeah.
-[light applause]
[Brad] 178.
[automated voice] To win this game,
the captain must fire missiles
at the opposing team.
Let's do this, baby.
Hey, warship team, baby.
[automated voice]
Players are only eliminated
when their entire ship is sunk.
First captain to sink
two of the other team's ships wins.
Please place your ships.
[Brad whispering] No, no, no. Vertical.
Vertical.
[suspenseful music plays]
[all players whispering]
[Jessi] Five.
[Bryton] I choose the boat
that has two seats
because it's easier to hide.
You can put it out of the way.
So, high risk, high reward.
[Jessi] Stop.
You and you, switch.
[Bryton] At the last second,
she moves our boat
from the back right corner
and puts it at the front.
Wait, I'm-- No.
I'm not getting on the edge.
I don't know how to play this game,
but I know that being on the frontline
cannot be safe,
especially when I'm in a two-person boat.
[Bryton sighs]
Let's win this all day.
[automated voice] The winning captain
and lieutenant will pass this game.
The losing captain and lieutenant
will be eliminated,
along with the players
in their sunken ships.
[Jessi] Oh my God, oh my God.
What did I just do to myself?
[automated voice] And with that,
let the game begin.
[Brad whispers] Okay.
[dramatic music plays]
-[sonar pings on speakers]
-[automated voice] Red missile launched.
Blue team, prepare for impact.
-[splashing sound plays on speakers]
-B2, miss.
-[softly] That's a miss.
-[Brad] It's a miss?
They guessed B.
I think they have one in B.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
Red team, prepare for impact.
-[splashing sound plays on speakers]
-B7, miss.
-[sonar pings]
-Red missile launched.
Blue team, prepare for impact.
-[explosion sound plays on speaker]
-G2, hit.
Red team have hit their first ship.
I knew it, bro.
[Bryton] I do wish I was the captain.
No disrespect to player 220,
but she has no strategy.
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
Red team, prepare for impact.
[musical swell plays and rises]
-[splashing sound plays]
-F3, miss.
[Bryton] We're just firing missiles
at random spots.
[fast-paced dramatic music playing]
[sonar pings]
-[splashing]
-H7, miss.
[Bryton] We're firing, we miss.
We're firing, we miss.
-[splashing]
-A2, miss.
[Brad] This game has nothing
to do with strength.
It has all to do with strategy.
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion plays]
And I'm looking at my lieutenant,
I'm like, "Oh, We got this."
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion plays]
There is nothing that's about to stop us
from taking this thing down.
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion plays]
[automated voice] D2, hit.
[Bryton] I am feeling
the most vulnerable I have felt
from the moment
that I walked through this door.
We need to hit something, bro.
[whispers] They have no plan.
They're just going
with whatever they think is right.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
Red team, prepare for impact.
[musical swell plays and intensifies]
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] D5, hit.
-Yes!
-[lieutenant] Yes! Let's go!
[automated voice] Blue team
has hit their first ship.
That doesn't mean shit.
It's only if the whole boat is knoc--
-[sonar pings]
-Red missile launched.
Blue team, prepare for impact.
-[explosion sound plays]
-C2, hit.
[siren wailing]
Red team has sunk their first ship.
-[178] Yes! Let's go!
-Let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go!
-First boat down. One more to go.
-One more!
Players 068, 041, 422,
447, and 452, eliminated.
[ethereal music plays]
[Jessi] I feel responsible for them.
And I feel responsible
for avenging them right now.
[sonar pings]
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
[tense music plays]
-[explosion sound plays]
-C5, hit.
-[Jessi] Yes! Yeah.
-Yeah.
-Come on.
-[sonar pings]
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[explosion sound plays]
-B5, hit.
[Jessi] Yes!
-[pings]
-Blue missile launched.
Red team, prepare for impact.
[musical swell plays and intensifies]
-[explosion sound plays]
-E5, hit.
-[siren wails]
-Blue team have sunk their first ship.
Players 142, 188,
389, and 343, eliminated.
[Bryton] We finally sink the boat.
It's 1-1 now, it's a much better game,
and now our team is starting
to feel a lot more confident.
[automated voice] The next team
to sink a ship will win the game.
[Brad] I am feeling the pressure
like crazy right now.
Me and my lieutenant's thinking, "What are
we gonna do to find this last ship?"
I am so scared on this one, bro.
'Cause they could go anywhere on this one.
[Brad] What's a better spot than C4?
And it stands for an explosive.
So I'm like, "I'm gonna go ahead
and drop the C4 on these guys."
Hope it sticks
and hope we blow something up.
[automated voice] Blue team,
prepare for impact.
[explosion sound plays]
C4, hit.
-[Brad] Yes, baby! Let's go!
-[178] Let's go! Let's go!
[Bryton] Oh my God.
[Brad] Sink the hell out of that ship!
Let's go!
Drop that C4 on that ass.
Okay. It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
Hey, hey! No tears. This is not over.
What are y'all doing?
It's not over yet.
I'm trying to stay hopeful.
There's a chance we can stay in this game
if number 270 doesn't get hit.
Dry it up. This is not over.
-[Jessi] I know, I know.
-Jesus Christ.
[sighs]
I think we have the worst captain
and lieutenant
we could have picked possible.
The odds are not in our favor at all,
but it ain't over yet.
-What do you think?
-[352] Mmm.
G2. G2, G2, G2, G2.
[Bryton sighs]
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
Come on. Come on.
[automated voice] Red team,
prepare for impact.
-[explosion sound plays]
-G2, hit.
-Yeah! Oh, my God!
-Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
[Bryton] Growing up playing sports,
I was taught
not to give up no matter what.
[automated voice] Red missile launched.
[Bryton] And that's exactly
what's going through my head right now.
"Don't give up,
don't give up, don't give up."
[automated voice] Blue team,
prepare for impact.
-[splashing]
-C5, miss.
-[Jessi] Yeah.
-[352] Yes. Oh my God.
-[Jessi] Yes, yes, yes, yes.
-[352 sighs]
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
[270] If this is their two-boat,
it's all over.
Yeah, that's it. We're off.
[automated voice] Red team,
prepare for impact.
-[splashing]
-[automated voice] F2, miss.
[breath trembles]
[Brad] All right, let's lock her in, baby.
-[sonar pings]
-[automated voice] Red missile launched.
Blue team, prepare for impact.
I'm not even gonna lie.
This is really exciting.
-This is really exciting.
-It really is exciting.
Winning or lose,
I'm gonna tell my kids about this.
[musical swell plays and intensifies]
[splashing]
[automated voice] D4, miss.
-G3, G3, G3, G3.
-G3.
[Bryton] I'm the type of guy where
I just wanna be able to control myself.
-G3?
-[Bryton] G3.
-[pings]
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-If we miss this, that's it.
-If the--
If we get this,
there's a good chance we win.
That could be their two-boat.
[suspenseful music plays]
[automated voice] Red team,
prepare for impact.
[Brad] G1, splash.
Splash.
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] G3, hit.
[blue team cheers]
-What's up, bro? What's up?
-Yes! [growls] Yes!
[Brad groans] Why is this happening?
[grand dramatic music plays]
Mmm, we got this.
-[sonar pings]
-[automated voice] Red missile launched.
[Brad] If we do not hit this,
they only need one more shot
to sink our second ship,
and we're gonna be the ones going home.
[music intensifies]
[automated voice] Blue team,
prepare for impact.
-[explosion sound plays]
-[siren wails]
[automated voice] B4, hit.
[Bryton] It's devastating.
[Beethoven's "Moonlight Sonata" plays]
[automated voice] Players 270 and 432…
eliminated.
[red team cheers]
Oh, wow!
-[178] Yes!
-[woman] Yeah!
Y'all crazy. Y'all didn't say
none of that shit
whenever y'all was to my face though.
[automated voice] The red team
have sunk two of the blue team's ships
and have won the game.
[red team cheers wildly]
Captain 220, Lieutenant 352, eliminated.
[178] Let's go! Let's go! Oh, my God!
[Brad] This is such a bittersweet moment
right now
because while we're all jumping around,
I see my fallen teammates,
and I'm just, like… [groans]
But I feel so good
to be able to lead my team to victory.
[automated voice] The surviving players
from both teams
may now make their way back to the dorm.
["Moonlight Sonata" continues playing]
[Bryton] Damn. You know, I--
I really thought
I was going to make it all the way.
[cheering wildly]
[Brad] Yes! Yes, baby! Yes, baby!
Seeing the smiles on everybody's faces
right now, I'm just going insane.
There's no greater feeling,
to know that, like, they put
all their trust in your hands
and you were able to deliver.
Squid dance.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
[tense pulsing music plays]
I love this game.
I play this game often. Um…
I'm not the best expert,
but I do play this game a lot.
I think you should be the leader, TJ.
I do not know nothing
about this damn game.
[TJ] Thank you so much.
[Trey] TJ's our captain.
He's a leader. A team player. Perfect.
[musical swell plays and intensifies]
[ominous tone plays]
When there was a shootout
in-- in-- in my old hood,
and I jumped on top of my little sister.
Just instinctively,
I didn't even think about it.
And, uh, uh, you know,
people calling me idiot.
"You a idiot! Why'd you do that?
Why did you do that?"
Like, I-- I didn't have no explanation.
And-- And then, you know,
seeing violence happen in front of me,
and I jump in front of people, you know,
because I'm big and strong,
and I know I can handle myself,
and I know I can protect people,
and I know I can fight for people.
You know, I've done it so many times,
I-- I-- I can't even count.
It-- It's just--
I don't know, it's just a part of me.
I-- I can't help that.
Bravery is something
that's a true part of who I am.
-[pings]
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
[musical swell plays]
[explosion sound plays]
-[siren wails]
-B4, hit.
The blue team has sunk their first ship.
Players 186, 187,
and 433, eliminated.
Let's go, man! One more!
One more, and we out of here.
[TJ] We sunk the first ship.
We already at an advantage,
but it's so stressful
because our five-man ship got hit,
and I have to present a calm demeanor.
We got this, y'all.
You not going home, none of y'all.
I promise that, y'all.
Thank y'all for trusting in me.
But when you are
in that pressure situation,
and people rely on you,
you have to deliver that.
Hey, trust.
Humility and gratitude.
TJ is a good guy, but he keeps
giving us these positive affirmations.
Hey, I love y'all.
[Lorenzo] And I'm like, "Bro,
we're in Squid Games. Let's get real."
"Let's-- Let's sink these ships."
I'm going for it, right? I'm going for it.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion sound plays]
-F5, hit.
-[TJ] Yes! Oh my God!
-[woman] I told you.
-[pings]
-[automated voice] Red missile launched.
-[explosion sound plays]
-D7, hit.
Hey, listen. Nobody's going today.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
[explosion sound plays]
F4, hit.
-[woman] Yeah. Oh my God.
-Let's go!
-[sonar pings]
-Red missile launched.
-[explosion sound plays]
-B7, hit.
[ominous tone plays]
You're not going home.
None of y'all. I promise that, y'all.
[Leann] I'm devastated right now
because I know
we're gonna be the first boat out.
So we either nail their boat,
or they're gonna nail us.
We could win this right now.
What do you think?
Down? Hey, I love y'all.
We got this.
-This could be it, guys.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-Red team, prepare for impact.
-[woman] Oh, please. Oh, please.
-[splashing]
-F6, miss.
[mouths silently]
[man] Go for it. Just do it.
[sonar pings]
[automated voice] Red missile launched.
[musical swell plays and rises]
Blue team, prepare for impact.
[woman] Please, please, please, please.
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] E7, hit.
[mouths silently]
[Trey] I am the final peg remaining
in this five ship, and the end is near.
Let's go, y'all.
We got this.
[sonar pings]
[TJ] My junior year in college,
we're playing one
of the best teams in the nation.
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
[TJ] When my teammate,
he shoots the ball, he misses.
I grab the rebound with no time to go.
[dramatic music playing]
One shot to win the game.
I shoot the ball.
The ball's flying forever.
[missile screeches]
[automated voice] Red team,
prepare for impact.
[TJ] All I can think about
is our kids and my wife.
"You got this, Dad. You got this, babe."
The moment's here. Step up.
And… [mimics explosion]
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] F3, hit.
[siren wails]
Players 136, 135,
and 386, eliminated.
The blue team has sunk
two of the red team's ships
and are the winners.
[blue team cheers wildly]
[man] Yes!
[automated voice] Captain 396,
Lieutenant 264, eliminated.
Oh, oh! Oh my God!
[gentle bittersweet music playing]
[woman] Oh my God.
Thank God.
I'm an atheist, but I-- I'm thanking.
Y'all trusted me all the way, yo.
Not one ship. Not one ship!
Not one soldier down, okay, on team five.
We all are walking out of there,
and it feels amazing.
[cheering]
-Not one person. Not one person.
-Not one person.
Like I said! Like I said!
-Not one person! Not one person!
-[man] Let's go, baby!
[TJ] Not one person.
[woman] Oh my God,
your whole team is back?
-That's crazy.
-[Trey] Our whole team's back.
-Who was your captain?
-[229] He was.
[222 gasps]
Steer that ship to safety, my man.
[laughs]
It was almost like winning a championship.
For real.
-Gimme a second, y'all. Gimme a second.
-Yeah, yeah. Go, go. Get your beds.
[TJ sighs]
I heard my wife in, like,
the little back of my ear. [chuckles]
"Humility and gratitude.
Humility and gratitude."
I kept hearing
that over and over and over again.
Baby, you was right there, baby.
[sobs gently] Thank you so much.
You was right there.
[sniffles]
You did that.
I'm so proud of you, man.
I'm so glad you were our leader.
I-- Like, I'll trust you to the end
in here. I'm so serious.
Thank you. That means so much, yo.
-I love you, man.
-I love you too.
-Thank you.
-Yeah.
[sobs deeply]
Thank you, baby. Thank you.
[woman 018] We are in my domain.
Let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go.
[man] So we got a gamer here.
-You're now in charge.
-Let's go!
I'm really good at games.
[whispers] I want you, one, two, three.
I play games for a living.
If there's anything
I'm going to be good at, it's this.
Come on, guys.
I think everyone knew that I was
a bit different from other people
from, like, a really early age,
and it was around the age of nine, even,
that I-- I started feeling more isolated
and perhaps more depressed
than other people my age,
and acting out in ways that maybe
weren't normal for that age either.
Um, I take a lot of pride
in my intelligence.
I love reading books,
and I love challenging my brain.
I was in Mensa at the age of 13
with an IQ in the top 0.5% of the UK.
My parents really put me forward for it
because I think they wanted me
to see on paper
that I was capable. [laughs]
I didn't apply my intelligence very well
for a very long time.
We decided we're gonna put our ships
in two corners, slightly away.
The middle was left empty
because once people panic spray,
that's where they aim for.
My team trusts me,
and I'm feeling pretty amazing.
-Okay. Let's do it.
-[lieutenant] Go for it.
Okay. Here we go.
[Bee] When you're playing warship,
one thing you should know
is that, for some reason,
people will always aim for C3.
Psychologically, it seems
the most comfortably safe place to go.
Three and three away.
[automated voice] Red missile launched.
-[musical swell plays and rises]
-Come on!
-[splashing]
-[automated voice] C3, miss.
-That's okay, that's okay.
-Sorry. All right.
[Bee] That's good. Okay.
-[pings]
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
[man 1] Get ready over there.
[man 2] Fire away.
-[explosion sound plays]
-[blue team cheers] Yes!
[automated voice] G2, hit.
Oh my God.
[man] Take the shot, Captain.
["Habanera" from Carmen
by Georges Bizet plays]
[automated voice] F2, hit.
-[woman 1] Yes!
-[man 2] Bye-bye!
-[Bee] Yeah! Gimme five.
-[man 2] Bye.
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion sound plays]
-[man 1] Yes, sir!
-[automated voice] E2, hit.
-[man 2] Bye-bye.
-[man 3] You know it.
-[woman] Yes!
-[man 3] You know it!
[Bee] We are absolutely smashing them.
We're getting hit after hit after hit.
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] D2, hit.
[Bee] This takes a lot of luck, but it
also takes a lot of maths and logic.
[sighs]
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] C2, hit.
It's okay.
[automated voice] The blue team
has sunk their first ship.
-[man 149] Yeah!
-[lieutenant] Yes!
[all cheering]
[man 3] You know it.
[Bee] We've already sunk
their biggest ship.
[automated voice] Players 438, 435, 267,
350, and 034, eliminated.
Blue missile launched.
[explosion sound plays]
-[blue team cheers in distance]
-A5, hit.
Blue missile launched.
-[explosion sound plays]
-A4, hit.
[cheering wildly]
Blue missile launched.
It's been a pleasure, guys.
[musical swell plays and rises]
[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] A3, hit.
-[siren wails]
Players 362, 226,
and 357, eliminated.
The blue team has sunk
two of the red team's ships
and are the winners.
-[cheering]
-[man 1] Yeah!
-[woman screams]
-[man 2] Yes, yes, yes, yes!
Captain 057, Lieutenant 434, eliminated.
[cheering continues]
I think I've been underestimated severely,
which is fine.
But I think people realize
I'm super intelligent,
and I'm probably now on people's radars.
So the more I'm visible,
and the more people get to know me,
I think the more they realize
I am a serious threat.
-[players chatter nervously]
-[man 1] Oh my gosh.
-[Stephen] What? What the--
-[man 1] This is insane.
What is this?
[man 2] Brownie, you're the person.
As long as you guys also tell me
coordinates, like, what you feel.
If you feel something
in your gut, tell me.
I'm backing you as my captain.
Like, honestly, I back you.
I am not the most familiar with warships,
but we all have a lot of faith
in Brownie and trust in her.
So, no questions asked.
We all are like, "Absolutely."
[tense music playing]
[man] If you believed in me there,
believe in me here.
I will not lose this game for us.
I am personally feeling confident
in-- in our team.
[all] One, two, three, gganbu gang!
-[players] Let's go!
-[man 031] Let's do this.
Gganbu gang is winning this.
You can count on it.
[musical swell plays and rises]
[rhythmic suspenseful music plays]
[sonar pings]
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
Red team, prepare for impact.
[musical swell plays]
[splashing]
D6, miss.
-Red missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
Blue team, prepare for impact.
-[musical swell plays]
-[splashing]
-G7, miss.
-Yes!
[Dan] Shh, shh.
[Figgy] I have no control
of this whole situation.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[Figgy] I'm feeling a lot of stress.
[automated voice] Red team,
prepare for impact.
[Figgy] I'm feeling a lot of anxiety.
-[splashing]
-[automated voice] G3, miss.
[Figgy] I have nothing to contribute
except my body in a boat.
[automated voice] Blue team,
prepare for impact.
[splashing]
-G4, miss.
-[Figgy] And I don't like that.
-[sonar pings]
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
Red team, prepare for impact.
[musical swell plays and intensifies]
[explosion sound plays]
C3, hit.
[blue team cheers]
Come on. Let's go.
-[Stephen] Let's go, baby.
-[man 375] It's all us. Come on, let's go.
[Figgy] I'm starting to panic,
and I need our captain
to get our boats to safety.
[tense music plays]
-[pings]
-[automated voice] Red missile launched.
Blue team, prepare for impact.
[musical swell plays]
-[explosion sound plays]
-F6, hit.
[mouthing silently]
-Red missile launched.
-[pings]
Blue team, prepare for impact.
[explosion sound plays]
-F5, hit.
-[siren wails]
Red team has sunk their first ship.
-Whoo! Oh, shh.
-Whoo! Let's go.
[automated voice] Players 218
and 414, eliminated.
Everyone on the team
is focusing on me right now,
looking at me to be the leader.
[softly] B3? B3?
[Dan] I have to capitalize on this moment.
I need to be focused on the prize,
I need to be focused on the mission.
-[pings]
-Blue missile launched.
[Dan] I need to win this game.
-[explosion sound plays]
-[man] Yeah!
B3, hit.
[softly] That's right!
[softly] Oh. It's all right. It's okay.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion sound plays]
-D3, hit.
[sonar pings]
-[explosion sound plays]
-E3, hit.
[Brownie] I just keep saying,
"That's Figgy's boat."
"She's going down."
[Figgy] When we realize
that we're going down,
it's heartbreaking.
My chance at getting
$4.56 million is over.
[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
[grand melancholic music plays]
[Figgy] I don't want us to go down.
-[explosion sound plays]
-[siren wails]
[automated voice] Blue team
have sunk their first ship.
Player 103, 248, 297,
035, and 033, eliminated.
I'm sorry. [breath trembles]
To feel like your time is over
and… [sniffles]
…it was out of your control,
that's really hard.
[automated voice] The next team
to sink a ship will win the game.
-Red missile launched.
-[pings]
[Brownie] It is literally neck and neck.
[explosion sound plays]
[automated voice] D4, hit.
-Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] F7, hit.
-Yes. Come on!
-[blue players cheer]
[sonar pings]
-[splashing]
-[automated voice] D3, miss.
[Stephen] They miss!
[Brownie] Now we know it's here.
[Stephen] But now they know
exactly where to go.
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] F6, hit.
[blue team] Yes!
[man] Come on!
-[automated voice] Red missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
[explosion sound plays]
[automated voice] E4, hit.
-[scoffs]
-Oh, fudge.
Damn it.
We are down to our last shot.
This is a $4.56 million decision
we're making right here.
We only have two choices.
We got two choices, right? That's it.
F5, F8. It's one or the other.
Have to get this one right, or we lose.
[Rick] We're all in panic mode.
We have to keep it together.
I mean, we're the gganbu gang.
We have each other's back.
If they miss, we got it.
[107] It's literally coming down
to the final shots.
It's a 50-50 chance for them to win,
but we know if they miss,
we can sink them and win this game,
'cause we know exactly
where that last boat piece is.
Five or eight, what are we thinking?
Who says five? Who says five?
-Who says five?
-Go.
I'd-- I'd go-- I'd go, personally go five.
Who says eight?
[Rick] Everybody putting
their hands up for five.
I got five kids, I don't know,
something's yelling to me F5.
[Rick] I have 18 grandchildren.
So, my heart is saying eight.
Doc? F5, F8?
I'll stick with eight.
[Dan] Doc says F8.
My gut is telling me it's F5.
[tense droning music plays]
I'm either making
the biggest move ever here…
or I'm the biggest sucker.
-Here goes everything.
-[kisses]
-[automated voice] Blue missile launched.
-[sonar pings]
Red team, prepare for impact.
Please let them pick five.
[107] I'm praying that I stay
in this game right now.
Miss it, miss it, miss it.
We're going back to that dorm tonight.
[music intensifies]
[music stops]
-[explosion sound plays]
-[automated voice] F8, hit.
[siren wails]
[automated voice] Players 107, 194,
367, eliminated.
The blue team has sunk
two of the red team's ships
and are the winners.
[all cheering]
[man 1] Yes! Oh my God!
[automated voice] Captain 258,
and Lieutenant 273, eliminated.
[gentle cheerful music plays]
[Dan] Doc won that game for us.
And Doc, I don't need you
to know anything else. You're my hero.
-My kids are gonna love this.
-[players laugh]
This is my biggest moment in Squid Game.
I helped.
We did it.
It's just shy of a miracle.
[all] Gganbu gang!
-Whoo!
-Let's go! [laughs]
[Rick] Lock it in.
[Stephen] All my trust was in Rick.
He is a dang hero.
I mean, we had a strong bond before,
but after all this, I--
I trust him with my life at this point.
[players cheering]
[players laugh]
[cheering and applauding]
Just waiting to see that door open
and crossing my fingers
and hoping it's Figgy.
[man 1] Oh!
-[man 2] Yeah!
-[cheering]
Like, "Where's Figgy? Where's Figgy?"
And, uh, there's no Figgy.
[tender melancholic music plays]
And that-- It sucks.
-I'm, like, really sad about Figgy.
-[Leann] I know.
You know, we-- we want
those numbers to go down,
but we forget…
why they're going down.
They're going down
because our friends are leaving.
It's not gonna get any easier.
[buzzer sounds on speakers]
[doors clang and whir]
[creepy choral music plays]
Oh no.
[254] Show me the money. [chuckles]
[musical swell plays and rises]
Attention, players.
We can now reveal
the results of the third game.
[melancholic music plays]
[clicking repeatedly]
[players exclaim]
[man] Oh, shit!
Oh my God.
Wow, seeing it all like that.
That's not a lot of people.
Let's go. Let's go!
[players cheer and whoop]
[Leann] I'm looking up
and seeing so much money.
It's-- It's well past the halfway point.
And then the people left in the game,
it's really so few people.
[cheering continues]
[players exclaim]
456 people started this game,
and we are still here.
[all cheer]
[Brad] It does feel good
just to… kick back,
and relax.
[ominous music plays]
[man] Yo!
[man whistles sharply]
-[man] Oh, get away from that thing.
-It looks like an ATM.
[man] It's a video game.
[woman 1] Oh no.
I wanna be sick. I don't like that.
-[woman 2] It's a game?
-[Brad] What the hell is that?
[automated voice] Attention, players.
Before the next game,
there will be two elimination tests.
[gasping]
[man] My God.
[dramatic music plays]
[automated voice] These tests will happen
in front of the entire dormitory.
[man] Oh my God, bro.
[automated voice] For the first test,
you will each have to choose
one player to eliminate.
The three players with the most votes…
-[all gasp]
-Wait. "The three players"?
[automated voice] …will all
be
eliminated.
[ominous tone plays]
[ominous closing theme music plays]