[bell ringing]
[dramatic music plays]
The pirates are coming!
-[woman] Pirates!
-[people clamoring]
[grunts]
[man] Clear the streets!
The pirates are coming!
They're here! Take cover!
-[woman] Pirates!
-[boy] Pirates!
They're here!
They're coming for all of us!
-The pirates are coming!
-[man 2] He's gotta stop.
-[boy] Everybody, run!
-[man 3] Not this again.
-[boy] Go inside!
-[man] Every day, this kid.
Pirates! The pirates are coming!
They're attacking the village!
Pirates! Pirates!
Pirates. Man the cannons!
Batten the hatches!
Oh!
I'll batten your hatches, you idiot!
Fear not! No pirate will get past me.
There are no pirates.
Haven't been in years.
That's where you're wrong.
I know they're coming any day now.
But fear not,
the Great Captain Usopp will protect you.
When are you gonna stop
wasting your life, Usopp? It's pathetic.
The pirates are coming! Pirates! Pirates!
The pirates are coming! They're coming!
[theme music plays]
[Nami] Never seen that before.
[Luffy] Hey, Nami.
-Nami!
-What?
[Luffy] It's ready!
And what is it?
Our Jolly Roger. Every pirate crew
has to have one. And now we do!
We're not a crew,
and you are not hanging that on my boat.
Zoro! Zoro, check it out.
That's unique.
Nami, I think the toilet's busted.
We don't have a toilet.
Oh.
Well, then something back there's leaking.
What?
No!
[shell coughs]
Shit.
-We're taking in water. What did you do?
-I didn't do anything.
They way you're clanging
those swords around,
you must've broken something.
Maybe you should've stolen
a better boat.
Guys. Guys. Guys. Okay, crew meeting.
-Not a crew!
-Not a crew.
We're gonna need a better ship
to make it to the Grand Line.
A real pirate ship.
Worthy of the Straw Hat Crew.
-Wait. Straw Hat Crew? Really?
-Yeah, I thought it had a nice ring to it.
"Demon" has a nice ring to it.
-Headgear? Not scary.
-Who says pirates have to be scary?
The point is we need a new ship.
So where do we get one?
Our closest bet is the Gecko Islands.
We can probably make it there
before our ship sinks.
Ditch this one and get a better one.
Good. With a working toilet.
Great job, navigator.
You're still not hanging that on my ship.
[dramatic music plays]
Get down that rigging!
[Marine] Aye, sir!
-Double time!
-[Marine 2] You heard him! Double time!
[Garp] Cadets had better prove yourself
if you're gonna sail under me.
The pirates who attacked Shells Town
have a head start.
But once I sink my teeth in,
I don't let go.
Am I understood, Marines?
[Marines] Aye, sir!
Why did I have to get
dragged along for this?
Mm-mmm.
Hey. Move.
I said move.
You too, cadet.
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
I already tied that knot.
Your knot would've slipped.
I was just trying to--
Just trying to show me up.
You think you can do anything I can't do?
No.
-I was just… I was trying to, like, help.
-[Garp] Cadets.
Which one of you secured this rigging?
He did, sir.
Is that true?
Yes.
Yes, sir.
Hmm.
It's a fine knot, son.
You've spent time at sea?
Yes, sir. I have.
[Garp] Why don't you come with me?
Leave all this drilling
to the raw recruits.
Uh, sir? What about me?
Find a rope and practice.
I would've hoped
your father would've taught you better.
[grunts]
[sighs]
[Zoro] You got to be kidding me.
That clown was worth 15 million Berry.
We should've stuffed his head in a bag
and brought it with us.
[Luffy] What Marine would pay you
that bounty anyway?
You're kind of a wanted man yourself now.
Hmm.
Didn't think of that.
[Luffy sighs]
[grunts]
All the more reason
to get to the Grand Line. Fresh start!
Right.
Hey! You got us a ship?
Working on it. Did you push the sloop
out to sea like I told you?
Yeah. No Marines
are gonna be following us here.
Well, we're not gonna be here very long.
Turns out Syrup Village
is known for their ship building.
Lots of options.
Well, what are we waiting for then?
Uh…
Stupid clown.
[dog barking]
[circus music plays]
[Buggy groans] Wait till I get my hands
on that rubber-hose little runt.
Nobody makes a fool of Buggy the Clown!
[footsteps approaching]
[Buggy] Well, it's about time
one of my sorry excuses
for a supporting cast showed up.
Now get out of my light!
[pirate] Buggy the Clown.
[dramatic music plays]
[Buggy] We're closed.
Show's on hiatus.
[pirate] Arlong wants a word.
Well, you can tell Arlong…
that I don't take requests.
-[dramatic music resumes]
-[Buggy grunts]
[pirate grunts]
[chuckles]
[upbeat music plays]
[indistinct chatter]
[Luffy] Look at 'em all.
-[Zoro] How much do these cost?
-If you have to ask, you can't afford it.
Okay, so we need to get one
with a very, very impressive figurehead.
At least two…
No, no, three masts!
And a really high crow's nest.
We are not gonna be able
to sail a ship anywhere near that size.
There's only three of us.
Three of us right now.
Well, unless you can find
another weird, desperate soul to help us.
[Zoro] Speak for yourself.
Listen. We are going to need
something a little less flashy
if we want to sneak out of here.
You want to steal a ship?
[scoffs]
How else did you expect us to get one?
I don't know. But we can't steal one.
What kind of pirate are you?
A ship is not just a ship.
It's a part of our crew.
We need to find the perfect one.
And we're gonna get it the right way.
Okay, pitch that to the salesman.
I'm sure that'll win him over.
Exactly.
-[sighs]
-So what are we actually gonna do?
[sighs] Find a ship and see how lax
the security is around here.
Got it.
[curious music plays]
[sighs]
[sentimental music plays]
[Usopp] Real beauty, huh?
You can talk?
No! Over here.
Yo.
This ship is amazing.
Yeah.
What can you tell me about her?
Caravel class, top-of-the-line.
Ninety-six feet of pure luxury.
Whipstaff rudder, full galley.
Cannon decks fore and aft.
Is she fast?
The fastest.
Not a ship in the East Blue
can keep up with this baby.
[exhales]
She's perfect!
You can say that again.
[Nami] There you are.
Guys!
I found it.
I found our ship.
And this guy will sell it to us.
[Usopp] Uh, wait. What? Uh…
Yeah! The ship, we'll take it.
-Technically, she's not for sale.
-Huh?
And technically,
I'm not a salesman.
-Do you even work here?
-Of course I do.
I'm Chief Technician
in charge of encrustation removal
and aviary waste eradication.
Encru what?
-He scrubs barnacles and cleans bird shit.
-He can't help us.
Wait! Wait! Wait! I can help you.
The owner of this ship just happens to be
my closest friend in the world.
Your friend owns this ship?
Not just this one.
She owns the whole shipyard.
She's rich rich.
Oh!
I'm sure you could strike a deal with her.
See?
Well, I guess it couldn't hurt
to say hello.
What the hell did I do with it?
Sir… is there something
I can help you with?
[Garp] You've quite a handle
on basic seamanship.
You learn that
on that pirate ship of yours?
Yes, sir.
I was forced to work alongside the crew.
They'd lock me in the bilge if I didn't.
Our experiences don't define us.
It's what we gain from them that matters.
You learned, and you survived.
Oh. Oh.
Here it is.
You play?
-A little, sir.
-Good.
[military music plays]
Let's see if you
can do more than tie knots.
[Luffy] I've never seen
a house this big before.
[Usopp] Impressive, right?
Kaya's given me an open invitation
to drop by anytime I want.
[Luffy] Wow.
All of this just for one person?
Well, she lives here
with her butler and a few other staff.
[Luffy whistles]
Money really shows you
who people truly are.
Most people only care about themselves
and what's theirs.
Sounds like someone I know.
[Nami] And a small staff
makes for easy pickings.
[Zoro] Why? Gonna rob the place blind?
At least a little blurry.
[Luffy] So if you have an invitation,
why are we going around the back way?
[Usopp] I never use the front entrance.
This is more of a VIP entrance
reserved for special guests.
[Zoro] This guy's full of shit.
Yeah. But as long as he gets us
inside the house, who cares?
Oops. You know, there's actually
a more exclusive entrance this way.
-[grunts]
-[Usopp gasps]
-The hell are you doing here, Usopp?
-Buchi, buddy, uh, Kaya's expecting me.
-Another one of your lies.
-Oh.
-You ain't welcome here and you know it.
-I know nothing of the sort.
I'm here to give Kaya
an extra-special gift.
[woman] Usopp!
[woman sighs]
[sighs]
What a wonderful surprise.
[wistful music plays]
[Usopp] Hmm!
Kaya!
[Kaya chuckles]
Happy birthday.
-You remembered.
-Of course I did.
[butler clears throat]
Usopp.
We've had this discussion.
You mustn't show up unannounced.
Nonsense, Klahadore.
Have you come to tell me another story?
I do love hearing about your adventures.
I'll do you one better.
I brought some of my crew.
Is he talking about us?
It's so nice to meet you.
You all must stay for dinner.
[Klahadore] Miss Kaya,
it is a bit last minute.
I'm afraid the kitchen
hasn't prepared for any extra guests.
[Kaya] Please, Klahadore.
It's my birthday.
Can't be too much trouble, can it?
Of course, Miss Kaya.
Anything for you.
All right! When do we eat?
You don't. Not dressed like that.
Sham, kindly show Usopp
and his friends to the guest suites.
You will bathe and change before dinner.
[Sham] Hmm.
A bath does sound nice.
[Luffy] All right!
[indistinct chatter]
[knocking on door]
Yo.
One of these days,
Klahadore is going to figure out
you use the servant's passageways
to sneak in here.
-[Usopp] Uh, uh.
-[Kaya giggles]
[Usopp] So what if he does?
I'll find another way in.
What are you doing here anyway?
Shouldn't you be getting ready?
I wanted to give you
your birthday present.
[gentle music plays]
Uh…
[Kaya] It's, um…
A giant pearl!
So it is.
[exhales] It wasn't easy to get either.
It was guarded
by a giant goldfish monster.
[gasps]
I had to weather a storm,
my ship almost capsizing, to find it.
Whoa!
-Phew! [grunts]
-[giggles]
I barely made landfall.
-[gasps]
-Only it wasn't land I was on.
It was… [sniffs]
…a massive piece
of goldfish shit.
[laughs] Ew!
[both laughing]
[coughing]
Kaya, are you okay?
Tea.
[clears throat]
[exhales]
How have you been feeling lately?
No different really.
When you've been sick as long as I have,
you get used to it.
This tea is the only thing
that makes me feel better.
That and your stories, of course.
Well,
I'll keep going on these grand adventures
as long as you want to hear 'em.
I wouldn't miss them for the world.
Why would anyone
even need this many clothes?
[Nami] It's not about need
with these people.
It's about want.
What are we even supposed to wear?
[Nami] Anything you want.
When are you ever going to get
the opportunity to wear things this nice?
Well?
What do you think?
You look like Nami.
Hey, Zoro!
What you gonna wear?
Something black.
[Nami] How edgy.
Hey, does that butler
seem familiar to you guys?
Yeah, I think he was
at the last dinner party I attended.
I swear I've seen him somewhere.
How's this?
-Still Nami.
-I said I'm wearing black.
I hate you guys.
I feel kind of bad for Kaya.
All this stuff.
All this space.
It's gotta make a person feel… lonely.
[Nami] Rich people don't have
the same emotions we do.
This stuff doesn't make her feel lonely.
It makes her feel important.
[Luffy] Well, Usopp likes her.
And she invited us to dinner.
I'm sure we can work out
a way to get that ship.
No way. Rich people don't stay rich
by giving things away.
You want to bet?
What are the terms?
I bet I can convince Kaya
to give us that ship.
And when you can't?
We go with your plan.
Steal one and move on.
You're on.
Nice.
[Klahadore] Eighteen years old.
I can hardly believe it.
You've grown into a fine young woman,
Miss Kaya.
Oh, Klahadore.
You know, I had nothing
when your parents took me in.
When they passed, well,
let's just say it has been an honor
to repay their kindness, and yours,
by serving you these past three years.
You do so much for me.
And not as a butler. As a friend.
I don't know how I'll ever repay you.
I know I can be
a tad overprotective at times,
but it's just because
I couldn't bear to think
what I would do
were something to happen to you.
You could lighten up just a bit.
[chuckles]
[sighs]
I shall try.
That could be my birthday gift to you.
[chuckles]
[Buchi mumbling]
Careful, you idiot!
Sorry. It's a chef's reflex.
You want to poison yourself?
[Klahadore] And how are
the dinner preparations coming along?
Uh… fine, sir.
[mysterious music plays]
Sham?
What is this?
I'm sorry, sir. It won't happen again.
No. It won't.
[gasps]
Everything must be perfect,
tonight of all nights, hmm?
[exhales]
[military music plays]
[Garp] Still your move, son.
Sorry, sir.
Game.
You're overthinking things, son.
You're too focused on not losing.
You won't win wars
if you keep playing defensive.
-I'm not very good, sir.
-[Garp] Nonsense.
You just keep getting in your own way.
Now,
two minutes.
Right. Your move.
Do it.
[adventurous music plays]
I won!
[Garp] That you did.
Because you acted decisively.
It's the same with pirates.
Action is the only language
they understand,
so we need to speak it louder.
Especially with these young upstarts.
They need a swift hand to put them
back in their place. Understood?
-Yes, sir.
-Clear the board. We go again.
[mysterious music plays]
[Luffy] Ah.
[indistinct chatter]
[Luffy] Mmm.
These are so good.
I know, right?
Reminds me of that one time
I slayed a dragon,
cooked it over an open flame,
ate the whole thing myself.
-You ever had dragon?
-Nope.
-Do you have dragon?
-Afraid we're fresh out.
Oh well.
Hey, Zoro. You gotta try this!
Mmm.
I've got all I need right here.
[Nami] So you manage
all of Kaya's finances?
[man] Oh yes.
I've handled her family's accounts,
both personal and professional, for years.
Fascinating.
You know, I've always been interested
in learning about the intricacies
of the shipbuilding business.
-Oh.
-[Klahadore clears throat]
May I present…
Miss Kaya.
Kaya, you look absolutely radiant.
Merry, I'm so glad you could make it.
This is a milestone
I wouldn't miss for the world.
Your parents would be so proud.
-Nami, I love that dress on you.
-Thanks.
It belonged to my mother.
It was one of her favorites.
-Oh, I'm sorry. I--
-Not at all.
I'm sure she would agree
it suits you splendidly.
Have we met before?
You look familiar.
Highly doubtful, sir.
Funky Bar?
Mirror Ball Island?
Well, I can assure you I've never
patronized that type of establishment.
Kaya, I wonder if I might have your ear?
There are matters concerning
the transfer of ownership of the shipyard
we need to discuss.
Merry, dear friend,
it's always business with you.
-[Merry sighs]
-[Klahadore] Tonight is about celebration.
Shall we all move to the dining room?
Yes!
Oh! Oh, I'm so ready for this…
[curious music plays]
-[Zoro] Keep this coming.
-Uh.
I'd love to try the fish tonight.
I'm sorry, Miss Kaya,
but that is not possible.
Maybe just a small piece?
Now, you know that certain foods
can affect your constitution.
Here, Buchi has prepared
your special soup.
Kaya, it's your birthday.
You should be able to eat what you want.
Miss Kaya's medical condition necessitates
that I closely monitor her dietary needs.
Does it mean you also speak for her?
I'll take her fish.
[gulps]
Luffy, isn't there something
that you wanted to talk to Kaya about?
Oh, yes! Usopp told me
that you own the whole shipyard.
Well, actually my parents
founded the shipyard,
and Merry's been
running the business since…
well, since they passed.
But all of that's about to change.
Tonight, at midnight,
I will become the sole owner.
Ah. Well, that's great,
because we want to buy a ship from you.
I see.
-Usopp mentioned that you're sailors.
-Nope, not sailors.
We're pirates.
[Zoro] This ought to be good.
-Pirates?
-[Luffy] Yep.
We haven't sailed together for long,
but we have already
defeated an evil clown,
raided a Marine base,
and taken down
a captain with an axe for a hand.
These sound a lot
like your adventures, Usopp.
[laughs] Yeah, that's… That's crazy.
Oh yeah. And we're just getting started.
What are you doing?
Get down from there at once!
Being a pirate has been my dream
for as long as I can remember.
And I'm finally making it a reality.
We're heading out to the Grand Line,
where even more adventures await us.
And at the end of the journey,
I'm gonna find the ultimate treasure,
the One Piece, and become
King of the Pirates.
You're serious?
[groans]
[Luffy] Kaya,
you have a beautiful ship out there.
A caravel with a sheep figurehead.
It spoke to me.
That's the ship we need
to follow our dreams.
I promise you,
we'll take care of it. Maintain it.
Treat it like
any other member of our crew,
because a ship is also a home.
[Klahadore] That will be quite enough!
I should've known Usopp
would bring riffraff to our doorstep.
Klahadore, it's okay. I--
[coughing]
Now look what you've done.
You've upset Miss Kaya.
-All of you, out of this house at once!
-No.
It's late. Let them stay the night.
As you wish, Miss Kaya,
but they are out
first thing in the morning.
[door opens]
-That went pretty well.
-[door closes]
Don't you think?
[footsteps approaching]
Vice-Admiral, I…
I'm sorry. Am I interrupting something?
No. You've just saved me
from getting beaten again.
What is it?
We spotted the wreckage
of an abandoned sloop.
Found this on board.
They couldn't have gotten far.
What's the nearest island to our location?
It's Gecko Island, sir.
[Garp] Gather a landing party
and make for shore.
I want those pirates found.
-Yes, sir.
-[Garp] Not you.
Him.
[both] What?!
Your position as senior cadet
has proven unwarranted.
Nepotism can only get you so far.
This is your chance
to show me what you've got, cadet.
Don't waste it.
Yes, sir.
[suspenseful music plays]
[sighs]
[gasps] Heavens!
Are you trying to give me a fright?
[Klahadore] So sorry.
I tend to be
light on my feet.
I must speak with Miss Kaya immediately.
This whole notion of transferring
the shipbuilding business to you
is highly unusual, to say the least.
I have run this estate
for Miss Kaya for years,
so it is only natural
that she should ask me to run
the family business until she's ready.
I would like to discuss the matter
with Miss Kaya.
These are our wishes, Merry.
Then she can tell me herself.
That young woman has been through enough,
and I won't let anyone
take advantage of her.
[suspenseful music continues]
[gasps] How did you…
[gasps]
[yelps]
Klahadore?
I won't stand for this any longer.
[gasps]
[knives clang]
[sinister music plays]
[gasps]
Is this the best way
to ask for an autograph?
I mean, sheesh! Fans have gotten so toxic.
All right, what do you want?
Tickets to the show?
I can get you house seats. They're pricey.
-[thud]
-[gasps]
[pirate] Oh, I'm no fan of yours.
[growls]
[snarls]
Arlong?
[Arlong] I run things here
in the East Blue.
I'm here to remind you
of your place in the food chain.
You pull a job in my seas,
you gotta pay tribute.
But, Arlong, baby,
you don't gotta worry about me.
I'm small potatoes.
Pirating's more of a side gig.
[clicking tongue]
Kuroobi tells me
you ransacked Orange Town.
[gasps] Ransacked?
You should've seen the place
before I got there, okay?
It was a real fixer-upper.
You bore me, clown. [growls]
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Wait. Wait.
You know who's out there
really disrespecting you?
It's that little rubber prick
in a straw hat. Goes by the name of Luffy.
-Never heard of him.
-[Buggy choking]
He just knocked over
a Marine base in Shells Town.
And then he stole a map of the Grand Line,
and now he's talking shit
about finding the One Piece.
[Buggy coughing]
[Arlong] The One Piece.
[chuckles] An excuse for humans
to spread their filth across the seas.
Listen, why don't you let me live,
and then I help you find Luffy?
Ah. Ah. Ah.
And how do you plan to do that?
I've got eyes and ears everywhere.
[both laughing]
[gasps]
[mysterious music plays]
Hey, Zoro!
Sh! Shut up.
You always carry those swords with you?
Wherever I go, the Wado Ichimonji goes.
-Where are you going anyways?
-I'm looking for a drink.
This place is a maze.
How about you?
Midnight snack.
Of course.
Come on.
We'll follow my nose to the kitchen.
[footsteps approaching]
-[Kaya] Nami?
-[gasps]
What are you doing?
Is everything all right?
Sorry, this house is so massive.
I was just trying to find the bathroom.
With a pillowcase?
So… you are a pirate after all.
I hate pirates.
But I am who I am.
And
I won't apologize for that.
To be honest, I find some of the decor
to be a bit gaudy.
I'd prefer to donate it to charity.
I'm not charity.
No, of course not.
I simply meant
what's the point in having so much
if you can't share it with others?
Like those in need. Family.
Friends.
So we're friends now?
You don't even know me.
Usopp does, and that's a start.
[gentle music plays]
So what do we do now?
Have a sleepover? Do each other's makeup?
[chuckles]
[coughing]
Kaya, are you okay?
Not you too.
What?
[Kaya] Everyone's so careful around me.
Like one wrong move and I'll break.
I don't want your pity.
Well, you won't get it then.
Couldn't sleep either, huh?
[chuckles]
Not after that dinner.
I hope I didn't get you
in trouble with Kaya.
Sometimes I get carried away.
Oh, no. It was worth it.
Seeing that look on Klahadore's face.
[laughs]
I thought his head was gonna explode.
All that stuff true that you said?
About the clown and the axe-hand guy?
Mm-hmm.
Every word.
I mean, they're not as exciting
as your adventures.
Yeah.
And the One Piece,
are you really going after that?
Yep.
I'm gonna be the one to find it too.
Man!
I wish I could do that.
But
I can't leave.
Kaya needs me.
-Is she your girlfriend or something?
-What?
Oh.
Um… [chuckles]
Usopp and me? No. No.
We've known each other for years.
Ever since his mother died.
He didn't have anybody, so my parents
gave him a job at the shipyard.
He likes to come around
and tell me all about his brave exploits
and grand adventures.
And truth is,
they make me feel better.
She's more like… my best friend.
Her parents died a few years ago,
and she… took it pretty hard, and…
and then she got sick on top of that.
I just want to be there for her, you know?
[Nami] Your parents,
what happened to them?
They, um…
They died at sea.
All these years
and it still takes my breath away.
I couldn't even
go through their belongings.
Just… locked up the memories
in the East Wing, where their bedroom was.
I'm sorry.
Have you ever lost anyone close to you?
No.
I'm jealous.
[scoffs]
Said the rich girl.
[chuckles]
You're not very good
at this friends thing, are you?
[chuckles]
[both laugh]
No, I guess I'm not.
[both laughing]
[Usopp] She's gorgeous,
and she's super smart.
She has the best laugh.
But, I mean,
you don't think
she, like, like likes me, do you?
You're asking the wrong guy.
Okay. But if you were Kaya,
would you like me?
I already like you.
Okay, that's not what I… I…
Never mind.
Wow.
You're a great shot!
Got it from my dad.
He's a notorious pirate.
I don't really remember him that well,
'cause he left for a life at sea
when I was just a baby,
but he'll be back one day.
[clang]
Yasopp the Great!
Yasopp?
He's your dad?
-Yeah. Why? You heard of him?
-[Luffy] Heard of him?
I know him! I… [chuckles]
He's a part of Shanks' crew!
Wait. You know my dad?
Yeah, yeah, I do! He's the best.
Always made time for some pirate wisdom.
So you guys, like,
hung out?
Yeah.
That's
cool.
If you're gonna talk about feelings,
I'm really gonna need a drink.
Uh, there's a wine cellar in the basement.
Why didn't you tell me that before?
You coming?
Nope.
Got everything I need right here.
[ominous music plays]
[sighs] Now we're talking.
I'm pretty sure
they keep the good stuff over here.
Oh!
[panting]
Zoro. Zoro?
It's Mer-- It's Merry. He's…
He's dea--
[Usopp panting]
[Zoro] Five blades.
I think I've seen this before.
Well, well, well.
It appears
we have some rats in our cellar.
[suspenseful music plays]
[Zoro] Those blades.
I knew I'd seen your face somewhere.
On a wanted poster.
You're Kuro,
captain of the Black Cat Pirates.
-Wait, Klahadore's a pirate?
-A dead one.
They say you were killed
by Axe-Hand Morgan.
A clever ruse.
One that imbecile's ego
helped me perpetuate.
And as you'll soon learn,
no one interferes in my plans.
So I will collect a bounty tonight.
Uh…
[breathing shakily]
[gasps]
-[hisses]
-Ah!
[suspenseful music plays]
[Buchi growls]
[huffing]
[ominous music plays]
Dispose of the bodies.
Outside of the house this time.
No trace left behind.
What about Usopp? He got away.
[Kuro] No matter.
But he could ruin the plan.
Let him say whatever he wants.
No one will believe him anyway.
"Oh, Usopp got away." Ooh.
Go on.
Why don't you join me
for breakfast tomorrow?
Your friends too.
We can discuss a deal for the caravel.
I'd like that.
This may not be my place,
but don't let Klahadore,
or anyone for that matter, run your life.
You're stronger than you think.
I appreciate that.
Good night, Nami.
Good night.
Don't forget your pillow.
Hmm.
[sentimental music plays]
[mysterious music plays]
Why do I have to push the cart?
Ugh, because you're twice my size
and half as smart.
[grunts]
[Buchi] A shame to get rid
of such nice swords though.
No trace left behind.
[swords clang]
Crack on.
[groans]
[Usopp] Pirates! Pirates!
Help, pirates!
Pirates, help!
Pirates, help, please! Help!
There really are pirates!
The pirates are here!
Someone, help!
Help me! Please open up!
I swear it's the truth.
There really are pirates!
Enough, Usopp. Go home!
[somber music plays]
-[young Usopp] Let me go, Mr. Mornin.
-It's really not funny.
-I've heard enough about the pirates.
-[Usopp] You know I'm right. Let me go!
He's at it again, Banchina.
Going on and on about pirates coming.
Get hold of your kid
before he gets himself in serious trouble.
Hey! Let me go.
Usopp,
you can't keep telling people
that pirates are coming.
But they are coming.
And Dad's coming with them.
He'll be home soon, I promise.
That's wonderful news, Usopp.
But you do know
that even if he doesn't come--
He will! I know he will.
Then you'll start feeling better.
You're right.
Of course you're right.
[Usopp] Mom?
Mom?
Mom!
The pirates are here.
They really are.
[sniffles]
Why won't anybody believe me?
[footsteps approaching]
[military music plays]
I believe you.
[ominous music plays]
[adventurous music plays]
[suspenseful music plays]