[pop song playing]
[Tao] Oh, no.
-No!
-[Charlie laughing] Hand over.
Thank you.
[Elle] It's nearly midnight,
can we please call it a draw?
No, because I'm clearly winning.
I just have unlucky rolls.
No, I'm winning because I have more money.
No, the winner is the superior
businessperson, and that's me.
No, I'm the superior businessperson
seeing as I have more money,
which is the goal of Monopoly.
You have more money
'cause you know the Monopoly cheats.
You can't cheat at Monopoly.
Oh, whoops.
Draw?
Draw.
Thank God.
There's never a good time to tell someone
their crush is going on a date
with someone else.
And I just don't like Nick.
I've seen him with those
nasty Year 11s at the school gate.
If they say anything mean to Charlie…
I'm going to crush them.
-[snickers] Crush them?
-Verbally.
Doesn't sound like the safest tactic.
Well, I don't like playing safe.
Crisp?
["UrbanAngel1999" playing on speakers]
Let's tell him when he gets back.
Fine, if it'll make you
stop talking about it.
-I think that Nick--
-Tao!
-What? Oh.
-Can we talk about something else?
Am I not being
entertaining enough for you?
No, you're not! You're being annoying.
Oh! I'm sorry.
What would you like instead?
Should I perhaps perform
a piece of interpretive dance?
Would that be less annoying?
That wasn't exactly what I had in mind.
Too late, you've said it now.
[laughing] No!
-How's this?
-This is worse.
I just think you can't
recognize talent when you see it.
I can, and this isn't it.
I can't believe this whole conversation
was a ploy for you
to witness
my incredibly erotic dance moves.
-Oh, my God, stop! Stop!
-Twerk!
Ow!
-Stop it.
-[Tao] Work that ass!
Do I even want to know?
Ow!
So, I was thinking of inviting Nick
to my birthday thing on Saturday.
I really want him to come,
but I don't want it to be awkward or weird
since you don't really know him.
No, it wouldn't be awkward.
I assumed he was coming anyway.
Okay.
Good.
♪ I know that you don't want me
But that's fine ♪
♪ I want you to be fine
No matter what the time ♪
♪ Oh, Urban Angel, realize ♪
♪ What I'd do to make you mine ♪
[students chatter]
[Nick] Imogen.
About our date…
-See, I wasn't sure if…
-[Imogen crying]
Are you okay?
My dog died last night.
Um…
I'm so sorry.
He was really old so,
like, we knew it was coming.
I loved him so much.
This is the worst week ever.
Yeah.
What were you going to say about our date?
Nothing.
So, shall we meet at Nando's for dinner
and then we could go to the cinema?
Yeah.
Okay.
-Yusef.
-Here.
-Owen.
-Ahmed.
-Here.
-Elliot.
So, it's kind of my birthday on Saturday.
Is it?
Yeah.
Me and my friends are going bowling,
and I was going to ask
if you wanted to come,
but I know you don't really know them,
so you don't have to.
Yes.
[teacher] Nick and Charlie,
keep it down please.
-Caleb.
-Here.
-Jack.
-Stanley.
-Here.
Kumar.
Thanks for giving me
barely any time to get you a present.
-You don't have to get me a present.
-No, I am.
-I'm serious.
-[shushing]
[boy] Here.
-[teacher] Oscar.
-Here.
-Zikh.
-Hakim.
-Here.
-Amir.
You all right, mate?
Hyped for your date on Saturday?
Date on Saturday?
Yeah. Imogen told me
you're "meeting up" on Saturday.
Like, she's telling everyone, actually.
Uh, yeah. Yeah, I forgot.
So, if we meet there at 4:00
then we can play two games,
then get some food
and then hang around the arcade for a bit.
Oi, boys, boys, watch this.
[boys laughing]
[Tao] Watch out, dicknozzle.
You all right, mate?
Harry, don't start.
What? Are you best friends
with these weird little Year 10s now?
Just stop picking on people for no reason.
Aw! Are you gay for them? [laughing]
[Tao] Classic Harry.
Resorting to homophobia when
you can't think of a good comeback.
Mate, are you in a mood today?
Are you? Serious question.
Life must be really hard
when your only personality trait
is rich bell-end.
[laughter]
-You shouldn't have done that.
-What do you mean?
I know you're trying to help
but you're making things worse.
[Tao] I'm sticking up for you.
We have to show Harry that
he can't just walk all over us.
It's more complicated than that.
It's not them versus us.
-Because of Nick?
-Yeah.
He can look after himself.
I really don't want him
to be dragged into this.
Well, we can't possibly hurt
your new best friend, Nick Nelson.
[whimsical music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[whimpers]
[door opening]
-[door closes]
-[Nellie barks]
Had a good day, Nicky?
Mmm.
What's up?
I said I'd go on a date with this girl,
but I kind of also agreed to go to
Charlie's birthday party on the same day.
Oh, do you like this girl?
Well, um…
Her dog died.
Uh, not following.
She was really upset, and I felt bad.
And she asked me out
and I didn't know how to say no.
And I tried to tell her
we probably shouldn't go out,
and I couldn't.
Because I didn't want to upset her
when she was already crying about her dog.
Oh, okay.
I mean…
A lot of people
are expecting us to get together,
but I don't think I like her like that.
You shouldn't go out with someone
because you feel sorry for them.
Yeah.
Don't worry. The right girl
will come along, just you wait.
["If You Want to" playing]
[people cheering]
♪ Go ahead and try my head ♪
♪ Experience is nothing compared to… ♪
You came.
Yeah, of course I did.
Happy birthday.
You didn't have to get me anything.
And I ignored you.
[Charlie] Come on.
Am I the first one here?
No, you're actually the last.
We're over there. Lane 17.
[speaking indistinctly]
I feel like I know her from somewhere.
That's Elle. She used to go to our school.
She would have been in your year,
but she moved to Higgs.
That's Isaac. He doesn't say a lot,
but he's really nice.
And you know Tao.
Sorry in advance if he says
anything rude to you.
That's just the way he is.
[Nick] Okay.
Ready to meet them?
Yeah.
[Charlie] Everyone,
this is Nick.
-Hey.
-[Isaac] Hey.
Oh, good. We're just choosing
fun names for the board.
Fun names?
Yeah, and for the record,
Elle Smells was Tao's idea.
Can you at least try to get to know him?
I'll… try.
["Buzzkill" playing]
-That's close.
-Oh, no!
[exclaims]
What are you doing?
That's it! I'm not doing it anymore.
No more, no more, no more.
-Yes! Come on!
-[Charlie] You did it!
Sorry.
-Why are these chips so good?
-They're so good.
[all yelling]
-Oh, yeah.
-[grunts]
[Nick] Yes!
I was so close.
You definitely cheated.
Oh, yeah? How?
You have strong rugby arms.
[Nick] Strong rugby arms?
-You okay?
-Yeah. Yeah. I'm good.
You've got an unfair advantage.
I thought you liked my arms.
Shut up.
Is everyone ready for a round two?
I'm just going to go find the bathroom.
I'm going to go talk to him.
About?
Tao. Tao, no. It's his birthday.
I have to.
Charlie.
Oh.
Hi.
Charlie, look.
I'm saying this to you as a friend.
You need to stop this thing
with Nick Nelson.
What?
He's going on a date with this girl.
I heard him agree to it
after that rugby match the other week.
That can't be true.
[Tao] Fine.
Don't believe me.
I'm clearly just lying for fun.
I'm going to go and get some chips.
Do you guys want anything?
Oh, can you get me a Coke?
-I'll pay.
-[Nick] No, I'll get it.
-Okay.
-Isaac?
I'll also accept a can of Coke.
If you're paying.
Okay, all right. I'll be back in a minute.
Thanks.
[pop song playing on speakers]
[Tao] You know
he's just an attention-seeker
like Harry and the rest of his mates!
[Charlie] Nick doesn't even like Harry.
Nick's basically risking everything
by hanging out with me, so--
Wow. I feel so sorry
for the popular rugby lad
who's almost getting picked on
because he dares to hang out
with someone below his popularity status.
You know that's not what I meant.
Now you're going to tell me
I'm being jealous
because you made a friend
and I'm scared of being alone?
Well…
Aren't you?
No!
I just don't like
seeing him mess with you.
[Charlie] Do you really think
he's messing me around?
[Tao] I mean, that's what it looks like.
But…
He's…
my
friend.
[Tao] Fine.
But if he is even slightly mean to you…
Yeah.
You'll murder him. I know.
I was going to say
I'd send him a strongly worded DM,
but murder's fine too.
[chuckles]
Ugh!
Just go.
Hi.
Are you getting more food?
[whimsical music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
[Charlie] I believe in you.
Yes! I win, I win!
Why am I so bad?
Uh, well, your arms are basically twigs.
Ah! How dare you?
I'm a very muscular individual.
You wish.
-How did you do that?
-I don't know.
-You're really good at it.
-[Elle] Thank you.
[Elle speaking indistinctly]
Good game.
Chip?
Thanks.
I don't know if this thing
with Charlie is a joke,
but for some reason, he really likes you,
and you're messing with him.
And I will not tolerate it,
so consider this your final warning.
Yeah.
You're right.
You're a good friend.
I know.
[Elle] Oh, my God,
what about the dance machine?
I'm so scared of it.
-[Elle] Well, what do you want to play?
-I don't know.
[Elle] Do we have to run?
Yes, before someone occupies
the dance machine.
[Nick] Okay, come on. Come on, come on.
-What?
-[Charlie laughing]
[Nick] I'm almost out of money now.
Don't look at me. I'm not giving you
more just so you can lose again.
Fine, I see how it is.
[both laughing]
So, I, um…
I kind of overheard you and Tao
in the bathroom earlier.
Oh.
I wanted to say sorry
about the date with Imogen thing.
You actually went on a date with her?
No, no.
She just asked me out
and I was so surprised,
and all our mates were watching
and expecting me to say "yes"
and I was such an idiot,
I just blurted out "yes"
because I didn't know how to say "no"
without embarrassing her
and confusing all our mates.
And then her dog died.
And I felt really bad for her and…
I'm so sorry.
Isn't that what
you always tell me not to say?
Yeah, but…
I've actually done something bad.
Well, it's not like we're… you know…
officially dating or anything.
I'm going to make it right
with Imogen, I'm gonna…
tell her I don't like her like that.
Okay.
I wish I'd met you when I was younger.
-Yeah?
-Mmm.
I wish I'd…
known then what I know now.
No being sad on my birthday.
[chuckles]
So, are you going to open my present then?
Yeah. As long as you don't mind.
Well, I kind of want to see your reaction.
I genuinely didn't have time to go out
and buy you something.
So…
Sorry it's a bit handmade.
That was just one of
my favorite days ever, so…
I really like you.
You like me?
Wasn't that obvious? [chuckles]
Do you like me?
Yes! Obviously.
Why are we like this?
I want to kiss you so bad right now.
Okay.
You don't have to.
I want to.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
["Paper Mache World" playing]
♪ Fall back into my open mind ♪
♪ Convinced you won't be hard to find ♪
-♪ I've been expecting you to call ♪
-♪ Call, call, call ♪
♪ 'Cause I'd find you in any world ♪
♪ Set out, no doubt, 'cause every time ♪
Come on,
we need to find the basketball machine.
♪ And you'll be waiting, after all ♪
♪ 'Cause I'd find you in any world ♪
♪ And they said to just sit still ♪
♪ Apparently, I'm just a girl ♪
Go!
Die, space aliens!
Oh, my God.
Yes!
♪ Who cares about the system
And everything they stole? ♪
♪ 'Cause I'll find you ♪
♪ In this paper mâché world ♪
Yes!
[Nick] There's no way
I can beat you in this game.
[Charlie yells]
Literally, how do you always beat me?
I don't know what to tell you.
I was just born to race.
You want to get slushies?
God, yes.
Wait, I think I have two.
Quick. Quick, quick.
♪ I'd rather travel 'round
To find you in this goldfish bowl ♪
[machine] Go!
[Elle] Go, go, go, go!
I am the killer of aliens.
Yes!
Come on. Yes! Ooh!
Yes! A great success.
I was born to kill aliens.
Whoo!
-Hi.
-[Nellie whines]
[Imogen] Oh, my God, is this Nellie?
[Nick] I'm sorry about your dog.
I thought Nellie might cheer you up a bit.
Thank you.
[Nick] Sorry about yesterday.
It's okay.
Imogen, I…
You're a really nice person but…
I don't like you like that.
It's not anything to do with you,
I just don't think we really
fit together.
I'm not sure I…
fit
with you or…
other people in our friend group.
But…
we've been friends for so long
and we hang out every morning.
Do you ever feel like
you're only doing things
because everyone else is?
And you're scared to change?
Or do something that might
confuse or surprise people?
Your real personality has been, like…
buried inside you
for a really long time.
I guess, um,
that's how I've been feeling recently.
Sorry, that probably makes no sense.
No.
I think I get it.
Thanks.
For being honest.
[sighs]
["I Want To Be With You" playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Yeah.
So, how was your date?
We decided we were better off as friends.
[boys exclaiming]
-All right, what did Nick do?
-Nothing.
I just think I can do better.
[boys exclaiming and laughing]
You're proper thick
about girls sometimes, aren't you, mate?
Every time, every time.
[song continues playing]