["Bang Bang Bang" playing]
♪ I would hate to be your next girl ♪
♪ Sat back roll neck yellow vest world ♪
Going somewhere?
-Jesus, Tori.
-[Tori] What?
How do you just appear out of nowhere?
Older sister magic.
Where are you going?
Nick's invited me to
the cinema with his friends.
[Tori] Oh.
Okay.
-What?
-No, nothing.
Glad Nick's such a nice… friend.
Well, yeah.
He is. But, um…
Actually, we're…
Me and Nick, we're kind of going out.
Called it.
You can't tell anyone.
He's not even out to his mom.
I know, I know.
I'm happy for you.
You've liked him for ages.
Thanks.
-You're hanging out with his mates now?
-Yeah. Why?
I've seen them at parties and stuff.
They don't seem
that nice compared to Nick.
I'll be fine.
None of them know about you and Nick?
Obviously not.
Okay.
So is he your boyfriend?
We're not ready to label it yet,
we're just…
-You know.
-"You know."
[laughing] Shut up.
Well done. Your crush on him
was super embarrassing.
Go away.
[Charlie] So, I was wondering
if you wanted to come over.
Just to hang out.
We hang out at school though.
Yeah, but…
I thought…
-since we're boyfriends…
-What?
We're not boyfriends.
Why would you think that?
-Pickup at 10:00, okay?
-Yep.
-Charlie.
-Yeah?
If any of those boys says anything,
does anything nasty,
you just call me, okay?
Nick's going to be there.
I'll be fine.
[uplifting music playing]
[car engine starts]
-Hi.
-[Charlie] Hi.
Um, are you sure your friends are going to
be okay with me being here?
Yeah, of course.
You'll be fine.
Ben and Harry aren't coming.
What, are you nervous?
I don't know.
They all probably think
I'm this, like, gay nerd.
Well, you kind of are a gay nerd.
[laughs] Shut up, rugby lad.
[both speaking indistinctly]
-All right. Look, Nick and his best mate.
-[laughter]
-[Harry] Why did he even bring him?
-Oh.
Oi. Just look at him
behind him. Like a little girl.
[glass shatters]
[laughter]
[boy] Is he your mate, Ben?
Who, Charlie?
-Never even spoken to him.
-[laughter]
[Harry] Why can't any of you
ever bring a girl with you?
Let's get popcorn.
Do you prefer sweet or salted?
Or we could get a mix of both.
I'm not really hungry, to be honest.
You get some though.
Char…
[whimsical music playing]
Are you okay?
I honestly had no idea they'd be here.
I wouldn't have suggested
we come if I'd known.
Char?
Uh… Wow, that just slipped out.
Oh, my God, say it again.
-No. No.
-Go on.
I like it. It's cute.
Now I'm never calling you it again.
[woman in movie screams]
[woman in movie crying]
[whispers] Sorry.
-[creatue growls]
-[woman sobs]
[woman screaming]
[crackling]
You're a dork.
-[woman in movie screaming]
-[audience gasps]
I can't believe what a wimp you are.
Uh, you jumped at all the scares too.
No, I jumped
when you screamed, that's all.
So, Charlie Spring, quick question.
What's it like being gay?
[laughter]
It's fine.
You don't seem that gay, to be honest.
You do sound sort of gay, but that's it.
-Do you like musicals?
-Harry, can you just piss off, please?
[boys chattering]
What sort of guys do you like then?
I don't know.
What about Harry Styles? He's pretty sexy.
-I guess.
-Just leave it.
What about Nick?
Do you think he's hot?
[boys laughing]
Are you joking?
-Nick's not even my type.
-[laughter]
-[Harry] You have a crush on him.
-No.
[Harry] You do.
Just stop.
Wow, take a joke, mate. [scoffs]
[boys laughing]
My dad's here.
I have to go.
Charlie.
Hey.
Wait.
I'm so sorry.
-It's fine.
-No.
Harry was being a complete idiot
and some of the others
were being really unfriendly and…
-We should have just left.
-Nick.
I'm honestly used to it by now.
I'll see you at school.
Charlie.
I saw you holding hands with him.
In the cinema.
Are you going out with him then?
-No.
-But you are getting with him?
-[scoffs] Don't lie.
Well, I believe that
you're not going out with him.
As if anyone would ever want to go out
with someone as desperate as you.
-You did.
-Are you joking?
You actually thought I liked you?
You were there like some tragic loser
with barely any friends,
who ate lunch alone and let bullies
walk over you. I never liked you.
I'm not even gay.
I just felt really sorry for you.
Charlie.
Ready to go?
Yeah.
[breathing heavily]
Are you okay?
-What was that about?
-Nothing.
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
Right.
Let's go home.
[boys chattering]
Go on then.
What's your problem with Charlie?
He doesn't exactly fit in
with us, does he?
He can't play rugby, he's got this
weird friend who won't leave me alone.
You can't just bring some gay boy
into our group
and expect us all to immediately love him.
So this is a problem with him being gay?
Come on, none of us are being homophobic.
Just shut up, Harry!
You made him so uncomfortable
with your gay questions.
Someone really needs to learn
to take a joke.
But you weren't joking though, were you?
You saw the perfect opportunity
to make someone feel
miserable and humiliated, as usual.
I'm sure he can deal with it.
He's probably used to it by now.
[chuckles]
Aw. You're getting so angry.
You can't help wanting to
protect him, can you?
Because he's a pathetic little fag.
[boys exclaiming]
So are you going to tell me what happened?
There's not really anything to tell.
Oh, Nicky, come on, baby.
[whimpering]
Harry was saying some
really nasty stuff about Charlie.
He's been really gross and mean
about him for ages, and I just…
I lost it.
I'm just so angry at myself for
not seeing that all my friends… suck.
Sweetheart, fighting is not the answer.
I know.
He just used a really bad word.
I see.
Charlie's a really special friend,
isn't he?
["Tired" playing]
Yeah.
He is.
♪ You haven't been good for long ♪
[alarm sounding]
♪ Is it the sound of your own thoughts ♪
♪ That always keeps you up at night? ♪
♪ Maybe it's time to say goodbye ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm getting pretty… tired ♪
Looking for your boyfriend?
I know I'm attractive, mate.
There's no need to stare.
What happened to you?
Ask Nick Nelson.
He's got some serious anger issues.
-Did you have a fight?
-He can't seem to take a joke anymore.
You know I was only joking in the cinema?
Yet he starts fighting
when I've done nothing.
What's going on? You okay?
It's fine. Let's just go.
You all right, mate?
You want to fight too?
You clearly didn't get
hugged much as a child,
but if you're craving human contact
that badly, you could just say so.
Tao. Just leave it. Everything's fine.
Yeah, maybe listen to your boyfriend.
At least he knows his place.
[intense music playing]
Hi.
What happened?
Oh, uh…
Yeah. I kind of got into a fight.
With Harry.
After you left
and I went back to the group, he…
he started saying some…
things about you.
I just lost it.
And punched him, and… yeah.
Nick.
You didn't have to do that.
I promise,
I'm used to people saying stuff about me.
No, but you shouldn't have to be.
People shouldn't be saying stuff
about you in the first place.
You shouldn't have to put up
with anything like that.
-I'm sorry.
-No.
You're not allowed to say the "s" word.
I don't want to be friends
with those people anymore.
I don't expect you
to dump your friends for me.
Some of the rugby boys are nice.
Even they just… stood there.
I'm tired of all of them.
["Any Other Way" playing]
♪ Hopped on a plane
For the first time today ♪
♪ I can't look back ♪
♪ Out of guilt and out of shame ♪
♪ But did we know any other way ♪
♪ I didn't know any other way ♪
[Tao] I think it was my fault.
What was?
Harry picking on me and Charlie.
I knew this would happen.
I could handle it 'cause I can stick up
for myself, but Charlie can't.
So I've been like…
fighting back.
Fighting?
Verbally fighting back.
You know that'll make you both a target.
Yeah, I can see that now.
I just kept thinking about
how bad it was for Charlie last year.
I just made things worse.
Sorry.
I feel like I'm always off-loading
my problems onto you.
I mean, I did the same thing to you
in my last term at Truham,
so it's basically payback.
Harry just thinks
it's fun to pick on people.
He was in my maths class last year.
Did he ever say anything to you?
Yeah. Sometimes.
Surprise, he's transphobic as well.
You should have said something.
We could have told a teacher…
Yeah.
Maybe.
But it wasn't like he was the only one
saying stuff to me.
I'm not surprised
Nick started a fight with him.
If Harry was being a dick
to Charlie, of course.
Is there something going on
between Nick and Charlie?
There is, isn't there?
Yeah.
They're going out.
Who else knows?
Um…
Isaac, Tara and Darcy.
But Charlie wants to tell you himself.
Well, he said
he wanted to tell you himself.
When did he tell you?
At the milkshake cafe.
That was ages ago.
[scoffs]
I feel so stupid.
I should go. My mum's probably waiting.
-Tao.
-[Tao] See you later.
Wait.
[pensive music playing]
[doorbell rings]
[door opening]
-[Elle] Hi.
-[Yan] Elle, come in!
[Elle] How are you?
[Yan] Oh, what a surprise!
Hi.
Uh, make sure you leave
the bedroom door open a tad, okay?
[scoffs]
-What are you doing here?
-Um…
Want to eat cookies and watch a film?
Is it… a potato?
It's supposed to be a shoe.
Oh.
Look, we all know
me taking Art GCSE was a mistake.
It's fixable. Here.
[Tao sighs]
See? That's better.
Thanks. I'll treasure
this shoe-potato always.
[laughs]
Sorry about earlier.
I know it's not your fault
he hasn't told me.
Charlie does want to tell you.
I think I know why he hasn't.
He thinks I'll say something stupid
and out Nick to all of Nick's mates.
And obviously he cares more
about Nick's feelings than mine.
Once you get into a relationship,
friendships don't matter anymore.
Or maybe he thinks
you'll force Nick to watch Donnie Darko
like you did with us.
Shut up, it's a good movie.
It's just complicated.
I don't know why
I'm so afraid of being alone.
That's how I felt.
My first term.
I got scared.
Everything turned out okay.
[whimsical music playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Hey.
You okay?
Um…
All right, mate?
Not in the mood for that fight, then?
Only if it's in the form of a board game
or a cake-eating contest.
-[laughter]
-[boy] What's he on about?
-What's this?
-Hey.
Tao and Elle? Who's Elle?
Just give it back.
-Aw! Did your girlfriend draw it?
-Just give it back now.
Come and get it.
Oi, lads, look at this.
[boys exclaiming]
I hate you!
[boys laughing]
You're going to regret that!
[breathing heavily]
So I was thinking
about me and you.
Okay.
And I just think…
The fight with Harry was my fault.
-It wasn't though.
-It was.
It was my fault.
Becoming friends with you and,
you know, everything that's happened.
I've been making your life
really difficult.
So I was thinking…
maybe it would be better if…
if we just…
Um…
Come on! Harry Greene's
fighting a Year 10 by the picnic tables.
[boys clamoring]
["Smokey Eyes" playing]
[both grunting]
♪ Smokey eyes, are you feeling good? ♪
[Tao] Just leave us alone!
♪ Seems like we've waited long enough ♪
♪ For someone else
To make us feel complete ♪
♪ It's not a bitter flavor
And it's not a sweeter drink ♪
♪ I'm scared to ask you if you
Would do the same for me ♪
[booing]
[teacher] Break it up!
Tao! What happened?
[crying] Why didn't you
tell me about you and Nick?
What?
I thought we were friends,
but you've forgotten about me.
-Tao…
-This is all your fault.
Just leave me alone!
♪ On a napkin, then ♪
♪ Hold it up to your mouth
So you can sleep ♪
[breathing heavily]