ADULT SHELDON:
While my sister and I
are twins, we've always
been different.
By the age of two,
I was reading books.
Missy was content to eat them.
By five, I had
a healthy appreciation
for a well-organized
work space.
My sister, less so.
(Missy giggles)
Which is not to say
she doesn't have
qualities I admire.
Get it! Get it!
It's just a spider.
Calm down.
It's got eight
legs and fangs.
I see no reason
to be calm.
Did you kill it?
Yup.
Are you sure?
You tell me.
(yelling)
The bond between twins
is an incredibly close one,
which is why I moved
1,500 miles to California
the first chance I got.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Hey.
Hello.
You got a minute?
John has something he wants
to talk to you about.
I brought you kolaches.
Ooh, yummy.
Mmm. Mmm. (chuckles)
So, what's up?
You comin' to me to ask
for Connie's hand in marriage?
No.
But if that were
to come to pass,
are you authorized
to bless the union?
He was joking.
Oh.
Tell him.
Okay.
So, some colleagues of mine
at the university are doing
a research study on twins.
I told them about
Sheldon and his sister,
and they were most intrigued.
Uh, what kind of study?
It's a longitudinal
investigation
of environmental
and genetic factors
in the development of cognitive
and other capacities
in pairs of fraternal
and identical twins.
You asked.
(chuckles): Well, geez,
I don't... I don't know
if I want some scientists
pokin' and proddin' the kids.
Oh, but they wouldn't
be poked and prodded.
They just have to, you know,
answer some questions.
And maybe some
puzzles and tests.
That's not too bad.
Where is it?
Houston.
Oh, it just got bad.
That's... that's a long drive.
It does pay $50 an hour
plus gas and expenses.
Really?
I told you to start with that.
Oh.
No. See, Mary,
that's the best part--
there's no pokin'
and proddin'. Plus,
you know how much
Sheldon loves puzzles and tests.
I'm not sure.
(sighs)
Think about the money.
50 bucks an hour,
four or five hours a week.
That-That's more than
our mortgage.
I know, I know.
But Sheldon's already
self-conscious
about being different
from other kids.
I worry how this might
affect him.
You're being too protective.
He's a rock.
A rock?
Are we raising
the same child?
And what about Missy?
Aren't these tests gonna
make her feel bad
that she's not
as smart as Sheldon?
(snorts)
I'm not as smart as Sheldon.
Doesn't make me feel bad.
And we could put the money aside
for their college education.
That's a good point.
It's a great point.
I don't have to tell you,
times are changing.
Kids are pitching in.
Like that Webster kid on TV--
he's making buckets
of money for his parents.
Well...
I suppose we could
give it a try.
There you go.
I'll call Sturgis,
tell him we're in.
Baby, I'm getting
a fishing boat.
So, Sheldon, Missy,
we got some exciting news.
Georgie took a bath?
No.
And how come I don't get
exciting news?
This isn't about you.
But after dinner, why
don't you go rinse off?
So, what's up?
Well,
a couple of scientists
at the college
where Dr. Sturgis teaches
are doing
a research
study on twins.
They want to meet you guys,
ask you some questions.
Oh, boy, a research study.
Will they give us written tests?
Yeah, I think so.
Oh, boy.
Now, you don't have to
do this if you don't want to.
It's purely volunteer.
I don't want to do it.
Why not?
They probably just
want to find out
why you're so smart
and I'm just average.
(quietly): Average?
That's a little generous.
Why don't they want
to test me?
Georgie, not now.
'Cause I'm available.
Listen, why don't we
just go there this Saturday
and give it a try?
And if you don't like it,
we don't have to do it again.
Or they'll love it,
and they'll do it till
they're 18, 19 years old.
I already love it.
My man. Missy?
I believe there might be
a Dairy Queen on the way there.
Can I get an Oreo Blizzard?
You know what I think?
I think you're smarter than him.
Dr. Thorpe and Dr. Pilson,
here are your
research volunteers,
Sheldon and Missy.
So nice to meet you.
Thank you for participating
in our study.
Always happy to help advance
our understanding of me.
I'm just in it
for the Dairy Queen.
All right.
Um, if you two wouldn't
mind waiting here,
we'd like to start by talking
to your mom, dad, and grandma.
Why?
Jut to get some
background information
on the both of you.
Smart. Ask how old I was when
I completed potty training.
You won't believe it.
I'll do that.
Will you keep an eye on 'em?
Well, I'll try, but
if they start running,
you may never see them again.
(laughs)
Shall we?
We are on the clock, right?
George.
Hmm?
(chuckles) Boy, this
brings back some memories.
How come?
Well, when I was your age,
I was also taken to a university
to be studied.
Because they thought
you were really smart?
I was clinically insane.
And it wasn't just me.
Did you know that
when Albert Einstein
was a little boy,
his parents worried
there was something
wrong with him?
Because he couldn't
comb his hair?
No, that was a choice
he made later in life.
When he was young,
he wanted nothing to do
with other children,
and would often have
extreme temper tantrums.
He sounds like you.
I know.
Isn't it great?
Well, to be perfectly honest,
Sheldon has always avoided
children his own age.
Tell 'em about
temper tantrums.
They're not temper tantrums,
he just has strong opinions.
(chuckles)
Yeah,
like when you yell
and stomp your feet,
and slam the door
off its hinge.
They're scientists.
You can't trick 'em.
And, as for Missy,
she's just the opposite.
Loves to be around people
and other kids.
Makes friends easy.
Does she have temper
tantrums as well?
Nope.
She's very even-keeled.
Except for when she's eating.
You put your hand
near her face
when she's working
on a lamb chop,
she will bite off a finger.
(laughs)
Our daughter doesn't bite.
Right here,
Thanksgiving, 1986.
Was there anything unusual
about your pregnancy?
No, not that I remember.
Really?
You cried for, like,
seven months.
Those were tears of joy.
(weak laugh)
What about all those times
you punched me?
Punches of joy.
You're not gonna get much
out of Fred and Wilma here.
Why don't you just
get crackin' on the kids?
Okay, Sheldon, this first
battery of tests measures
basic problem-solving abilities.
Is the Kaufman test or the
Wechsler Intelligence Scale?
Are you familiar with those?
It's embarrassing, but I enjoy
a little light reading
in the bathroom.
Okay.
Are you ready?
Will I be timed?
Yes.
Fantastic.
(stopwatch clicks)
Okay, Missy,
the first thing
we're gonna do is test
your problem-solving ability.
Okay.
You ready?
I just have one question.
What's that?
Do you always wear
your hair up?
Uh, well, usually at work, yes.
I bet it looks cute down.
Thank you.
Okay,
you're all set.
Is that camera
gonna be on?
Yes.
Can you move it
over to that side?
Why?
If I've learned one thing
from school picture day,
it's that I look better
from that side.
Sure, I'll move it.
Okay...
And bring it a little closer.
How's that?
Great.
Okay.
(sighs)
Whenever you're ready.
Wait.
Do I have any Oreos
in my teeth?
No.
Ready to start?
One last thing.
Did you ever think of wearing
that white coat with a belt?
No.
You should.
'Cause you have
a very nice figure,
and it's lost in there.
Hey, check this out.
Did you see
Honey, I Shrunk the Kids?
No.
You should.
'Cause there's a lot of
good science stuff in it.
(laughing)
Kudos on the question
"Which train gets
to St. Louis first?"
Hmm.
I have to tell you something.
Why don't you
finish the test first.
This can't wait.
The other doctor's
got a crush on you.
Oh, dear Lord.
Oh, um...
I don't...
I don't think so.
Let's get back to the test.
Okay.
Why? What did you see?
When you're not looking,
he stares at your tushy.
(whispering):
Really?
Imagine if you
wore the belt.
Clever girl.
That would accentuate
her buttocks.
I can't watch. Switch
it back to Sheldon.
Hot dog, syllogisms.
If all squares
are parallelograms,
and all squares
are rectangles,
then some parallelograms
are rectangles.
Who was this test
made for, children?
I'm bored.
Turn it back to Missy.
Go ahead.
This question about a train
going to "S-T" Louis
makes no sense.
DR. THORPE:
It's okay to guess.
Take your time, baby.
The meter's running.
(cash register dings)
DR. THORPE:
Well, thank you all very much.
This was a great start.
Thank you.
Did you have fun?
I got to take a test
on a Saturday, heck yeah!
He's like a young version of me,
but without corrective shoes.
(chuckles)
Missy, what'd you think?
The tests were
just okay,
but I like Sandra.
Well, thank you, Missy.
I like you, too.
PILSON:
All right,
we'll see y'all next Saturday.
You bet we will.
Good God, George,
have a little dignity.
Hm.
Are you doing something
different with your hair?
No, uh, why?
No reason, just looks nice.
Oh! (chuckles)
Thank you.
Um, uh, what do you think
about maybe stopping
for a drink after,
to discuss the test results?
I would like that.
♪ ♪
Oh, yeah.
Get down.
(door opens)
MARY: We're home.
Hey.
What you watching?
Soul Train.
I like trains.
It's not that kind
of train, dummy.
Well that seems like
false advertising.
Ooh, you sexy little thing.
MARY:
George!
Oh.
I do not like what this study
is doing to Sheldon.
What're you talking about?
He had a great time.
All the way home
all he could talk about
is how that doctor thought he
was so smart. It's not healthy.
Would it make you
feel any better
if I told you how much money
we made today?
No, it would not.
$300.
Really?
Cash.
Okay, well, still, I...
I'm not interested
in profiting off my children.
You see, honey, that's where
you and I are very different.
Boats.
Sheldon, what do you think
is happening in this picture?
Easy. There are four chimpanzees
in a living room.
PILSON:
Okay, but what can you
tell me about them?
They're not behaving
like chimpanzees.
Anything else?
Chimpanzees don't drink tea.
Is that it?
Well, I suppose
it might be coffee,
but they don't
drink that either.
Anything interesting
about their body language?
No.
I think they found
his kryptonite.
THORPE:
Missy,
what do you think
is happening in this picture?
The girl monkey on the couch
is telling the
guy monkey a secret.
Must be something juicy,
'cause he's smiling.
Anything else?
It might be dirty,
'cause this girl monkey
is sending
the kid monkey out of the room.
He doesn't want to go.
He looks sad.
Is that all?
The monkeys on the couch
are drinking tea,
so it's a tea party.
Okay, very good.
Let's look at another picture.
I'm not done.
The monkey in the painting
is wearing an old lady hat,
so she's probably
a meemaw monkey.
She's not
at the party,
so she must be bowling or dead.
Well, Missy
won that round.
It's actually
not a contest, George.
This is Texas.
Everything's a contest.
A woman in a doorway.
Anything else?
She's holding her head
with her hand.
And what do you think
that means?
Um...
Wouldn't you rather ask me
about trains going to St. Louis?
Good gravy, she's sad,
Sheldon, come on.
Oh, she's very upset.
I don't know why.
Oh! Maybe she wasn't invited
to the tea party
at the monkey house.
(chuckles)
Also, she's wearing a belt,
like you are.
Nice going.
Very cute.
(mouths)
And I'm loving the hair.
(whispers):
Yeah.
A lion sitting in a chair,
holding a pipe.
Good.
But what do you think
is on his mind?
How should I know?
Maybe he's wondering
why he's posing
for a silly picture
instead of eating a gazelle.
PILSON:
Anything else?
What exactly are we doing here?
I thought the purpose
of this study
was to find out how smart I am.
PILSON:
That's what we're doing,
but there are different kinds
of intelligence.
Poppycock!
There's only one kind
of intelligence...
George, Sheldon's getting upset.
I don't like it.
All right, I'll just
change it back to Missy.
You are an insightful
young lady.
I don't know what that
means, but thank you.
It means perceptive.
You see things most people miss.
My name is Missy-- go figure.
Have you always been that way?
I guess so. I think when
you're on your own a lot,
you get good at seeing
that kind of stuff.
THORPE: Really?
MISSY: My dad
does football
with my older brother,
so they're like a team.
And my mom and meemaw spend all
their time fussing over Sheldon,
so they're like a team, too.
So no one's on your team?
Nope.
It's just me.
Oh, Lord.
Hey, what's up with you
and Dr. Pillsbury?
Dr. Pilson?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Oh.
You can't say
'cause we're on camera.
(sighs)
Insightful.
A little late for me
to start cooking.
Why don't we stop
somewhere for dinner.
Really?
The five of us?
That's kind of pricey.
Would you rather
buy a fishing boat?
You're a blabbermouth,
you know that?
(Meemaw laughs)
Missy, we're gonna
eat in a restaurant.
Where would you
like to go?
I get to pick?
Why don't I
get to pick?
Because your sister's
getting to pick.
It's not just about you
in this house.
What do you think, baby?
I pick...
Red Lobster.
You got it.
Damn.
There goes our per diem.
ANNOUNCER: Out of an
I formation, it's the option...
George, you got a minute?
What's up?
Not you,
him.
What?
Sheldon told me that we get paid
to go to that college
and answer their questions.
Yeah, so?
I want to know
how much we're making.
Why?
'Cause I want my fair share.
Is that so?
What do you think
your fair share is?
Half.
Hm, guess that sounds right.
So how much are we making?
$7.50 a week.
Really?
Really.
Well, I want half that.
Which is?
Hang on.
Sheldon!
Can we put on
Soul Train?
Why?
There's a girl on there
I kind of want to marry.