With us tonight is
Pastor Jeff Difford
from the First Baptist Church
of Medford.
Thank you
for being here, Pastor.
My pleasure.
So it would appear
that your church's
Halloween Hell House
has stirred up
quite a bit
of controversy this year.
Oh, I wouldn't call it
controversy.
What would you call it?
A-As you know,
the purpose of a Hell House
is to demonstrate
the wages of sin,
so as to lead people
back to God.
That's wonderful.
But doesn't it
concern you that a lot
of parents were alarmed
at the gruesome scenes
you portrayed?
Once again,
our intentions were pure.
Why don't we take a look
at just how pure they were.
Let's roll the clip.
Oh, boy.
I need another beer.
Oh, darling, don't you
think you've had enough?
I'll tell you
when I had enough!
(screams)
Whoa! Hey, cowboy,
why don't you put that
down and call it a night.
Don't you tell me
what to do.
(screaming)
JEFF:
That's enough, Peg.
Dear Lord.
As you can see,
our last attempt at a Hell House
may have been a tad...
traumatizing.
I thought it was a hoot.
Some of the little ones
peed their pants. (chuckles)
But that wasn't the goal.
A nine-year-old crapped
himself. (chuckles)
Why are you showing me this?
Well, Mary, this year,
we'd like to go
with a more family-friendly
production.
And I thought you'd be the
perfect person to head that up.
Really? Me?
Yes, you. Absolutely.
Gosh, I don't know.
(scoffs)
I always felt I had a flair
for the creative arts,
but putting on a
big show like that...
You'll have a sizable budget
and all the help you'll need
constructing sets,
building props,
special effects, makeup.
Does sound tempting.
But, most importantly,
you'll have an opportunity
to bring people to God
by vividly demonstrating
the perils of sin.
Be careful
if you touch on adultery.
Last year,
one of the actors got pregnant.
Thanks, Peg.
So, what do you say?
I already know the first change
I'm gonna make.
Instead of calling it
"Hell House,"
which is a little off-putting,
I'm gonna call it...
"Heck House."
Isn't that great?
That is great.
You don't
really mean that.
Yes, I do.
Oh, I get it.
Happy wife, happy life.
You need to stop talking.
So it's not
gonna be scary?
It will, but without
all the blood and gore.
But I like
blood and gore.
Hang on, y'all are trying
to scare people
into joining the church?
Yeah. But people like
getting scared
on Halloween anyway.
Why not make 'em jump
in the right direction?
Actually, fear has been
a recruiting tactic
used by organized religion
for centuries.
When you add guilt
to keep people in line,
it's an extremely efficient form
of crowd control.
Our religion is based on love,
Sheldon, not fear.
So what happens when people
don't follow the rules?
They burn in hell.
Because God loves 'em.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
(school bell rings)
(indistinct chatter)
Sheldon.
Oh. Hi, Georgie.
Why was Veronica
Duncan hugging you?
I'm tutoring her
in trigonometry.
And that gets you hugs?
Thanks to me,
she got her first C-minus.
Just between us,
she's a little slow.
That's not what I heard.
What did you hear?
Is she secretly clever?
Because if she is,
I completely missed it.
It doesn't matter.
You just need to
introduce me to her.
Why?
I want to be her friend.
Well, you better take a number.
She's friends with a lot of boys
around here.
Let me worry about that.
You just need to introduce us.
All right.
You know, she pays me
two dollars for every one
of our tutoring lessons.
How much did it cost
her to get a C-minus?
$26.
That's a good deal.
LUNDY: Now, remember,
next week, we start our work
on Streetcar Named Desire.
So please prepare a monologue
for either Blanche
or Stanley.
Usually, the girls do Blanche
and the boys do Stanley,
but no judgment--
you follow your heart.
(indistinct chatter)
Thank you again
for letting me come by
to pick your brain.
Oh, please.
Anything for the church.
Are you a religious man?
I'm an actor.
I'm whatever
you need me to be.
All right.
As I told you on the phone,
I have been tasked
with mounting this year's
Halloween production.
Oh, is that a haunted house
kind of deal?
Yes, but with the goal
of bringing people to God.
I do know something
about that.
When I played Puck
in Midsummer,
the Tulsa Herald called
my performance heavenly.
Wow! Good for you.
Thank you, thank you.
(giggling)
(chuckles)
Okay. Um, I was hoping
to put on a little play
in each of the rooms
that portrays one of
the seven deadly sins.
Pride, envy, gluttony, lust,
sloth, wrath and greed!
Wow, you know your sins!
Well, again, I'm an actor.
They are the tools in my box.
Um, have you
considered
a narrator, you know, um,
like, a tour guide
kind of thing?
Oh, that's interesting.
But who would that be?
Well, I'd have to think
the big man himself.
God?
Satan.
Oh! That's spooky.
And he's trying
to lure people toward sin.
Exactly.
That's a pretty big role.
I wonder who could do it.
Huh.
Well, it would
have to be someone
with enough range to
convey sincerity and charm,
all the while, hiding
a dark and corrupt soul!
(cackles)
Good golly.
(chuckles)
If you were just a little
taller, you'd be perfect.
I have lifts.
(indistinct chatter)
What are we doing here?
Waiting for Veronica.
How do you know she's in there?
It's kind of her homeroom.
Oh, hello again.
Oh.
(chuckles)
Hey. What's up?
This is my brother Georgie.
He wanted to meet you.
Really?
Really.
I like your hair.
Uh, me, too.
(crows cawing)
(engine shuts off)
What do you think?
Pretty great, huh?
Realtor's letting us
use it for free.
Wow. How'd you swing that?
Well, I promised
Fred Murphy a lead role
in the lust room.
Ooh.
(laughs)
Look at you,
just wheeling and dealing
like a big-time
Hollywood producer.
(chuckles)
Maybe you're
in the wrong business.
Being a mother?
Being a Christian.
Ah.
Greetings!
Oh, good! Mr. Lundy,
you made it.
(chuckles)
Oh, we're gonna be working
together. You can call me Gene.
All right, Gene, this
is my mother, Connie.
Hi.
Hello.
Now, I would've bet
she was your big sister.
(chuckles)
I thought you said
he was a good actor.
Oh, now.
(chuckling)
So, what do you think?
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm.
Spiderwebs.
What?
We're gonna need
some spiderwebs and I think
maybe some fire effects
on the left
and right side
of the portal.
Portal?
Portal to hell.
(chuckling)
Sure, sure.
Now, the script calls for me
to appear
from beneath the house
in a cloud of smoke.
But I think
that's gonna be ambitious.
Script? What script?
Oh, I wrote a script.
Don't worry about it.
I was gonna write the script.
Well, now you don't have to.
(chuckles)
Do you believe this?
Believe it, love it,
glad I didn't wait
in the car.
I can't believe this.
No good?
It's awful.
It makes sin
seem like a good thing.
Well, that's the problem,
isn't it?
I mean, if sin didn't seem
like a good thing,
nobody would do it.
George, please, I'm in no mood.
Hey. Wrath.
That's one of the seven sins,
right?
Pastor Jeff gave me this project
because he knew
I'd be best at it.
Now Gene... Lundy
is taking over.
Oh, look, pride. And envy.
Don't stop. Four sins to go.
I'm guessing lust
ain't happening tonight.
You see a large red button.
What do you do?
I press it.
The floor opens up and
you plunge into a 60-foot pit.
I fly out.
Up, up, and away!
Again, you're not Superman
in this game;
you're Superman for Halloween.
Which isn't till next week.
So I'm in a pit.
You're in a pit.
Then I blast my way out
with my super breath!
(blowing)
Just let him do it.
Dinner's ready.
Five more minutes.
Hey, Georgie.
I saw you talking
to Veronica Duncan.
Yeah. So?
How well do you know her?
Not as well as I'm gonna.
I introduced them.
He math skills
are dreadful.
Did you know Superman
has a dog?
His name is Krypto.
He plays fetch in space.
♪ Please allow me
to introduce myself ♪
Cut. Cut. Cut.
Cut. Cut. (sighs)
It's supposed to be wrath.
♪ I've been around
for a long, long time ♪
(gasps) Oh.
♪ Stole many a man's soul ♪
Give him a little kick
now that's he's down.
Give him a little kick.
♪ I was 'round ♪
That's right,
that's good.
Yes. Yeah.
(groaning)
No, go for it.
Yes.
♪ Pleased to meet you ♪
♪ Hope you guess my name ♪
♪ Woo-woo ♪
♪ Yeah, woo-woo ♪
♪ Ah, what's puzzling you... ♪
Kind of stomp down on him,
stomp down on him.
Yes. That's the way. Good.
Now, Fred, remember,
you are the
personification of lust.
Your sole reason for being
is to try to satisfy
this unquenchable thirst
for physical pleasure.
Great. Will there be
kissing and touching?
Oh, you bet.
Mm. Mm.
Now what?
Pretend kissing.
Pretend touching.
Oh.
Fred, would you just
give me a moment?
Mary, I-I've tried
to be patient,
but if I'm gonna do this,
put my reputation
on the line,
I'm gonna need you
to back off just a little bit.
Do I need to remind you that
the purpose of Heck House
is to show how sins
destroy our lives?
Yeah, so?
You are making them
into a good thing.
Have you read the script?
He's gonna get syphilis.
He goes home,
he gives it to his wife.
She goes crazy.
She kills him
and her entire family.
What am I missing?
Sorry I'm late.
I couldn't find my keys,
and then my car
wouldn't start.
Then I got lost.
Holy smokes.
Hi. Are you
my make out partner?
No. No. No one's making out.
This all stops right now.
You have got to calm down.
I will not have innocent
children walk through this house
on Halloween and see
a half-naked woman.
A half-naked woman
chock-full of syphilis.
BOTH:
What?
It's pretend syphilis.
Mary, I am a trained
theater professional.
Why don't you just let me
do what I do, while you,
you know, go home and make
a nice tuna casserole.
Hmm?
All right, Fred...
ADULT SHELDON:
I know what you're thinking:
she's going to tear
his throat out.
But what in fact happened
is she did
what she thought Jesus
would do.
She went home and made
that tuna casserole.
It was a little salty
but I ate it
because she was in a mood.
KIDS:
Trick or treat!
(laughter)
(eerie organ music playing)
(recorded screams playing)
(gasping, laughing)
Greetings.
Pleased to meet you.
I go by many names:
Satan, Lucifer,
Mephistopheles,
Beelzebub.
Of course, when I make
a dinner reservation,
I-I go by "Eric."
It's easier to spell.
Before we begin
tonight's descent into Heck,
I'd like to tell you
a little about myself.
'Cause it's all about you,
isn't it?
I was God's chosen angel.
I was his favorite.
We used to go camping together.
But then, because I wanted
to have a little bit of fun,
I was cast from heaven.
Tonight, you will bear witness
to that fun.
You will decide
whether it is sinful...
or just another Saturday night.
(laughs)
Come with me... if you dare.
(thunder rumbles)
Just watch your step
right over here,
'cause there's some
electrical wires.
(hisses)
(knock on door)
ALL:
Trick or treat.
Oh, look how cute y'all are.
Now, I know you are Superman.
What about the rest of you?
I'm Cyndi Lauper.
I'm a wizard.
Uh-huh.
And I'm Carl Sagan.
Who?
Carl Sagan.
He's the host of Cosmos.
Well, isn't that something.
Now, y'all be safe
and have a fun night.
I'm Super...
(laughter, shouting)
You like Guns N' Roses?
They're all right.
Yeah, they're all right.
You as smart
as your brother?
Nobody is.
I got an older sister
that's kind of a genius.
Oh, yeah?
Why didn't she tutor you?
She's in jail.
What'd she do?
She sold a piñata
full of weed
to an undercover cop.
Doesn't sound like
much of a genius.
Oh, I don't know, she
graduated high school.
BILLY:
Ooh, peanut butter cups!
Superman loves
peanut butter cups!
(thunder rumbles)
So you see, the sin of greed.
Very wealthy man,
a beautiful house,
swimming pool,
several German cars,
and a young wife
who worshipped him.
Excuse me, Mr. Satan.
What?
You kind of left out
how greed is the root
of all evil,
and how it corrupts
the soul.
It's in there.
It's called subtext.
Why don't we take a gander
at the eternal torment
that is sloth.
Eh!
I can't believe
no one in this town knows
who Carl Sagan is.
Why even have a TV?
Stupid Mrs. Gifford
gave me a banana.
SHELDON:
Where's Billy?
He had to go
to the bathroom.
So he went home?
No.
He's right behind
that tree.
Wait up, guys.
Oh, I got a little on my cape.
Ew.
There's nobody at my house.
You want to come over?
Yes.
Okay, let's go.
(ethereal music playing)
Look at this.
We threw a party for heaven
and nobody came.
Not one person
chose to be saved.
Well, did you tell 'em
about the cupcakes?
MEEMAW:
Where I think you went wrong
is in your timing.
If you'd done this deal
during a war or a plague,
then you'd have
a boatload of converts.
Famine.
Famine would bring 'em in.
What do you know about famine?
Hola, amigos.
Hey, Pastor Jeff.
Why so glum?
This is going great.
Donations are through the roof.
(laughs)
Nobody wants to be saved.
Yeah, but donations are
through the roof.
Is that all this means to you,
raising money?
Hey, that money is
gonna do a lot of good
for a lot of people.
Now, quit being
such a fun sponge.
Here, have some grapes.
(laughing)
What's that?
Some stupid haunted house
my mother's doing
for the church.
Let's check it out.
But I-I thought we were
going to your house.
We are, let's just
do this first.
It'll be fun.
(whimpers)
Pleased to meet you.
I go by many names:
Satan...
ADULT SHELDON:
My mother's fears
that no one would be saved
that Halloween night
were proven incorrect.
As they kissed, she
thought about the choices
that led her to this moment.
ADULT SHELDON:
Mr. Lundy's scene about lust
made a deep impact
on my brother's date.
Her youth was gone.
She had traded her
beauty for a few
tawdry dollars, and now she had
nothing left but shame...
...and venereal disease.
ADULT SHELDON:
She asked to be saved by Jesus.
(crying): I don't want to live
like this anymore.
Oh, just repeat after me...
ADULT SHELDON:
And as it turns out, she was.
She went on to live a life
devoted to God,
feeding the poor,
even helping her sister
start a literacy program
for female prisoners.
My brother, on the other hand,
became a devout atheist
after that night.
MARY:
We got one!
ALL: Trick or treat.
Aren't y'all precious.
And you look like
a little Carl Sagan.
ADULT SHELDON: Vindication,
the sweetest candy of all.
♪ ♪