Previously on Young Sheldon...
Why was Veronica
Duncan hugging you?
I'm tutoring her
in trigonometry.
Just between us,
she's a little slow.
That's not what I heard.
There's nobody
at my house.
You want to come over?
Yes.
What's that?
Some stupid haunted house
my mother's doing
for the church.
ADULT SHELDON:
Mr. Lundy's scene about lust
made a deep impact
on my brother's date.
She asked to be saved by Jesus.
(crying): I don't want to live
like this anymore.
ADULT SHELDON:
And as it turns out, she was.
Dear Lord Jesus,
set me free.
(music playing over TV)
ADULT SHELDON: In Conquest
of the Planet of the Apes,
we learned how humans taught
the apes to become civilized.
Which I think should start
with potty training,
but I'm not a screenwriter.
Can you help me
with my math homework?
No.
Please. It's really hard.
"It" isn't the problem.
Sheldon.
Fine, what are you working on?
There's a number,
then there's a line,
then there's another number
under it.
Fractions?
Yes, fractions.
ADULT SHELDON:
At that moment,
it occurred to me if I could
teach mathematics
to someone as dull-witted
as my sister,
I could create
a race of superhumans
that would do my bidding.
And who wouldn't want that?
Please, Sheldon.
You know what, Missy?
I'd be happy to help you.
Thank you.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Try thinking of it this way:
imagine a pie.
The number on the bottom
of the fraction
is how many pieces the pie
has been sliced into.
What kind of pie is it?
Doesn't matter.
But it would help me picture it
if I knew the kind of pie.
Fine, it's banana cream.
I don't like banana cream.
Okay, what kind of pie
would you like it to be?
What about those little
apple pies from McDonalds?
Sure.
I burned my mouth
on one of those.
Didn't stop me. I still ate it.
(doorbell rings, door opens)
Veronica. Hi.
Hey, Georgie.
You-you changed your hair.
I did.
It's shorter.
It is.
I like it.
Thank-thanks.
You here to see me?
I-I'm here for your mom's
Bible study.
Oh, sure, of course.
I'm glad you could join us.
Come in, won't you?
(chuckles)
You're part of the group, too?
Faith, the Bible, God,
I'm nuts for that stuff.
(laughs softly)
So one-fourth
of the 12 pieces of pie is...?
Three?
Yes.
And one-third
of the 12 pieces is...?
Four?
Yes. Now how much is one-third
of the pie plus
one-fourth of the pie?
Well, three plus four is seven,
but there's 12 pieces,
so seven-twelve-iths.
It's twelfths. And yes.
I did it.
ADULT SHELDON:
Actually, I did it.
In less than ten minutes,
I taught fractions to a monkey.
Welcome, Veronica.
We're so glad to have you.
What are you doing?
What's it look like?
I'm here for Bible study.
Did you just take a shower?
No.
(sniffs)
You did, too.
So I want to be clean for Jesus.
Get off my back.
Interesting.
Georgie, if you want
to be a good Christian,
maybe you should stop
lying through your teeth.
Just be happy
I brushed them, okay?
Hmm...
MISSY:
Okay.
All done. Thanks.
While we're here,
would you like me
to introduce you to algebra?
Al who?
Oh, boy.
It's not a person, it's
an ancient Arabic method
of finding the value
of variables.
Oh. Nah.
ADULT SHELDON: Clearly, I needed
a more sophisticated technique
to motivate my simian sister.
Are you sure?
If you learn a little algebra,
I'll give you a banana.
All right, now we're reading
from Matthew 4.
Georgie, why don't you get
us started on verse 17?
Me?
Yes, you.
Oh. Okay.
Um... Verse 17...
(quietly):
Verse 17...
Give me a minute.
Here.
Bless you.
Okay, here we go.
"From that time,
"Jesus began to preach
and say 'Repent,
"c-change your inner self,
your old way of thinking,
"regret past sins,
"live your life in a way
that proves repentance:
seek God's purpose
for your life."
Powerful stuff.
Can I get an amen?
ALL:
Amen.
Need any help there, Sheldon?
I'm looking
for some books
on education theory.
What for?
I'm trying
to develop a technique
to teach someone
who falls into the conventional
category of "stupid."
Oh. Well, now, there's a wide
range of stupid.
Can you narrow it down?
She wrote a fan letter to Alf.
Got it. So you're looking
to make a pretty radical change.
Well, ideally, I'd like to wipe
my sister's brain clean
and start over,
but my mom wouldn't like that.
Yeah. Moms are no fun.
Hey, Veronica.
Georgie.
So, listen,
I was doing my prayers
last night and, uh,
you won't believe it,
but I think God spoke to me.
Really? What did he say?
Well, I couldn't
understand
all of it, 'cause it was in
an ancient language,
but the part I did understand
is he wants us to spend
more time together.
Doing what?
Oh, you know, praying,
helping the needy.
Your usual Christian activities.
Well, I'm okay with that.
Good. So you, me and God,
we'll hang out.
Sounds good.
Okay. See you later.
(chuckles)
See you.
I may be going to hell.
(exhales sharply)
So you're hoping
to create an army
of super-intelligent children
who will do your bidding?
In a perfect world, yes.
You should spend more time
with my mother.
That's her goal, too.
SHELDON: Ooh, this
is interesting.
According to Socrates,
all knowledge exists
within the student
and just needs to be drawn out
through skillful questioning.
Are you saying I knew that
before you even said it?
I don't know, did you?
Well, according
to Socrates, you do know
and the answer's inside you.
Well, then, ask me a skillful
question to draw it out.
Do you know
if I knew before I knew?
No.
Hey, it works.
It does.
(camera beeps, whirs)
I'm recording my findings
so that future generations
of mankind can understand
the steps I took to create
homo novus, "new man."
Of course, there's a strong
likelihood that my homo novi
might've wiped out
all future generations,
so I have no idea
who's watching this.
What are you doing in here?
I'm keeping a video diary of my
experiment to create homo novus.
Homo what?
Novus. It's Latin.
It means "new man."
Oh. I guess that's okay.
Y-Your mom's at church.
W-What do you want for dinner?
I believe you know
what I want for dinner.
Is that right?
It's Thursday.
What does Mom always make me
on Thursdays?
Spaghetti and hot dogs?
Socrates. Got to love him.
CONGREGATION:
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My savior God to Thee ♪
♪ How great Thou art ♪
♪ God to Thee ♪
♪ How great
Thou art ♪
♪ How great Thou art ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My savior God to Thee ♪
♪ How great Thou art ♪
♪ How great Thou art. ♪
PASTOR JEFF:
And now,
why don't we take
a moment to pray,
uh, keeping in mind
that our prayers
should not be
for our own benefit,
but for our family, friends,
fellow Texans, Americans
of all races and religions
and the world.
Well, most of the world.
Y'all know what countries
to pick.
MARY: Lord, please look
after my family.
Give them everything they need
to be happy and healthy.
And this lovely young girl
with me tonight,
help her stay on the path
of righteousness.
VERONICA: God,
please look after my sister.
You can find her at the women's
correctional facility
in Lubbock.
Help her seek salvation in you
instead of cocaine, marijuana
and bass players.
GEORGIE: Jesus, I'm sure,
even from Heaven, you can see
how hot the girl
sitting next to me is.
And I know I'm not supposed
to pray for myself,
but here's the deal:
if you can get her
to fall in love with me,
and you know,
make some bad decisions,
I swear I'll come to church
every Sunday.
MARY: And thank you
for bringing Georgie tonight,
even though you and I
both know why he came.
Speaking of which, whatever
he's praying for right now,
ignore it.
VERONICA: And please protect me
from impure thoughts,
and teach me to respect
the sanctity of my body.
GEORGIE: Now if for instance she
and I were to go skinny dipping
and one thing
were to lead to another
under the moonlit sky,
get this:
not only do I become
a devout Christian,
I will also bug everybody
I meet to do the same.
And you know
I can be real annoying
when I set my mind to it.
MARY:
Amen.
VERONICA:
GEORGIE: I'm gonna take
your silence as a yes. Amen.
What are you working on?
A list of possible boyfriends
for my Cabbage Patch doll.
How do you think Celeste would
look next to Joey Lawrence?
I don't know who that is.
He's Blossom's brother.
It's a show. She wears hats.
Anyway, I've been
doing some research,
and I've come to the conclusion
that I don't need
to teach you anything.
You already know everything.
Cool.
Your brain already
contains all the math
that will ever be known.
I heard you and I said "cool."
Well, wouldn't you
like to explore
that great treasure
trove of knowledge?
That depends. What's a trove?
We'll circle back to that.
True or false?
At times, you have referred
to yourself as being dumb.
True.
And do you enjoy
feeling that way?
No.
Well, let me change that.
I'm presenting you
with an opportunity
to achieve the full potential
of your mind.
Are you gonna do some experiment
where we switch brains?
No.
'Cause I've seen it
on Gilligan's Island
and I've seen it
on The Flintstones
and it never goes well.
(exhales sharply)
Ooh. Gilligan.
♪ Then sings my soul,
my savior God... ♪
Oh, who do you think
you're fooling here?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Listen to me. Veronica has
a rough family situation,
and she's trying
to improve her life.
And I admire that.
Very inspirational.
Georgie,
believe me, I'm glad
to see you in a church,
but I do not want you taking
advantage of that girl.
Taking advantage? Veronica and I
are Bible buddies, nothing more.
I'm serious.
Right.
Maybe you should ask yourself
what's in you
that makes you see sin
in the hearts of others.
Okay, now you're pushing it.
Lord Jesus, please help
my mother with her anger.
Can I get an amen?
No.
Why do we need the camera?
So people in the future can see
your transformation.
(camera beeps)
Where are you going?
To put on a dress
for the future people.
Hello, people of the future.
My name is Missy Cooper and this
is my best friend Celeste.
(whispers):
She's dating Joey Lawrence.
(sighs)
You want to hang out Saturday?
Can't. I signed up
to get baptized.
Oh, yeah. I've been
meaning to do that.
Well, why don't you join me?
We could do it together.
Sure. You and me, getting
double dunked. I like it.
Can you imagine afterwards?
All of our sins
will be washed away.
Yeah, and we can start
cranking out fresh ones.
I just don't know
where I went wrong.
Are you sure your questioning
was skillful?
I thought so, but after
two hours of interrogation,
all I could extract
from my sister's brain
was that there was some sort
of block with new kids on it.
Sheldon, how's your
educational project going?
Poorly. I've hit a wall.
Have you considered B.F.
Skinner's behavior modification?
What's that?
It uses punishment
and reward to get
the results you want.
Ooh, punishment.
I like the sound of that.
(quietly):
In the right context, so do I.
I took a real beating
at the craps table,
and then I won it all back
playing Caribbean Stud Poker.
Well, how does
Caribbean Stud Poker work?
I have no idea.
I was drunk off my ass.
(both laugh)
MARY:
Way to go, Mom.
Way to lead a Christian life.
Oh, does my daughter
think poorly of me?
Yes.
Good. I can die happy.
Hey, Mom, just a heads-up,
I'm getting baptized tomorrow.
Good Lord.
That boy's randiness
knows no bounds.
What are you talking about?
He's only doing it
'cause of that Veronica girl.
Oh, sure. That makes sense.
What do you mean,
it makes sense?
When I was his age,
I hitchhiked to Florida
'cause I had a friend
that had a girlfriend
who knew a girl
who might be willing.
But then you met my daughter
and you didn't have
to travel so far.
(laughs)
(bottles clink)
SHELDON:
According to B.F. Skinner,
if I can find the appropriate
punishment to motivate Missy,
there's no limit to what
she might be able to learn.
But what might
that punishment be?
Whip her with a rubber hose?
No. That sounds like a recipe
for tendonitis.
Administer small
electric shocks?
Tricky.
If I get the voltage wrong, I
could spend the rest of my life
in an institution
for the criminally insane.
Or I inflict harm
on the object she loves
more than life itself.
Celeste, you're about to become
part of scientific history.
All right, everybody,
welcome to the 1990
East Texas Baptist Olympics.
(laughs)
'Cause we're in the pool
of water.
Anyway, I want to welcome
our little sister
Veronica Duncan,
who I will be dunkin'.
(chuckles)
Sorry.
I can't turn it off.
And I also want to welcome
George Cooper,
who has recently found
his way to the Lord.
Howdy. Praise Jesus.
(sighs)
Are you ready to learn
some advanced calculus?
Nope.
Be right back.
Take your time.
Veronica, do you trust
in Jesus Christ
as your personal
Lord and savior?
(laughs softly):
I do.
JEFF: It's upon
your profession of faith
that I baptize you, my sister,
in the name of the Father, the
Son and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
♪ Wade in the water ♪
♪ Wade ♪
♪ In the water, children, wade ♪
♪ In the water ♪
♪ Washing me down,
washing me down ♪
♪ Wade... ♪
Dang.
All right, let's
try this again.
Would you be ready to learn
some advanced calculus
if it saved Celeste's pigtails?
What are you doing?
Put her down.
Not until I modify
your behavior.
In the name of the Father, Son
and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
♪ Drop me in the water... ♪
Sheldon, I'm warning you.
ALL:
Hallelujah!
(laughs)
We did it!
♪ Tease me... ♪
Ooh, I'm so happy.
I love you.
Is it working?
Are you feeling motivated?
Very.
(animal growling)
(Georgie grunts)
(all gasping)
Care to explain yourself?
I was trying
to motivate Missy
to expand her
intellectual horizons.
By torturing
her Cabbage Patch doll?
Well, it's not like I shocked
her with electrodes,
which was an option.
Enough.
To be clear, I meant to
shock Missy, not the doll.
That would be ineffective.
Enough! And you.
Getting baptized just to kiss
a girl? What were you thinking?
Sounds like you know
what I was thinking.
Well, you are both grounded.
I like you because you're
an alien but you're funny,
unlike my brother
who's an alien but just a jerk.
Anyway, I hope you're enjoying
your time here on our planet
and have found things to eat
other than cats.
I recommend chicken nuggets.
Sincerely, Missy Cooper,
age ten.
ALF: "P.S. My favorite color
is pink. What's yours?"
Ha. What a cutie pie.
Hey, hey, Barbara, we got
any more of those pink T-shirts
with my face on them?
I want to send one
to this Missy Cooper kid.
Oh, oh, and get me
some chicken nuggets, huh?
Hello? Anybody out there?
Apparently not.
Barb!