Previously on Young Sheldon...
Veronica.
I-I'm here
for your mom's Bible study.
I'm glad you could join us.
What are you doing?
Come here for Bible study.
If you want to be
a good Christian,
maybe you should stop
lying through your teeth.
Hey, Mom, just a heads-up:
I'm gettin' baptized tomorrow.
We did it!
I'm so happy!
I love you.
(congregation gasps)
Oh!
(George Jr. grunts in pain)
ADULT SHELDON:
There are certain phrases
that are used by dads
around the world.
(Japanese pop song playing)
♪ Well, it's all right... ♪
Close the fridge.
You're wastin' money.
I'm having trouble deciding
between pudding and Jell-O.
Well, decide what you want,
and then open it.
But I need the visual input.
Does the pudding have a skin?
Plus, it's good fun
jiggling the Jell-O.
Do you have any idea
what our electric bill is?
Yes.
I do our taxes.
And it's higher
than it should be.
And why do you think that is?
Well, I don't want
to point any fingers,
but Missy sleeps
with a night-light.
Make a choice
and close the door.
Okay. There's only one
logical way to settle this.
Eenie-meenie...
Close the door!
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
(school bell ringing)
Hey.
(sighs)
What do you want?
I just wanted to
apologize again.
My behavior was crazy.
I blame hormones.
Really?
'Cause I blame you.
Is there any way
you can forgive me?
Please?
Fine. I forgive you.
You're not just saying it
'cause you're trying to be
a good Christian and you're
afraid of going to Hell?
Do you want me
to forgive you or not?
Very much.
Then stop talking
and let's move on.
So... so we're friends again?
Sure.
Just as friends, would
you wanna hang out
on Saturday night?
In a no-kissing
and no-punching-in-
the-face kind of way?
I can't. My boyfriend's
taking me to dinner.
(echoing, distorting):
Boyfriend, boyfriend,
boyfriend...
You know,
I got to run.
I'm glad we're friends again.
Your brother
looks upset.
Really?
I would have
guessed hungry.
See you later.
Mr. Givens,
a moment of your time?
(sighs heavily)
I'm curious about
more cost-effective methods
of generating electricity.
And?
And I came to you. Go.
Well, there's fossil fuels,
like oil and coal.
Too dirty.
Oh. Hydro?
Too wet.
Solar?
With this fair skin? Next.
Wind?
You know what the problem
with wind is.
It's too reliant on wind.
I think I'm looking
for something
a little more indoors.
How about nuclear power?
It's clean and efficient
and very safe,
until something goes
horribly wrong.
That could work.
Oh. Goody.
Are we done?
Almost. I have one last question
about nuclear reactors.
What?
How do I build one? Go.
ADULT SHELDON:
Spoiler alert: he didn't know.
Hello?
Hello, my little vicuña.
(Meemaw chuckles)
Well, hello to you, too.
And more importantly,
what is a vicuña?
Only what I feel is the cutest
camelid on the planet.
Well, I suppose I could ask you
what a camelid is,
but you're just gonna say
more words that I don't know.
What's up?
There's an upcoming event
at the university,
and I'd like you to be
my plus-one.
Oh. Well, I'd love to go.
Wonderful! It's a date. Bye.
Wait, wait.
Hang on there, partner. I need
a little more information.
When is this event?
This Friday night.
Oh. What time?
I'm not sure.
Well, will there be food?
I have no idea.
What's the dress code?
Not a clue.
Well, what do you know?
You're my plus-one.
Well, you go do a little more
research and get back to me.
You got it!
Bye.
Wait.
What?
Love you!
Love you, too.
(chuckles)
Hello. Is this the studio that
makes the Professor Proton show?
Excellent.
May I speak to him, please?
Well, then I'd like
to leave him a message.
My name is Sheldon Cooper,
and I'm trying to build
a nuclear reactor,
and I could use his help.
My number is 409-356-6049.
Thank you.
I'm gonna hang up now,
because this is long-distance,
and my father
doesn't make much money.
Good-bye.
(door opens)
Georgie, question:
In the hallway
earlier today,
were you upset or hungry?
Shut up.
That's hungry.
STURGIS:
Connie, I believe
I have answers
to all your questions.
Lay it on me.
Time: the event begins
at 6:00 p.m.
The dress code is:
business attire.
Dinner will be served,
but it's been suggested
that we eat first,
because the food is dreadful.
Good to know.
And last but not least,
a camelid is any member
of the camelidae family,
such as llamas,
alpacas or vicuñas.
You didn't ask that one,
but, uh, it seemed like
something you should know.
John...
is everybody at this party
gonna be a scientist like you?
Not everybody.
You'll be there.
That's kind of
what I'm gettin' at.
Is there a problem?
Well...
yeah.
I didn't go to college.
I was a total screwup
in high school.
I might not fit in at all.
Don't be silly.
Everyone's gonna love you!
And I'm excited
to show you off.
The general consensus among
the faculty is you don't exist.
Well, I don't know
how I feel about that.
Oh, don't worry-- it says more
about me than it does about you.
-(chuckles)
-(doorbell rings)
I'll get it.
It's like dating
the Encyclopedia Britannica.
Oh, hello, Sheldon.
Good evening.
Do you have any idea
where I could obtain
radioactive material?
That's an interesting question.
What do you need it for?
I'm trying to build
a small nuclear reactor
to provide electricity
for my house.
And possibly
the whole neighborhood,
if they're nice to me.
Fun.
The problem is,
I don't know
where to get the necessary
radioactive material.
Oh. Do you happen to have
any unexploded atomic bombs?
Not a one.
Shoot.
What about an X-ray machine?
Nope.
That makes sense.
You're just a kid.
Oh! I know!
Smoke detectors
contain trace amounts
of americium-241.
Interesting.
But I'd need a lot of them,
and they're expensive.
True.
Hey, I bet if you
call a few companies
and say it's for
a school project,
you could get them for free.
That's a great idea. Thanks.
You're very welcome.
What a cute kid.
Who was that at the door?
Sheldon.
What did he want?
Oh, nothing.
He just had a science query.
Ooh, biscuits!
Where's Georgie?
I don't know.
I called him ten minutes ago.
He's probably
curled up in a ball,
crying about
Veronica.
Why do you say that?
It's just what I'm hearing.
From who?
I'm kinda plugged
into this town.
I'll go check on him.
Where exactly you getting
all this info?
There's a lot of kid
sisters out there.
We talk.
Honey?
Can I come in?
GEORGE JR.:
No.
Aw, baby,
everything all right?
I don't want to talk about it.
You might feel
better if you do.
Is it about a girl?
How do you know?
Sometimes a mother
can sense these things.
Veronica has a boyfriend.
You mean Dustin?
You know him?
Well, yeah, she met him
through the church.
Lovely young man.
You like him?
Oh. Well, um...
the Lord teaches us
to like everybody.
I just can't stop thinking
about her with another guy,
and it's making me crazy.
Aw. Why don't you come eat
something?
You'll feel better.
I can't.
I feel like I got punched
in the stomach.
Trust me,
this'll pass.
You will meet other girls.
They won't be Veronica.
Is he taller than me?
It doesn't matter.
It's what's inside a person
that counts.
How much taller?
A lot.
Mrs. Sparks' credit card
got declined at Payless.
No kidding.
She went nuts.
But you didn't hear it from me.
Mm.
Poor baby is just crushed.
Oh, man.
I've been through that.
Brutal.
When did I break your heart?
Oh, it wasn't you.
Then who was it?
Oh, doesn't matter.
It was a long time ago.
But who?
Dad, I don't want
to get ahead of myself,
but I think I solved
our electricity problem.
Not now, Sheldon.
I wouldn't mind hearing it.
Who?
If you want,
I'll ask around.
ADULT SHELDON:
For many children,
their happiest memory
is the day they learned
to ride a bike.
For others, it's when they got
their first puppy.
For me, it was the day
I received a box
of 57 defective
smoke detectors loaded
with americium-241.
Yes!
(laughing)
GEORGE JR.:
My dearest Veronica... No.
My beloved Veronica...
Better. It's got "love" in it.
Every minute I'm away from you
is an eternity.
But it feels longer than that.
I can't eat, I can't sleep,
it's like there's a hole
in my heart
that only your love can fill.
So true.
And yes, I know about Dustin,
but he can't love you
the way I do.
Because my love
is the kind of love
that is true love.
The kind that lovers feel
when they're in love.
Beautiful.
So in conclusion, I hope,
no, I pray,
I hope and pray
that you'll give me the chance
to be the boyfriend
you deserve.
And when the time is right,
I'm able to shower you
with diamonds, houses,
boats, and cars,
the husband of your dreams.
Loving you with my heart,
my soul,
and my lips,
Georgie Cooper.
Just tell me her name.
It's not important.
It was a long time ago.
Then how come I don't know
about it?
Because I married you,
and no one else matters.
If that's so,
why'd this mystery woman
break your heart?
(sighs, chuckles):
Come on, Mare.
We were young.
We were kids.
Leave it alone.
Just tell me her name,
and I'll drop it forever.
You swear?
You know I don't swear.
You promise?
Absolutely.
Kathryn Dempsey.
Kathryn Dempsey?!
You watched me make cupcakes
for her daughter's birthday,
and you never told me
you were in love with her?!
I was 15 years old,
and she didn't love me back.
If she did,
would you have married
her instead of me?
But she didn't!
Okay!
Now I have my answer.
Kathryn Dempsey?!
I was 15!
(footsteps approaching)
Hey, Sheldon.
Hello, Billy.
What you doing?
Building a nuclear reactor.
Cool. I'm having Lucky Charms
for dinner.
What are you gonna do with it
when you're done?
Stand in front of the
refrigerator as long as I want.
Cool.
Why are you eating
cereal for dinner?
I was hungry,
and my parents
are in their bedroom kissing.
♪ Two, three, four ♪
("Born to Be My Baby"
by Bon Jovi playing)
(Bon Jovi vocalizing)
♪ You were born to be my baby ♪
♪ And, baby,
I was made to be your man ♪
♪ We got something
to believe in ♪
♪ Even if we don't know
where we stand ♪
♪ Only God would know ♪
Hey, pal.
♪ The reasons, but... ♪
What's this,
a love note?
Give that back!
(chuckles): Oh,
I don't think so.
"To my beloved Veronica,
"Every minute I'm away
from you is an eternity.
"But it feels longer
than that.
(students chuckling)
"I can't eat,
I can't sleep,
"it feels like there's a hole
in my heart that only you
can fill..."
♪ ♪
(indistinct chatter)
Champagne?
Oh, I'm fine, thank you.
These are for me.
Are-are you all right?
No, I'm very nervous.
That's interesting.
Normally, I'm the one
who's unsure of himself
in a social situation,
but tonight, it's you.
(chuckles) Yeah.
Frickin' fascinating.
Dr. Sturgis,
good to see you.
Dr. Linkletter.
Please meet
my girlfriend,
Connie Tucker.
Nice to meet you, Dr. Tucker.
I'm not a doctor.
But I would like
to point out,
she's quite real.
I can see that.
And our
relationship
is more
than just friends.
That's enough.
In fact,
it's flat-out erotic.
Change the subject, John.
You got it,
girlfriend.
Dr. Linkletter
is working
on an intriguing theory
of quantum gravity.
Is that so?
He can explain it
much better than I can.
Are you familiar
at all
with string theory?
Remind me.
Well, basically, it's a string
theoretic interpretation
of the graviton.
Every force is an exchange
of particles.
Gravity is the exchange
of gravitons.
Meemaw, are you even listening?
MEEMAW:
What?
The graviton
is a massless string.
The graviton is
a massless string.
Wow!
Well, yes, it is.
(chuckles)
When did
you learn that?
I get around.
In fact,
I would go so far as to say
that every force is an exchange
of particles,
and gravity is
an exchange of gravitons.
Correct!
Yes!
(laughs)
John, where have you
been hiding her?
I haven't.
I've talked about her
quite a bit,
but you all said she was
a figment of my imagination.
(chuckles)
She's dynamite.
(Linkletter and Sturgis laugh)
Hello. I'd like to speak
to Arthur Jeffries.
He plays Professor Proton.
But you probably know that,
since you answer the phone
at the station
that makes the show,
you lucky duck.
Then I'd like to leave him
another message.
Please tell him Sheldon Cooper
called again
and that
I've successfully obtained
the radioactive material
that I'm looking for.
Yes, americium-241.
I have lots of it.
I live at 5501 Grant Avenue,
Medford, Texas.
If you're sending me
an autographed picture,
I already have one.
Ooh, how about one
of his bow ties?
And then Bryan Larkin
read the letter
out loud in the hall.
No.
Georgie used the word "love,"
like, 30 times.
It was pathetic.
That hurts to hear.
Really? I think it's hilarious.
Also, my math teacher's
pregnant.
Well, that's nice.
(quietly):
It might not be her husband's.
Whose do you think it is?
Hey.
Going somewhere?
Alaska.
Gonna work on the pipeline.
Alaska, huh?
That-That's pretty far.
Not far enough,
but it'll have to do.
Look, Georgie,
I know it feels bad
right now, but...
I promise it'll get better.
How's it gonna get better?
Veronica thinks I'm a jerk,
and everyone in the school's
calling me Lovey Cooper.
Ooh, that is not a good name.
It doesn't matter, 'cause I'm
never going back to that school.
Listen to me.
Hey.
You're a good-looking kid,
and you got a big heart.
Once we get you
on a daily shower schedule,
the girls
are gonna be lining up.
I don't want girls.
I want Veronica.
Yeah, maybe you'll get her
and maybe you won't.
But someday,
you'll find the woman
who was really meant for you.
You mean like
Kathryn Dempsey?
Alaska's beautiful.
How 'bout I go with you?
Who's Kathryn Dempsey?
I was 15 years--
I was 15 years old!
(Meemaw and Sturgis laugh)
Connie, tell me,
did you grow up in Texas?
Took my first bath
in a ten-gallon hat. (laughs)
(laughs)
That's wonderful.
My goodness, you're as funny
as you are beautiful.
(stammers) That's
a nice thing to say
to your friend's
girlfriend.
STURGIS: Actually,
I don't think
it is so nice.
If I didn't know any better,
I'd say you were sweet-talking
my date right in front of me.
You're a pretty smart man, John.
Trust your gut.
Oh, look!
Shrimp cocktail.
Let's get some.
Now, hang on.
Hey. Take your hand off her,
or there are gonna be
some severe consequences.
Whoa, John, calm down.
What do you see in this guy?
All right, that's it!
(grunts)
(gasps)
Oh, boy,
you shouldn't have done that.
(shouts)
Oh!
(gasping)
That's enough!
Both of you,
just cool your jets.
This isn't over,
Dr. Linkletter!
Anytime, anyplace,
Dr. Sturgis.
And your graviton
research
is mediocre at best!
(guests gasping)
Keep moving.
Are you angry with me?
More turned on.
Ooh. Great. Let's go.
Good morning, Mary.
Hmm.
(sighs, grunts)
What's that about?
I'm punishing him.
What for?
Nothing, really.
But once I got started,
I couldn't stop.
(laughs)
(doorbell rings)
GEORGE SR.:
I'll get it!
(filtered breathing)
The hell?
Sheldon Cooper live here?
(Geiger counters clicking)
Mare!
(garage door clacking)
(indistinct radio chatter)
Am I in trouble?