ADULT SHELDON:
I'd like to tell you a story
about a time I was right.
Now, I'm sure you're thinking,
"But, Sheldon,
you're never wrong."
And you'd be right.
But it's worth taking
a closer look
at this particular incident.
Because it began
with a loaf of bread,
and ended with me and my family
almost being kicked out of
the United States of America.
Uh-oh.
What's the matter?
Something's wrong
with my sandwich.
Did it go bad?
No. It just tastes... different.
If you don't want it,
I'll trade you for my dumplings.
I'm already unhappy.
Do you really think dumplings
will fix the problem?
It'll fix my problem.
I'm sick of dumplings.
(phone rings)
Mary Cooper,
how may I bless you?
SHELDON:
Hello, Mom?
Sheldon? Everything okay?
No.
What's wrong?
What happened?
My sandwich tastes different.
(sighs) You know you're not
supposed to call
unless it's an emergency.
I'm well aware.
So what did you change?
I didn't change anything.
Same bread, same peanut butter,
same jelly.
Did you use one knife
for the PB and the J?
No.
Are you sure?
That was one time two years ago,
and all the other knives
were dirty.
It was 14 months
and 11 days ago.
When we made the big switch
from Wonder Bread.
Oh, how could I forget?
Sheldon, I didn't
change anything.
Can I get back to work now?
I suppose so.
Thank you. Bye.
Don't I get an "I love you"?
I love you.
One more time,
with a little more energy.
(phone hangs up,
dial tone sounds)
Must've been disconnected.
Well, my mother didn't do
anything differently.
Are you gonna eat it?
Better. I'm going
to do science on it.
(sighs)
I would eat it.
Are the goggles necessary?
No, but they really
set the mood.
Okay, subject "A," jelly.
That's definitely strawberry
and definitely Smuckers.
Subject "B."
That's Jif all right.
Creamy and delicious.
It must be the bread.
Hold on. This is a
scientific experiment.
We can't make
assumptions.
Subject "C."
It's the bread.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Welcome to the family, Hacksaw.
(sniffles)
Hey.
Oh. Hey, Georgie.
You okay?
Mm-hmm.
You sure?
Not really.
Um... Dustin broke up with me.
What?
He said I was immature.
(sniffs)
Is he crazy?
Everything about you
screams womanhood.
See?
Happy Hearth Home Bakeries,
just like always.
Well, something is rotten
in the state of Denmark.
What?
That's Shakespeare, Mom.
Great.
Missy, did your sandwich
taste different today?
Couldn't tell you.
I traded it for a Ding Dong.
Your sandwich is exactly
the same, Sheldon.
What's going on?
This bread is different.
Let me see.
You know, he
might be right.
Ow.
Shelly, it's probably
just your taste buds
changing as you get older.
But I don't like change.
Then you're gonna
hate puberty.
Got me with your ring.
She wasn't wrong.
Studies do support
that your sense of taste
changes over time.
So the bread's the same
and you're different?
Apparently so.
Nope, it's the bread.
(school bell rings)
Hey.
Hi.
I was wondering if you wanted
to grab a bite to eat
at the Waffle House?
Not like a date.
But as someone who recently
had his heart broke,
I think I could help.
Who broke your heart?
I love you.
(others gasping)
Ooh!
You did.
Oh. Yeah.
I'm just saying,
I know what
you're going through.
So if you need a friend with
a pocket full of waffle money...
(chuckles)
(woman speaks indistinctly
over P.A.)
TAM:
Look at these prices.
No wonder supermarkets
are running my parents
out of business.
Your parents own
a convenience store.
They charge extra
for the convenience.
How is this not convenient?
Excuse me, sir.
Has anything changed
with the bread
from the Happy Hearth
Home Bakeries?
I have no idea.
How can you not know?
You work here.
What do you want from me?
I get $3.35 an hour
to stock shelves.
Are you kidding?
My father pays me
five dollars a week.
I bet they're violating
child labor laws.
Look. This loaf says
"A subsidiary of the Domestic
Food Corporation."
This older loaf doesn't.
I wonder if I can take
my parents to court?
(sniffs)
It smells like my bread.
Or I could start a labor union
with my sisters.
This is it!
This is my bread!
We could go on strike.
Bring them to their knees.
SHELDON:
Vindication!
(phone rings)
Happy Hearth Home Bakeries,
this is Pete.
How can I help you?
Hello, Pete.
My name is Sheldon Cooper,
and I would like to know
what changed
in your white sandwich loaf
to make it taste different?
Sheldon, hang up the phone.
It's dinner time.
Be right there, Mom. I'm doing
battle with corporate America.
I'm sorry, Pete.
You were saying?
Any chance your bread was past
the expiration date?
No, it was brand-new.
But I did a taste comparison
after it was bought out by
the Domestic Food Corporation,
and they are definitely
not the same.
Well, I can assure you that,
"the recent acquisition
"by the Domestic Food
Corporation has not affected
"the quality of our products
in any way.
"Every single bread, baked good,
and pastry
is made with love.
From our hearth to your home."
Then why does it taste
different, Pete? Why?
Well, because
now we make everything
really cheap and fast. Bye.
I thought Dustin
was different.
I thought he wanted to live
a Christian life like me.
But... all he wanted
is what every guy wants.
(scoffs)
Guys.
Oh, please, you're
all the same.
Hey. You rejected me,
you punched me in the face,
and I'm still here.
Happy eating waffles with you.
Georgie, do you really think
you're capable
of just being my friend?
That's a good question.
My brain says yes.
What about the rest of you?
Honestly, I wouldn't trust it.
(laughs)
Excuse me. Would you
like to sign my petition
against Happy Hearth
Home Bakeries?
Maybe on the way out.
Excuse me. Would you like
to sign my petition
against Happy Hearth
Home Bakeries?
Oh. Maybe on the way out.
I hate to say it.
But everybody's way out
is at the other
set of doors.
I have noticed.
Why do you think that is?
Cowards. The whole
bunch of 'em.
Mr. Givens!
(sighs)
Hello, Sheldon.
Meemaw, this is my science
teacher, Mr. Givens.
Nice to meet ya.
Hi.
This is strange,
I never think of you
as existing outside
of school.
Well, it turns out I do.
And you're here
buying food.
I am.
Fascinating.
All right.
Well, I'll see you on Monday.
Wait.
Would you like
to sign my petition
against Happy Hearth
Home Bakeries?
Well, what have they done?
They're making their bread
faster and cheaper
to save money.
That's terrible.
It is. Would you like to sign?
I would.
Excellent.
I'll get you on the way out.
Thank you.
Well, that's one.
Yeah.
GEORGE JR.:
I know it's tough,
but you gotta be strong.
And remember,
you're not alone.
Hello?
Kinda busy.
Well, there's only one bathroom
in the house, Georgie,
and it's not
for phone calls.
I got to call you back.
Sorry.
Who you talking to?
That Veronica girl?
Yeah.
What's going on with that?
Nothing. We're
just friends.
Okay. You ever want to run
any of this stuff by me,
I'm here for you.
Why would I want
to run it by you?
Well, I was once
a 15-year-old boy.
I know what it's like to have
strong feelings for a girl.
Gross. I'm not gonna
talk to you about this.
I-I saw that kid
on Who's the Boss
talk to Tony Danza
about his problems.
They're not related.
This is totally different.
Damn it, Georgie, you could
flush once in a while.
(toilet flushes)
On behalf of
sandwich-loving children
everywhere, I thank you.
How many is that?
13.
A baker's dozen.
What do you say we
pack up and head
outta here?
No, we have to wait
for Channel 7 news.
Channel 7?
Yes. I called them this morning
and told them
there was a human interest story
at the supermarket.
What story?
Classic Americana.
Little guy
versus corporate greed.
Honey, Channel 7
is not coming.
(horn honks)
You Sheldon Cooper?
Yes, ma'am.
You got to be kidding me.
How's my hair look?
Hey, how'd it go?
Great.
Turn to Channel 7.
But I'm watching
the game.
But I'm going
to be on Channel 7.
What's he talking about?
He's gonna be on Channel 7.
SHELDON (on TV):
I was shocked to learn
that the Happy Hearth Home
Bakeries had been bought out
by the Domestic
Food Corporation,
and they started making
their bread faster and cheaper.
And you don't
like that, do you?
No.
REPORTER:
And you're collecting signatures
to make them stop.
I am.
Corporations
shouldn't be allowed to make
these decisions on their own.
REPORTER:
Well, who should?
The people who eat the bread.
This wouldn't happen if there
were centralized control
over all these big corporations.
REPORTER:
Are you suggesting
a communist form of government
in Texas?
I suppose I am.
MEEMAW:
Hang on a sec...
There you have it.
Local boy Sheldon Cooper
says communism
is what Texas needs.
Oh, dear God.
I just... You...
Why... I-I-I-I-I...
Why would you...
What were you th...
Oh, God.
MARY:
Calm down.
It was just the 4:00 news.
I'm sure no one saw it.
I hope a lot of people saw it
and Happy Hearth is forced
to give our country
good bread again.
No! No more bread.
No more country.
No more talking.
Excuse me.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go put up an American
flag in front of my house.
That's a great idea.
Mare, where's our flag?
Uh, uh, it's in the garage.
Is something wrong?
Yes, Sheldon,
something is wrong.
(doorbell rings)
Oh, now what?
Is anybody going to fill me in?
Not a good time, Brenda.
I don't want your boy playing
with my boy anymore.
Excuse me?
(phone ringing)
Someone get that!
I just saw Sheldon on the news.
He doesn't need to be filling
Billy's head
with crazy commie ideas.
Crazier than sitting on an egg
and trying to hatch it?
'Cause I saw your precious son
do that the other day.
Oh, so you're spying on us.
Good to know.
(grunts)
Yes, I do understand we're
in the middle of a cold war.
But have you seen
how many people wait in
line for bread in Moscow?
It stands to reason their
bread must be great.
Who you talking to?
A reporter from Time magazine.
No!
He didn't mean it.
God bless America.
(exhales)
Traitors.
Yeah, go back to Russia.
Go back?
I've never been there
in the first place.
Well, have a great
day, Georgie.
A great day?
Are you out of your mind?
Our lives are over.
Well, you'll never have a
great day with that attitude.
♪ You're a grand old flag ♪
♪ You're a high-flying flag ♪
♪ And forever in peace
may you wave ♪
♪ You're the emblem of
the land I love ♪
♪ The home of the free
and the... ♪
Look, you made my mom's note.
"Don't talk to Sheldon. Mom."
That's fine. I usually do
most of the talking.
Yes, you do.
♪ My country, 'tis of thee ♪
♪ Sweet land of liberty ♪
♪ Of thee I sing ♪
♪ Land where our fathers died,
la... ♪
Sing along.
♪ Land of the pilgrims'
pride... ♪
(indistinct chatter)
Mind if I sit?
Y-You sure
you want to be seen with me?
Oh, please.
You're not a commie.
Everyone else seems
to think I am.
Do you even know
what a communist is?
Yeah. It's the big blond guy
Rocky fights in Rocky IV.
And he also fights
them when he's Rambo.
(chuckles) That's it?
Well,
I know in every movie it looks
like the commies are gonna win,
but they don't.
(laughs)
You ever seen any Rocky movies?
Um, I saw Rocky II.
That's the second one.
♪ Oh, say, does
that star-spangled banner ♪
♪ Yet wave... ♪
Hey, you wanted to see me?
Have a seat.
(sighs)
Guess what I've been getting
a lot of calls about today.
I know it looks bad,
but we're handling it.
It-It'll all blow over.
I'm sorry, George,
but I can't have
a suspected communist
coaching our boys.
(chuckles):
Whoa, Tom. I'm not...
I love my country.
This is just Sheldon
getting bent out of shape
over a loaf of bread.
Well, this bread better be worth
you losing your job.
Now, hang on. G-Give
me a chance to fix it.
Please.
(sighs)
All right, George.
But if I hear
from one more angry parent...
Thank you. Thank you.
(phone rings)
He's not here.
Mary, you understand
these people are atheists.
I get it. They're not my people.
You're my people.
Then what's this all about?
My son just wanted
a better sandwich.
Why is this so hard
for y'all to understand?!
♪ From the mountains ♪
♪ To the prairies ♪
♪ To the oceans
white with foam ♪
♪ God bless America ♪
♪ Our home sweet home... ♪
Pinko!
Screw you!
♪ God bless America... ♪
MAN:
Three, two...
Thanks for having me on.
You're welcome.
Now, I understand
you wanted to set
the record straight
regarding your
son's communism.
Yes. N-No!
He's not a communist.
He's ten years old.
Listen,
I fought for this country.
I love this country.
My kids love this country.
Isn't that right, Sheldon?
Yes.
Although, in all fairness,
the Social Security system
is a form of...
You love this country!
I love this country.
I have something important
that I'd like to say.
These last few days,
I've been giving
the new Happy Hearth bread
another chance,
and I've decided
it's not so bad.
Also, it toasts well.
So, I'm going to say
that's a sign of personal
growth on my part.
In fact, let's call it maturity.
Still not talking to me, huh?
Well...
I'll check back in tomorrow.