("Girls Just Want to Have Fun"
by Cyndi Lauper playing)
ADULT SHELDON:
It's typical for young people
to admire rock stars.
For my sister,
it was Cyndi Lauper.
("Livin' On A Prayer"
by Bon Jovi playing)
For my brother,
it was Bon Jovi.
Well, Jon, we look good.
♪ Oh, we're livin' on... ♪
(classical violin playing)
For me, the rock star
I admired most was...
Albert Einstein.
♪ ♪
Did you know Einstein
loved playing the violin?
So?
He believed music
helped him formulate
his theories.
So?
Einstein was arguably
the greatest
scientific mind
of the 20th century.
If music helped him,
maybe it could help me.
So?
I got to go talk to my mom.
Everything okay?
Yeah,
she's just got some problems
she's dealing with.
Kind of personal.
Will you make the kids lunch?
Ah, do I have to?
George?
Happy to.
Be right back.
(sighs)
What do y'all want for lunch?
Peanut butter and jelly, please.
Great. Missy?
Tuna salad on rye toast,
with sliced pickles and...
Two PBJs, got it.
What is going on?
Well...
Well, what?
I'm trying to say it.
You woke me up.
Spill it or I'm going
back to bed.
I'm pregnant.
I'm awake now.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
Are you sure?
Yes. I'm late.
How late?
Two days.
Oh, two days.
That's nothing.
Last time I was two days late,
I had the twins.
I had menopause.
(chuckles)
Just trying to lighten the mood.
So do you have...
reason to think
that you might be?
Well, we try to be safe, but...
you know, heat of the moment.
Still? After three kids
and that beer belly
hanging over his pants?
Mom?
I think you might be getting way
ahead of yourself.
I'm telling you, I just know.
You were also convinced that
Georgie was gonna be a girl.
That's true.
Although he does have
very pretty hair.
Hello.
Hi, Sheldon.
I'd like to learn to play
the violin.
Really?
Well, that's terrific.
Do you have any experience
with stringed instruments?
Stringed instruments, no.
String theory, yes.
That was a joke.
I'm a joker.
I think I have an old violin
you can take home
and get the feel of.
That's great.
Thank you.
But I have to warn you,
it can be a frustrating
instrument to learn.
Can you play it?
Yes.
I'll be fine.
(country music playing
over speakers)
I don't see them.
Excuse me.
Where do you keep
your pregnancy tests?
Mom.
Behind the counter
at the pharmacy.
Thank you.
Would you please be
a little more discreet?
She doesn't know it's for you.
Well, it sure
isn't for you.
Come on.
Ow. (gasps) No.
Well, go ahead.
I can't.
Why not?
His daughter goes
to Missy's school.
You are being
ridiculous.
I don't need the world
knowing my business.
Okay, fine.
Hello!
Oh!
Excuse me.
Hi, can I help you?
Yes.
Uh, I need a...
pregnancy test.
NELSON:
Sure.
We have a few options.
Hey, Connie.
Oh, hey, Brenda.
Oh, you-you pick.
Is that a pregnancy test?
Uh, yeah.
(quietly):
It's for me.
Really?
Yes.
I come from a long line
of really fertile women.
My mother had me
when she was 57.
Can you believe it?
I don't think I can.
MEEMAW:
Dr. Sturgis and I
have been dating
for some time and we
really try to be careful,
but you know how it is.
Heat of the moment.
BILLY:
Hi, Mrs. Cooper!
(whispers):
Hi, Billy.
Are you playing
hide-and-seek?
Um, yeah.
Don't tell anybody. Shh.
Bye, Mrs. Cooper!
Oh!
Thank you so much. Bye.
Wish me luck.
It's a bit worn.
But it's fine for a beginner.
(violin screeching)
That was unpleasant.
It just takes some practice.
Very well. When is
my first lesson?
I'm... pretty busy
right now.
But I can give you
this in the meantime.
Anyone Can Play Violin.
They don't set the
bar very high.
MEEMAW:
You know what you need to do?
MARY:
Yes.
How's it going?
MARY:
It'd be a lot easier to pee
if you'd stop talking.
Sorry.
(exhales)
Now it's too quiet.
Say something.
I know you didn't expect this,
and you still might not be,
but...
but if it turns out you are...
I'm here for you.
Thanks, Mom.
(toilet flushes)
You're not the one
I'm worried about.
If I'm pregnant,
George is gonna flip out.
I'm sure he would at first.
Then he would
calm down.
Take a few beers.
Maybe some malt liquor.
I suppose.
(sighs) The truth is,
he and I were both
freaked out
about having twins.
But now I can't imagine
life without them.
Well, see,
there you are.
So, no matter what
that test says,
you're gonna be okay.
You're right.
What's it say?
(sighs)
I'm gonna go
buy that malt liquor.
To get started,
place your violin
in rest position.
Your feet should be together.
Your right arm
should be
over your instrument,
not touching the strings
or the bridge.
Put your left hand...
What are you doing?
What does it look like?
Like you're looking for another
excuse for kids to pick on you.
Now, you are ready
to position your feet.
Zip your feet open
and step forward
with your left foot.
Your feet should...
What are you doing?
I was gonna watch DuckTales,
but this looks funnier.
...procedure for positioning
the violin on your shoulder.
Hold your violin
above the left foot
with the neck
of the instrument pointing up.
Left foot, neck up.
Now rotate the neck
of the instrument
counterclockwise,
so that the neck points
at your left foot.
Oh, boy.
I was right.
Bend your left elbow
so that the violin
rests on your shoulder
and place your head
on the chin rest.
Now try dropping your left hand.
See if you can
hold your instrument
without your hands.
Time yourself at this...
What's going on?
(mumbles):
I'm learning to play the violin.
It's my new favorite show.
Once you feel you have control
of your instrument,
try moving your hands around.
(laughing)
Repeat this procedure
until you can position
your instrument
comfortably and quickly.
He'll just be
another minute.
Thank you.
What's that about?
Oh...
just trying not
to breathe the smoke in.
(chuckles)
Come on.
It already went through
the filter and my lungs.
This stuff is squeaky clean.
(coughs)
Well, still.
He's all yours,
your highness.
(muffled):
All right.
(coughs)
Hey, Mare, what's up?
Other than the big guy. (laughs)
God joke.
Actually, um,
I could use some guidance.
I got some news today,
and I'm not quite sure
how I feel about it.
Of course. Sit.
Well... I am...
um...
with child.
That's wonderful!
Congratulations!
How far along are you?
Uh, could you keep it down
just a little?
I haven't exactly
told George yet.
Got it. And why not?
It is his, right?
Of course.
Apologies.
Hey, I'm a pastor
in a small town.
You wouldn't believe
the juicy things I hear.
This just wasn't
part of our plan.
Well, luckily...
it's part of God's plan.
And let me tell you
about another Mary
who didn't know how to tell
her husband she was expecting.
And her story is way weirder
than yours. (chuckles)
In order to practice this,
move your bow
in a counterclockwise direction.
Keep your hand moving right
with the tip of the bow.
For our next song,
"Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star,"
remember, posture
is our most important thing.
Set, play.
(violin screeching)
(violin playing over TV)
Did you hear that?
I did it!
I don't think you did.
And now we see how
it helps my science.
Hmm.
Hmm...
(groans)
Come on, think.
Probably needs more
"Twinkle, Twinkle."
INSTRUCTOR: ...for
learning new songs.
You can play them
along with me.
(violin screeching)
(screeching continues)
What the hell is that?
Sheldon's learning
to play the violin.
Oh. Well, that's
unfortunate.
Mm-hmm.
I'm gonna go change.
Hey, Dad. Can you believe
I only started playing today?
I really can.
(screeching continues)
Hey, so there's something
I've been meaning
to talk to you about.
Sure, what's up?
Now, before I say it, um,
I want to tell you a story
of another Mary.
Um...
(clears throat)
Okay, anytime...
GEORGE SR.:
Are you kidding me?
Keep your voice down.
(whispers):
Are you kidding me?
Look, I was a little thrown,
too, but Pastor Jeff said...
Pastor Jeff?
Pastor Jeff knows before me?
Well, yeah, I needed
someone to talk to,
and, you know, my mom...
Your mom?
Shh!
Does the whole damn town know?
No. Just my mom and Pastor Jeff.
And maybe Brenda Sparks.
Probably Peg...
and whoever she told,
but that is it.
Oh, is that it?
(knocking on door)
SHELDON: Great news!
Not a good time,
Sheldon.
(knocking on door)
SHELDON: But it's
really important.
Ugh.
I figured out why the violin
worked for Einstein
and not for me.
I need to become
a Jewish person.
MARY: Sheldon, dinner!
SHELDON: Coming.
Sorry I'm late.
Shalom.
(sighs)
What's on your head?
A yarmulke.
A yama-what?
It's a special Jewish hat.
It reminds the wearer
that God is always over you.
(laughing)
Mom.
Oh, come on, it's funny.
It's not funny
and it's not a yarmulke.
It is a coaster I crocheted
at Bible camp.
Are you gonna say
something to him?
Normally I would, but I got
bigger problems right now.
Let's just say grace.
SHELDON: Hold on.
Are these
hot dogs kosher?
(laughing, snorts)
(violin screeching)
ADULT SHELDON:
Over the next few days,
I continued to play the violin
in an effort to replicate
the mental prowess of Einstein.
I was asked to confine
my practice to the garage
by my father, mother,
sister and brother.
Meemaw was fine with me
practicing in the house,
but why would she care?
She doesn't live with us.
Hey, George.
Hey, Herschel.
Let me guess,
you're here to complain
about Sheldon's violin playing.
Under normal circumstances,
I'd say yeah,
but since he started,
my chickens been
dropping eggs like crazy.
That's weird.
Hey, uh,
I hear congratulations
are in order.
What's that you hear?
Maybe I didn't hear it.
Never mind.
It's all right.
Seems like everybody knows.
You don't seem
terribly enthusiastic.
(sighs)
It's the money, Herschel.
It's all about the money.
(sighs) Well, there's only one
solution to that.
Which is?
You got to make more money.
Thank you.
Welcome.
Hey, I got to ask,
did that fiddle playing
increase the fertility
in all the females
around here or just
my chickens? (chuckles)
I was just throwing it
out there, never mind.
Wait here, I'm-a go
get you some eggs.
That's okay.
You're getting eggs.
Guess I'm getting eggs.
PETERSEN:
All right, George,
what's so damn important?
Well...
I don't want to get into
the why's and wherefore's,
but I'm gonna
need a raise.
Is this 'cause Mary's pregnant?
You got to be kidding me.
Does everybody in this damn town
know my business?
I just-- it was taking a guess.
Tom.
My wife told me.
Doesn't matter. What do you say?
Are you threatening to quit
if you don't get it?
No, Tom, I'm threatening
to rob a bank.
Okay.
All right, well,
let's not do that.
$100 a week do the trick?
Yes. Thanks. Bye.
(line ringing)
RECEPTIONIST (over phone):
Temple Judea,
how can I help you?
Hello, I'd like
to become Jewish.
Who would be in charge of that?
How old are you?
I'm ten.
Please hold.
("Hava Nagila" hold music plays)
RABBI: Hello, this is
Rabbi Schneiderman.
To whom am I speaking?
Hello, this is Sheldon Cooper.
Hello, Sheldon.
Um, how can I help you?
I'm currently a Baptist and
I'd like to convert to Judaism.
A Baptist named Sheldon.
Okay.
And why do you want to convert?
Very simple. It's my intention
to become a great scientist
and I couldn't help but notice
most of the great scientists
are Jewish, so logic dictates
it's time to switch teams.
Well, I'm sure there are
many Baptist scientists
you could emulate.
That's kind of you to say,
but other than Cornelis Drebbel
in the 1500s,
it's pretty slim pickings.
(chuckles)
Well, Sheldon, you sound like
a very smart young man.
Oh, you have no idea.
Can I ask how your parents
feel about this?
Well, when I presented them
with my plan,
the words "over my dead body"
were used.
(Rabbi chuckles)
I'm not surprised.
But they were
similarly resistant
when I wanted to get an ant farm
and eventually they came around.
All right, here's what
I'm gonna tell you to do.
Read your Bible.
Already did, cover to cover.
Really?
Quiz me.
No, that's okay, I believe you.
All right, my advice to you
is to stay with the faith
of your parents.
What else you got?
Okay.
Then I'm gonna tell you
to be your own man.
But I want to be a great
scientist like Albert Einstein.
Sheldon,
when your days are over,
God will never ask you,
"Why weren't you Einstein?"
But he might ask you,
"Why weren't you Sheldon?"
(door opens)
What's going on? You all right?
I'm not feeling great.
Is it a pregnant thing?
'Cause I got
some good news on that.
I got a decent raise.
It doesn't matter.
What do you mean
it doesn't matter?
We can pull this off now.
I lost the baby.
Oh.
(sighs)
You're probably relieved, huh?
Actually...
...no.
I love the first three.
Fourth one's a charm, right?
(knocking on door)
SHELDON: Dad?
SHELDON: Mom?
(sighs)
Yeah, Shelly? (clears throat)
(door opens)
I just thought you should know
I'm not going to be Jewish.
I'm going to remain the atheist
Baptist you've come to love.
Good to hear.
Are you crying?
(sighs)
Yeah, but don't worry,
everything's okay.
Good.
(exhales)
ADULT SHELDON: Once again,
I brought my mother so much joy
she was moved to tears.
I don't know how I do it.
(intercom beeps)
RECEPTIONIST: Tom,
George Cooper's here for you.
Send him in.
Hey, Tom, you got a minute?
Pretty busy.
Make it quick.
It turns out I don't
need that raise.
What happened,
you win the lottery?
No, no.
Aw, George, I am so sorry.
Well, what can you do?
Listen, I cleared
your raise already,
why don't you just
keep the money.
Oh, no, I couldn't do that.
No.
No, I mean it. It's yours.
Okay.
Thanks. Bye.
Thank you, but I will
no longer be needing these.
You're giving up
so soon?
What happened?
Did it hurt your fingers?
No.
I'm following the advice of
a very wise Rabbi Schneiderman
from Temple Judea in Houston.
Is this another one
of your jokes?
No. If it were a joke,
your mouth would be open
and the sound "ha-ha"
would be coming out.