ADULT SHELDON:
Living in a small Texas town,
a few things are guaranteed:
someone nearby
will have chickens...
(chickens clucking)
George...
Yeah?
Go shoot
those chickens.
Everyone will know
your business.
You sure you want
to eat that?
(mouth full):
Why not?
I heard your triglycerides
are through the roof.
Who told you that?
My brother plays poker
with your doctor.
But on the brighter side,
in a small Texas town,
people take care of each other.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
(exhales)
You know that
Veronica Duncan girl?
The one that
Georgie likes?
Yeah.
I was thinking about having her
stay here for a couple days.
Is it Georgie's birthday
or something?
No.
She's just having a rough time
at home.
What's going on?
Her mother's boyfriend has
a drinking problem,
and... things have been
getting out of hand.
You waited till I had a beer
to tell me
this story, didn't you?
You always have a beer.
So good news.
We're gonna have a houseguest
for a couple days.
Oh, not Aunt Ruth.
Her beard is very scratchy.
My sister doesn't have a beard.
Did she shave it?
MARY:
It's not Aunt Ruth!
It's Veronica Duncan.
(angelic choir sings)
And while she's here,
I expect y'all to be
on your best behavior.
Why are you looking at me?
Was I?
Yeah, and you still are.
Where is she going to sleep?
She can have my room.
I'm fine on the couch.
Thank you.
Why is she staying
with us?
Because she needs to be out
of her house for a few days.
Why?
Because her family
is dealing with
some personal business.
What personal business?
Well...
I heard her mama's
boyfriend is a drunk.
Where did you hear that?
Mom told you outside
and I heard it.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
(drumbeat playing)
Let's sweat!
I plan on it, Richard.
RICHARD: Oh, yeah!
♪ ♪
(phone ringing)
(music stops)
Hello?
Did you know that word "hello"
wasn't used as a greeting
until the invention
of the telephone?
Hi, John.
To end a phone call,
it was suggested to say,
"That is all."
Is that all, John?
No, I wanted to invite you
to dinner tomorrow night.
Great. Where we going?
I can't tell you that.
It's a surprise.
You want to give me a clue
so I'll know how to dress?
Well, dress as if you were going
to a Mexican restaurant.
Oh, we're going to Puerta Roja.
I can't tell you that,
it would ruin the surprise.
John, you do realize that I'll
be the one driving us there.
Fine, we're going to Puerta
Roja, but everything else
is a surprise.
That is all!
(chuckles)
RICHARD:
One more time! Come on!
♪ ♪
("Clean Up Woman"
by Betty Wright playing)
♪ ♪
Sorry, Axl.
You'll be back.
♪ A clean up woman ♪
♪ Is a woman who ♪
♪ Gets all the love
we girls... ♪
What are you doing?
Documenting.
This may never happen again.
♪ So much about her ♪
♪ Is because she picked up ♪
♪ A man of mine ♪
♪ The clean up woman ♪
♪ Will wipe his blues away ♪
♪ She'll give him
plenty loving ♪
♪ 24 hours a day ♪
♪ The clean up woman... ♪
What's in there?
Don't open it.
But what's in there?
♪ When you dump him
in the street... ♪
(TV playing indistinctly)
Are you
wearing cologne?
No.
Georgie, I have
the olfactory
senses of
a polar bear.
They can smell a seal
through three feet of ice.
Mind your business.
He's exhibiting Zahavian
signaling theory.
Is that from Star Trek?
No, biology.
He's trying to communicate
his more desirable qualities
in order to attract Veronica.
Too bad he doesn't have
any desirable qualities.
(doorbell rings)
Be the Danza. Be the Danza.
Be the Danza.
(quietly):
What a doofus.
Hey, there.
Thank you for having
me, Mrs. Cooper.
Hey, Veronica.
Let me take your bag.
Hi.
Are you wearing
Old Spice?
Don't worry about it.
Here, let me
show you around.
Oh. O-Okay. (chuckles)
Of course you remember
the living room,
where we have
our prayer group.
(quietly):
Oh, my Lord...
And this is the dining room.
That's where we'll dine.
But in the mornings,
we dine in the kitchen.
Of course, if you'd
like a snack,
that'd be in the
refrigerator or the pantry.
You know, where
your snack foods would be.
Sure.
Washer, dryer.
Plus, we got those
little sheets that smell nice
and fight
static cling.
And here's our
entertainment room.
Hey, guys.
Hi.
Hello.
We don't have cable,
but we do have
all three major
broadcast networks.
Here's the bathroom,
for hygiene and whatnot.
And... here's where
you'll be sleeping.
Did I take your room?
Yes,
but I'll be
on the couch.
Which is right near
the TV and the kitchen,
so I'm peachy.
(Spanish music playing)
Hello. I'm John Sturgis.
We have a reservation.
Follow me.
♪ ♪
(quietly):
Was a reservation
really necessary?
I didn't want to take
any chances.
(chuckles)
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
I sit in that seat.
You sit here.
Oh, uh, okay.
What's going on?
Don't you remember?
John, I don't even remember
where I just parked.
I'm recreating our first date!
The same restaurant,
the same table,
the same jacket.
Different eyelashes,
though, because
they regenerate
every two to three months.
Mine are the
same, actually.
They're fake.
(both laugh)
I wanted this night
to be special
because it's the one-year
anniversary of that date.
Is that a thing that people
our age celebrate?
No idea.
I've never been this age before.
And I've never dated anyone
for a whole year.
(chuckles)
Well...
Happy anniversary.
(chuckles)
(classical music playing)
Sorry for the mess.
I emptied out this drawer
so you can put your stuff away.
Where are
your clothes?
I threw most of them out.
You didn't have
to do that.
It's okay.
They were old and full of holes.
And it worked out great.
I found some firecrackers
and a bag full of my baby teeth.
Thank you.
Oh. I also hung a cross
over the bed for you.
It's just Popsicle sticks
and glitter. I glued it together
in Sunday school
when I was a kid.
(crying softly)
Is-is it too much?
I can take it down.
(sniffles) No, it's...
it's really sweet. (sniffles)
(crying)
Why are you crying?
Did Georgie bring up
your unfortunate home life?
Uh, no.
Good. My mom said not to,
so that you
would be comfortable.
Thank you.
Are you comfortable?
(laughing) And I remember
how cute you looked
in your little pearl snap
shirt with your bolo tie.
Well, I'd say it wasn't
my first rodeo, but it was.
(both chuckling)
Thank you for
a wonderful year.
To many more.
Which leads me
to the final surprise
of the evening.
What are you doing?
Hang on, I don't want
to spoil the surprise.
Getting down on one knee,
it makes it pretty damn clear.
Surprise!
Connie, will you
do me the honor
of being my wife?
Oh, John, I don't know.
How can you not know?
It's a binary decision.
It's more complicated
th-than that.
I don't see why.
We're compatible.
(quietly): I know.
We enjoy each other's company.
I know.
And we've become extremely
proficient in the bedroom.
There's very little
wasted effort.
(quietly):
John, sit back down
and lower your voice.
Little help?
Down is easier than up. (groans)
Sure.
MARY: Thank you, God, for this
food we're about to receive,
and for the nourishment
of our bodies, and bless
the hands that prepared it.
And an extra special thank-you
for allowing us
to share our home with
our friend Veronica.
ALL: Amen.
GEORGE JR.: Oh, yeah.
That's a big amen on that one.
MARY:
All right, everybody, dig in.
Would you like a dinner roll?
Mmm. Sure.
I find it really
rounds out the meal.
Mom?
Yes, honey?
Do I have to sit downwind
of Georgie's cologne?
So, Veronica, I understand
that you're a junior?
Mm. Yes, sir.
Do you have any plans
for after high school?
I'm hoping for a
scholarship to Baylor
so I can get
a teaching degree.
Mm.
I like kids. (chuckles)
Really? Kids? Ugh.
You're so tall and pretty,
you should be Vanna White.
How can she be Vanna White?
Vanna White is Vanna White.
Fine. She can be Vanna Blue.
See? This is the kind
of nonsense you have
to deal with when
you're around kids.
He does have a point.
No. I-I love this.
We never eat dinner
together at my house.
You eat alone?
Mostly. Yeah.
(quietly):
Lucky duck.
(indistinct chatter)
John...
I've already been
married once.
I wasn't really planning
on ever doing it again.
Why not?
I was somebody's wife
for a long time.
I just like being...
Connie Tucker now.
Not Mrs....
somebody else's name.
Well, what if I took your name?
John Tucker, it sounds great.
Like a football player
or an astronaut.
You're missing the point.
I just think it's important
for people to know
that we're an official couple.
We don't have to be married
for that.
Buy a billboard,
take an ad out in the paper.
I understand. Thank you.
Are we good?
Yes.
But if I should
pre-decease you...
(voice breaking):
I want you to have the ring.
Fine.
It'll be in the...
top right corner
of my dresser drawer.
Got it.
(crying):
Under my tube socks.
Veronica. Veronica.
VERONICA:
Come in.
Hey, Sheldon, what's up?
I printed out
my bathroom schedule.
I can't speak for anyone else
in this family,
but you can count on it
being occupied
during these times.
Thank you.
This is very helpful.
I know.
Is there anything else?
There is, but...
I'm not allowed to ask about it.
Oh, it's okay.
You can ask me anything.
Oh, good.
I don't like cats,
but I share
their curious nature.
(laughs)
What do you want to know?
Your mom has
a boyfriend.
Yeah.
Where is your father?
I don't know.
Why do you not know?
Well, he left
when I was really young
and I never
heard from him again.
And why are you staying here?
My mom's boyfriend
isn't very nice.
I understand.
My sister isn't very nice.
(chuckles) So you get it?
I do, thank you.
Okay, well,
talk to you later.
But not between
7:00 and 7:12.
Yup, I see it right here.
(drops keys)
So... how about
I make us a pot of tea
and we'll get cozy?
Sure, sounds good.
Just make yourself comfy,
I-I'll be right back.
Mint tea?
Or would you like to go crazy
and have a little hibiscus?
(door closes)
(water turns off)
Ah, damn it.
BOY (over TV): Buddy,
they let you out?
BUDDY: Yeah, but
they let Charles in.
Hey, can I join you?
Sure.
What you watching?
Charles in Charge.
It's kind of like Who's
the Boss? but with Chachi.
They should have called it
Chachi in Charge.
Cha-Chi in Charge.
That's three cha's. I like it.
(laughs)
Georgie, you're so funny.
Really?
Not everybody gets me.
I get you.
♪ ♪
Uh-oh.
Oh, Mom. If you're sleeping
with the man,
you should be married to him.
Why do I come here?
I got to find
a cooler chick to talk to.
You know I'm right.
I know no such thing.
It's my life,
I don't have to do
anything 'cause
I'm "supposed to."
I do it because I want to,
and right now,
I don't want to, end of story.
Good morning.
Can I get you
some breakfast, honey?
Yes, please.
How was your anniversary date
with Dr. Sturgis?
You knew about that?
Yes.
So you knew
he was gonna propose?
Propose? No, that's wonderful.
Although, it's a little
disconcerting he didn't tell me.
I thought we were
closer than that.
Well, we're not
getting married any time soon.
You should. You're old;
you don't have many years left.
I really need to meet
a whole new group of people.
Hey, what you doin'?
Helping your mom with laundry.
Oh, yeah. That's usually my job.
(TV playing indistinctly)
Uh, maybe when you're done,
we can go down to the mall
and hang out.
Oh, I promised your sister I'd
take her out for some girl time.
Maybe I can come along.
Then it wouldn't be girl time.
No, not entirely,
but it would be mostly.
Take a hint, dummy.
(phone ringing)
(machine beeps)
STURGIS (recorded):
Greetings.
You've reached Dr. John Sturgis.
Leave a message
and I'll be in touch.
Thank you very much.
Hey, that rhymed.
(machine beeps)
(chuckles)
John, I know
you're there, pick up.
If you don't pick up,
I'm gonna get really mad.
I'm getting really mad.
Call me back.
(exhales)
(indistinct chatter)
(horse nickering)
Sorry, I know this isn't
the most fun thing in the world.
I was happy just riding
in the front seat
of your car.
(laughs)
♪ Oh, yeah... ♪
You probably hear this a lot,
but you're, like,
princess pretty.
Oh. I don't know
about that.
But you are definitely
princess material.
Well, until I'm allowed
to wear makeup,
this is as hot as I get.
You don't need makeup.
I hope you're right. Mom says
I have to wait till I'm 16.
Mm. That'll get here
sooner than you think.
Sure doesn't feel like it.
Don't be in a rush.
Honestly...
I'd rather be
your age again.
Really?
Yeah.
Being a grown-up is, uh...
complicated.
Maybe, if we make
a wish at the same time
we could switch places.
You think?
It's worth a try.
Okay.
What do we need to do?
We close our eyes
and at the exact same time say,
"I wish I could switch places."
Ready?
One... two... three.
BOTH:
I wish I could switch places.
♪ ♪
♪ I'll tell you
what we need to do... ♪
Well?
I'm still here. You?
Same.
That's too bad.
I really wanted to drive home.
(chuckles)
Can I anyway?
Sure.
Really?
No. (laughs)
♪ Hey! ♪
Please, can
we keep her?
No, we cannot keep her.
We don't have a dog
'cause of Sheldon,
why can't I have Veronica?
I'm not participating
in this conversation.
We could give Sheldon
to Veronica's mom.
(doorbell rings)
Like a trade.
VERONICA:
I'll get it, Mrs. Cooper.
Look how helpful she is.
Come on!
Out.
What do you want?
Grab your stuff, your
mama wants you home.
Yeah, well, when she wants me
to come home, she can call me.
Damn it, Veronica.
I'm in no mood.
What's going on?
I'm taking her home.
She's not going
anywhere with you.
(scoffs)
What'd you say?
Clint, stop.
You mind
putting down my kid?
(laughs)
We were just playing around.
This is my mom's
boyfriend, Clint.
Hello, Clint.
What can we do for you?
I'm here to
pick up Veronica.
Come on.
You want to go with this man?
No, sir.
You heard her.
Thanks for stopping by.
You really want to mess with me?
Sure.
Why not?
(thudding outside)
What's going on out there?
You might want
to call the police.
Why?
There's a bum
sleeping on our front porch.
(birds chirping outside)
What's this?
"Connie Tucker
is proud to announce
"that she is sweet
on Dr. John Sturgis and they are
(laughs):
officially a romantic couple."
Oh, boy!
I'm back in business! (laughs)