(distorted voices,
radio crackling)
What on Earth...?
Hello?
Hello, Mom.
Hi.
I bet you're wondering.
I sure am.
It's a shortwave radio.
Dr. Sturgis
is letting me use it.
STURGIS:
It picks up broadcasts
from around the world.
Listen.
This is the time being announced
every minute from Ottawa.
OPERATOR: At the sound of the
tone, the local time in Ottawa
will be 5:13.
(beeps)
Spellbinding, ain't it?
And you thought this was okay
to go on in my house?
It was that or my house,
so here we are.
Wednesday morning, the
Nobel Prize winners are going
to be announced in Sweden, and
we'll hear it as it's happening.
Well, 2.8 milliseconds later.
Sure, because
of the propagation.
And what's this?
Some kind of antenna?
Yes. It needs to go
up on the roof.
You're not going on the roof.
Of course he's not. I am.
You're not going, either.
Excuse me, I have six years
of tai chi under my belt.
I have the balance
of a jungle cat.
You doing some kind of
slow-motion hula dance
in the park is not gonna
change my mind.
I do much more than just this.
♪ Nobody else
is stronger than I am ♪
♪ Yesterday I moved a mountain ♪
♪ I bet I could be your hero ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man ♪
♪ I am a mighty little man. ♪
So you want me to put
that thing on that roof?
Yes.
So you can hear who won
a science prize?
The Nobel Prize.
(sighs) Why can't you read
who won in the newspaper?
I could say the same thing
about the Super Bowl,
but you still watch it.
He got you there.
The Super Bowl is football.
Your thing is... I don't
even know what your thing is.
It's the most prestigious award
in the field of physics.
I'll think about it.
When I win one, I might
just thank you in my speech.
(sighs)
The things I do for you.
Georgie, get out here!
Got a chore for you!
Good call.
You have no business up there.
(distorted voices)
OPERATOR:
Radio Sweden International.
There it is.
Excellent. Which scientists
are you rooting for?
Oh, I don't
have a favorite.
There's so much good
work being done.
I think it's time
Frederick Reines
finally gets his due
for the neutrino.
I suppose he has a shot.
I should think so, he confirmed
the neutrino's existence
35 years ago.
What the heck
are they waiting for?
Lots of talented people
don't get recognized.
NARRATOR (over TV):
Giraffes aren't able to have...
(Donald Duck jabbering)
You know if we had cable,
we'd have, like, 60 channels?
We have plenty of channels.
We have seven.
Hey! There are starving kids
in Africa
with no channels.
Come on, it don't cost much.
I'm not paying for television.
Television is free.
Always was, always will be.
You're so cheap.
If you want cable,
pay for it yourself.
Or better yet, try turning that
thing off and go read a book.
"Read a book"?
STURGIS:
♪ Inch by inch ♪
♪ Row by row ♪
♪ Gonna make this garden grow ♪
♪ Gonna mulch it deep and... ♪
John?
Hello, my sweet.
What are you doing out here?
Weeding. You have goosegrass.
And you can't have a nice lawn
if you have goosegrass.
(chuckles):
It's kind of dark out.
Goosegrass doesn't sleep.
It kills the good grass
and leaves
bald spots.
But don't worry,
I'm on the job.
(chuckles)
Oh. Okay.
Can I get you a flashlight?
I would prefer a headlamp, such
as one would use for spelunking.
Okay.
Let me check
my spelunking supplies.
You're a peach.
♪ Pulling weeds
and picking stones... ♪
(xylophone playing)
Good morning,
Medford High School,
this is Class President
Sheldon Cooper
with an important
science bulletin.
This Wednesday morning,
the Nobel Prize in Physics
will be announced,
and I'd like to invite each and
every one of you to my garage
to listen live at 5:00 a.m. and
be a part of scientific history.
Food and refreshments
will be served...
You worried your kid
just invited the whole school
to your house?
At 5:00 in the morning
for a Swedish science thing?
(chuckles)
Not at all.
In other school news, this
Friday night our football team
will be playing
another football team.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Hi, Connie,
this is Dr. Linkletter.
I work in the physics department
with Dr. Sturgis.
Oh, sure, I remember you.
What can I do for you?
Well, I'm just calling to let
you know that John is fine,
but there's been a bit of
an incident at the school today.
What happened?
He broke into
the mainframe computer lab,
tripped off an alarm.
Security came,
and there was a chase.
A chase?
It was a short one.
He's not a fast man.
Uh-- well, where is he now?
He's in the dean's office.
He has you listed
as the emergency contact,
so I just wanted
to let you know.
Well, uh-- thank you
so much for calling.
My pleasure.
If there's anything I can do,
feel free to reach out.
Or if you'd like to go
grab a coffee sometime,
I know a cute little cafe.
Do you like scones?
You're not actually trying
to hit on me right now, are you?
Is it working?
No.
I should go.
What kind of snacks
do you think I should serve
at my Nobel gathering?
It's on Swedish radio.
How about Swedish meatballs?
But it's at 5:00 a.m.
Swedish breakfast balls?
I could offer an assortment
of breakfast cereal.
My mom doesn't let me have
cereal with sugar in it.
Or anything that makes me happy.
Connie. What are you doing here?
Well...
I got a call
from your friend Linkletter,
and, uh... I-I was a
little worried about you.
What did he say?
That you had some
kind of scuffle
with the campus security?
No scuffle.
I was using
the university's mainframe,
and they asked me to leave.
Simple as that.
So nobody chased you?
I was startled, and so I did
what any normal person does
under the circumstances:
climb out a window
and run like the dickens.
KURT (over TV):
Hi, I'm Kurt Loder,
this is MTV News...
Since when do we get MTV?
Since I got cable.
What do you mean, you got cable?
I called up the cable company
and I said, "Hello,
I'd like cable,"
and they put in cable.
I'm not paying for that.
Keep your shirt on.
I paid for it.
Is that so?
Yeah, with money
I saved from my job.
Well, okay.
So do we get any
of those movie channels?
Dad, I'm trying
to watch the news.
KURT:
Billy Idol has recovered
so well from...
What's so important
that I had to run over here?
Come here. I want
to show you something.
Look at this.
John did it.
Oh, dear.
"Oh, dear" is right.
Was he in here taking a bath
and just started thinking
about science stuff?
Read the top right part.
MARY:
"Time plus heat
plus bread equals toast."
(whispers):
That ain't science.
Well, it's not wrong, either.
Look at this.
Yeah, well, that's... peculiar.
You'll be amazed to know
that the Nobel Prize,
while being the most prestigious
award in science,
is not generally celebrated
in this country.
No parades, no fireworks.
Which is why I thought having
a breakfast celebration
was not only appropriate,
but long overdue.
You may have noticed
that I went with Cheerios,
and believe me, it was
a decision that I came to
after careful consideration.
There were birds
on the Froot Loops,
Cocoa Puffs and Corn Flakes,
so they were out.
And leprechauns and elves
are magical creatures
that would be a slap in the face
to the scientific community.
Anyway, the festivities begin
at 4:30 a.m.
You're most welcome to come.
As are you, unhappy bag boy.
What the hell is this?
TV's asking me
for some kind of code.
Yeah, that's the
parental control lock.
So how do I take it off?
You don't.
This is my cable
that I bought with my money.
You got to be kidding me.
Here's an idea,
how about you go read a book?
Oh, this isn't over, little man.
Not by a long shot!
You know what I like
about you, Sheldon?
You're incredibly smart,
but you're also really dumb.
Why would you say that?
You think people are gonna
come here to hang out with you?
Yes.
To hear about science?
On the radio?
Yes.
At 5:00 in the morning?
And you're asking me
why you're dumb?
Well, I happen to have
a little more faith
in the curiosity
of my fellows.
See, you sound smart,
but you're still dumb.
I bet you don't even know
the first thing about Sweden.
Well, you're wrong,
it's where those little
meatballs come from.
And that chef on The Muppets.
That's two things.
Oh,
and is in Canada. That's three.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Hello, Dr. Linkletter.
This is Connie Tucker.
Connie, how lovely
to hear from you.
Stop. I'm worried about John.
He was supposed to be here for
dinner and he never showed up.
That's not good. He also missed
two of his classes today.
Do you have any idea
where he might be?
Hard to say.
If he's having another episode,
he could be anywhere.
Hold on, what do you mean
"episode"?
Oh, I thought you knew.
In the past,
John has struggled
with his grip on reality.
What kind of struggle
are we talking about?
The kind where he's had
to be hospitalized.
Well, he never said anything
about that to me.
Well, I certainly wouldn't
fabricate such a story.
Okay, look, i-if-if you
hear from him or see him,
please let me know.
Of course.
Now, if down the road
things don't work out
with you two, I'd love to...
Good-bye.
♪ ♪
(car engine starts)
(TV playing faintly)
Here, this is for you.
What is it?
Read it. You do remember
how to read, don't you?
A bill? Really?
Room and board, buddy.
$50 a month for food?
The way you eat,
I should've gone $50 a week.
Laundry services?
Your poor mother has to touch
your underwear.
What's the $10 a month
"peema" charge?
Oh, P-I-M-A, that's
a "Pain in My Ass" tax.
My way of getting
compensated for you
taking years off my life.
John?
Your bike's here. John?
(sensual music playing on TV)
(chuckling): Well, look at that,
there's boobies on my TV.
Ooh!
Get out of here!
I'm telling Mom!
(gunshots,
horse neighing over TV)
(sensual music playing)
John?
Hello.
What-What're you doing?
I was doing tai chi
and then I realized
that I was
continually being bombarded
by subatomic particles
and it behooves me, perhaps,
to pay slightly closer
attention to them.
Maybe "chi" is the
ancient Chinese word
for the subatomic
universe.
You're scaring me, John.
Well, there's nothing
to be scared of.
Tomorrow, somebody will win
the Nobel Prize
about these
particles...
not me.
But I'm experiencing them
firsthand... (laughs)
...which could be better.
Why don't you come down
and experience them
on the floor?
I think I just felt
a neutrino. (laughing)
You know, neutrinos
are interesting.
They never bond with anything,
they're always alone.
I think that one went
right through my pants.
All right,
why don't we
go downstairs,
and I'll fix us both
a nice cup of hot tea
and you can tell me
all about it.
Please?
Okay.
It was my dream
to win the Nobel,
and I'm not going to.
I bet Sheldon will.
(chuckles)
That'll be something.
Yeah.
(radio static)
CARL-OLOF JACOBSON (on radio):
Welcome to Radio Sweden...
How's it going, baby?
I don't think anyone's
showing up, not even Tam.
I'm here.
Yeah, but you're my mom.
You live on the premises.
At least Dr. Sturgis
should be here any minute.
Shelly, I'm afraid Dr. Sturgis
isn't coming this morning.
Why not?
He isn't feeling well.
Oh, dear.
Should we send him
a get well card?
I think that'd
be terrific.
JACOBSON:
Good morning and welcome
to the Royal Swedish
Academy of Sciences.
The announcements are starting.
You want me to stay?
JACOBSON: Uh, the Academy has
concluded its meeting and we are
ready to announce this year's...
I'll be in my room
if you need me.
JACOBSON:
As usual, I will read the
announcements first in English,
then in Swedish,
then the citation in German,
French, and Russian.
And this year's
Nobel Prize in Physics
is awarded to...
Come on, neutrinos.
...Henry Kendall,
Jerome Friedman,
and Richard Taylor
for the discovery of quarks.
ADULT SHELDON:
A primary feature of quarks
is that they're always
bonded together,
but in that moment,
I felt like a neutrino,
destined to be alone forever.
(Jacobson speaking German
on radio)
BEVERLY HOFSTADTER: Leonard,
dear, you should be in bed.
(snoring)
♪ My, my baby
as there are stars above ♪
♪ Want to say, I want to say,
I want to say it ♪
♪ Some day we'll be together ♪
♪ Yes, we will,
yes, we will... ♪
MRS. WOLOWITZ: Howard!
Turn off that fakakta game
and go to sleep.
♪ Someday we'll be together ♪
♪ Yes, we will, yes, we will ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ We'll be together ♪
♪ Honey, honey, honey,
honey, honey ♪
♪ Someday... ♪
ADULT SHELDON:
Thankfully, I was wrong.