[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat jazz piano music]
♪ ♪
[bird chirping]
[cooing]
[narrator]
If you're an avid bird watcher,
it helps to be good
at climbing trees.
[whistling]
[narrator]
And to have a friend
who's good at getting
birds' attention.
[chuckles]
Nice shot.
You're getting
quite the collection
of bird photos, George.
-[bird chirping]
-[gasps]
[whistling weakly]
Oh.
Different birds
talk to each other
by making different sounds.
Easy for birds,
not so easy for us.
Oh.
But luckily, there are bird
calls that do the work for you.
[chattering excitedly]
See, the pictures
on the side
tell you which bird
you're calling.
-Ah!
-Try one.
Oh.
[chatters]
[narrator] George had photos
of robins and warblers,
but he really wanted
a picture of an osprey.
Ah.
[bird call sounding]
[grunts happily]
Ah...
Nice job.
Only, ospreys
are harder to find.
I've never seen one myself.
Huh.
Ospreys usually live
near the ocean or big lakes,
where they can find
more fish to eat.
But if you're lucky,
someday you might see one.
Ah. Uh-huh.
[man]
Popcorn! Fresh popcorn!
[narrator] It's Mr. Popper
and his popcorn wagon.
Whoo!
[chattering excitedly]
George.
See any good birds today?
Uh-huh.
[chuckles] You'll have
to show me your photos.
Popcorn and a lemonade?
You bet ya.
Oh, want to help me
make a new batch?
[grunts happily]
[pops lips, chuckles]
[chattering excitedly]
Ah!
[upbeat piano music]
[narrator] George loved
helping Mr. Popper.
He leveled off
one cup of popcorn...
poured it into the machine...
and then...
Whoa! Ah!
I know.
It started all by itself.
[narrator] Mr. Popper always
served the popcorn the same way.
First, he grabbed
a cup and a bag.
Second, he pressed the button
for the lemonade.
Third, he scooped in the popcorn
and tapped the bag.
♪ ♪
And he always served
his customers with a smile.
-[slurping]
-Oh, whoops. [chuckles]
I like to keep things tidy.
♪ ♪
Now, let's see those photos.
[grunts happily]
My goodness!
Did you see
a yellow-throated warbler today?
-Uh-huh.
-Mm-hmm. We sure did.
He flew off that way.
[chuckles]
I wish I could've seen him.
Ah...
[chattering excitedly]
Ah.
You'd run my wagon for me?
-Uh-huh.
-Sure.
George can run the wagon,
and I'll show you
where we saw the warbler.
Oh, goody!
My nephew wears this
when he helps me.
[chuckles] Perfect fit.
You shouldn't have
many customers.
It's a slow day!
Ah!
[narrator] And just like that,
a monkey was in charge
of a popcorn wagon.
Excuse me? I'd like
a popcorn and lemonade, please.
[narrator]
It was his first customer.
Make that customers.
[children shouting excitedly]
George's slow day
had suddenly gotten very busy.
He tried to remember
all the steps.
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
[grunts worriedly]
[narrator]
But he got off to a rocky start.
♪ ♪
[grunts in frustration]
Yay!
♪ ♪
[narrator] But the order
of the order was all wrong.
Huh.
Ah!
♪ ♪
[narrator]
The lemonade went in the cup.
The popcorn went in the bag.
[grunts happily]
Oh. [chuckles]
[narrator] And the scooper
stayed in the machine.
[all cheering]
♪ ♪
Soon, George
had the system down so well,
he could fill two orders
at the same time...
♪ ♪
[all] Bye! Thank you!
[narrator] Until, finally,
all the customers were gone.
♪ ♪
So was the popcorn.
George would have to make more.
Ah
♪ ♪
Oh.
[narrator] George remembered
he had to measure carefully.
Just one level cup.
♪ ♪
[chuckling with satisfaction]
[narrator]
Now to tidy up a bit.
[chattering happily]
[pigeon coos]
♪ ♪
Ah. [chattering excitedly]
[pigeon coos]
[narrator] Compass wondered
if there was more
of that fluffy stuff inside.
♪ ♪
Maybe it was hidden
in the bag.
[cooing excitedly]
♪ ♪
Aah!
[narrator] Most people don't like
pigeon in their popcorn.
[shooing]
♪ ♪
Ah-oh.
[narrator] A very big bird was
next to Compass.
Ah.
[narrator]
Could that be an osprey?
Whoo!
[chattering excitedly]
[ominous jazz piano music]
Ah? Ha.
[narrator]
Nope, it was just a raven.
Oh.
[popcorn popping]
Aah!
♪ ♪
[narrator] Something
had done something wrong.
[chattering worriedly]
Aah!
[grunts]
[chattering]
Aah!
[popcorn popping]
[narrator] The popcorn bag
had a hole in it.
George had to find
the off switch.
[upbeat jazz music]
Ah! Ah!
[narrator] But it's hard
to find a switch
in a wagon full of popcorn.
[gasps]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George could put
the extra popcorn
in the trash bag.
♪ ♪
Ah, aha.
[grunts]
[ominous jazz music]
♪ ♪
Huh?
Uh-oh.
[chattering worriedly]
[shouting]
♪ ♪
[narrator] What a mess.
This would take
all day to clean...
maybe weeks.
[cooing]
[narrator] If only George had
20 Compasses to eat popcorn.
Ah!
[narrator] Or even 100.
Ah, aha!
[whistle imitates pigeon cooing]
[gasps]
Ah!
[upbeat jazz music]
♪ ♪
[narrator] But there was popcorn
in the lake, too,
and pigeons didn't swim.
[gasps]
[narrator] But ducks did.
Ah!
♪ ♪
[whistle imitates duck quacking]
[ducks quacking]
Yah!
♪ ♪
[narrator] It looked like George
was gonna need bigger birds.
Hmm.
Huh?
[geese honking]
♪ ♪
[whistle imitates geese honking]
[narrator] George
could never blow hard enough
for birds
that high up to hear.
Ah.
[narrator] Or could he?
[chattering excitedly]
[amplified whistle
imitates ospreys calling]
[narrator]
That wasn't a goose call.
It was an osprey call.
♪ ♪
[amplified whistle imitates
geese honking]
[geese honking]
-[amplified whistle continues]
-Oh!
That's the loudest goose
I've ever heard.
Oh, that's no goose.
That's my monkey.
♪ ♪
[chatters excitedly]
[laughing]
♪ ♪
[panting]
-George, is everything okay?
-Uh-huh.
-[osprey calls]
-[Mr. Popper gasps]
-An osprey...
on my wagon.
It's magnificent!
♪ ♪
[camera shutter clicks]
[narrator] And that's how George
made Mr. Popper's
the most popular popcorn place
in the park...
with bird-watchers, that is.
♪ ♪
[narrator] It was always quietest
at Renkins' Farm
just before dawn.
All the animals
were fast asleep...
Including one little monkey
on a campout with his friend.
[rooster crowing]
Huh?
Come on, George,
let's check the animals.
[grunts happily]
[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
The chickens
are following Mom.
-Check.
-Hi.
♪ ♪
Hello.
The pigs are wallowing.
Check.
♪ ♪
And the horses are eating...
Again.
Check.
Hey...
[chattering]
Good idea, George.
If we hurry, we can ride
the tire swing before breakfast.
Aha!
[horse chuffs]
♪ ♪
And... go!
[grunting happily]
♪ ♪
Whoa! Oh!
What happened?
Oh.
Hmm. Looks like
the rubber gave out.
Well, it was old.
It's been there my whole life.
[gasps, grunts]
♪ ♪
Ah!
[chattering excitedly]
Wow. That would make
the most "giantest" tire swing
in the world.
Can we have it, Grandma?
I was going to use it
as a planter.
-Ah.
-Oh.
Hey...
[chattering happily]
[gasps] Good idea.
What if we trade you for it?
Trade me?
Mm-hmm.
We could, uh...
gather the eggs
for you all week!
And you give us the tire.
Hmm.
I could use more time
to spruce up the farm stand.
But Jagger, the rooster--
well, I'm not sure
he'll let you in the yard.
He's pretty protective
of those hens.
[chattering excitedly]
Yeah, one little rooster's
no match
for a girl and a monkey.
[laughs] Okay,
if you think you can handle it.
You're now
the official egg gatherers.
[giggles] Thanks.
Come on, George.
[chatters excitedly]
♪ ♪
[chickens clucking]
Ooh!
♪ ♪
[narrator] That rooster reminded
George of a wiener dog
who was very protective
of his lobby...
but with feathers and a beak.
George knew how to handle him.
Ah...
[chatters happily]
[clucking angrily]
[narrator] But Hundley
was nothing like this.
Quick, George! Run!
[chattering fearfully]
[clucking angrily]
[narrator]
Jagger only allowed Mrs. Renkins
in his chicken yard.
And this furry person
wasn't her.
Hmm.
We are
the official egg gatherers.
We can do this.
It's just going to take a plan.
[grunts in agreement]
♪ ♪
Those are the nesting boxes.
It's where the hens
lay the eggs.
♪ ♪
[narrator]
They had to get those eggs out
without Jagger catching them.
♪ ♪
Oh!
[whistling inconspicuously]
[narrator] It was going to take
something special
to outsmart him.
♪ That's why chickens
are so lucky ♪
♪ I wish I could be so clucky ♪
[chickens clucking]
♪ That's why chickens
are so lucky ♪
♪ I wish I could be so clucky ♪
♪ That's why chickens
are so lucky ♪
♪ ♪
[narrator]
Distracting did not work.
♪ ♪
Who wants a snack?
Delicious... whatever this is
that you eat!
♪ ♪
[narrator] Apparently
Jagger wasn't hungry.
Oh.
-[chickens clucking]
-[sighs]
Earning that tire is going to be
harder than we thought.
-Uh-huh.
-[goat bleats]
♪ ♪
-[clucking wildly]
-[bleating]
[narrator] Jagger didn't seem
to want anyone around
who wasn't a chicken.
[gasps] Hey!
[grunting happily]
I found one in the attic.
-You ready?
-[grunts happily]
[laughing]
[narrator] George wondered
why chickens didn't laugh more.
Feathers tickled.
Oh, and my birthday hat.
[giggles]
Perfect.
Uh-huh.
[chickens clucking]
Ah...
[imitates chicken clucking]
♪ ♪
[whispering]
You have to chicken-walk more.
[continues imitating
chicken clucking]
[chickens clucking]
♪ ♪
[clucks angrily]
[narrator] Jagger wondered
who was inside his coop.
It was that furry person.
-[clucking angrily]
-[shouts]
Oh.
[squeals]
-[egg breaks]
-Oh.
[grunting angrily]
[narrator] Jagger wanted it
out of his henhouse.
[shouts]
♪ ♪
Ah, you got zero.
Oh.
[narrator] Before he went back
into the coop,
George wanted a helmet.
Ooh!
[narrator] George realized
he could get the eggs
without going
into the chicken coop.
[gasps, grunts happily]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Good thing
the nesting boxes were slanted.
♪ ♪
[grunts happily]
[narrator] First,
George needed a chute.
♪ ♪
Hmm. [gasps]
[narrator]
Eggs were break-y...
so George would give them
a soft ride.
♪ ♪
Aha!
Ah!
[narrator]
George was ready
to make
an automatic egg gatherer.
♪ ♪
Getting the egg chute
inside the coop was a breeze.
Ah!
[rooster clucking angrily]
[grunts]
[narrator]
Getting a monkey inside
was going to be
more difficult.
[chattering happily]
[narrator] But what if all Jagger
saw was another rooster?
[chickens clucking]
♪ ♪
[clucking angrily]
[narrator]
Wait a minute.
When did Mrs. Renkins
get a new rooster?
[grunts angrily]
[whispering] It's working.
[narrator] Jagger would have to
show this new whippersnapper
who ruled the roost.
♪ ♪
[squawks]
[narrator]
George would attach the chute,
and eggs would roll right in.
[hammer pounding]
[narrator] Jagger wondered
who was inside his coop.
It was that furry person.
♪ ♪
[Jagger squawks angrily]
[chatters happily]
[squawks angrily,
clucks wildly]
Aha!
[squawks angrily]
♪ ♪
How's the egg gathering
coming?
We're gathering them
right now.
[laughs]
Right now? How?
Come on, we'll show you.
[grunts happily]
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
Uh, how did that happen?
[chickens clucking]
[grunts happily]
[clucks]
[grunts, chattering happily]
♪ ♪
We'll, I'll be...
an egg gatherer.
It's brilliant!
So brilliant,
you can have that tire
six days ahead of schedule.
-[chuckles]
-[gasps] Thanks, Grandma!
-Ooh, yes!
-[both laugh]
I told you
we could do it, George!
♪ ♪
[narrator] The Renkins Farm's
new tire swing
was the largest in the area...
big enough for two riders.
[squawks wildly]
[narrator]
And sometimes three.