[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[narrator] The holidays were over,
and Bill's decorations
were already down.
But not George's.
Ooh!
[laughs] She's still got
some life in her.
Sort of.
[blows]
[chittering]
Oh, hey, I almost forgot
the erector set.
[George] Ah!
Ready to tackle
the 1889 Paris Exhibition?
Uh-huh!
[pieces rattling]
Hmm, sounds like
a big project.
What do you say
we set it up in the attic
where there's more room?
Uh-huh!
Hang in there, George.
I'm just getting it
started for you...
then she's all yours.
[chitters sadly]
Huh? Ah!
[chittering happily]
[narrator] It had been too cold
to climb with Jumpy Squirrel.
Or run with Dottie Deer...
Or...
[quacking]
waddle with Dumpling Duck.
[sighs]
[narrator] George missed
his animal friends.
[sighs]
Since it was too cold
for George to play outside,
maybe his friends could
come inside for a sleepover!
Ah!
[muttering]
Ah! [giggles]
Oh, uh... Let's see here.
Um...
Are these sleeping bags?
[chitters excitedly] Uh-huh!
Okay, so you wanna have
a sleepover...
with your... friends?
Yeah! Uh-huh! Uh-huh!
Sure. Why not?
Hooray!
[man in the yellow hat] Oh, and when
you talk to Allie, and Bill,
and whoever
that other person is,
see if one of them is good
with erector sets.
[narrator] If you're having
a sleepover, you'll need snacks,
fun party games...
And cozy sleeping bags.
Ah!
[narrator] Now all George needed
were guests.
Ahh...
-[chitters]
-[startled squeak]
[narrator] Jumpy didn't
like being startled.
Whatever the monkey wanted,
it had better be good!
[chattering excitedly]
[tantalizing musical flourish]
[excited shrieks]
[narrator] Who was Jumpy
to say no to free nuts?
Dottie wondered
where Jumpy had gone.
[chattering excitedly]
[quacking]
[narrator] If it was good enough
for the squirrel and the deer,
Dumpling wanted in too.
[chattering happily]
Hm...
[giggles]
[narrator] Maybe they'd like to
play a game.
[happy chattering]
[all munching]
[quacking]
[narrator] Dumpling knew
what to do with eggs.
Fortunately, George had
extra game pieces.
Jumpy thought they were nuts.
And Dottie thought
the dice were sugar cubes.
Oh!
[frantic chattering]
Ah-ha!
[mysterious music plays on TV]
Ah?
[dinosaur growling]
[all shrieking]
[terrified chittering]
[scary music plays on TV]
Oh.
[narrator] Maybe
they should just go to bed.
Huh?
[narrator] Was this
their first sleepover?
George would have to show them
how sleeping bags worked.
[all clamoring]
[terrified chittering]
[exclaiming]
[thud]
Oh! What was that?
[crashing]
[chuckles] Aw. Pillow fight.
[all clamoring]
[confused chitters]
[narrator] George wondered
why this wasn't going so well.
[gasps]
Oh!
[narrator] Then he realized...
unlike little monkeys,
most animals didn't sleep
in sleeping bags.
And they probably
didn't play board games
or watch movies either.
[happy chittering]
[narrator] George wanted to
find out what his guests liked.
Hm...
[narrator]
Jumpy's nest was a hole
filled with sticks,
leaves, and feathers,
Ah.
High up in a tree.
[sighs] C'est magnifique!
[mimics French laughter]
[gasps]
[accordion plays jumbled notes]
My first accordion!
[Dumpling quacking]
[narrator] Ducks swam in water.
Even in winter.
Oh!
[shudders]
[grunts]
Hmm...
[narrator] And they slept
in nests of straw.
♪♪
Deer slept hidden
under many trees on a soft bed.
[chitters happily]
[narrator] Now George knew
what he needed
to make his sleepover
a success.
Ooh...
[grunting]
[quacking happily]
♪♪
[quacking]
[gasps happily]
♪♪
♪ Frere Jacque ♪
♪ Fre--
Frere Jacq-- Jacque ♪
♪ Dormez-vous ♪
♪ Vous, dormez-vous ♪
[happy music]
♪♪
[grunts]
Hm...
[faucet squeaking]
♪♪
Ah!
[narrator] George had made
a perfect space for each friend.
Now they just needed
to come back inside.
[inhales deeply]
Ah! [giggles]
[happy chitters]
[quacking]
[faucet squeaks]
♪♪
[narrator] Success!
George's friends loved it!
Jumpy nested in his clock.
Dumpling perched in her nest.
And Dottie slept
on her soft, forresty bed.
Aww.
But George was still missing
one thing.
[night sounds play]
Everyone slept well.
[snoring and mumbling]
♪ Dormez-vous ♪
[snoring]
[birds tweeting]
[narrator] The next morning,
George made sure
everyone had
the perfect breakfast.
[chatters conversationally]
[dramatic musical sting]
What on Earth...
George!
[sniffs] Ah.
The zucchini muffins are ready,
George! Your favorite!
[mumbles sleepily]
Ow! [whimpers]
Are you all right?
[cries]
A hurt tooth, huh?
Mm-hmm.
You might have a cavity there.
We'd better see the dentist.
[whimpers and sighs]
Oh, I'll grab the muffins.
Ow!
[meowing]
[cries]
[meows]
[narrator] Gnocchi didn't know
what language
George was speaking,
but it wasn't cat.
Hi, you two.
Hi, Dr. Chu.
[chitters softly]
I'm glad you came in.
Don't worry, we'll get rid
of your toothache.
[chitters]
Oh, this is a model
of what your teeth look like.
Your incisor teeth
bite pieces from food.
Your canine teeth hold
and tear food apart.
And your molars grind food.
[chitters questioningly]
That's plaque.
It contains bacteria.
[chitters questioningly]
-Oh, bacteria are germs.
-That's right.
And these germs
feed on the food bits
that gets stuck in your teeth,
especially sugar.
The bacteria make acid that can
create holes in your teeth--
cavities.
[fearful chittering]
Don't worry.
I know you're a good brusher.
Fluoride toothpaste usually
keeps them away.
Dan, can you get George ready?
Sure. This way, George.
Be a good little
monkey patient.
[mumbles]
Go on, you can climb
into the chair.
[chitters excitedly]
Oh, I didn't mean--
[laughs] Okay.
Huh...
[chitters questioningly]
This is a saliva ejector.
It's like a little vacuum
cleaner to keep your mouth dry.
Ooh!
And this squirts air
and water.
Oh!
[giggles]
Ah!
Oops!
[chitters sheepishly]
[chitters questioningly]
Dr. Chu wants me
to take an x-ray
to see if you have any cavities.
This protects you while I do it.
Oh.
This is a digital sensor.
-Open...
-Ah!
Now bite down and hold still.
[mumbling]
[Dan] Oh, you won't feel
anything.
It's just like when someone
takes your picture.
[camera clicks]
Excellent.
Open.
[chitters questioningly]
Yep, those are your teeth.
You sit back and relax.
Dr. Chu will be right in.
[tired sigh]
[narrator] George's toothache
kept him up all night.
He sure hoped the dentist
could find the problem.
[tired sigh]
Huh?
-Ah!
-[meows]
[narrator] George remembered
that spaceship.
He and Gnocchi rode it
through his body
to find germs like Toots
that made him sick.
[giggles]
[narrator] Maybe
they could find out
what was making
his tooth hurt.
-[chitters happily]
-[meows]
[George] Ooh!
[narrator] George wondered
if all cats
could drive as well as Gnocchi.
This felt squishy.
It had to be his tongue.
♪ We love sugar,
that's the truth ♪
♪ Especially when it's
on the tooth ♪
[all vocalizing]
Yee-haw!
Mm, yummy!
[narrator] These creatures looked
familiar to George.
They seemed a lot
like Toots, the germ!
[fearful chittering]
Well, howdy! I'm Beckah.
These are my sisters,
Rebecca and Tribeca.
Together we're the Beck-Terias.
[all vocalizing]
♪ We love sugar,
that's the truth ♪
♪ Especially
when it's on a tooth ♪
[all vocalizing]
♪ If we find munchies,
we gobble 'em ♪
♪ Tooth decay, no problem ♪
[all vocalizing]
♪ We're bacteria ♪
♪ And you won't find nothin'
scarier ♪
♪ We're bacteria ♪
♪ Sticky sweets,
our favorite things to eat ♪
It's a dental fundamental.
[narrator] They were bacteria?
Maybe they were causing
George's toothache.
Hold it! His mouth is opening.
[sniffs]
I smell zucchini muffin.
Must be snack time!
[sniffs]
Oh!
[fearful chittering]
[meows]
[gasps]
[narrator] Unfortunately, George
always followed a muffin...
with milk.
[both shriek]
[gurgling]
[both] Phew.
[narrator] George knew
this place.
He was inside his stomach!
The bacteria were probably
having a feast on that muffin.
George had to stop them.
[frantic chittering]
[country music plays]
Ahh!
[narrator] The bacteria
were everywhere!
♪ It's our favorite
thing to eat ♪
♪ Gotta have sugar,
anything sweet ♪
Oh, hi! We invited friends.
It's a party.
[angry chittering]
Oh no. If there's food for
snackin', we're not packin'.
Right, girls?
♪ We go wherever
the goodies hide ♪
♪ The front, the back,
the top, the side ♪
♪ And when you're sleepin',
we're wide awake ♪
♪ Giving you
that old toothache ♪
[narrator] They had to do
something.
[meows]
[gasps] Huh?
[excited chitters]
[narrator] If George could get
rid of the food,
the bacteria might leave.
But they didn't leave.
Hm...
Ah-ha!
[narrator] Gnocchi thought
she could help too.
[liquid sucking]
[both cheering]
♪ Gotta have sugar,
anything sweet ♪
♪ It's our favorite
thing to eat ♪
♪ Gotta have sugar,
anything sweet ♪
[narrator] There she was,
eating that yellow stuff.
It must be the plaque!
[shimmering tone]
[both cheering]
♪ Gotta have sugar,
anything sweet... ♪
[narrator] It couldn't be...
Where could they be hiding?
This was a job for...
The X-ray machine.
[chitters excitedly]
[narrator] If George could get
rid of that last piece of food,
maybe his toothache
would go away.
And the bacteria too!
[shrieks]
[both straining]
Ah-ha!
[narrator] There was
one thing left.
[giggles]
[narrator]
A toothbrush with toothpaste.
George's secret defense
against plaque.
Uh-oh! Brace yourselves.
[Rebecca] I'm skedaddlin'!
[Tribeca] Me too!
[Beckah] Wait for me!
♪♪
[liquid sucking]
[both cheering]
[Dr. Chu] George?
George?
-George?
-Huh?
Open wide.
Ahh...
[chitters]
You think
the problem is there?
Uh-huh. [mumbles]
I don't see any cavities.
Hmm. You're right!
There is something
caught in your teeth.
Got it!
Looks like a sesame seed.
How's that?
[chitters happily]
Then just rinse
and we're done.
No more toothache.
That's great news, doctor!
Zucchini muffin anyone?
-Sure.
-Yes, please.
[chitters]
[gargling]
Huh?
The Beck-Terias have left
the building.
[narrator] George hoped he never
saw those bacteria again.
But they sure could
carry a tune.
[upbeat music]
♪♪