[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[jazzy music]
♪♪
[narrator] George
and the Man With the Yellow Hat
had been invited by Mr. Quint
to go ice fishing.
[humming happily]
[narrator] George thought
he should practice.
The trouble was...
[grunts happily]
[narrator]
The ice weren't biting.
Hey, George.
What happened to all our...
George, you do realize
that ice fishing
doesn't mean fishing for ice?
[puzzled grunt]
Mr. Quint will show you.
Better go pack a coat,
hat, and mittens.
It's gonna be cold up north.
[chattering happily]
[exciting music]
♪♪
Mr. Quint?
We're here!
Well, hello, you two!
Come on in.
Thanks for the invitation.
I have always wanted to try
ice fishing.
Ooh!
[chattering excitedly]
Well, to get
where the fish are,
you have to drill a hole,
George!
Ahh.
[giggling]
George doesn't believe
that fish can live in the ice.
-Uh-uh.
-[Quint] See down there?
-[gasps]
-The fish are in the water.
Under the ice.
[puzzled grunting]
[chuckles]
No, George.
It takes an expert fisherman--
[clears throat]
Like me-- to catch them!
They don't just jump up
and say hello.
[rumbling]
[chattering in alarm]
Oh, my goodness!
[grunts]
Ahh!
[ice cracking]
Maybe they do jump up
and say hello.
-Ah!
-[gasps]
[chattering excitedly]
[playful music]
[gasps]
[narrator]
It was George's old friends,
Professors Einstein and Pizza.
[chattering happily]
Oh, my!
You look a lot like
our pal George.
Why, it is George!
What brings you up here,
fellas?
We're here
on an important mission.
But we're having trouble
with our sub.
Someone spilled his juice box
on the control panel.
Someone drives like this.
Whee! Whee!
At any rate, it appears that
we'll have to scrap the mission.
Aww.
[somber music]
Wait a minute, Einstein!
George is here!
[both gasp]
The minisub!
George, how would you like to
do some whale counting for us?
[chattering excitedly]
Um, that sounds like yes
to me.
[both] The mission is saved!
[whirring]
[upbeat music]
Okay, George, in you go.
♪♪
You remember how to use
all the controls?
[grunting happily]
[whirring]
Ah!
[embarrassed chattering]
[Quint] I got one!
I got a big one!
♪♪
Ooh.
Thanks, Mr. Quint.
George, this time of year,
several species of whales
are swimming
to their winter homes.
We're trying to track them
as they migrate.
Your mission is to count
the whales you see going by.
[chattering happily]
Now, see the screen
on your dashboard?
Uh-huh.
That shows
the different kinds of whales
you might encounter.
Ahh.
[Einstein]
Beluga whales are white,
bowhead whales are dark,
and narwhals have long tusks.
Ooh! [giggles]
Now, George,
whales aren't fish.
They come up to the surface
of the water to breathe air.
[Einstein] Some of them also
swim really deep,
so you'll have to look up
and down.
[grunting happily]
When you see
one of these whales,
just touch the picture
on the screen that matches it,
and the computer will count it.
[chattering happily]
Okay, George,
here we go!
♪♪
[grunting happily]
[upbeat jazzy music]
♪♪
[narrator] Mr. Quint was right.
There were a lot of fish
down here!
♪♪
Ahh.
[narrator] George knew
what seals looked like,
but he had never seen one
this close.
♪♪
[giggling]
[narrator] The walrus had never
seen a flying minisub before.
[huffs]
♪♪
[giggling]
[Pizza] Uh, George?
The mission?
[grunting excitedly]
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
So George got back to work.
He hoped to see the little seal
again afterwards.
♪♪
[monitor beeping]
He's on his way!
[sub puttering softly]
[gasps]
[narrator] What a big fish!
♪♪
George had found
his first whale,
and it was white.
A beluga whale.
[screen chimes]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] Could there be more?
[chattering in alarm]
[exciting music]
Hmm.
[narrator]
Number two was a bowhead.
George could tell
by its dark coloring.
One beluga...
[screen chimes]
And one bowhead.
George had already counted
two whales.
[upbeat jazzy music]
♪♪
[chattering in concentration]
Wow, great job, George!
Seven belugas
and five bowheads!
[chattering happily]
[Pizza] Hmm.
No narwhals yet.
They can dive deeper
than the others.
Why don't you try
going lower, George?
[grunting in agreement]
♪♪
[eerie call]
[narrator] George wondered what
was making that strange sound.
[soft clicking]
This whale had a tusk.
A narwhal!
In fact, a whole pod of them!
George knew
he'd better count fast.
Three over there,
and that one made four.
This one made five.
[grunting]
[narrator] And all those made...
[disappointed grunt]
[narrator] George wasn't going
to let anything stop him
from counting the rest.
♪♪
[determined grunt]
[crashing]
[narrator]
Except maybe an iceberg.
George, are you okay?
[static crackles]
[chattering excitedly]
I think he hit something.
An iceberg, maybe?
Perhaps.
[static crackling]
George, I think it's time
to head back.
We'll help you find your way.
[chattering happily]
Whoa, what happened?
Hmm.
The communications systems
must have been damaged!
♪♪
[narrator] George thought
he was heading home,
but it was hard to tell.
[grunting worriedly]
♪♪
[chattering]
[narrator] George didn't know
this whale...
♪♪
Because it was a seal!
[chattering excitedly]
♪♪
[narrator]
His friend had found him.
♪♪
[giggling]
[narrator] And he seemed to be
leading George somewhere.
♪♪
Ah!
[triumphant musical flourish]
♪♪
Oh, my!
I finally caught one!
-[gasps]
-Oh!
[chattering excitedly]
George!
You made it!
You're okay!
Tremendous work!
You saved the mission, George.
Hey! My fish!
[narrator] But George figured
the seal deserved it.
After all,
he'd led George home.
[chattering excitedly]
♪♪
Oh, well.
There are plenty more fish
where that came from.
Right, George?
Uh-huh!
[giggling]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[jazzy music]
[narrator] George loved visiting
the firehouse.
There were so many things
that made noise.
[bell ringing]
[grunting happily]
[horn blaring]
[narrator] But today,
George was being a very,
-very quiet little monkey.
-Shh, shh.
[floorboard creaks]
[gasps]
[narrator]
Because the firehouse band
was rehearsing for
the annual pancake breakfast.
♪♪
Hold it!
Hold it, everybody!
This music's kind of...
mm, I don't know,
lacking in something.
Yeah, like oomph and pizzazz.
-Exactly.
-We'll get it.
Let's just try it from the top.
And a-one, and a-two.
[jazzy music]
[narrator] George was doing
a pretty good job
-of being quiet...
-Shh.
[ball squeaking]
[gasps]
[narrator] So far.
[ball squeaks]
[grunts]
[clanging]
[chattering worriedly]
[ball squeaking]
[chattering in alarm]
Shh, shh.
[chattering worriedly]
[instruments clinking]
Whew.
[grunting]
[clattering]
[ball squeaks softly]
-Wow!
-George, you solved it!
That sounded great.
[puzzled chattering]
You sure did.
We needed some bang
with our bounce.
Nothing like the cymbals
to add pizzazz to music.
Hey, how about playing
the cymbals with us
at the pancake breakfast,
George?
[gasps]
Huh?
[chatters excitedly]
You're gonna love 'em.
The sound comes
from the vibrations
moving through the metal when--
[cymbals clash]
Ooh!
[giggling]
He's way ahead of you.
[cymbals clashing]
[grunting happily]
You ready to try playing
along with us?
[grunting happily]
Okay, let's do it.
And a-one, and a-two.
[jazzy music]
♪♪
[cymbals clashing]
[clashing out of rhythm]
[music stops]
Hold on, George!
[clashing continues]
George!
[puzzled grunting]
The music's played
in beats of four.
Listen.
One, two, three, four.
And on the fourth beat,
you clang the cymbals.
One, two, three, clang.
Got it?
Oh!
[chattering excitedly]
Okay, here we go.
And a-one, and a-two.
[jazzy music]
[puzzled grunting]
One, two, three...
-Now!
-[cymbals clash]
Great! Two, three...
-Now!
-[cymbals clash]
-[gasps]
-You've got it.
Big finish, George!
[musical flourish,
cymbals clash]
[chattering excitedly]
-Wow!
-Terrific!
-Sounds great!
-That was beautiful!
[grunting happily]
Practice as much as you can,
and you'll knock 'em out
at the concert tomorrow.
[chattering excitedly]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[chattering in rhythm]
Ah, ah, ah...
[cymbals clash]
[chattering in rhythm]
Ah, ah, ah...
[cymbals clash]
[narrator] George got so excited,
he forgot about
the one, two, three part.
[cymbals clashing]
[dog whines]
[clashing continues]
[glass shatters]
Hi, Mr. Zoobel, Mrs. Pippin.
-[clashing continues]
-Hey there, Hundley!
[dog whines]
Just wondering
if everything's okay?
-[clashing continues]
-Huh?
All that racket.
What?
-[clashing continues]
-The noise?
[shouting]
The noise?
Ooh, sorry.
I couldn't hear you.
George is practicing
for the pancake breakfast
at the firehouse.
[grunts excitedly]
-Say, George...
-[cymbals clash]
Is it possible to practice
a little more quietly?
Oh.
[narrator]
George wanted to cooperate...
[chattering]
[cymbals scraping softly]
[narrator]
But those soft little sounds
weren't going to cut it.
He needed a big loud...
[cymbals clash]
Maybe you should find
somewhere else
to practice, George.
[soft music]
[grunts excitedly]
[narrator] George needed a place
where he could be noisy.
The roof was perfect.
[chattering in rhythm]
Ah, ah, ah...
[cymbals clash]
[chattering in rhythm]
Ah, ah, ah...
[cymbals clash]
[narrator] George finally got it!
Time for the big finish.
[chattering in alarm]
[cymbal clanging]
[chattering worriedly]
♪♪
[disappointed chattering]
[grunting]
Aww.
[chattering frantically]
♪♪
Aha!
[grunting worriedly]
♪♪
[cymbal clanging]
[chattering in alarm]
[cymbal clattering]
♪♪
[grunting in distress]
[chattering worriedly]
[chattering frantically]
♪♪
[gasps]
[chattering]
♪♪
Aww.
[disappointed chattering]
[narrator] How was George going
to play in the concert
with just one cymbal?
-Well...
-Ah!
[narrator]
Maybe he only needed one.
[dull thud]
No, definitely needed two.
♪♪
[grunts excitedly]
[narrator] Maybe George
could find a replacement.
Something big and flat
just like his cymbal.
[chatters]
♪♪
[narrator] The book was a square
with four corners,
and the cymbal was a circle
with no corners.
Hmm.
[gasps, giggles]
[narrator]
Maybe what George needed
was a big, flat circle.
He knew just where to find one.
[chattering excitedly]
[dull clang]
Hmm.
[grunts happily]
[soft clang]
[grunts in distress, gasps]
[narrator] It was looking like
George wouldn't be able to play
in the pancake breakfast
tomorrow after all.
[pans clattering]
[grunting in alarm]
[loud clashing]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] George needed
his big, flat circle
to be made
of whatever that was.
[grunts]
[intrigued chattering]
[soft clang]
[grunts in frustration]
[louder clang]
[disappointed chattering]
[loud clashing]
[chattering happily]
Georgie!
What is going on?
[grunting happily]
[loud clashing]
Oh, I see you replaced one
of your cymbals, eh?
[chattering eagerly]
Oh, you want to borrow it.
Of course.
But take good care of it, eh?
[chattering excitedly]
♪♪
[narrator] With a cymbal
in each hand,
George was ready
for the breakfast.
[chattering in alarm]
[chattering worriedly]
[chattering]
♪♪
Hmm?
[gasps]
♪♪
[chattering worriedly]
[chattering]
♪♪
[chattering in alarm]
[toy cymbals clinking]
♪♪
[chattering]
[gasps, grunts]
♪♪
[breathing heavily]
[grunting happily]
[giggling]
Welcome to Firehouse 86's
annual pancake breakfast!
Eat up, everybody!
Let's hit it.
Ready, George?
Uh-huh, uh-huh!
And a-one, and a-two,
and a-three.
[jazzy music]
♪♪
[clashing in rhythm]
Love it, George!
[loud clash]
[chattering excitedly]
[laughing]
That's my lid.
[chuckles]
[giggling]
[cheers and applause]