[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[narrator] It was Autumn
in the country.
Leaves were falling...
And so were acorns.
Jumpy had stashed away
plenty for winter.
[chattering]
[narrator] But there was always
room for more.
[chittering]
[gasps]
[narrator] Jumpy's acorn stash
was gone!
He had just hidden those nuts.
Whoever had taken them
couldn't have gone far.
He just had to find
someone eating.
[door opens]
[munching happily]
[shrieks]
[narrator] The monkey!
[whirring]
George?
Come back and finish lunch.
[squeaks and giggles]
[gasps]
[narrator] The monkey was eating
Jumpy's nuts for lunch?
[gasps]
[narrator] Jumpy had to get
his acorns back!
He would watch that monkey
like a hawk.
"And his friend got into
the car and went home."
Good night, George.
[chattering sleepily]
[gasps]
Ah!
[chattering excitedly]
Oh, no.
You can play
with Jumpy tomorrow.
[mumbles sleepily]
[chattering excitedly]
[chittering angrily]
Huh?
[narrator] What Jumpy was
so grumpy about?
Ah! Ah!
[narrator] He liked nuts.
Maybe if George gave him
a nut, he'd feel better.
[shocked chittering]
[narrator]
Jumpy couldn't believe it!
The monkey was stealing acorns
right under his nose!
-[angry chittering]
-Huh?
Oh!
Huh.
[gasps and chitters] Ah!
[scoffs]
Huh?
[excited chattering]
[angry chittering]
Huh?
Ohh.
[narrator]
Jumpy had usually saved
more nuts than that
by Fall.
Someone might have
taken them.
[shocked chittering]
[narrator] And Jumpy seemed to
think that someone was George.
[hurt chittering] Uh-uh!
[narrator] If someone had
taken those nuts,
it was up to George
to find out who.
[nuts cracking]
Could those be Jumpy's nuts?
Hiya, George!
Want a piece of pie?
Fresh out of the oven.
Huh?
[narrator] But...
how could Mrs. Renkins
have gotten up Jumpy's tree?
Hmmm...
[exciting music]
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Nah!
[narrator] Not possible.
[gasps] Ah!
[narrator] There had been a storm
last night.
Maybe the wind blew so hard
the nuts rolled out of the tree.
And Mrs. Renkins found them.
Hm...
Ah! [chattering excitedly]
[narrator] George had to
tell Jumpy.
He would see
it was all a big mistake.
[chittering angrily]
[narrator] Jumpy could see
there was a mistake all right.
His nuts were acorns.
And those nuts were pecans!
Oh. Huh.
[narrator] Jumpy was right!
Mrs. Renkin's nuts were
different.
[scornful chittering]
[narrator]
So George kept looking.
[nuts cracking]
Ah... Huh.
[narrator] Could Bill's nuts
be Jumpy's?
-Ah.
-Oh, hi, George!
As Junior Sprout
Assistant Leader,
I'm in charge of testing
snack options for our next hike.
So far, this trail mix
is in first place.
Here, try some.
Nah.
[narrator] But how would Bill
have gotten Jumpy's nuts?
George realized the wind
must have
knocked the nuts
into Bill's yard.
Ah!
[narrator] George would tell
Jumpy,
Bill would return the nuts,
and Jumpy would be happy.
[both chittering]
[narrator] But a walnut
was not an acorn.
Ah.
Hmm...
[narrator] George could see
Jumpy was right.
These nuts were different.
Hm...
[Bill] Whoa, whoa, whoa George!
People don't eat acorns.
[confused chittering]
Well, not usually.
We prefer other nuts.
You know, walnuts, almonds,
pecans, cashews...
What have you.
Oh...
[narrator]
If people didn't like acorns,
an animal must have
taken Jumpy's acorns.
But which one?
Ah-ha!
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator]
Deer, turkey, crow,
bear, pig,
squirrel, raccoon.
All these animals ate acorns.
This needed more research.
[mumbling]
[gasps] Ooh. A-ha!
[gasps]
Oh. [giggles]
[narrator] George had never
seen him before.
He carried nuts in his cheeks,
just like Jumpy!
Ooh! Ah, ah!
Oh. [chattering excitedly]
[confused chittering]
[mumbling happily]
[gasps]
[chatters happily]
[narrator] George thought
he'd find the acorns
if he followed that little guy.
[angry chittering]
[narrator] And Jumpy thought
he'd find them
if he followed George.
Huh?
[narrator] The thing
also ate flower bulbs?
And seeds?
[chattering]
[chattering excitedly]
Huh?
Huh... [chattering]
[narrator] The little guy
stored food for winter
just like Jumpy did.
At last!
Jumpy had surely found where
the monkey stashed the nuts.
[George giggles]
[cheerful music]
♪♪
[angry squeaks]
Ah!
[angry chittering]
[calm chittering]
[narrator] It wasn't the monkey
after all.
Ah.
[angry squeaks]
[narrator] Jumpy wanted to give
that squirt a piece of his mind!
But...
that squirt was kind of cute.
Ohh... [giggles]
[narrator] And generous.
Jumpy didn't like
him taking his acorns...
But anyone could see he
was a good kid.
He just needed someone to show
him the ropes.
Someone with experience;
someone like...
Jumpy.
[both chittering]
[excited chattering]
Oh!
[George giggling]
I see you've made
a new friend.
Chipmunks are cute
aren't they?
Ah?
[narrator] A chipmunk?
So that's what that was.
Oh!
[Mrs. Renkins] Oh! My pecan pie!
Uh-oh...
♪♪
[both chittering]
Huh, that may be the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
Aww...
Ah!
[George giggling]
Ooh!
[narrator] Monkeys love Scotland.
It's a country with
interesting clothes...
[giggles]
[narrator]
Fun musical instruments...
[car horn honks]
And a monkey's uncle.
Step lively, laddies!
The Highland Games
wait for no man!
Uncle Tam!
[chattering excitedly]
[contented chittering]
That's Loch Ness, Georgie.
Loch is Scottish for lake.
And a bonnie loch
she is indeed.
Loch Ness?
As in Loch Ness Monster?
Ah! [fearful chittering]
[laughs] Don't worry, George;
it's just a story.
Oh.
Well, no man can say for sure.
Could be just a story.
But, on the other hand,
for hundreds o' years...
people have sighted
the prehistoric beast
that inhabits the deeps
o' the loch.
Oh! [impressed chittering]
Well, maybe we could take in
a little monster-watching
after the Highland Games.
[happy chittering]
[narrator]
But George couldn't wait.
If there was a Loch Ness
Monster,
he was going to see it...
even if it meant missing
part of the Highland Games.
[crowd exclaiming
and applauding]
[grunts]
[straining]
[cheers and applause]
Wow, I can't believe
they can throw those giant logs
like they're sticks.
The caber toss is
an old Scottish tradition.
And a tradition
for our family, as well.
Amazing.
Aye, but there's one
wee problem.
I got myself all practiced and
ready,
but woke up this mornin'
and my back's a wee bit sore.
[grunts] I thought
the family tradition
was to end here and now.
But then I remembered
who was coming!
Uh, who?
-You!
-Me?
The family tradition shall
remain unbroken.
You-- you want me to--
You mean, I'm gonna...
throw that tree?
Och, thank you, lad.
I'm touched.
Hmm... Huh?
[gasps]
[frantic chittering]
Ooh, a dark shape!
[ducks quacking]
[sighs]
It's just a bunch'a birds.
But keep lookin' Georgie!
[sighs]
[George] Hey!
[chattering]
Sure. You can go look.
[chatters contentedly]
[narrator] George wanted
to be the first monkey
ever to see
the Loch Ness Monster.
Hm... [chattering]
Huh?
[frightened chattering]
[straining]
[grunts]
[audience groans]
[grunting] Oof?
That's it, nephew!
Och, you've got
the family touch.
I can see it sure as day.
Ah, well... um...
[grunts]
[back cracks]
Oh, boy.
[frightened chittering]
Monster?
You found the
Loch Ness Monster?
[panting and chittering]
Uh-huh!
-Where?
-Where, George?
[George chattering]
[excited chittering]
[all panting]
I cannot see it!
Ooh, look at that, Georgie!
Oh, my goodness!
It's... it's...
[all gasp]
A scuba diver.
Och, that's just
Ewan MacDonald.
He's always diving in the loch.
[sighs]
Well, we better be getting back.
Keep a-lookin', Georgie!
Uh-huh.
[sighs]
♪♪
[thoughtful chittering]
Ah!
[straining]
Ahh!
Huh?
[grunts]
Ahhh!
[narrator] Monster!
[terrified chattering]
Another monster?
[frightened chattering]
[chattering]
It's there--
[softly] It's there?
Uh-huh.
[squeaks]
Ready?
One, two, three!
[Man in Yellow Hat groans]
[George sighs]
I tell ya Georgie,
Nessie is tricky.
As soon as she appears,
she vanishes.
Ah.
[narrator] How would George ever
share his discovery?
[George] Hmm...
Uh-huh!
We were right here, I believe.
Oh, I can go
to the back of the line.
Oh, no, no, no, please!
You were ahead of me, sir!
Oh, gee, thanks.
[narrator] George decided
he needed picture proof
of his discovery.
Ah!
[happy chattering]
Yay!
[grunting]
[sighs happily]
[narrator]
Now George would wait...
And wait...
and wait.
[sighs]
[creature snorting]
Oh!
[narrator] It was the monster!
[chattering]
[narrator] But it was on land
and Uncle Tam said
it lived in the lake.
[giggles]
[gasps]
Oh...
Oh!
[chattering]
Huh...
[creature lowing]
Huh?
[gasps and chatters]
[camera shutter clicks]
[groans]
[gasps]
[groans loudly]
Oh!
[creature snorting]
huh? Ooh.
[narrator]
How did the monster get there?
Maybe the monster could fly.
[shrieks]
Huh?
[creature snorting]
[narrator] It was another
Loch Ness Monster!
There were two of them!
[lowing]
[George shudders]
[narrator] No!
A whole family of monsters!
[chuckles nervously]
[chittering nervously]
[fearful chattering]
Ahh!
Uh... okay.
[straining]
All right, this is it!
Don't be nervous, laddie!
You can do it!
Show these weaklings
what we're made of!
Right. Okay.
Here goes.
[straining]
[cows lowing]
Behind you, laddie!
[chittering]
Whoa!
[cheers and applause]
Ahh!
[terrified chattering]
Those are nae monsters, George.
They're just cows.
They're Scottish cows!
Huh?
[cows lowing]
-Huh?
-Aye.
They may not look like
the cows you have back home,
but just the same,
cows they are.
Phew!
[narrator] It turned out
there weren't just
interesting clothes
in Scotland...
Ah.
[narrator]
But interesting cows too!
[giggles]
[narrator] And even though George
had not found the monster,
he'd made a whole herd
of new friends.
[camera shutters clicking]
[upbeat music]
♪♪