[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[light music]
♪♪
[plane humming]
[narrator] George loved
visiting the Maldives...
♪♪
Mostly because
of Uncle Hassan...
And now breathe calmly
in and out.
[narrator] Whose morning
ritual included yoga.
-[sighs happily]
-[grunting]
Oh!
♪♪
[narrator] He made them
traditional Maldivian food.
Not too spicy, I hope.
[chatters happily]
[coughs]
Just like your mom
used to make.
[narrator] And just
when George thought
it couldn't get any better,
it did.
Snorkeling?
Oh, that's a great idea.
And of course you can
use my boat.
-[grunts excitedly]
-You'll love it.
The coral reef is the home
of so many different
kinds of fish.
There are glass fish...
[grunts]
[Uncle Hassan] Parrot fish.
[squawks]
[Uncle Hassan] Butterfly fish,
and surgeon fish.
[grunts]
Ooh.
♪♪
[yawns]
George, are you ready
to go snorkeling?
Ahh.
[chatters excitedly]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
Ahh!
♪ Take a trip,
see somewhere new ♪
♪ Learn about what others
like to do ♪
[chomp]
♪ There's different words ♪
-♪ And different ways ♪
-[chatters happily]
♪ At every turn,
you'll be amazed ♪
♪ So head on out ♪
♪ There's so much to see ♪
♪ A million things to spark
your curiosity ♪
♪ There's something there
for every boy and girl ♪
♪ Let's learn about
the wonders of the world ♪
Huh?
[squeaks]
[grunts happily]
[squeaking]
♪♪
♪ So head on out ♪
♪ There's so much to see ♪
♪ A million things to spark
your curiosity ♪
♪ Yeah, there's
something there ♪
♪ For every boy and girl ♪
♪ Let's learn about
the wonders of the world ♪
[grunts happily]
[squeaking]
[chatters happily]
So the simplest route is
to go around this bit of land.
[narrator] George wanted
to bring his ball,
but was there an extra seat?
Oh.
Aha!
[chatters inquisitively]
Yes, George?
[grunts]
Sure, you can put
the ball in there.
♪♪
[grunting]
[groans]
[giggles]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
That seems easy enough.
Ready to get going, George?
[grunts happily]
All right, off we go.
♪♪
Bye, happy snorkeling!
-See you later!
-[chatters happily]
♪♪
Huh, that person must be
expecting a big emergency.
♪♪
Here, George, I'll steer
while you navigate.
[chatters happily]
We wanna keep going east.
Keep the E pointed
toward the front of the boat,
and make sure the red arrow
is pointed toward the N.
♪♪
If the red arrow moves away
from the N, let me know.
[grunts]
[narrator] Were those
George's dolphin friends?
[chatters happily]
Okay, George,
which way do we go?
[chatters excitedly]
♪♪
[narrator] George kept
trying to catch up
to his dolphin friends,
but it was difficult.
[grunts]
♪♪
[narrator] The day
was almost over.
I don't get it.
We should've reached
the reef long ago.
Hey, we're here!
That's the reef right there.
[grunts happily]
Hassan must've sent us
on the scenic route.
Ready to see a lot of fish?
-[grunts happily]
-Here we go.
♪♪
♪ Take a trip,
see somewhere new ♪
♪ Learn about what others
like to do ♪
[narrator] There really were
a lot of fish.
♪♪
There was one that could
blow itself up like a balloon.
♪♪
And one that looked like
a circus clown.
[laughs]
[narrator] And who knew
that glass fish had bones?
Ooh.
♪ Let's learn about
the wonders of the world ♪
♪♪
Wow, that was fun.
[chatters happily]
Better head back
if we want to get
to the village before dark.
[chatters happily]
[motor hums]
♪♪
[motor splutters]
Hmm.
♪♪
-Huh, must be out of gas.
-[chatters inquisitively]
No problem, just need
to refill it.
♪♪
[chatters happily]
Your beach ball,
that's right.
Here you go.
[grunts]
Huh?
Hmm.
Uh, George?
Did you take the extra gas can
out to make room
for the beach ball?
Uh-huh.
And the flashlight?
And the flares?
[giggles]
Ahh.
♪♪
Well, I guess we'll have
something to play with...
Until someone finds us.
♪♪
[laughs]
Catch, George.
Ooh, I got it, I got it.
Oh, good catch.
[chatters happily]
♪♪
[chatters unhappily]
Huh?
[man in the yellow hat]
What the...?
[both] Huh?
[thud]
Ooh.
[chatters excitedly]
George, what are you--?
Well, look who's here!
It's your buddies,
the dolphins.
[squeaking]
[grunts happily]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
[squeaking]
[grunts]
[clicks happily]
[squeaking]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
Huh?
Oh, wow, it's the dolphins.
They're stirring up
the bioluminescent plankton.
[chatters]
They're tiny, tiny
sea creatures.
Millions of them.
They give off a glow
when they're moved.
Ahh!
[clicks happily]
[humming]
[gasps]
George, you hear that?
[humming]
[George chatters excitedly]
It's a rescue plane!
[plane humming]
[chatters excitedly]
♪♪
Oh, I am happy to see you,
my friends.
How did you ever
come up with the plan
to get the dolphins to light up
the water like that?
Um, actually,
we were playing catch.
♪♪
[clicks happily]
[grunts excitedly]
[squeaking]
[laughs]
George that was amazing.
I'm glad you packed that ball.
[grunts happily]
♪ Let's learn about
the wonders of the world ♪
♪♪
[light music]
[narrator] George loved
the way the Renkins
had a special home
for each of their animals.
[chatters happily]
[narrator] The pigs lived
in the pig pen.
[chickens clucking]
The chickens lived
in the chicken coop.
And the horses lived
in the stable.
-[grunts happily]
-[neighs]
♪♪
Hmm...
[narrator] But George had never
seen that pen before.
What kind of animal
lived in there?
-Hiya, George?
-Ahh!
Aww.
[laughs]
Oh, sorry, didn't mean
to scare you.
Hey, you know what all these
are here for?
[chatters inquisitively]
[whispers]
People are going to sit on them
for the...
[yells]
Hootenanny!
[exclaiming and laughing]
[chatters inquisitively]
George, are you telling me
you've never been
to a hootenanny before?
Uh-uh.
Oh, yeah, well,
neither have I, but this year,
it's at our farm,
so I can stay up late and go.
And Grandma says
there's gonna be music.
-[gasps]
-And dancing even!
Ooh.
[chatters happily]
♪♪
[narrator] That night, George
couldn't stop thinking
about the hootenanny
when he heard...
[hooting]
[grunts]
[narrator] A hoot?
Huh?
[hooting]
[grunts]
[narrator] Maybe the hoots were
here for the hootenanny.
[giggles]
[narrator] Either way,
it sounded like an owl,
and George had to see it.
♪♪
[hooting]
[narrator] Where was
the hoot coming from?
[hooting]
[narrator] Could it be
from inside the jug?
It was too dark
to see anything...
[hooting]
But George sure could hear it.
[chatters excitedly]
[narrator] Maybe this jug was
an owl's special home.
♪♪
It must be a baby jug owl.
[hooting]
[grunts]
[narrator] George wondered if
anyone was taking care of it.
He decided he would.
He'd keep it warm.
♪♪
He fed it...
and snuggled it to bed.
The jug owl was quiet.
It must have fallen asleep.
George couldn't wait
to tell Allie about it.
Hoo, hoo, hoo.
[chatters]
An owl, huh?
I can't see it.
[chatters]
[hooting]
There is an owl in there!
Uh-huh!
[chatters happily]
You know, an owl
small enough to fit
in that jug has
got to be a baby.
[chatters]
So there's probably
a mommy jug owl nearby.
[chatters]
[chatters excitedly]
Good idea, maybe she's
in the barn
in one of Grandma's old jugs.
♪♪
[chatters]
Yep, it's owl-less.
The mommy jug owl must be
in a different jug.
♪♪
Not in here either.
[hooting]
[chatters excitedly]
[laughs]
We found the mommy!
[chatters excitedly]
George and Allie were ready
to show the jug owl family
a good time.
♪♪
[quacking]
[hooting]
[laughter]
[both] Hoo, hoo!
The jug owls have had
a long day, George.
Maybe it's time for the baby
to take a nap.
[grunts]
♪♪
[gentle music]
George, have you seen
my valve oil?
[tuba plays]
[both] Shh!
[grunts quietly]
Ooh, sorry, I didn't know
your jug was sleeping.
♪♪
[narrator] After the nap,
George and Allie for ready
for more play.
[shattering]
Ahh!
[chatters sadly]
But we would've seen it
fly away.
I heard a crash.
Everybody okay?
[chatters anxiously]
Yeah, a baby owl
lived in that jug,
but it broke and now
the owl is gone.
Whoa, whoa, you think
an owl lives in that jug?
Uh-huh.
Well, not anymore,
but we don't know
where it went.
[hooting]
[both gasp]
-Hey!
-[grunts happily]
-Do you hear it?
-Oh, well,
that does sound like
the hoot of an owl.
[chatters excitedly]
But it's not.
-Hmm...
-It's not?
That's the sound a jug makes
when wind blows
over the opening.
Listen.
-[hooting]
-See?
The wind pushes air
in and out of the jug.
-Huh.
-[grunts]
Which create vibrations,
which make sound.
[chatters inquisitively]
Yeah, you can also
use your breath.
Let me see.
[hooting]
[exclaiming]
[chatters excitedly]
Here you go.
[chatters]
[inhales deeply]
[lips buzzing]
Aww.
It just takes practice,
George.
Keep at it, and you'll be
hooting in no time.
♪♪
[lips buzzing]
[narrator] George found
that practicing took
a lot of patience.
[hooting]
[chatters happily]
You did it, George!
Can I try now?
[chatters happily]
[inhales deeply]
[hooting]
[laughs]
That's the greatest thing ever!
[bonk]
[laughter]
You know what we need?
-Another jug!
-[chatters]
[laughter]
♪♪
[high-pitched hooting]
[hooting]
[narrator] George wondered why
the jugs made different sounds.
[high-pitched hooting]
♪♪
Who played the jug
didn't matter.
[high-pitched hooting]
[hooting]
Where they played
didn't either.
Maybe it was the size
that changed the sound.
George needed more jugs
to figure it out.
[higher-pitched hooting]
[high-pitched hooting]
[hooting]
[low-pitched hooting]
[lower-pitched hooting]
George was right.
The size of the jugs made
the difference.
[higher-pitched hooting]
[high-pitched hooting]
The small jugs made
high tooting sounds.
[low-pitched hooting]
[lower-pitched hooting]
The big jugs made deep,
low sounds.
I thought you kids
might be thirsty
after working all day on
whatever it is you're doing.
-[grunts]
-Thanks, Grandma!
♪♪
Oh, you think these would work?
[chatters]
[highest-pitched hooting]
Yep, they hoot all right!
[chatters]
♪♪
[slightly lower hooting]
[both gasp]
Hang on, it changed!
How come it changed?
[chatters]
[narrator] The bottles were
exactly the same size.
So what else could it be?
[slightly lower hooting]
[chatters excitedly]
[gasps]
The water!
[grunts]
♪♪
[lower hooting]
[narrator] The amount of water
in the bottle
definitely changed the hoot.
[lower hooting]
[even lower hooting]
♪♪
[laughter]
[narrator] And without water,
they hooted the same.
[chatters happily]
Yeah, more water!
[chatters excitedly]
♪♪
[hooting]
Look, George, everybody's
showing up for our hootenanny.
[chatters excitedly]
♪♪
[chatters inquisitively]
[chattering]
Yeah, they're not here.
Grandma, when's
the band coming?
It isn't.
-[grunts]
-They're not?
'Cause in a hootenanny,
we are the band.
-We are?
-[grunts happily]
Uh-huh, a hootenanny
is about everybody
making music together.
Oh!
[giggles]
[tuba playing]
Huh?
And you can't have
a hootenanny without a tuba.
[tuba playing]
[laughs]
I brought you an instrument
too, George.
Ooh.
[chatters happily]
You wanna play those instead?
[chatters excitedly]
I can't wait to hear it.
[hooting]
[folk music plays]
♪♪
[hooting]
[both gasp]
♪♪
[hooting]
[upbeat music]
♪♪