[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat piano music]
♪♪
[narrator] There's nothing
a little monkey likes better
than playing in the sand
at the beach...
[grunting happily]
[grunting surprisingly]
[narrator] Except for finding
seashells!
Ha, looks like the ocean
gave you a present, George!
[chattering happily]
Oh, George, we better hurry!
Our tour of the marine rehab
center starts in a few minutes.
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] George liked having
his special shell.
[grunting worriedly]
[narrator] But he didn't
want it to break.
[chattering happily]
-Hello?
-[grunting happily]
-Well, hello!
[narrator] George didn't know he
was going to see his friends,
Professors Einstein
and Pizza.
Thanks for inviting us
to check out your marine lab.
Our pleasure!
We love sharing our underwater
world with visitors.
And we're hoping you'll help
us clean the fish tanks later.
[chattering excitedly]
[piano music]
Wow... those are a lot
of fish tanks.
[grunting happily]
[counting indistinctly]
[narrator] George had never seen
an animal with eight arms
before.
[grunting curiously]
Why, that's Octavia
the octopus.
And like all octopuses,
she's very smart.
[chattering thoughtfully]
[narrator] George could do a lot
with four hands,
but what could he do
if he had eight?
[dog barking]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] George noticed one
of Octavia's arms was short.
-[chattering curiously]
-Oh, she's fine.
Before Octavia came to us, she
must have lost one of her arms.
Luckily she's an octopus,
so it's growing back.
Oh, wait, what?!
That's right; an octopus can
re-grow an arm.
Not only that, she can taste
with her arms, too!
Here, hold this out,
George.
She's tasting it with her arms
the way you taste
with your tongue.
[chattering curiously]
[narrator] George wondered what
it would be like
to taste something
with his arms.
[slurping happily]
[grunting and spitting]
[man in yellow hat]
Look, George.
Seahorses!
[grunting excitedly]
[narrator] The seahorses
were beautiful.
Their bright colors reminded
George of his shell.
George realized
he'd put his seashell
on the table earlier.
[chattering worriedly]
What's the matter,
George?
[grunting worriedly]
You're looking
for your shell?
Uh-huh.
Hm, well...
Maybe you dropped it somewhere?
Uh-uh.
[narrator] But George hadn't
dropped it.
He'd left it on the table.
He was sure of that.
Well, it wouldn't be the
first thing
that's gone missing 'round
here, lately.
Oh, no. Just yesterday I left
my shoes in the lab
and one of them disappeared
too!
[giggling]
Anyway, don't worry, George.
There are lots of shells
around here.
We'll find you one that's just
as nice.
[grunting sadly]
[narrator] But George wanted
his shell.
The one the ocean
had given him.
But...
where could it be?
[grunting in surprise]
[narrator] What was a snake
doing in water?
[chattering curiously]
[narrator] Maybe the snake took
George's shell.
And then hid out
in the fish tank.
Aha!
[chattering happily]
Oh, he can't come
out of the tank, George.
That's an eel.
[chattering curiously]
Eels are a kind of fish.
A long, skinny fish.
[narrator] If the eel couldn't
come out of the water,
it couldn't have taken
George's shell.
Or Professor Einstein's shoe.
So where was it?
[man in yellow hat] Wow!
Scallops!
-See those?
-Uh-huh.
Scallops, clams and oysters
are animals
that live in shells,
like the animal that lived
in your shell.
[chattering curiously]
[narrator] George wondered what
happened
when those animals wanted
a new house.
[upbeat instrumental music]
Hm.
[grunting curiously]
Scallops get around by
clapping their shells together
to squirt water out.
We call it "jet propulsion."
They move like that because
they don't have hands or feet.
[chattering confusingly]
[narrator] No hands meant
scallops
probably couldn't use
fishing poles.
So they couldn't have taken
George's shell, either.
Has anyone seen my mug?
[chattering surprisingly]
[narrator] This was becoming
very mysterious.
Not again!
Why does everything
keep disappearing?
Maybe you simply left it
in the other room.
Let's look.
Come on, George, let's see
the rest of the lab.
[chattering happily]
[grunting thoughtfully]
[narrator] Someone had taken
the kitten mug, the shell,
and the shoe.
He didn't know who did it...
but he had a pretty good idea
what they looked like.
[man in yellow hat] Look at
that shell!
[grunting happily]
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] It was a shell,
all right.
But it wasn't George's.
That's a loggerhead sea
turtle.
[giggles]
She's injured so we're taking
care of her until she heals.
[chattering sadly]
[narrator] George wondered...
Could the sea turtle be the one
taking things?
Those flippers make them
very fast in the water,
but on land they're quite slow.
[chattering curiously]
[narrator] If the turtle was
slow on land,
it probably didn't steal
George's shell.
Still, it was worth a look.
Hm...
Hm. Maybe it's time we
cleaned the turtle enclosure.
And if you're up for it,
we could use two extra hands.
[chattering excitedly]
Ha! He's right!
Four extra hands.
Oh, I'll help. Even though
I only have two hands.
Every hand helps.
We'll need some sponges
and a bucket.
[grunting happily]
[narrator] Luckily George had
brought his own bucket.
Where was it?
[chattering unhappily]
[narrator] George couldn't
believe it!
Someone had stolen
the octopus too!
Huh?
[narrator] His bucket!
What was it doing over there?
[chattering in confusion]
Aha!
[giggling]
[exclaims]
[chattering excitedly]
What is it, George?
[grunting happily]
[all] Hmmm...
-[gasps]
-Wow.
[Professor Einstein] You did it!
You solved the mystery,
George!
So this is where
everything went!
[chattering happily]
But how did the octopus get
those things into the water?
Octopuses live in water,
but they can venture onto land
for short periods of time.
[chattering curiously]
Yeah, why did Octavia take
all these things?
Well, in nature,
octopuses collect things like
shells and coconut husks
to use for protection
near their dens.
Like my shoe.
And my coffee mug.
[chattering happily]
And your shell, exactly.
The collection is called
an octopus' garden.
[grunting happily]
[groaning]
Guess we'll need to
secure this lid
so she doesn't keep
getting out.
[chattering in distress]
[narrator] George liked
his shell,
but he knew someone
who liked it even more.
[chattering happily]
Why, it looks like
that's how an octopus says
"thank you," George.
[grunting happily]
That was very generous
of you, George.
[giggling sheepishly]
You can come back and visit
Octavia and your shell anytime.
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] George thought
that any seashell
that got to be a part
of an octopus' garden
was one lucky shell.
[upbeat piano music]
[man in yellow hat]
I solemnly promise...
[grunting thoughtfully]
To never, ever tell...
[grunting somberly]
The super-top-secret
ingredient...
[chattering thoughtfully]
In great-great-grandpa
Bernie's...
[chattering]
Banana bread.
Secret handshake.
[chattering excitedly]
Okay.
The super-secret ingredient
in great-great-grandpa Bernie's
banana bread is...
[speaking quietly]
almond butter.
Mm-hmm. It keeps it
moist and nutty.
I think the Renkins
will love it.
[chattering happily]
First, we mix the dry
ingredients.
One teaspoon baking powder...
and one of salt.
Hit it.
[chattering happily]
Now sift!
[chattering excitedly]
Okay.
When you're done,
we'll combine that
with this bowl of butter
and eggs and mi--
Oh, hmm...
Where is it?
[grunting curiously]
Well, to make Grandpa
Bernie's banana bread,
you need
a very special tool.
[sighs]
Ah! I know.
[cupboard squeaking]
Found it!
This was handed down from
great grandfather Bernie
to my grandfather,
who gave it to my dad.
His mixer.
[chattering amazingly]
Hey, do you want to do
the mixing, George?
[gasps]
[chattering excitedly]
[chuckles]
Okay, you're on!
Give it a crank.
[mixer squeaking]
Hm. Hang on.
Hm.
Aww.
Well, it looks like Grandpa's
hand mixer has mixed
its last banana bread.
[chattering sadly]
Well... Luke and Ada probably
sell one just like it
-in their store.
-Ah!
[squeaking noises]
George, do you mind squeaking
that mixer a little less?
[squeaking noises]
[chattering curiously]
Yeah, it's a bit--
[engine grinding]
Uh-oh.
[narrator] Just like
little monkeys
sometimes visited the doctor...
cars sometimes visited the
repair shop.
Sounds like you could use
a checkup.
[door squeaking]
Yeah, you seem to have a
problem with lubrication.
Like...
[door squeaking]
Ya hear that?
Squeaks.
You see? The two metal parts
in that hinge are rubbing
against each other.
That's what gives you a squeak.
Now, your car has lots
of moving parts.
To keep them running smoothly,
you need one magic ingredient.
[chattering curiously]
Oil.
[grunting happily]
Your car has a way of keeping
itself oiled.
But if it runs out of oil...
[imitates squeaky sounds]
Exactly.
[chattering happily]
[chuckles]
Why sure, you can oil it!
Just put a drop on the hinge.
[grunting astonishingly]
Yup! No more squeaks!
[grunting happily]
Ah, the mixer.
[mixer squeaking]
[chattering frustratingly]
Ah. I see your problem.
[chattering happily]
Ha. Good idea, George.
But we'll need to use cooking
oil for this.
We just need a teeny-tiny bit.
Uh-huh.
Okay, only put a drop
on the gears.
Um.
I think some got on the gears.
[chattering excitedly]
[mixer whirring]
Hey, we fixed it!
[grunting happily]
Okay. Let's do some mixing!
[grunting in agreement]
That's it George,
you've got the touch!
[mixer whirring rapidly]
Huh?
Oh, looks like the batter
jammed the mixer.
We'll just clean it out
and take it slower.
[soft instrumental music]
♪♪
Perfect.
We're meeting the Renkins
at 4:00,
so the bread will be
nice and hot.
Right out of the oven.
[cupboard door squeaking]
[grunting excitedly]
[chattering thoughtfully]
You're right, George.
[cupboard drawer squeaking]
We'll need the oil
from my toolbox for this.
[cupboard drawer squeaking]
[chattering excitedly]
Okay.
[cupboard door squeaking]
[narrator] George conquered
all the squeaks in the kitchen.
But he was pretty sure there
were more hiding in the house.
[clock squeaking]
[grunting excitedly]
[upbeat piano music]
♪♪
Huh...
[grunting happily]
[clock bird chirping]
[gasps]
4:00!
We're late!
[panting]
Burning bread!
Burning! Bread!
Huh? Not burning bread?
It's only 3:00?
[chatters]
[chattering happily]
[clock bird chirping]
[squirrel shrieking]
[water knob squeaking]
[narrator] It turned out there
were a lot
of squeaks in the country.
And George was going to find
them all.
[seesaw squeaking]
[grunting happily]
[grunting excitedly]
[sign squeaking]
[chattering curiously]
[gruntingly happily]
[squeaking noises]
Huh?
Ah!
[narrator] George found
some squeaks
couldn't be fixed with oil.
But they could be fixed
with cheese.
[squeaking noises]
[grunting excitedly]
[weathervane squeaking]
[narrator] Thanks to one little
monkey with an oil can,
the country was squeak-less!
[clock dings]
4:00! George was late!
[bicycle gears squeaking]
[grunting excitedly]
[narrator] Maybe Bill
could help.
Oh, I'd love to give you a
ride to the Renkins', George,
but I left my bike out in the
rain and...
now the gears barely
want to move.
[chattering excitedly]
You've got oil?
[bicycle wheels whirring]
[both] Weee!
[Bill] Weee!
[laughs]
-[chattering happily]
-George, there you are!
You two are just in time
for some banana bread.
Come on in!
[chattering happily]
Oh, this must be
the top-secret banana bread
I've been hearing so much
about.
[grunting happily]
Can't wait to taste it!
[squeaking noises]
[grunting curiously]
[squeaking noise]
Aha!
-No George! Wait!
-Whoa, whoa!
[grunting worriedly]
[narrator] George had learned
how to make things slippery,
but how could he make them
un-slippery?
Then he remembered the mixer.
Flour made the gears stick.
Would it work on shoes?
[Mr. Redkins] Whoa! Ah! Ah!
[narrator] There was only one
way to find out.
[grunting excitedly]
Whoa! Ah!
Whoa, that was pretty fast
thinking, George.
Saved the day!
[chattering sheepishly]
Here you go.
Grandpa Bernie's Super-Secret
Banana Bread.
Don't wait, dig in!
Mmm... oh, that is...
Mmm-mmm-mmm!
Mmm... Oh, that is
delicious! Mmm.
Mmm... Do I taste...
almond butter?
[both] Uh-oh.
I solemnly promise
to never, ever
tell the secret ingredient...
[Redkins and Bill] I solemnly
promise to never, ever
tell the secret ingredient...
[man in yellow hat]
In great-great-grandpa
Bernie's banana bread.
[Redkins and Bill]
In great-great-grandpa
Bernie's banana bread.
[jazz music]
♪♪