[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[smooth jazz music]
♪♪
[hooting]
[narrator] George was
a going to a new country
where they did things
differently,
and he wanted to be prepared.
Oh. [gibbering]
George is really excited
about going to Japan,
Mr. Okano.
He's just about
mastered his chopsticks.
Whoa, whoa, yi!
I can see that.
Hello, George.
George, say hi to my old
friend, Mr. Okano.
He's helping me research
the museum's
new Snow Festival exhibit.
Ah, hi!
Huh?
Ah! [hooting]
Nice to meet you, George.
See you soon!
Bye!
[crash]
Argh!
[narrator] George could hardly
wait to get to Japan.
[gong sounds]
[upbeat music]
♪ Take a trip,
see somewhere new ♪
♪ Learn about what others
like to do ♪
♪♪
♪ There's different words
and different ways ♪
♪ At every turn
you'll be amazed ♪
♪♪
♪ So head on out ♪
♪ There's so much to see ♪
♪♪
♪ A million things to spark ♪
♪ Your curiosity ♪
♪♪
♪ There's something there
for every boy and girl ♪
♪♪
♪ Let's learn about the wonders
of the world ♪
-Ah!
-Wow.
Automatic doors!
♪ A new way
to say hello ♪
♪ Take a seat my friend ♪
♪ Get in the flow ♪
♪ With an open heart ♪
Yay! [laughing]
♪ And open mind ♪
Ah, ah? Hey.
♪ So many sights to see ♪
♪ Let's explore
the possibilities ♪
♪ It's a show ♪
♪ We're ready to go ♪
♪♪
♪ So let's learn about
the wonders of the world ♪
♪♪
Ahh.
Ah! [chattering happily]
Aw, I know, George.
It's wonderful.
[dramatic music]
Welcome to the Snow Festival.
Ah, hello, Mr. Okano.
George, did you know he's the
director of the Snow Festival?
Konnichiwa.
Huh?
That means hello in Japanese.
Ah! [gibbering]
Ready for the big tour,
George?
[chattering]
How about starting
with some sushi?
[gibbering]?
Oh, sushi is delicious--
fresh raw fish,
which is prepared by
specially trained chefs.
[hooting]
Ohh!
Ah-ah!
[chomping] Ah!
[chuckles]
I'm glad you like it.
Ah!
Now, have a look over here.
[narrator] So far, George's trip
was everything he'd hoped for.
-[squealing]
-Huh?
Eh?
[narrator] Another monkey
to play with?
[gibbering]
Ooh.
[upbeat music]
♪♪
Wow. Pretty fantastic,
huh, George?
George?
Oh, looks like George
found some new friends.
Oh, dear. George!
Be careful!
[all hooting]
Aw... huh?
Those are wild
Japanese snow monkeys.
Wow!
Right here in town?
Yes.
They're very smart--
and unfortunately,
very mischievous.
[chittering]
[shrieking]
Sorry, George, but it's
better to leave them alone
if you don't want trouble.
Aww. [whimpering]
Do not worry.
There's lots more to do
at the festival.
Follow me.
Ah, okay.
Ah!
[drumbeat]
♪♪
George, you found
the kumi-daiko drummers.
A popular sight
at the Festival.
Ooh!
[humming]
[all chittering]
And these sculptures are
the heart of the festival.
Wow!
Artists come from
around the world
to carve them.
Ooh! [hooting]
[chattering happily]
Yes, George, they all start
with a big mound of snow.
Oh. [giggling]
The snow is good material
for sculpting
because it packs really well.
Oh.
[chattering]
Ah!
The artists have spent days
carving these masterpieces.
Wow!
But all work must finish
by tomorrow;
that is when the judges
pick a winner,
and it is a great honor.
[chatters excitedly]
Whoa, ooh-ooh-ah!
Ahh!
[man in yellow hat]
Yeah, that is some dragon!
Do you think I could
interview the artists?
Of course!
You've picked my favorites.
Meet my niece, Yuki...
Konnichiwa.
And her husband, Seiji.
-Konnichiwa.
-[gibbering]
And that is my Uncle Hideki.
He has been carving snow
sculptures for decades.
[George shouting]
Huh? Chisel!
He is a master craftsman--
but also a little clumsy.
[hooting]
Domo arigato.
Thank you.
Maybe with your help,
this will be the year we
finally win the contest.
[chattering]
We use special tools
to carve the snow,
like this one for the lines.
Oh, I see.
Would you like to try,
George?
Ooh!
[chattering excitedly]
You can practice over there.
Aha!
Let me show you some
of our other tools.
[humming]
Ah!
[gasps]
Ah?
Ah.
[giggling]
Huh?
[narrator] George remembered
that the snow monkeys
could be trouble.
But what harm could there be
in throwing one
little snowball?
Ehhh!
[all chittering]
Ah! Huh?
[narrator] The snow monkeys
played to win.
[yelping]
Uh, I guess George is ready
for the rest of the tour.
I have
arranged for you to see
one of our oldest Japanese
traditions,
the tea ceremony.
Oooh, [gibbering].
You two enjoy.
I must return to the festival.
Bye.
Thanks again, Mr. Okano.
[whispering]
Now, remember, George,
we have to be quiet.
It's a formal ceremony.
[muttering]
[traditional music]
♪♪
Oooh!
Huh?
Mmm.
[gulps] Ha!
[gasps]
[snow monkey chittering]
[chatters frantically]
[both] Shh.
Quiet, George.
Sorry.
[all chittering]
[narrator] The snow monkeys?
They could upset the whole
tea ceremony!
[gasps]
[whispering] George,
where are you going?
[both] Shhhh!
[chuckles nervously]
[all hooting and hollering]
Augh!
Ooh, ooh, ahh!
Shh.
[narrator] George explained
that the snow monkeys
had to be quiet
and he couldn't play.
But, something got lost
in the translation.
[monkeys hooting]
Oh, no!
[screeching]
[chatters frantically]
Uh, what do you say we
get out of here
before they come back, huh?
[murmurs]
Ah.
[gibbering]
[chuckles]
That's origami, George.
A Japanese art form.
By folding paper,
you can make all sorts
of things.
Oh.
[gibbering]
Sure, let's both do it.
Fold the paper in half.
Aha.
Got it?
[squealing]
Then fold the top corners
down, like so.
[chattering]
-Aw?
-Now fold the bottom piece up,
and you have a hat.
Here you go, monkey.
Ahhh.
Yeah.
Huh?
Huh?!
Hey!
[monkeys chittering]
[hooting]
George, wait!
Remember what Mr. Okano said!
[hollering]
Whee!
[laughing]
Ha, ha!
[chittering]
[hooting]
Whoa!
I'm coming, George!
Whoa! Coming through!
Pardon me.
[grunting]
Here I am, George.
Wh-wh-wh-whoa!
[crash]
[monkeys laughing]
[sighs]
Maybe it's time to call it
a day, huh, George?
[murmuring]
Goodnight, George.
[murmurs]
[narrator]
George was disappointed
he didn't get to enjoy
the whole tour,
all because of those
snow monkeys.
Ahhh.
[narrator] But maybe there
was a way
he could avoid them tomorrow.
Come on, George.
We don't want to be late
for the snow sculptures.
Huh?
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ah.
[giggles]
George!
Oh, okay, I really like how
you're embracing
Japanese culture.
[murmurs]
[narrator] George was certain
that if his friend
didn't recognize him,
neither would the snow monkeys.
[indistinct chatter]
This is the big day, George.
Boy, I really hope Mr. Okano's
family wins today.
[chattering happily]
Uh, huh? [gasps]
[monkeys gibbering]
Uh-oh.
[humming]
[light dramatic music]
[gasps]
[grunts]
[straining]
[laughter]
Aww!
[all hooting and hollering]
[grunts]
Whew.
Ahhh.
Hi, everybody.
Wow, your sculpture
looks amazing!
I'm glad you think so.
The judges will be coming soon,
and we're almost finished.
Chisel!
Sorry! I mean, I left
the chisel in the tool bag.
I need it to carve the eyes.
I'll get it.
That's funny, I could've sworn
I put the chisel in here.
Maybe Seiji has it...
Uh?
Huh.
Aw.
[narrator]
George knew those prints
in the snow weren't his.
That could only
mean one thing...
[chittering]
Hey!
[chattering excitedly]
[laughter]
Hey!
[all gibbering]
[chittering]
Aha!
Hmm...
[dramatic music]
♪♪
Aw!
[growling]
[hooting]
[upbeat jazzy music]
♪♪
Uh?
[narrator] How was he
going to get to that rock?
[chittering]
[narrator] Maybe he could swim--
but the water was
probably freezing.
It wasn't.
It was as warm as a bathtub.
[splash]
[calm music]
♪♪
[gasps]
[narrator] The chisel!
[all jabbering]
Aha! Yeah!
[both straining]
Ahhh!
Ooh!
Ooh.
Yeah! Ha, ha!
[muttering]
[panting]
[gasps] You found it!
And just in time.
Arigato, George.
[chatters]
-Finished!
-Hooray!
-Good job, Uncle.
-We did it!
[sighs]
I did not think we
were going to make it.
[gasps]
Ladder!
[overlapping shouts]
[man in yellow hat] Oh, boy.
That's not good.
-[gong sounds]
-The gong!
Here come the judges.
[Yuki] We don't have much time.
How will we ever get
enough snow up there
to carve a new one?
[whimpering]
I wish we could help, too,
George.
[monkeys jabbering]
[narrator] George realized
there was something
he could do.
But he would need help.
Hey! [hooting]
[taunting]
[all chittering]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
Hey! Ah, ah!
[laughing]
Wait, George. This isn't a
good time for a snowball fight.
Aha!
It is a good time
for a snowball fight!
More to the left, George.
[chittering]
♪♪
[narrator] Luckily for George,
this snow stuck together
really well.
Oh.
[chittering]
Here you go, George!
[grunting]
-We have done it!
-Yeah!
[gasps] Look!
The judges!
We're next!
[monkeys grunting]
[shouting]
[laughing]
Whee!
Ha, ha, ha!
We award this dragon
a prize for best sculpture.
-We won!
-We did it!
-[hooting]
-Good job, everybody!
[chattering]
[all hooting excitedly]
[narrator] George was happy
for all his new friends.
Especially the furry ones.
Hey!
Nice, George.
Your origami display is
sure to be a big hit.
Now the exhibit is complete.
Ah!
[fanfare]
Aw.
[confused chattering]
[chuckles] Don't worry.
I didn't forget
your favorite part.
Huh?
[gasps] Ah!
♪ So let's learn about
the wonders of the world ♪
[upbeat jazz music]
♪♪