[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat ragtime music]
♪♪
[narrator]
It was late summer,
and everyone's garden
was full of
all kinds of fresh fruits
and vegetables.
♪♪
Except George's.
-All he had were...
-Cucumbers.
[chattering happily]
And... more cucumbers.
[laughs]
Um, George?
Next time, try to plant
different kinds of seeds,
instead of all the same kind.
Oh...
[grunts comprehendingly]
[laughs]
[grunts obligingly]
Well,
good thing I like cucumbers.
[chattering happily]
Let's find
some more containers.
We can't leave those
on the vine.
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
It took all the pots, bowls,
hats,
and a few boots, too.
[grunting happily]
[narrator] But they finally got
all the cucumbers
out of the garden...
-Oh!
-[grunts in alarm]
[narrator] And into the house.
[both laughing]
[grunting happily]
Good job!
[quiet piano music]
Only...
What do we do
with the rest of them?
Hmm...
[narrator] Maybe they
could build cucumber houses.
[gasps]
[grunts dejectedly]
[narrator] Or cucumber boats?
[fish chomps]
Uh-uh.
[narrator]
Cucumber action figures?
[sighs]
[Bill] Hi, George!
I gotta feed the rabbits,
and I thought maybe
you'd like to--
Wow, that's a lot of cucumbers.
[grunting happily]
[chattering happily]
Gee, thanks, George.
I do love a fresh cucumber.
[grunting happily]
[upbeat piano music]
Cool.
I bet the bunnies
will like some, too.
[chattering generously]
[laughs]
Whoa, George.
Rabbits do eat a lot,
but they could never eat
all those
before they went bad.
[grunts dejectedly]
The other neighbors
might want some, though.
[chattering happily]
Yeah.
I'm not a city kid like you,
but I have my moments.
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[laughs]
[coins jingling]
♪♪
[grunts generously]
[narrator] George gave cucumbers
to every person he saw.
[grunting happily]
♪♪
[cow mooing]
[narrator] He even
gave cucumbers to people
who weren't people.
But he still had
a lot of cucumbers left.
Oh, no thanks, George.
I have plenty of cucumbers
already.
See?
♪♪
[narrator]
Those weren't cucumbers.
They were pickles.
[chatters incredulously]
No, really.
Pickles come from cucumbers.
[grunts confusedly]
They sure do.
There's no such thing
as a pickle tree, George.
[laughs]
[snaps fingers] You oughtta
pickle those, too.
[grunts inquisitively]
It's easy.
I'll show you.
First, I boiled these cucumbers
for a few minutes,
then drained out the water.
It's called blanching.
Now,
I'm ready to make my brine.
That's my pickling liquid.
Brine is a boiled mixture
of salt, vinegar,
and water.
[sniffs]
[grunts disgustedly]
[flame whooshes]
[laughs]
Oh, my, well, vinegar
is in a lot of salad dressings,
but it's also used
for pickling.
It makes the cucumbers ferment.
[grunts uncomprehendingly]
"Ferment"
is a fancy way of saying
a food changes so that
it won't spoil.
[grunts understandingly]
Uh...
[chatters curiously]
Oh, well,
we pour the brine
over the cucumbers...
[upbeat music]
Cover it up...
And this is where
it gets hard.
[chatters curiously]
We wait.
[grunts dejectedly]
Get comfy.
Pickling whole cucumbers
takes about two weeks.
[grunts impatiently]
Mm-hm.
But it's worth the wait.
[pickle crunching]
Mm...
[sighs]
Pickling is a delicious way
to keep things from going bad.
[pickle crunches]
By the time
you've pickled all of those,
that batch'll be done.
[grunts amiably]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[narrator] Pickling was going
to be super easy.
All George needed was
salt and vinegar.
Hmm...
[narrator]
Only, which one was vinegar?
[sniffs]
[grunts negatively]
[pops]
[sniffs]
[grunts negatively]
Aah!
[sputters]
[narrator] Yep.
That one was vinegar.
[grunts disappointedly]
[narrator]
Now he needed more vinegar.
Did I hear a crash?
Oh!
Why do you smell like
salad dressing, George?
[laughs]
[narrator] Luckily,
George knew someone
who could drive him
to the store.
[man in yellow hat]
Let's see... vinegar...
vinegar...
Ha.
Vinegar.
Making pickles out of
all those cucumbers
is a great idea, George.
Did somebody say "pickles"?
Well, you're in luck.
We're celebrating
harvest season
with an international
pickle display.
Here's our country,
and here's India,
Korea,
Norway,
Ireland,
and Mexico.
[lively piano music]
[clears throat]
♪ Some pickles are sweet ♪
♪ They're really a treat ♪
♪ While sour is king
hot ones have a zing ♪
[pants]
♪ If a pickle is very
hot try some dairy ♪
♪ Like raita ♪
♪ Delight-a ♪
♪ Here's chutney ♪
♪ From India, you see ♪
♪ Embellishing
their food so tastefully ♪
♪ In a rainbow of colors ♪
♪ We've got orange, green,
and brown ♪
Keep the raita,
there's yogurt in it!
Kinda cools things down.
♪ In Korea,
they like to eat kimchi ♪
♪ It's great stuff
I think you'll all agree ♪
♪ It's cabbage, radish,
and green scallions ♪
♪ I could eat it by the pint ♪
♪ Or by the gall-i-on ♪
♪ In Norway they eat herring ♪
♪ A pickled fish, how daring ♪
♪ The Irish have
pickled corned beef ♪
♪ And a Peter Piper pickled
a peck of peppers ♪
♪ Wouldn't you know? ♪
♪ A peck of pickled peppers
is what you eat ♪
♪ In Mexico,
they pickle it the best ♪
♪ It's salsa
I'm sure you'll be impressed ♪
♪ Yes, anywhere you travel ♪
♪ The whole world round ♪
♪ There's tasty pickles there
to be found ♪
[both clapping]
So, George,
what kind of pickles
do you want to make?
[chatters happily]
[sighs]
I was afraid you'd say that.
[laughs]
[upbeat piano music]
[narrator] George made
some of his pickles sweet
and other pickles,
he made savory.
[grunts hesitatingly]
I've gotten used to them.
[laughs]
[narrator] And some of them
he made spicy.
Now, we just have to wait
two weeks
for our pickles to be done.
[grunting happily]
♪♪
We did it!
[grunts triumphantly]
[laughs triumphantly]
Only now, instead of having
lots of cucumbers, we--
we have lots of pickles.
Hmm...
Aha!
Gee, thanks, George.
I love pickles even more
than I love cucumbers.
[grunting happily]
[gasps]
♪♪
[narrator]
So people took a lot.
Well, I do have pickles
of my own.
But I've never had a pickle
made by a monkey.
[chatters amiably]
[narrator] Finally,
the last pickle was gone.
-[sighs]
[knocking at door]
Your pickles were so tasty,
I thought maybe
you could pickle
some of our vegetables, too.
[grunts amiably]
How do you feel about
pickling eggs?
Um...
I've got some fish!
This is great.
-Could you pickle this?
-Thanks, George!
This is great
when it's pickled.
Looks like
we'll need more vinegar.
[grunting happily]
[laughs]
♪♪
[Compass cooing]
[narrator] It was
the perfect afternoon
for a trip.
George and his friend
were going someplace special.
[chatters happily]
[narrator] To see the stars.
[grunting happily]
[narrator]
George knew the stars
were really, really far away.
He wanted to make sure
he had everything he needed
for the trip...
[Compass cooing]
Including trail mix.
[chattering admonishingly]
[Compass coos]
[narrator] If you're going
into outer space,
it's a good idea
to bring a snack.
[straining]
Ready, George?
Uh, George?
It's not that far
to Mr. Griggs's house.
Huh?
You can take a toy
and a snack,
but let's leave the rest here,
buddy, okay?
[chatters in agreement]
[light music]
♪♪
[Compass cooing]
[engine turns over]
Let's go see some stars.
[grunting happily]
♪♪
[Compass cooing]
[grunts appreciatively]
Here we are.
♪♪
[Compass cooing]
[grunts happily]
Huh?
[narrator] George wasn't sure
how they were going to see
stars in a house.
Hmm.
[narrator] Unless they were
friends of Mr. Griggs.
[people chatting]
Ooh!
[laughs]
[Compass coos]
See, George?
There it is.
[George grunts appreciatively]
[man in yellow hat]
It's something, all right.
Mr. Griggs built
his own observatory.
Oh, I'm so glad you're here.
And on the perfect night.
[stars shimmering]
Let's go on up.
[grunts happily]
[upbeat music]
[Compass coos]
[narrator] George learned
Mr. Griggs was an astronomer.
He studied the moon,
and stars,
and all sorts of other things
in space.
[chattering excitedly]
Oh, that's a picture
of a supernova.
An exploding star.
[George grunts admiringly]
Do you want to see
how I got all these pictures?
-[chattering excitedly]
-Can't wait.
Right this way.
Welcome to my observatory.
-Amazing.
-[grunts admiringly]
And this is the telescope
I use to see the stars.
-[man in yellow hat] Wow.
-Ooh.
You've come on
the perfect night
to see something astounding.
[chattering excitedly]
[computer] Isn't it exciting?
[chatters in surprise]
Oh, allow me to introduce
Failsafe.
This is the first time
I've ever met a monkey.
Hello. And hello,
tall person wearing yellow.
-[grunts happily]
-Uh, hi.
Failsafe helps me
control the telescope.
He took all the pictures
you just saw.
[grunts uncomprehendingly]
♪♪
[grunts admiringly]
I can sense you're confused.
It works like this:
Say we want to look
at the Crab Nebula.
[mechanical whirring]
We point the telescope
towards one teeny-tiny area
of the sky.
You can't see it
with your eyes,
but our powerful telescope can.
And I can snap a picture.
[shutter snaps]
[chattering excitedly]
Tonight, we'll get a picture
of a comet
hitting the planet Mars.
[chatters curiously]
"What's a comet?"
Oh, I'm glad you asked.
[grunts admiringly]
It's a giant, giant, giant
chunk of ice and dust
that flies through space
like a snowball.
As it nears the sun,
some of the ice
starts to melt and trails off.
It looks like
a big, shiny tail.
-Wow.
[Failsafe] Wow indeed.
Sometimes comets collide
with other objects in space,
like the one that will hit Mars
tonight.
[grunting happily]
In the meantime, Mr. Griggs,
perhaps our friends are hungry?
You might offer them
some of your tasty sandwiches.
Ah, excellent idea, Failsafe.
And of course,
you'll want some fresh fruit.
And beverages.
[chattering excitedly]
And napkins.
And silverware.
♪♪
Well, I'll give you a hand.
Oh, thank you.
♪♪
We'll be right back, George.
[chatters amiably]
♪♪
[Compass coos]
[grunts curiously]
Oh, that's Saturn.
It's one of the planets
in our solar system.
[grunting happily]
[tapping]
Say, do you hear
a tapping sound?
[Compass coos]
[grunts curiously]
[narrator] George wondered
what Compass was doing
way out here.
Maybe he wanted to see
the comet hit Mars, too.
[tapping at window]
But Compass wanted
something else.
[chatters agreeably]
[Compass coos]
♪♪
[electronic whine]
[beeping]
Hmm.
[buzzes negatively]
Definitely not.
[buzzes]
Unlikely.
Oh, how nice.
He's a pigeon, right?
Uh-huh.
Oh, wow.
I met a pigeon and a monkey
on the same day.
Pinch me!
Hi there, pretty bird.
[Compass coos]
Look, he's on my head.
Say, would you like to see
some pictures
of some deep sky objects,
pretty bird?
[Compass coos]
[narrator] Compass
wasn't interested
in seeing stars.
The food was gone,
and it was time for him
to go home.
[Compass coos]
But, Compass being Compass,
he went the wrong direction.
Oh, dear.
He wants to get out.
[Compass coos frantically]
[grunts happily]
[chatters excitedly]
Use the window, birdie.
That way.
Go to the monkey.
Go to the monkey!
[Compass coos]
[grunts disappointedly]
Oh, dear, it's not working.
Wait, I know.
I'll open the telescope door
for him.
[Compass coos]
The door is right there.
It's behind you.
Look.
[gasps]
[Compass coos]
Oh, the tension is too much.
♪♪
[grunts excitedly]
[Failsafe] Good idea, monkey.
Just don't let him
go inside the telescope.
He might hurt himself.
Or it!
[grunts fearfully]
Oh!
I can't look.
[Compass coos]
You better take him
to the window, George.
He can't find it by himself.
[grunts amiably]
♪♪
[electronic beeping]
[grunting in alarm]
♪♪
[Failsafe] Fetch it.
You've almost got him!
[chatters in exertion]
Uh-oh!
♪♪
[foreboding music]
Oh, no!
[disorienting music]
[Compass coos]
[alarm blares]
♪♪
Here.
Try this.
Mm.
Wonderful tuna salad.
Try and guess
the secret ingredient.
Ah, no idea.
A touch...
of mustard.
Really?
Mm.
[siren blares]
[grunts fearfully]
[Compass coos]
[whines in alarm]
♪♪
[narrator] George worried
Compass might try to exit
through the telescope.
[chatters excitedly]
♪♪
[Compass coos]
[Compass coos rapidly]
[calm music]
Whoa!
[panicked chattering]
[fast-paced music]
Whoa!
[Compass coos]
[grunts happily]
[man in yellow hat] Um, George?
Hi!
Systems restored.
What happened?
Nothing.
We were just trying to help
the pigeon.
A pigeon?
[chattering excitedly]
Is everything all right,
Mr. Griggs?
I believe so.
Oh, dear, the telescope
is no longer pointing at Mars.
I'm going to have to move it.
Wait a minute.
Look at this.
Huh?
It's an exploding star.
A supernova.
Quick, Failsafe, photograph it!
[Failsafe laughs]
I'm way ahead of you.
[shutter snaps]
[grunting happily]
Oh, George.
This is much better
than Comet 331P.
[laughs]
Thank you, George.
[chatters affectionately]
[laughs]
[narrator] Other astronomers
had photographed the comet,
but only Mr. Griggs
saw the supernova.
[applause]
I couldn't have done it
without my curious friend,
George.
[chatters appreciatively]
[narrator] George was happy
that Mr. Griggs got the award,
but he was even happier
to learn a little more
about the stars.
[George] Ooh.
[fast swing music]
♪♪