[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat ragtime music]
♪♪
[narrator] Little monkeys
love riding buses!
But a ride on the Z bus
was the best trip of all.
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
Because it ended at...
Welcome to Zany Island!
[chattering excitedly]
Say hello
to our new friends, Petey.
-Hello.
-[caws]
How would you like
your own Petey?
[chattering appreciatively]
Wow!
Nice, George!
Thar be adventure ahead.
And here's a map
to keep ya on course.
[chattering excitedly]
[caws] Have fun.
[grunts appreciatively]
[narrator] George planned
on having a great time.
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
And thanks to his map,
he wouldn't miss a thing.
[exciting music]
-[chattering exhilaratingly]
-[yelling]
[narrator] George and
his friend rode fast rides...
[toads croaking]
Slow rides...
[both yelling]
Scary rides...
[both laughing]
Wet rides...
[relaxed music]
And scenic rides...
[grunts happily]
[narrator] Until, one by one,
George, Petey, and
the Man with the Yellow Hat
had ridden them all.
[upbeat music]
Too bad they don't come
in yellow.
♪♪
Lucky you!
You got
the last one in your size.
We're usually out of stock
by this time of day.
[grunts appreciatively]
♪♪
-[cannon blasts]
-[gasps]
[grunts excitedly]
[Captain Zany] Avast, mateys!
That be yer warning shot!
Zany Island be closing
in 30 minutes I say.
One more ride?
[grunting happily]
[light music]
♪♪
[straining]
[chattering drowsily]
So, did you have
a good time today, George?
[chattering, yawns]
What was your favorite part?
[cawing, chattering]
[laughs]
Yeah, you sure
had fun with Petey.
[light piano music]
[yawns]
Huh?
[gasps]
Hey, um...
Where is Petey?
Did we leave him behind?
[grunting in alarm]
[panicked chattering]
Whoa, George, hang on!
I...
Look, I know you're
worried about Petey.
[grunts fearfully]
But it's really late.
I promise,
we'll look for him first thing
in the morning, okay?
[grunts obligingly]
[sighs impatiently]
[narrator] But George didn't
want to wait until morning.
[chatters happily]
[narrator] Luckily,
he didn't have to.
The Z bus ran all night.
[upbeat piano music]
[grunts excitedly]
[narrator] He could rescue
Petey now.
♪♪
[chattering happily]
[narrator] Zany Island
was a big place.
Good thing George
had kept his map.
It showed everywhere
he and Petey had been that day.
[grunts dejectedly]
[chatters in exertion]
[narrator] Let the hunt
for Parrot Petey begin.
But George wondered
where to look first?
[grunts hesitatingly]
[narrator] Maybe right here.
The store where George
had gotten his pirate hat!
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] Those shelves
had been empty,
and those tables
had been messy.
[quiet piano music]
[chatters in surprise]
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] Maybe this was
where they put all the toys
children left behind!
-[chatters amiably]
-[gasps]
[laughing] Whoa!
You're a real monkey.
And an awfully cute one too.
What are you doing up there?
[chatters, caws]
Oh, you're looking for
your lost Parrot Petey, huh?
[chatters agreeably]
Well, we only have
new toys here.
But it might be somewhere
behind all those boxes.
I'll help you look
once I'm done restocking.
[grunts excitedly]
[chatters in exertion]
Which may happen
in record time
if you're helping out!
[lively piano music]
♪♪
[grunts triumphantly]
Sorry we didn't find
your Petey.
[grunts disappointedly]
Let's ask the guys outside.
They go everywhere!
[grunts curiously]
[chatters happily]
[grunts confusedly]
[narrator] Where had
all the confetti gone?
Hey, guys! My friend here
lost a Parrot Petey.
Anybody found one?
Not yet, but it's a big park.
We've got a lot of ground
to cover.
Want to come along?
[chatters agreeably]
[grunts in exertion]
Good catch!
[light music]
[container whirs]
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] How did everything
from that big bag
fit into that little barrel?
Nice, huh?
The trash cans are fake.
They cover
these underground tubes.
[grunt echoes]
They're like
big vacuum cleaners!
The trash gets sucked down
to a central collection area.
[grunts in awe]
That way, trash collectors
don't disturb
our guests during the day.
Ready to roll?
[chatters agreeably]
I hope you find your Petey.
[grunts happily]
[chatters dejectedly]
[narrator] But Petey
wasn't to be found.
At least not on the streets.
[grunts inquisitively]
[narrator] It was time
for George to search the rides.
First up,
the roller coaster.
[wheels screeching]
[chatters aggravatingly]
[narrator] George hadn't
remembered the coaster
being that noisy before.
Well, hi, little fella.
What are you doing here?
[chatters, cawing]
[chatters sadly]
You lost your Parrot Petey?
[chatters agreeably]
That's tough.
[grunts]
So's oiling the far wheels
on this coaster.
[chattering excitedly]
[upbeat music]
Hey!
Be careful!
[grunting happily]
Wish I could do that!
[chatters amiably]
Tell you what.
You oil that side.
I'll oil this side.
Then we can search the cars
for your Petey together!
[chatters in agreement]
♪♪
[chatters curiously]
Found nothing at this end.
How about you?
[chatters dejectedly]
[grunts inquisitively]
What's this? A map of all
the places you went today?
-[grunts in agreement]
-Hmm.
All those rides
need maintenance too!
What do you say
we help each other out?
[chattering agreeably]
[sighs]
I forgot
the most important part!
[chatters curiously]
To take a test ride!
Think you're up for it?
[chatters excitedly]
[chatters exhilaratingly]
[narrator] There were nuts
to be tightened...
[chatters gleefully]
[narrator] Light bulbs
to be changed...
[chatters happily]
[narrator] And cables
to be replaced.
[chatters cheerfully]
[narrator] But there was
only one more ride to go,
and George still
hadn't found Petey.
Swamp boats, it is.
[toads croaking]
[triumphant melody]
[light piano music]
[grunts disappointingly]
[narrator] George had worked
on all the rides
and not found Petey.
-[light tap]
-[gasps, chatters in surprise]
[chattering triumphantly]
[laughs]
Whenever I lose something,
it's usually
in the last place I look!
Ready, George?
[grunts agreeably]
And Petey?
[chatters agreeably]
[light music]
[toads croaking]
♪♪
[birds chirping]
Hey there!
Has anyone seen my monkey?
[all shushing]
[chattering drowsily]
[snoring]
[lively piano music]
♪♪
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator]
George loved snowy days.
Wherever he wanted to go,
he could ride his toboggan.
[chatters in fear]
[grunting in alarm]
-[grunts]
-Oh!
Oh, my goodness!
Morning, George.
[chattering amiably]
[grunts in surprise]
[grunts, groans]
George, is that you
inside that snowman?
[shivers, chatters happily]
[grunts amiably]
[chattering inquisitively]
Oh, this?
It's my hockey stick.
I'm on my way to the ice rink.
[chatters curiously]
Sure, try it out!
-[grunts admiringly]
-Whoa!
-[chattering happily]
-[laughs]
You don't hold it like
a baseball bat, George.
[grunts understandingly]
[playful music]
[laughs]
You don't ride it either.
Want me to teach you
how to play?
[chatters agreeably]
Great!
Let's go to the rink.
[chattering excitedly]
[chattering curiously]
Oh, that's
the ice-resurfacing machine.
It makes the ice smooth
so you can skate on it.
Hey, boys.
Sorry to tell you this,
but the rink's closed
for a week.
-Aw!
-[chatters dejectedly]
Yeah, the community theater
is rehearsing
for "Goldilocks and
the Three Bears on Ice."
[chuckles]
[light piano music]
♪♪
Well, no harm done.
You can use the rink next week.
-[grunts disappointingly]
-Mm.
[grunting]
This tarp's frozen solid!
Hey, could you give me a hand?
-[chatters agreeably]
-Sure!
♪♪
[straining]
Whew!
Thanks!
[chatters inquisitively]
[narrator]
The layer of ice on top
made the frozen tarp
look just like...
a little ice rink.
[chattering excitedly]
I don't know, George.
I think that tarp's
a little small to skate on.
[grunts curiously]
[chatters happily]
[chatters inquisitively]
Sure, you can use that.
What do you need it for?
[chattering happily]
Ohh!
George wants
to make our own ice rink.
[chattering agreeably]
Hmm.
Sounds like a fun project.
-[grunting cheerfully]
-Yeah!
[upbeat piano music]
♪♪
[water splashing]
Wow!
Looks good, you guys.
It should freeze to ice
by tomorrow morning.
Meanwhile, you two look like
you could use some cocoa.
-[chatters excitedly]
-Yeah!
[wind whistling]
[water freezing, ice cracking]
[shimmering tone]
[chattering happily]
[grunts triumphantly]
[chatters fearfully]
[grunts in relief]
Hey, George!
[chuckles]
It worked!
You know, you're pretty good
at building ice rinks,
for a city kid.
[chatters appreciatively]
Let's play hockey!
[grunts excitedly]
[groans]
[chatters gleefully]
Here we go!
[chatters happily]
[scraping]
[chatters in fear]
This is not good!
Whoa!
[snow tumbling]
[chattering fearfully]
[grunts in alarm]
[thud]
You okay, George?
[grunts agreeably]
Hmm.
That is not supposed
to do that.
This ice is a lot lumpier
than at the rink.
[grunts in agreement]
[chatters curiously]
Good question, George.
[tree creaking, wind whistling]
[chatters curiously]
-[grunts happily]
-Ah!
It was really windy last night.
The wind must have made
the water wavy
when it was freezing.
[grunts disappointingly]
We'll never be able
to skate on that.
Guess we'll just have to wait
till the rink opens again.
[grunts curiously]
[chatters excitedly]
What is it, George?
[chatters happily]
[grunts in exertion]
Oh, yeah!
The ice-resurfacing machine!
[chattering excitedly]
Huh. You think
they'd loan it to us?
[chattering curiously]
[cars honking]
[grunts hesitatingly]
[chatters negatively]
[sighs]
Me neither.
[chatters curiously]
[grunts curiously]
[chattering happily]
Yeah, maybe we can make one
if we figure out how it works!
[light piano music]
-Uh, George.
-[chatters inquisitively]
Maybe we should figure it out
someplace else.
[chatters in agreement]
[keyboard clacking]
[grunts understandingly]
Okay, I see.
The machine wets down
the surface of the ice
with warm water.
Then this big cloth smooths
the surface before it freezes.
[grunts comprehendingly]
[groans]
We better get to work.
[chatters agreeably]
[narrator] If George and Bill
were going to make
their own
ice-resurfacing machine,
they had to find the parts
they would need.
Let's see.
We need something
to wet down the ice.
Hmm.
[chatters curiously]
I don't know.
It's kind of small.
[grunts excitedly]
[chattering happily]
We'd need to put holes
in it to drip water.
[chatters happily]
[light tapping]
That's great!
Then what can we use
to smooth out the surface?
[chatters excitedly]
Perfect!
Now, how do we pull
the tub and doormat?
[chatters triumphantly]
[duck winding]
[duck quacking]
[ducks quacking]
[quacking slows, stops]
[grunts disappointedly]
Time to wind them again.
[chatters negatively]
[chatters triumphantly]
[chattering excitedly]
[grunts happily]
[water hissing]
Hit it, George!
[chattering in exertion]
[grunts uncomprehendingly]
Let's switch places.
[grunts in agreement]
Here we go!
[panting]
[shimmering tone]
[upbeat music]
Is it working?
[chattering happily]
[laughs]
Great going, guys!
[narrator] Before long,
the ice was nice and smooth.
[shimmering tone]
All set for your first game?
[chatters agreeably]
Here it comes!
[grunts]
[chatters frightfully]
[grunts negatively]
-[chatters happily]
-[laughs]
Just have to work
on the form a little.
-[grunts in agreement]
-[man in yellow hat] Hey, George!
Got room for one more?
-Yeah!
-[chatters excitedly]
[laughter]
[Man in the Yellow Hat
laughing]
[Bill] Nice one, George!
[giggling]
[fast swing music]
♪♪