[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
♪♪
[narrator] It was
the last day of the year,
which meant George was busy
putting up decorations.
[grunting happily]
Whoa-- whoa--
[yelling]
-[muffled chatter]
-Uh-oh.
Streamers get away
from you again, George?
Mm-hmm.
[narrator] After decorating,
there was baking...
[cheerful music]
-And preparing for guests.
-Uh-huh.
Looks like we're
all set for New Year's.
Uh... [chatters]
You're right, George.
Tomorrow starts
the brand new year...
Uh-huh.
Which means
we'll need a new calendar.
Ooh...
[chatters]
♪♪
We'll tear off
the last number at midnight,
and you know what happens then.
Yeah!
[party horn toots]
-Happy New Year!
-[chatters happily]
[both laugh]
Hey, you think you can really
stay up till midnight
this year, George?
[chattering happily]
Well, if you wanna
be awake at midnight,
it might help to take a nap.
Ah... [chatters]
Okay, your choice,
but you might fall asleep and
miss the party, like last year.
Ah... ah, ah.
[lively brass music]
[yawns]
[soft music slows down]
♪♪
Oh...
[narrator] George didn't
wanna miss the party...
[grunting happily]
[exciting music]
[sighs]
[narrator] So he decided
to give the nap a try.
[groans]
[narrator] But it was
too bright to sleep.
[grunting]
[sighs]
[soft, playful music]
Huh?
[chatters, grunting]
[sighs]
[narrator] Finally, George
was ready to fall asleep.
[groaning]
[groaning intensifies]
George, wh-- what are you--
[chatters, giggles]
♪♪
-Trouble sleeping, huh?
-Uh-huh.
You know what my grandmother
used to tell me?
Mm.
If you can't sleep,
count sheep.
Oh... uh-huh.
Give it a try.
You'll be asleep in no time.
-Uh-huh.
-[door creaks]
-Ah...
-[narrator] One...
♪♪
D'oh... [chatters]
[narrator] George needed
to count more than one sheep
to get sleepy.
Oh? Ah!
[narrator] Luckily, he knew
just where to find some.
[sheep bleating]
[gate creaks]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
-Ah...
-[narrator] One...
-[narrator] Two...
-Ah...
-[narrator] Three...
[sheep bleats]
♪♪
-Ah...
-[narrator] Four.
-[narrator] Five.
[sheep bleats]
-Ah...
-[narrator] Six...
-Ah-wah.
-[narrator] Seven...
♪♪
Hey!
[narrator]
The sheep kept moving.
George couldn't tell
which ones he'd counted.
-[sheep munching]
-Hey!
Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo-
hoo-hoo-- [groans]
[narrator]
If George wanted to know
how many sheep there were,
he could only count
each sheep once...
Ah!
Hoo-hoo-- [chatters]
[grunting]
-Hey! Hoo-hoo-ha!
-[sheep bleating]
[narrator] So he asked
the sheep to line up.
[soft piano music]
[sheep bleating]
[groans]
[grunting] Ooh...
[grunting]
[groans]
[narrator] Getting sheep
to follow directions
was harder than
George expected.
If only sheep
came with numbers.
Hmm...
[gasps] Ah!
[playful music]
-[chattering happily]
-George?
I thought you were
taking a nap.
[chatters]
Ah-ha!
[chattering happily]
Okay, have fun with...
[door closes]
Our calendar?
[sheep bleating]
[narrator] Now George
could number the sheep
as he counted them.
♪♪
[giggling] Aww...
[narrator] Sheep number one
was very friendly...
-Ah...
-[sheep bleats]
[narrator]
Number two was sleepy...
♪♪
Ah...
[narrator]
And three was small...
[chattering] Ah!
[sheep grunting]
[narrator] Four was shy...
♪♪
-Ah...
-[sheep bleats loudly]
D'oh!
[narrator]
Sheep five was loud...
-[sheep bleating, grunting]
-[chattering happily]
♪♪
[narrator]
And six was springy...
[sheep bleats, sneezes]
Sheep seven had
a little cold...
-[sheep munching]
-Ah!
♪♪
[narrator]
And eight liked to eat...
-A lot.
-Ah!
[sheep bleating]
♪♪
[narrator] There was only
one more sheep to count...
-[sheep bleating]
-Ah... ah!
[narrator] Nine.
Sheep number nine had
a lot of energy too.
♪♪
[giggles]
[narrator] George was ready to
get sleepy, like number two.
Now all he had to do
was count the sheep.
-Ah...
-[narrator] One...
-[narrator] Two...
-Ah...
-[narrator] Three...
-[narrator] Four...
-[sheep bleats loudly]
-[screams]
Oh... [giggles]
-Ah...
-[narrator] Five...
But where was number six?
[chatters softly]
[narrator] There were
seven, eight, and nine.
Sheep six had to be there too.
[gasps]
[narrator] George accidentally
left the gate open.
Sheep six escaped.
[gasps, screams]
[chattering anxiously]
[dramatic music]
[narrator] Maybe sheep six
was in the barn.
[panting]
[cows moo]
[groans]
[pigs grunting]
Oh!
[narrator]
Nope, not in the barn either.
[whistling]
Well, lookey here.
Uh, I guess Mrs. Renkins
must've numbered you all
to keep you organized.
[sheep bleating happily]
Huh?
Uh, but we only have
eight sheep.
Why are you wearing a nine?
Oh, I see,
the nine is just a six
turned upside down!
Uh, well, I can fix that.
[playful music]
Ah! [chuckles] There.
[chuckles]
That's more like it.
[sheep bleating happily]
[whistling]
♪♪
[chattering softly]
[soft, slow piano music]
[grunts]
♪♪
[gasps] Hey!
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
Sheep six came back!
[gasps]
♪♪
[narrator]
But how did he get in?
[gasps]
Huh... [chatters]
[counting]
[playful piano music]
♪♪
Ah! Nine!
[narrator]
Sheep number six was back,
but now number nine was gone.
-Hi, George.
-[bike bell ringing]
[grunts]
What are you doing?
And... why are the sheep
wearing our calendar?
[chatters]
[counting]
Oh, I get it.
You're counting sheep.
[bashful chatter]
George, when I said,
"If you can't sleep,
count sheep,"
did you think
I meant real sheep?
Uh-huh.
I see.
Well, Grandma just meant
to count sheep
in your imagination,
not go to an actual sheep pen.
Ah?
Ah, okay.
[narrator]
George thought Grandma's way
sounded a lot easier.
[yawns, cooing]
[sheep bleating]
[soft, slow piano music]
[snoring]
♪♪
[yawns]
Well, I'm gonna finish
my bike ride.
I'll see you after your nap.
[sheep bleats loudly]
[narrator] But George
couldn't take a nap yet.
He still had to find
sheep number nine.
[sheep bleating happily]
Oh, no!
[narrator] George went
to get the number six,
when it turned into a nine.
Huh?
[narrator] Then it turned
into a six again.
How was the number doing that?
A six was an upside-down nine,
and a nine was just
an upside-down six.
Huh?
[sheep bleating happily]
[narrator] Sheep number six
and sheep number nine
were the same animal.
The missing sheep
had been there all along.
[yawns]
[coos, chatters]
♪♪
[narrator]
George's way of counting sheep
was harder than Grandma's.
-but...
-[relaxed grunt]
[narrator]
It sure tired him out.
[relaxed mumbling]
[snoring]
[lively music playing,
lively chatter]
[narrator] That night, everyone
came to George's house
to celebrate the New Year.
Ready for the countdown?
Uh-huh!
[dramatic chords]
[clock ticking]
[both]
Five, four...
three, two...
one...
-Happy New Year, everyone!
-[chatters happily]
-[lively chatter]
-[party horns toot]
♪♪
-[chattering happily]
-[dog panting]
[dog chattering, panting]
[narrator]
It was perfect weather
for pitching practice
with Charkie.
[upbeat jazz music]
♪♪
[saxophone squeaking]
[dog panting, sniffing]
-[inhales sharply]
-[saxophone squeaking]
-[inhales]
-[saxophone squeaks]
[crowd cheering]
♪♪
[dog panting, chatters]
[dog chomps]
Yeah!
♪♪
[narrator] The best part about
pitching in the park
was making new friends.
-[grunts]
-[dog barking happily]
[playful music]
♪♪
-[dog chomps]
-Oh! Ah! Whoo!
[laughs]
[cheers, laughter]
Oh! [laughs]
[chattering happily]
Okay...
-[grunts]
-[dog chatters]
[cheers, laughter]
[chatters]
[slow saxophone music]
[ball bounces]
[dog barking]
[playful music]
[dog chomps]
Hooray!
♪♪
[slow saxophone music]
Whew...
♪♪
Ooh!
[chattering happily]
Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-- [grunts]
[dog barking]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
Hey... [chatters]
Huh. [chatters]
-[dog barks]
-Ow.
-[dog panting]
-Huh...
[grunts]
[narrator]
There was something sticky
stuck on George's head...
[groans]
[narrator] And that something
was chewing gum.
Huh? Oh.
[grunting]
[gasps]
[groaning]
[slow, clumsy brass music]
[dog barking, panting]
♪♪
[dog barking]
[groans]
[grunts happily]
Oh...
[chatters]
Mah-mah-mah-mah-mah-mow!
[grunts] Huh?
[soft piano music]
Ah...
[narrator] The solution
to George's problem.
He would wash it off.
Huh... [groans]
[narrator]
If the ball stuck to him...
♪♪
The fountain could too.
[shivers]
♪♪
Ah...
[grunting] Ooh...
[instrumental flourish]
D'oh! Huh...
Ah!
[slow, playful music]
♪♪
[groans]
Ah!
[dog barking, panting]
Ah... [chattering]
-[dog barking]
-Whoa!
[narrator]
Charkie loved keep-away.
Huh...
Huh?
[bumblebee buzzing]
Huh? [gasps]
[screams]
[dog barking]
[chattering]
-[dog barking]
-[bumblebee buzzing]
[exciting music]
[chattering]
[grunts]
-[bumblebee buzzing]
-[dog barking]
Oh...
[narrator]
The coast was clear...
[soft piano music]
But his head was not.
♪♪
[chattering, grunts]
[dog barking, panting]
Oh... [chattering]
♪♪
-Huh?
-[dog barking]
[chattering]
[chatters softly]
[groans]
♪♪
Ah!
[grunting happily]
Huh?
[groans]
[bird cooing]
Oh! [chattering happily]
[narrator] Compass worked
with sticks all the time.
Maybe he could help
get rid of this mess.
[bird cooing]
[narrator] But to Compass,
it was a ready-made nest.
Oh... [groans]
[dog barking, panting]
♪♪
[groans]
[gasps]
[uplifting piano music]
[chatters happily]
[narrator] The man would know
how to get rid of the gum.
[chatters happily]
[narrator] George could take a
short-cut through the dog run.
-[dog barking]
-[bird cooing]
Compass was thrilled.
He had landed on his first
mobile home for birds.
[bird cooing]
[chattering happily]
[dog panting]
[narrator] If tennis balls
stuck to gum...
[playful music]
Ah! Ah, ah!
[narrator]
Other dog toys might too...
♪♪
-[dog panting]
-Or even other dogs.
♪♪
The long way home
might be safer.
[dog barking]
[upbeat music]
Oh, no!
Our kite's getting away!
[chatters happily]
-[gasps]
-Whoa!
[narrator] But what if the kite
got stuck in the gum too?
[panting]
It's my turn to fly the monkey!
♪♪
Hey!
[grunts happily]
Gee, thanks! Nice save!
Ah... [bashful chatter]
And thanks for
shortening the tail.
Huh?
♪♪
[sighs]
[grunting]
[narrator]
George had to get home
before anything else
got stuck to him.
[slow, playful music]
-Too late.
-[bird coos]
Compass couldn't believe
breakfast was included.
-[dog barking]
-[chattering]
[cat licking, purring]
♪♪
-[cat meows]
-[chattering]
-[grunts, groans]
[dog barking]
[soft piano music]
[narrator]
His hands were dirty...
Ah...
[narrator]
But they weren't sticky.
[laughs]
[slow, playful music]
-[dog chattering, panting]
-[cat growling]
-[chatters]
-[bird cooing]
[cat meowing happily]
♪♪
[dog grunts]
-[cat meows]
-[dog gasps]
♪♪
Hi!
[dog grunting]
Ah.
[narrator] There was no way
Hundley was going to
let that messy monkey
into his lobby.
Ah...
[soft piano music]
Ah!
[upbeat music]
[grunting happily]
[cat meowing happily]
♪♪
-[chatters happily]
-[cat grunts]
[grunting]
♪♪
[sighs] Shoo.
[bird cooing]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
[sighs]
[bird cooing]
[beak tapping]
[soft piano music]
[gasps]
♪♪
-Ah...
-[narrator] George was certain
he could think better
on a full stomach.
[slow, playful music]
♪♪
Uh-oh.
Oh...
[soft, slow piano music]
[grunting]
Ah. Huh...
[slow, playful music]
♪♪
[yelps]
Oh...
[narrator]
Now George was gummy...
[groans]
[narrator]
And peanut buttery.
Huh?
Ah-ah!
-[narrator] But not for long.
-Yeah!
[narrator] Peanut butter
unstuck sticky stuff.
[cheerful music]
♪♪
Finally, the gum was gone.
George?
[giggles]
[slow, playful music]
Ah... [giggles, chatters]
[narrator] But peanut butter
was almost as hard
to get rid of as gum.
Uh-huh?
♪♪
You need another shampooing.
Again?
Peanut butter is so oily.
It's hard to get
out of your fur.
[giggling]
But it could've been worse.
You could've gotten
gum stuck in there.
Ah... [chatters]
Did you know someone tracked
gum outside the building?
It got on my shoe.
Gum is the worst.
Uh-huh.
♪♪
[narrator] George knew
if you had a problem,
the solution was
to stick with it,
but if your problem
stuck to you,
there was always
peanut butter.
[giggles]
♪♪
[upbeat music]