[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat jazz piano music]
♪♪
[narrator]
It was a perfect day
in the country for a hike.
♪♪
[both gasp]
Uh-oh.
♪♪
[narrator] Some places in the
country were hard to reach.
[rhythmic music]
♪♪
Whoo!
[narrator]
But they were worth it.
[upbeat jazz piano music]
♪♪
Hmm.
Pretty good hiking
for a city kid, George.
Aww.
We're almost there.
The super-secret hidden,
nobody-but-us-knows-about-it
view!
[giggles]
Hey, I'm getting hungry!
Sandwich break?
[chatters hungrily]
♪♪
Uh-oh!
Whoa! Ow!
[grunts]
[grunting worriedly]
I'm all right! I'm all right!
[groans] Ow!
I guess I'm not all right.
[whimpering]
I don't think I can walk
on my leg, George.
Aww...
Maybe if I go slow.
[chatters encouragingly]
Ouch!
That's not going to work.
[chatters nervously]
[narrator] George knew
he needed to go for help.
[chatters soothingly]
♪♪
Hey, thanks
for the lift, guys.
You did a great job getting
help for your friend, George.
[chatters happily]
I called your mom, Bill.
She's gonna meet you
at the hospital.
You know, I'm actually
looking forward to going there.
-You are?
-[chatters]
Yeah! They have the best
fruit cup I've ever tasted.
It almost makes
all this worth it.
[chatters happily]
Hey, George,
would you like to ride
in the ambulance with us?
[chatters happily]
Sure. Why not?
[upbeat jazzy music]
[siren wailing]
♪♪
[chatters curiously]
It's the paramedic's job
to give people first aid
and bring them
to the hospital, George.
[chatters happily]
Right.
And the ambulance
has all the equipment
we need.
It's almost like
a rolling hospital.
Oh!
♪♪
[clatters]
Hey, Danny. Hey, Nurse Paula.
How's it going, Barry?
Hi, Trish!
Wow, you seem to know
a lot of people here.
Yeah, I've been
in the hospital before.
[chatters in confusion]
Oh, yeah,
broke my arm playing chess.
Met everybody.
Well, hello, Bill.
What happened?
Hurt my leg.
What was it this time?
Checkers?
Turkey sandwich.
[chatters curiously]
It's a wristband
for the doctors and nurses
to keep track
of all of us patients.
Oh!
♪♪
Well, Bill,
it looks like your leg
is broken in three places.
Really?
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] Bill's leg looked
like it was all in one piece.
[laughs]
You can't see the break
on the outside.
That's why we radiologists
use an x-ray machine.
It takes pictures of how you
look on the inside.
[chatters happily]
[narrator] George had seen
an x-ray before.
[counts to three]
That's right,
there are fractures
here, here, and here.
What happened?
Slipped on a turkey sandwich.
Of course.
I should've guessed.
[chatters thoughtfully]
[narrator] George
thought he'd like to have
an x-ray machine of his own.
[chattering wistfully]
Looks like Bill's
gonna need a cast
so his leg can heal.
We make a cast
by wrapping your leg
with lots of layers
so it can't move.
[bright piano music]
That's strange.
Where's my...
[gasps]
[grunting spookily]
[laughs]
[both laughing]
Thanks for lunch!
Now, your job is to rest up
until your mom gets here.
Enjoy your lunch.
Oh, I will!
Yes!
Fruit cu--
Grapes? Ugh.
I was really looking
forward to that fruit cup.
I'd trade,
but I can't leave the bed.
[chatters helpfully]
[narrator] Bill couldn't leave,
but George could.
♪♪
Huh?
[narrator] George didn't think
food carts could disappear.
But maybe they did.
♪♪
A refrigerator!
Maybe they kept the fruit cups
in there.
Ahh! Ah-ha!
♪♪
Oh, hello, little monkey.
Are you lost?
[chatters in embarrassment]
This is the lab.
Oh!
We help the doctors
figure out
what's wrong with the patients.
Hey, want to see?
[chatters happily]
♪♪
Oh!
I'm checking to see if
this patient's blood cells
are healthy.
[chatters happily]
[gasps and chatters]
[chatters excitedly]
Oh... Goodbye!
Who were you talking to?
A monkey.
Oh.
[upbeat jazz music]
♪♪
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] There was a sink.
George hoped a kitchen
with fruit cups was nearby.
[gasps and chatters happily]
Sorry, only doctors
can come in here.
[chatters curiously]
This is the operating room,
where we perform
operations on patients.
[chatters in confusion]
Oh, well, when a person has
something wrong
with their body
that needs some--
[chatters excitedly]
Huh?
♪♪
[narrator] Another cart!
Maybe it had the lunch.
[chatters in disappointment]
[narrator] Nope, only laundry.
♪♪
Oh...
A-ha!
[narrator] This must be where
they kept the fruit cups.
♪♪
I brought a funny book
to read you today!
[children cheering]
And who do we have here?
[chattering happily]
[laughter and applause]
Hey, my name's Jesse.
I lead story time
for these children
who are staying
in the hospital.
Would you like to stay
and hear a story?
[chattering conversationally]
[all] Bye-bye.
[narrator] Unfortunately,
George couldn't stay.
He was on an important mission.
♪♪
Hello!
[narrator] George wondered
who that man was talking to.
[chatters inquisitively]
Do you want to see
my son in the nursery?
Uh-huh.
Ooh.
[chatters happily]
Want to say hi?
[sleepy music]
Look at my son.
Isn't he adorable?
Ah.
[chatters excitedly]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
[narrator]
George was in the cafeteria!
[triumphant music]
♪♪
A-ha!
[chatters in confusion]
Oh, hi there.
[chatters]
Mm.
Wish they had some grapes.
[chatters excitedly]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
Oh, thanks!
♪♪
Oh, good! You're back!
[chatters triumphantly]
[giggles]
Fruit cup?
Whoa! You got it!
Thanks, George.
[chatters happily]
♪♪
Ah...
Just like I remember.
[narrator] George was happy
he could help out his friend.
-Want some?
-Ah!
♪♪
Mm-mm.
Check out my new wheelchair.
The doctor says this is how
I have to get around
for a few weeks.
[chatters happily]
My mom's on her way,
but do you want a ride
before she gets here?
[chatters happily]
Well, climb aboard!
[upbeat music]
Whoa, George!
[laughter]
♪♪
[narrator] The next day was
a perfect day in the country
to build a city.
This was the biggest,
best block city
George had ever built.
It had roads,
and ramps,
and bridges.
[making car noises]
[narrator]
It even had a car wash.
[Bill] Yoo-hoo!
[chatters happily]
[narrator] Bill was back.
Wanna sign my cast?
[chatters happily]
The doctor says I have to
wear it for a few more weeks.
Check out the signatures
I've got so far.
My cousin, my mom,
and look!
One from my neighbor's dog.
[chatters happily]
Nice! Thanks, George!
Ooh! [chatters]
Um... My delivery replacement
is coming to pick up the
newspapers soon, but...
I can come in for a minute.
[chatters excitedly]
Ta-da!
Oh?
Huh?
Wheelchair means
I can't come in.
[chatters in disappointment]
[narrator]
What good was building a city
if you couldn't
show it to your friends?
[chatters thoughtfully]
[gentle piano music]
♪♪
Yeah!
A-ha!
[narrator]
Maybe there was a way.
♪♪
[chatters happily]
Hey, a ramp!
That is a particularly
good idea for a city kid.
♪♪
Whoa!
[narrator] Bill's weight made
the ramp bend in the middle.
They needed a way
to make it stronger.
[upbeat music]
Good idea!
[Carla] Excuse me!
Whoa!
Are you Bill?
That's me!
Carla.
And this is George.
[chatters happily]
Nice to meet you, George.
So where are those newspapers
you need delivered?
Uh, wait, uh...
You're the newspaper deliverer
who just moved to town?
You're looking at her.
You hurt your leg too?
Nope!
I've always used a wheelchair.
This is how I get around.
[giggles] Woohoo!
Wow!
[chatters in surprise]
Anyway, I'm happy
to take over your route.
What's the matter?
Are you sick?
Oh... No!
Uh, that is...
I was worried about getting
my whole route done
in time in a wheelchair.
Oh. In that case,
why don't we each take half?
That way, we'll do the job
twice as fast.
Sure!
Wanna come along?
Uh-huh!
[upbeat piano music]
♪♪
Whoa! Nice form!
Perfect accuracy!
Not bad, not bad at all.
Okay, my turn.
[grunts]
Uh... I gotta get used
to this chair.
[chatters helpfully]
Thanks, George!
[grunts]
And that's the last one!
We did it!
[chatters happily]
We're going over
to George's house
to see his block city.
Wanna come?
Sure! Sounds like fun!
[rock and roll music]
♪♪
[panting]
Whoa, nice ramp!
[imitating car noises]
Best block city
I've ever seen.
George is a city kid,
knows everything there
is to know about cities.
What's that?
[gentle piano music]
[chatters happily]
We've got a real
bowling alley in town.
We can take you there.
We know all the best spots
around here, right, George?
Ah!
Like where to pick
wild berries,
and a really cool cave.
Oh! And there's
a super secret...
[whispers]
middle of the woods pond.
Shh!
[whispers] A super secret
middle of the woods pond?
Yeah!
It's one of the best places
I've ever--
Actually, never mind.
It's not that great.
Huh?
Sounds great to me!
Yeah.
But it's a long hike,
and I broke my leg
just trying to walk there.
I'm up for the challenge.
Where is it?
It's way deep in the woods!
You have to get past
a bunch of thorn bushes.
Then there's a tree
across the path.
I don't think we could
get there in wheelchairs.
Well, we won't,
unless we try.
[chatters encouragingly]
I wish we could see all
the things we'll have to cross.
[gentle piano music]
Ah...
♪♪
Uh-huh... [giggles]
Good idea, George!
This is the log
we'll have to get over.
And there's the thorn bush
we'll have to pass.
Great! Now let's make a plan
to get through the woods.
Okay.
So how do we get over the log?
[chatters thoughtfully]
Ah!
But there's no ramp
in the woods.
[chatters disappointedly]
We can bring one.
[chatters happily]
Now, how are we going
to deal with that thorn bush?
Hmm...
[upbeat piano music]
Hard-packed trail
makes it easy!
Just you wait!
It gets a lot harder,
believe me.
♪♪
These are thorn bushes
I told you about.
[upbeat piano music]
[chatters happily]
Okay, if you really
think it'll work.
[chatters reassuringly]
♪♪
Hey, what do you know?
It worked!
♪♪
[grunting]
[all cheering]
[cheerful piano music]
♪♪
[giggles]
[laughing]
Huh. The rain must have
created a creek.
Ah!
[cheerful piano music]
[chattering helpfully]
♪♪
Good idea, George!
[chattering helpfully]
Okay, um...
[stammering]
Well...
Here goes nothing!
♪♪
Crossing... Crossing...
Ha! I made it!
[all laughing]
All right!
[squelching]
Oh, no!
Ugh. Mud.
Too sticky for our wheels.
[chatters in disappointment]
Guess you were right
after all, Bill.
[sad piano music]
It sure was nice up 'till now,
though.
Wait!
You're not--
You can't turn back!
We're almost there!
But we don't have a way
to get across.
Ooh! Hey!
[upbeat piano music]
♪♪
[chatters excitedly]
But...
[chatters helpfully]
Okay!
♪♪
This is working!
So let's figure out
how to get more boards.
[chatters happily]
♪♪
Good thinking!
Nice going, George!
♪♪
-Great job!
-We did it!
I told you we could do it!
Come on!
[cheerful piano music]
♪♪
You ready?
You bet!
♪♪
Wow!
[majestic music]
♪♪
The super secret
middle of the woods pond!
[frog croaks]
♪♪
[croaking together]
[giggling]
Wow!
I must be the only kid
who's ever
gotten his cast signed
by a dog, a city kid,
and a frog!
[all laughing]
Hey, you know
what the best part
of this super secret
middle of the woods pond is?
Getting to share it
with friends!
♪♪
[all oohing and aahing]