[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
♪♪
[narrator] Summer days
seem to last forever.
[air hissing]
[narrator] You need
a lot of ideas to fill them up.
Ooh.
[pigpen gate
squeaks rhythmically]
[narrator] Like playing "Jingle
Bells" on a squeaky hinge.
[squeaking]
[pigs oink]
Aww!
Aw, face it, George.
We'll never get to
"jingle all the way."
[grunts]
Whoa!
[squeals]
Huh?
[chittering]
Ah!
[chattering happily]
[chatters]
Ah!
Huh?
[blows]
Hmm.
That's me, all right,
at the Bucket Toss
at the ol' country Fair
when I was a kid.
If you tossed a bean bag
in a bucket,
you got points...
and the bucket!
Ah!
Oh, I remember.
[chatters]
Oh, that's a dunk booth!
[sighs] Doesn't get
better than a dunk booth.
You mean
hitting the bull's-eye
and dunking some poor guy
into the water?
No, being that guy!
[sighs]
What's more fun than getting
dunked
in a tank of cool water
on a hot summer day?
Yeah!
Ha!
Never thought of it that way.
Well, not that I'd know.
I never did get dunked.
But I always wanted to be.
Oh!
[narrator] And there it was.
One bona fide,
fun-filled, terrific idea
for a summer afternoon.
[chatters]
You want to make
our own fair, George?
[chatters excitedly]
[chuckles]
That's a great idea!
[chattering and laughing]
Okay.
Let us know if there's
anything we can do!
[grunting]
[both grunting]
[both laughing]
[chatters]
Yeah, we can use this!
We just need more buckets.
Hey! Aha!
[George chittering]
[chatters]
Hi, George.
Are those for your fair?
[chatters]
Okay. Great!
Wow.
Wonder where he
got all that stuff.
Oh.
[chatters]
Five, 10,
15, 20, 25.
Here, see how many
points you can get, George.
[chatters]
[metallic squeaking]
[grunts]
-[bell dings]
-Oh!
[laughs]
Hi, guys! Whatcha doing?
We're building
our own country fair.
No kidding?
Hey, what about a boat race?
I saw one at Sprouts camp.
Ooh! [chatters]
[chattering]
[mimics boat motor]
Ahoy, all hands on deck!
Aye, aye, Cap'n.
-[chatters]
-Huh?
[chatters]
Oh. Sure.
Of course.
I was just, you know,
cleaning them.
Wouldn't want dirty bath toys.
[chatters]
Wow, looks like your fair
has turned into a big project.
[chattering]
[water spraying]
Water?
Check.
Boats for the boat race?
[moans]
Making them go?
No idea.
[chattering]
[water sprays]
[chatters]
Maybe we should
forget the hose idea.
[chatters]
[water spritzing]
You want this, George?
Uh-huh.
Sure. I'm all done here.
[chatters]
Huh.
So you want another one?
Uh-huh!
[water spritzing]
[chatters]
Watch out, I'm catching up.
[George inhales and exhales
rhythmically]
Country fair?
We haven't had one
around here in years!
Uh, actually,
George and his friends
are putting one together
at the Renkins' farm.
Really?
Now, that's a fine idea.
If it's a fair,
you're gonna need
a lot more watermelon.
[water spraying]
I think
the water slide's ready.
What do you think, George?
[cheers]
[laughing]
Well, will you look at this?
Boat Race,
Bucket Toss, Water Slide:
you've got everything you need.
[chatters]
The dunk booth?
Actually,
I think I can help you there.
Got it after
the fair closed down.
Yep.
[chatters]
Mind if we borrow it?
Well...
only if you
invite me to your fair!
[laughs]
[chatters]
Wow!
That's the most wonderfullest
dunk booth
I've never-ever seen.
[water spraying]
[grunting]
[chattering]
[button clinks]
[metallic click]
Huh?
[chatters]
I think I know where
your problem lies, George.
Yep.
Thought so.
It's your hinge, all right.
Rusted stiff.
Hmm.
Huh?
Hinges are very important.
They're what let things
open and close.
Like the ones on this door.
Oh.
[chatters]
Hinges even help you
get around.
Huh?
Like your knees
and your elbows,
even your fingers:
all hinge joints.
[chatters]
Wow!
But fingers won't help
with a dunk booth.
We need a real hinge!
Hmm.
Ah!
[chatters]
[metallic squeaking]
[laughs]
[chatters]
Good work, George!
Lucky you found a hinge.
[chatters]
Guess what I brought!
A...
[gasps]
It's...
A dunk booth?
I'm goin' in!
This is it!
Okay, George, have at it!
[grunts]
Oops.
Don't worry.
Try again.
You can do it!
Dunk him!
-Hit the target!
-Come on, George!
[grunts]
[ball pings]
[gate thuds]
[pigs oinking]
Holy cow!
The pigs!
[chatters]
[pigs oinking, squealing]
[water splashes]
[munches]
Little Mike!
Stop eating the fair!
[oinks, munches]
[chatters]
Where's Little Mike?
Whoa, look!
I hear you're having a fair!
You don't mind if we
pitch in with a little music?
[chatters]
Um, George?
You guys?
Remember me?
[jaunty music]
[crowd chattering
indistinctly]
[both laughing]
[water splashing]
[metallic squeaking]
Watch and learn,
Mrs. Renkins.
'Cause if you got it,
you got it.
[grunts]
Eh.
Just warming up.
Concentrate now, George.
Eye on the target.
Come on, George.
You can do it!
[chatters]
-[pig thuds]
-Whoa!
[button clicks]
[yelps, water splashes]
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
George!
[laughs]
Thank you!
Oh, my! This is great!
[chatters]
Nice arm for a city kid,
George!
[chatters]
Stand back!
My turn!
I want to dunk
Mr. Yellow Trunks!
♪♪
[exciting music]
[dogs barking]
♪♪
[narrator]
When you know big stars--
even small big stars--
you sometimes get invited
to private rehearsals.
Ooh!
[narrator] And you can
bring your friends.
[barks]
[cheers and applause]
[music crescendos]
[cheers, barking, and applause]
Come up and say hi
if you want to.
[chatters]
Great show, Mr. Teckel!
Amazing!
[dogs barking]
[laughing]
Just need to paint the ramps,
and we're ready for tonight.
I'd be happy
to help if you like.
Me too.
Anything
for a fellow dachshund lover.
That's right kind of you!
[dogs licking]
[George giggling]
I'll need a place
to keep my dogs.
Can't have
paint-spattered pups.
[chatters]
You want to look after them,
George?
[chatters]
Terrific!
Here are their leashes,
if you want to take them
for a walk.
[chatters]
We'll be back to get them
before showtime tonight, okay?
[chatters]
[dogs barking]
Ah!
[narrator] No wonder
the dogs were so skilled.
They never stopped practicing.
[chatters]
[narrator] Though some parts
of the act still needed work.
[chatters]
[narrator] An apartment
was no place for rehearsals.
Huh?
[utensils crash]
[chatters]
[narrator] If only
George knew a spot
where dachshunds
stayed calm and quiet.
[chatters]
[narrator] He did!
The lobby!
It was the perfect
wiener dog habitat.
But...
how could he keep them there?
[chatters]
[narrator] Maybe that old gate
could help.
Hundley was amazed.
The monkey had created
a wiener wonderland.
[dogs barking]
[dogs slurping, whining]
[narrator] The doxies
had run out of water.
[dogs barking]
[Hundley barks]
[narrator] Hundley was happy
to have his guests
enjoy the entire lobby.
[dogs barking]
[howls]
[narrator]
If only they would stay there.
[barking]
[gate clattering]
[dogs barking]
[gasps]
[Hundley barking,
George chattering]
[both groan]
[narrator] They had to
get those doxies back.
[both whimper]
[narrator] But first
George wanted to know
how many he needed to catch.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Eight leashes in all...
which meant they had to find
eight missing dogs.
[barking]
[chatters]
[narrator] But where would
all those performing dogs go?
Ah!
[upbeat carnival music]
♪♪
[crowd chattering indistinctly]
[dogs barking, crowd murmuring]
[dogs barking]
-[grunts]
-[barks]
[both gasp]
[dogs barking]
[cheers and applause]
[leashes clicking]
[chatters]
No,
please thank your friends!
I've never sold so many melons!
[chatters]
[dogs barking]
[narrator] Hundley didn't want
the doxies to run off again.
What luck!
It was a big crate!
[barks]
[barking]
[chatters]
[dogs barking]
[narrator]
Even performing doxies
couldn't escape from there.
One, two, three.
With those three dogs safe,
George could count how
many he still had to go.
[Hundley whimpers]
-Huh?
-[whimpers]
Hmm.
[narrator] George started
with eight leashes,
and he'd found three dogs.
One, two, three, four, five.
He had five empty leashes.
So five dogs
were still missing.
Ack!
[narrator] Where did they go?
-Huh?
-[Hundley howling]
[whimpers]
Hey!
[chatters]
[narrator] Hundley
and the three doxies were safe.
Now to find the others.
-[dog barking]
-[gasps]
[narrator] It was the longest
wiener dog
George had ever seen.
Huh?
Oh!
[laughs]
[chatters]
[upbeat music]
[dog barking]
Way to go, Doggy!
-[barks]
-[grunts]
-Oh, hi, George.
-Hi.
[chatters]
You want to take a run?
Sure!
[dog barks, George chatters]
Ah!
[dog barks, licks]
[George giggles]
That was awesome!
Next time my dog gets loose,
I'm doing that!
[Hundley howls, whimpers]
[narrator] This wasn't right.
Weiner dogs were built
to be low to the ground.
[dogs barking]
[barks]
[narrator] Then again,
being up high
did have its advantages.
[barks]
[chatters]
[barking]
[gasps]
[barks]
[dogs barking]
[cheers]
[narrator] Hundley
had to admit
catching that thing was fun,
even if it
didn't taste very good.
One, two,
three, four, five, six.
There were
eight wiener dogs in all.
George now had six.
That meant he had to find...
[chatters]
[narrator] Two more dogs.
Eight dogs was
two more than six.
[dogs barking]
[barks]
[chatters]
[dogs barking]
[melodramatic music]
[grunting]
[barking]
[chatters]
[chatters, grunts]
[dogs barking, George yelps]
[dogs barking]
Ah.
[grunts]
Whoo-hoo!
[whimpers]
Aha!
Whoo-hoo!
[mechanical whirring]
[dogs bark]
[grunts]
Aha!
[mechanical whirring]
Did a monkey carrying two
wiener dogs just go by, Harold?
I think it's quittin' time,
Lloyd.
-[chatters]
-[narrator] One, two.
Two dogs plus six made eight.
George had them all.
[cheers]
[narrator] But he still had to
get them back home
before the show.
-George?
-Huh?
[chatters]
[dogs barking]
You guys brought my dogs
to the theater for me?
How kind.
[laughs, chatters]
[exciting music]
♪♪
Mr. Teckel
was really impressed
with how well you
took care of his dogs.
Yeah.
He said when he comes
to town next month,
he wants you to look after
his whole troop.
All 36 of them!
[cheers, chatters]
[whimpers, gulps]