[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[bright music plays]
♪♪
[bell rings]
[narrator]
When the firehouse bell
-rang across the countryside...
-[gasps]
[narrator] The volunteer
firefighters responded...
[bell tolls]
Even if there wasn't a fire.
Okay, George,
I think everyone has heard it.
Whoo-hoo!
[chatters]
You wanna get the siren,
George?
Uh-huh!
[sirens wailing]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
[laughs]
Hi!
♪♪
What a doozy of a turnout
for this year's
fireman's muster games.
I hope everyone
has been practicing
hose and ladder work.
I must've climbed up and down
to my tree house 100 times.
Excellent!
As you know,
each year,
our town volunteer firemen
face a different squad
in games that test
individual skills and teamwork.
And each year,
something goes wrong
and we lose.
Hmm...
[narrator] George remembered
that at last year's muster,
things did go wrong.
[dramatic music]
And got very wet.
But if we stay focused,
maybe this year,
we'll win that trophy!
Hooray!
[all cheering]
[sirens wailing]
Looks like this year's
opponents are here.
[punchy music]
Hi, everyone!
-Well, look at that.
-[excited chatter]
[narrator]
George couldn't believe it.
It was his friends
from the city,
Rescue Squad 86--
even Blaze.
-[barks]
-[laughs]
All right,
there are three games.
Allie here will keep score.
The team with the most points
at the end wins the trophy.
Our first game is a test
of teamwork and strength:
the fruit and veggie wash.
[both teams ooh and ahh]
[martial music]
Each team must
build up enough pressure
in these antique
water pumpers
to hit their
red or yellow targets.
[both teams
chatter indistinctly]
[chatters]
Oh, that looks
kind of challenging, huh?
Very challenging.
Is this fair?
Our team has more people.
Now, now, now.
The number of people
on your team
isn't as important
as how you work together.
The key is teamwork.
[bright music]
Captains,
are your teams ready?
-Ready.
-We're ready.
Go!
[upbeat music]
♪♪
-[grunts]
-[worried chatter]
Other side!
Oh, my gosh, we need people
on the other side!
♪♪
No, no, no.
Not everybody.
You four on that side.
Everyone else over here!
♪♪
That's it.
Now, pull for your lives!
-[all grunting]
-Faster!
♪♪
Ah, steady rhythm, team.
Steady!
♪♪
[Rescue Squad 86] Yeah!
The Red Team wins!
Aww, fiddlesticks!
Aww.
A bucket brigade takes
teamwork and coordination.
Fill your buckets,
pass them down the line,
and empty them down there
into your trough.
The first team
with a full trough wins.
Wanna try it, George?
Uh-huh.
[grunts]
[disappointed chatter]
Full fire buckets
are really heavy.
-Uh-huh.
-[cow moos]
[bright music]
Ah!
Great idea, George!
These milk buckets
are a lot lighter.
Too bad they don't hold
as much water, though.
[chatters curiously]
Nope.
Why don't you see for yourself?
[chattering]
Huh?
[narrator] It took
two small milk buckets
to hold as much water
as one large one.
The little ones
are easier to carry,
but we have to carry more.
That's math for you.
[groans]
Lucky for us,
we have more people.
Ah.
Go!
[all grunting]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
Winner-- the yellow team!
-Yeah!
-Whoo-hoo!
[all cheering]
Both sides have one point!
We did it!
We tied!
Yippee!
Yi-hoo!
Ya... hoo for us.
Our final event
is Midnight Alarm.
It's a humdinger.
Whoever wins,
wins the muster!
This game tests
each team's response
to a surprise
nighttime emergency.
When the alarm sounds,
each team must
put on their gear,
attach their hose
to their truck,
and run it all the way
to the other side of that hill,
and shoot it off.
-We got this.
-Oh yeah, we're gonna win.
[chattering excitedly]
[woman]
Yellow team's got this one.
Okay,
night night, everyone.
["Brahms' Lullaby" plays]
[happy grunt]
-[music cuts off]
-[alarm rings]
Get up! Get up!
There's an emergency!
All right,
let's do this.
[panicked chatter]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[grunts softly]
[barking]
♪♪
[George] Ah!
That's a new way to do it.
[uneasy music]
[wobbly chattering]
Huh?
Ah!
[chattering energetically]
[upbeat music]
♪♪
[laughs]
Nice shortcut, George!
[chattering happily]
[barking]
[wood creaks]
Yellow ready.
Turn on the hose now.
Hurry, turn it on.
Red ready.
[hoses hissing]
[chatters]
♪♪
Red Team wins.
-All right!
-Yeah!
-[disappointed grunt]
-Aww, so close.
So darn close.
Congratulations, Stig.
-[wood crashing]
-Huh?
[Blaze barking loudly]
[chattering]
[whimpers]
-[barks]
-Hang tight, boy!
-[radio buzzes]
-We're gonna need a long ladder.
It's too short.
We should get our ladder truck
from the city.
Oh, that'll take hours.
[determined chattering]
[narrator] George knew
Blaze couldn't wait for hours.
-[barking]
-Ah.
[chatters]
Okay, it's set up.
Come on, Blaze!
[chatters]
-[whimpers]
-[encouraging chatter]
[airbag whooshes]
[victorious music]
-[all cheering]
-Whoo-hoo!
Ah, that's well done,
George!
-Yeah!
-Way to go, guys!
And so,
the winner of this year's
fireman's muster is...
the Town Volunteers!
What?
[excited chatter]
You get extra points
for a real rescue.
It's in the rules.
-Here you go.
-[gasps]
A muster tests who's
best prepared for an emergency,
and today, that was you.
We only brought
a truck and a ladder.
You brought the monkey.
Well, Neptune's knickers...
[laughs]
Well, thank y'all,
and thank you, George.
Aww.
[all cheering]
-[chattering happily]
-[barks]
[yelps]
[sputters]
[laughs]
[bright music]
♪♪
[narrator] The city
could be a hectic place
for both man and monkey.
[cars honking]
[drivers shouting angrily]
Hmm, looks like
the traffic light is out.
Oh.
Phew.
Home, sweet home, George.
Ready for breakfast?
[excited chatter]
[indistinct chatter]
[gasps]
[busy music]
[phone rings]
Uh-huh?
Yes.
No.
Maybe.
Oh, okay.
Right.
-Bye-- oh, ah!
-[elevator dings]
Whoa.
Ah!
I'll get that.
The good news is,
the carpet cleaners
are coming today.
The bad news is,
they were supposed
to come tomorrow.
Plus,
one person is moving out,
someone else is moving in,
two apartments
are being renovated,
and the air conditioning
on the roof is being fixed.
Oh.
-[lead hiker] All right, folks.
-[gasps]
Keep those knees high.
Oh, and did I mention the
Senior Citizens' Hiking Club
is practicing
for a big climb?
-Oh-- hang on!
-[crash]
It looks like
we need to get more eggs.
Yeah.
By the way, have
either of you seen Hundley?
I sure could use his help.
-[chatters]
-Haven't seen him.
[chattering]
You want me
to get more eggs
while you look for Hundley?
[approving chatter]
Good thinking, George.
Looks like they need
all the help they can get.
I'll be right back.
Uh-huh.
[indistinct chatter]
[sniffing]
Ah!
[chattering]
Huh?
[narrator] George was sure he'd
seen Hundley go into the box.
Huh?
Huh.
This way, gentleman!
Gently, gently.
Easy does it.
This way.
George,
this is Bruno the Great.
He's a magician who's
moving into our building.
Ah.
Salutations,
my simian friend.
Well, what do we
have here, hm?
Ah-- whoa!
-Ah, ooh.
-Amazing!
Thank you, thank you.
Enjoy, yes.
-Isn't he the greatest?
-[crash]
[grunts] Now if only he could
make some confusion disappear.
[chomping happily]
Oh!
[wacky music]
♪♪
-[gasps]
-Gadzooks, my bunnies!
Don't worry, Bruno,
I'll give you a hand.
Oh.
Huh?
[squeaks worriedly]
[panting, yips]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
[whistle blowing]
[mellow music]
♪♪
Ah.
[whistle blowing]
[narrator] George was amazed
at how the officer
could make the traffic
flow so orderly.
Ah.
[indistinct chatter]
Buford!
Where did you scamper off to?
[gasps]
[chattering]
Egad!
Florence!
[narrator] The lobby
needed to be orderly too.
Maybe George could help.
♪♪
[chattering excitedly]
Uh...
[groans]
[narrator] But first,
he needed a way to get
people's attention.
[whistle blowing]
-Ah!
-[narrator] A whistle.
That's what he needed.
[chatters]
-[gasps]
-[whistle trills]
[laughs]
-[inhales]
-[whistle blows]
Ah!
[narrator]
It worked!
Huh?
[narrator] George wasn't sure
what to do next.
[whimpers]
[chatters]
[chatters uneasily]
[squeals]
-[elevator dings]
-Huh?
-[whistle blows]
-Ah.
[chattering]
[narrator]
No one understood
what George
was trying to tell them.
[grunts]
Ah!
Oh...
[squeaks]
[groans]
[vacuum whooshing]
Oh.
[narrator] George needed
to do more research.
[whistle blowing]
The traffic officer
had a different signal
for each command.
[chattering quietly]
[narrator] Stop.
Go.
Stop.
Turn this way.
Turn that way.
Ah...
[laughs]
[upbeat music]
[narrator]
George had the signals.
Now he just needed
to look the part.
[victorious music]
George was ready to put
his skills to the test.
[whistle blows]
He had the contractors stop...
and the movers go.
[whistle blows]
-[elevator dings]
-Turn this way.
Go that way.
♪♪
-Ah.
-[elevator dings]
Huh?
[uneasy music]
George needed the movers
to go under the boards,
but he didn't have
a hand signal for that.
Ah.
[whistle blowing]
[narrator] Over and under.
Ah!
[narrator] It worked!
[victorious laugh]
Huh?
♪♪
[whistle blows]
Bunny crossing.
Florabelle!
You are full of beans,
you naughty little hopper!
Hey, George.
Nice signals.
You've really got
the lobby under control.
[phone rings]
[barking]
[chatters]
[laughs]
[confused chattering]
[whistle blows]
[narrator]
With George's help,
the lobby traffic
was all flowing smoothly.
[gasps]
[gasps,
relieved sigh]
[narrator] But there was still
one mission left to accomplish.
-[wood skidding]
-[gasps]
[uneasy music]
[gulps]
[squawks]
[grunts]
Phew.
Close one.
[whistle blows]
Oh!
[chatters]
[narrator] Bunnies were
not good at taking direction.
Genevieve...
[laughs]
I've been looking
all over for you.
Ah.
That's the last bunny!
[elevator dings]
[whistle blows]
[mellow music]
♪♪
[chatters]
[victorious music]
[laughs]
Made it!
[applause]
♪♪
Good work, George.
I think Hundley and I
can take it from here.
[chatters]
Uh, where is Hundley?
[muffled barking]
[gasps]
[both] Huh?
[drum roll]
-Ah!
-[barks]
[panting, barking]
[mellow music]
♪♪
Time for breakfast, George.
[cheers, chatters]
[whistle blowing]
[narrator] George had never
worked so hard for breakfast,
nor had so much fun.
Phew.
[elevator dings]
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪