[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[marimba music]
♪♪
[narrator]
George loved fishing.
Eh...
Hey!
[narrator] But his technique
needed a little work.
You city kids sure do some
strange things
to pass the time.
Hello!
[grunts]
Fishing is lots more fun than
catching algae.
Wanna join me tomorrow?
I'll lend you a rod.
[hooting]
Fishin' is best really early.
So you have to meet me here
at 4:30 in the morning.
Ah? Hmm...
[narrator] George didn't think
he'd ever been up that early.
Aha!
You just wind this dial
in the back.
And then move
the thinnest hand
to when you want to wake up.
Oh. Ah, ah, ah, ah.
Four in the morning? Okay.
You sure you don't want me
to wake you?
Uh-uh.
Goodnight, George.
Happy fishing.
Ah-ah.
[snoring]
[alarm jangling]
[narrator] Sure enough, George
woke up at exactly 4:00 a.m.
[grumbling]
[dresser rattling]
[narrator] Or did he
wake up at all?
[snorts, yawns]
[gasps]
Oh George,
you're still here?
Uhh...
Someone's here to see you.
[chattering excitedly]
It's 8:00. I've been
back for an hour already.
Aww.
That's okay.
You can come with me tomorrow.
Ooh! [hooting]
But after tomorrow there's
only one fishing day left.
Then I'm putting away
the boat until next year.
[chattering worriedly]
You want me to wake you,
George?
Uh-uh. [jabbering]
[narrator]
George knew he could do it
because this time,
he had a plan.
Ahh.
[narrator] There was no way
George's sleepy self
would sleep through this
obstacle course.
[grunting happily]
Ah! [laughs]
[jabbering]
[sighs contentedly]
[alarm jangling]
[grunts]
[grumbling]
[narrator]
But George's sleepy self
was even smarter than
his awake self.
[grunts]
[dresser rattling]
[exhales softly]
George?
[yawns]
Ah! [jabbering]
Ah! [chattering]
You overslept, but you still
have one more chance.
You sure you don't me
to wake you this time?
Hmm...
[chattering]
Okay. Good luck, buddy.
[narrator] There had to be a way
for George to wake himself up!
[gibbering]
[narrator] But what was it?
Hey! Ah!
Hmm.
Aha!
[narrator] If an apple
fell on his head,
he'd wake up for sure.
[Allie] Hey, George!
Wanna help me feed
the chickens?
Yeah! [hooting]
[narrator] George's
problem could wait.
Nothing beats feeding chickens!
[laughing]
[chickens clucking]
Ah!
[gibbering]
[narrator] Birdseed wasn't
heavy like an apple,
but it still could wake him.
Ah! [chattering]
This birdseed?
Whatcha gonna do with it?
Pour it on your head?
Uh-huh, uh-huh!
Okay, we got plenty more
in the barn.
Ah. [chattering]
[humming]
[chickens clucking]
[clucking]
[duck quacks]
[screams]
[narrator] Birdseed
was way too messy.
Aww.
[narrator] And it was all gone.
Now what was he going to do?
[clucking, tweeting]
[quacking]
Eh?
[narrator] Foam balls
could wake him up!
Ah!
Aww, hey!
[murmuring]
[narrator] But how could George
get them to fall on him?
Ah!
Ah-ah-ah!
[pleasant music]
♪♪
Ah!
Ahh! [laughs]
[narrator] Now all he had to do
was pull the string at 4 a.m.,
and--
[murmuring]
[narrator] How was George
going to pull the string,
if he was asleep?
[muttering]
[clucks]
Yeah!
[narrator] The heavy book
could fall on the string--
that would open the flap!
Yeah!
Oh.
[narrator] But now George needed
something to push the book,
so that it could pull
the string.
[groans]
[tweeting]
Ah!
[narrator] His toy truck
could push the book!
[chattering happily]
[grunts]
Yeah! [hooting]
[narrator] Now, he would
he get the truck to go?
[gibbering]
Hmm. [jabbering]
[narrator]
George needed something
to make the truck start moving.
And move at the right time.
Ah.
[grunting]
[alarm jangling]
The ringer hit the bells
when the alarm went off.
Could the ringer
push the truck?
[jabbering excitedly]
[relaxed music]
♪♪
[jangling]
[cheering]
[narrator] George's
wake-up-machine was set to go.
[yawns]
[narrator] And just in time.
He was tired.
[grunts]
[narrator] But it was hard to
sleep with a tube of balls
hanging over his head.
[yawns]
[groaning]
[sighs]
[narrator] George decided to
watch from the sidelines.
[yawns, mumbles]
[jangling]
[cheering]
[hooting]
[narrator] George's wake-up
machine was even
better than he'd imagined!
But now George was
really tired.
[yawns]
[narrator] He didn't see
the harm in closing his eyes
for just a minute...
[snoring]
[birds clamoring]
[narrator]
The birds were tired, too,
and they couldn't sleep
with that snoring.
[clucking]
Uh, [gasps]
Huh? [chattering]
[narrator]
George hadn't overslept!
Now he had two
ways to get up:
a wake-up machine,
and wake-up birds.
[jabbering]
[chattering]
[laughs] Wow!
[gasps] Hey George! I think
you got something!
Ah! [hooting]
[straining]
[cheerful music]
♪♪
[narrator] It was time
for Spring Cleaning,
when you give away stuff
you don't want
to someone who does!
What about these?
Keep or give away?
[gasps] Eh?
[chattering happily]
George, are you sure you want
to keep them both?
Eh...
Ah-ah!
Okay. Another child
will love that toy.
Would you take this downstairs
and put it with
the other donation boxes?
[chattering]
-Hi.
-Oh, great, George.
Why don't you put that over
there with the other donations?
Ah?
[narrator] What was a lampshade
doing in Hundley's bed?
[gasps]
[barking]
Is everything alright, boy?
[chattering]
Hundley just got
back from the vet.
He's got an ear infection
and the cone
is to prevent him
from scratching.
Ohhh.
[alarm beeping]
Oh, lunch time!
I'll go get us our food, boy.
[woofs]
[upbeat jazzy music]
♪♪
[grunts]
[moans]
[narrator] Hundley looked like
he could use a little help.
Hey! [gibbering]
[narrator] Hundley knew George
wanted to hold the bowl.
But he remembered the last
time George tried to help.
[jabbering]
[narrator]
It didn't turn out well.
But Hundley was thirsty.
[groans]
Ah!
[slurping]
[murmuring]
That was nice of you, George.
Wow, you were thirsty!
But you sure made a mess.
Here you go, boy.
Eat up.
[watch beeps]
Oh, duty calls!
George, would you take
over until Hundley's finished?
Uh-huh.
[humming]
[chomping]
[narrator]
George liked helping Hundley,
but it was a little
boring being a table.
[sighs]
Aha!
[narrator] Maybe that was
all Hundley needed!
[jabbering excitedly]
[grunts]
[hooting]
George, which tie should
I donate?
There's such a subtle
difference in the yellow.
Ah-ah.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, glad to see you're getting
into the hang
of Spring cleaning.
Yeah!
[bright music]
♪♪
[gibbering]
Ha, ha! Aww.
[groaning]
Aww.
Ooh, ah!
Ah!
♪♪
[narrator] Maybe George could
build more stands for Hundley.
♪♪
Would you look at that,
Hundley?
[toys clatter]
Uh-oh.
[narrator] Maybe the cone made
it hard for Hundley to see.
Special delivery!
Nice sculptures.
Ah!
Sign here, please!
[hooting]
Hey, little guy.
Ahh.
Hi! [giggling]
[narrator] The mirror helped
the bike messenger see.
That's what Hundley needed.
♪♪
[chattering]
Hey! Ah!
[chitters]
Oh, good idea.
I should donate some
sunglasses.
Don't forget to take a box!
[murmuring]
Ooh, I'm definitely
keeping these!
Eh!
[narrator] This would make
a perfect mirror for Hundley.
Now all he needed was a way
to attach it to Hundley's cone.
[gasps] Huh?
Ah!
Aha.
[pleasant music]
♪♪
Ah!
Ooh!
[gibbering]
Ah!
[sniffs, groans]
Urh?
[yelping]
[objects clattering]
Ah-ah.
[growls]
[narrator] Poor Hundley.
The mirror seemed
to confuse him.
[Mrs. Parker]
Now, where's my sweet Hundley?
[barks, panting]
[narrator] It was Hundley's
favorite tenant, Mrs. Parker.
Are you ready to escort me?
[narrator] Hundley always
escorted Mrs. Parker
up a few stairs.
Ooh, [chattering]
[groaning]
Oh, are you stuck, dear?
Well, don't worry, you can
escort me some other time.
[whimpering]
Hmm.
[narrator] If he had a ramp,
Hundley could
easily escort Mrs. Parker.
[funky music on headphones]
Whew.
Only one more box to go.
Huh?
[cheerful music]
♪♪
Hmm?
Huh.
[grunting happily]
Ah!
♪♪
Ah...
Whoa!
[groans]
[gasps]
♪♪
[barks]
Aha! [chatters]
[narrator] Hundley couldn't
believe it!
George's ramp actually worked!
[barks, panting]
[rumbling]
Urf?
[both yelp]
[barking frantically]
Aww.
[narrator] George felt sad.
Hundley was so upset.
And he had to wear that cone!
Aww.
[narrator] George couldn't
imagine being stuck
in a cone all day.
Hmm.
[gasps]
[narrator] Or could he?
Whoo!
[cheerful music]
♪♪
Yeah!
[narrator] George could now
experience the world
through a coneheaded
dachshund's eyes.
[grunts]
[narrator] It sure
was hard to see.
[moans]
[grunting]
[narrator] And hard
to get comfortable.
[groans]
Hey!
[narrator] But he could show
Hundley he knew how he felt.
Urh, urh?
[panting]
Urh?
[narrator] What on Earth
was George up to?
Ah! [barking]
[narrator] George had a cone
so he could be like Hundley?
[growling]
Aww.
[narrator] Hundley thought
that was the nicest thing
George had ever done for him.
[grunting]
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ah!
Ah! [giggling]
[pleasant music]
♪♪
[sighs softly]
[humming]
[both snoring]
[upbeat jazz music]
♪♪