[upbeat theme music plays]
♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[chorus] Swing!
-♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Every day ♪
-♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-♪ And everything ♪
[chorus] ♪ Everything ♪
-♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Wondrous ♪
♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[chorus] Whoa!
-♪ I get curious ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Curious ♪
-♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[chorus] ♪ Marvelous ♪
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
♪♪
[chattering happily]
[narrator] George loved
visiting the Renkin's farm,
because there was always
something new to see.
[chattering cheerfully]
[narrator] And in Spring, there
were even more new things.
-[chuckles]
-[cow moos]
Yep, Leslie had a new calf.
And she wasn't the only one!
Gertie had a kid.
[coos softly]
And Pearl had
a litter of piglets.
[pigs snort and squeal]
[chatters sadly]
Oh, that's Hamilton.
He's the runt of the litter.
[jabbering in confusion]
The runt is
the smallest one, George.
He'll need special care
until he's a little bigger.
[playful piano music]
♪♪
[coos]
[chatters helpfully]
You want to
take care of Hamilton?
[chatters happily]
George, taking care
of a little piglet
is a big responsibility.
How about you help me plant
these gladiola bulbs instead?
[melancholy piano music]
[groans]
Now, you want to plant
these four inches deep.
[playful piano music]
[squealing]
[cries worriedly]
[chattering]
[squealing]
Wow, that little pig
sure is fast!
Thank goodness
George stopped him.
[chatters]
♪♪
Okay, I guess Hamilton comes
home with us for a while.
[chatters triumphantly]
I'll get you some supplies
and make a list
of all the things you'll have
to do to take care of Hamilton.
First, you're going
to have to feed him
four times a day.
-[chatters]
-[snorting]
[narrator] George tried
to listen to Farmer Renkins.
You'll need a warm blanket.
[narrator] But he couldn't help
dreaming of all the fun
he and his little buddy
would have.
You want to give him a bath.
[jazz music]
[sighs]
[cheerful jazz music]
[snorting]
Here's the list of
directions from Mr. Renkins.
Don't want to lose this.
♪♪
Everything Hamilton needs
is in the sack.
I'm gonna take these bulbs
to the garden.
[giggles]
Holler if you need anything.
[chattering happily]
[snorting]
[narrator]
Hamilton must be hungry.
Feeding him would be George's
first piglet care task.
[rumbling]
And George
would feed himself too.
♪♪
Why was Hamilton so squealy?
[squealing]
♪♪
He probably
just wanted a better seat.
[snorting]
Who didn't like a peanut
butter, jelly, banana,
and carrot sandwich?
[gasps]
[narrator]
Hamilton, that was who.
Maybe he just
needed a little help.
[chattering happily]
♪♪
[snorting]
[cries]
[narrator] Feeding a piglet
required patience.
[clattering]
[playful marimba music]
[snorting]
[chattering worriedly]
♪♪
Hi, George.
Huh? How'd you get up there?
You hungry, Hamilton?
[snorting]
[chattering inquisitively]
This bottle?
This is Hamilton's food.
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
Who knew it was so easy?
[chattering happily]
You sure you can feed him?
Okay, here you go.
[coos]
[narrator] After lunch,
George was ready
to give Hamilton some exercise.
[grunting happily]
[chattering happily]
[squealing]
[chattering worriedly]
[narrator] Well, at least one
of them would get exercise.
[cheerful marimba music]
♪♪
[chattering in confusion]
[chewing]
♪♪
[chattering questioningly]
Well, Hamilton uprooted
all my gladiola bulbs.
[unsure chattering]
Pigs like to dig things
out of the ground.
How about you two play
in the front yard?
[chattering happily]
[cheerful marimba music]
♪♪
[groans]
[narrator] Maybe soccer just
wasn't Hamilton's game.
Luckily,
George knew plenty of others.
[chattering happily]
[giggling]
[coos]
[groans]
[cheerful flute music]
[chattering happily]
[snorting]
[spitting and gasping]
[narrator] George was ready
for his very first
Hamilton sleepover.
[squealing]
[snorting]
[whines]
You know, George, not every
animal likes to be picked up
like a little monkey.
[chattering in confusion]
Yeah.
Maybe we should make
him a bed down here
so we don't have
to carry him upstairs.
[whines]
[sleepy piano music]
[snorting]
♪♪
Say good night, George.
[coos]
Don't worry, George.
You can have more fun
with Hamilton tomorrow.
[coos]
[narrator] But George didn't
really have fun with Hamilton.
And now, they weren't
even having a sleepover.
[bluesy piano music]
♪♪
George wondered
why the day hadn't gone better.
[hooting]
♪♪
But there were a lot of things
George wondered about.
Like how those baby owls
could eat a worm.
Ew!
♪♪
Owls must just be different
than monkeys.
[chattering happily]
[narrator] Maybe that was it.
George was caring for Hamilton
like he was a little monkey,
instead of a little pig.
[squealing]
[chattering in concern]
[chattering]
[squealing]
[coos]
[narrator]
George remembered that Hamilton
liked drinking from a bottle.
[squealing]
[coos]
[narrator] Nope, not hungry.
[whines]
[narrator] George wished
he knew what Hamilton wanted.
[chattering happily]
[narrator] Mr. Rankin's list!
Maybe that had the answer.
[snorting]
[coos]
[narrator] That was the problem.
Little pigs liked
to be cozy and warm!
[chattering happily]
[snorting]
[narrator] It worked.
[coos]
[narrator] George finally slept,
thinking of all the fun he and
Hamilton would have together
tomorrow, little piggy style.
[soft piano music]
♪♪
[cheerful music]
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
Before George knew it,
Hamilton was big and strong,
and it was time
to take him home.
Ha! You did a fine job
raising Hamilton, George.
Now we just have to see
if his brothers and sisters
will accept him.
[cheerful piano music]
[chattering nervously]
[snorting]
♪♪
[squealing]
-[chattering happily]
-Yay!
[narrator] George had done it.
He had raised a pig.
Okay, George.
Time to go.
[coos]
[snorting]
[whines]
[narrator] Had Hamilton
forgotten George?
[snorting]
[squealing]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] Not a chance.
[coos]
[ominous marimba music]
♪♪
[narrator] George was excited
to try out
his brand new watercolors.
[grunts]
Time for bed, George!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to startle you.
♪♪
There, it's still okay.
[chatters gloomily]
[soft piano music]
♪♪
Sleep well.
Tomorrow, we're going
to the park with Hundley.
[sighs]
♪♪
Nighty-night.
[sighs]
[dreamy music]
[laughing]
[panting]
[chattering happily]
[barking]
[cheerful music]
[growling]
[chattering in curiosity]
[gasps]
[narrator] George had never seen
a green rhino
in the park before.
[screams]
[tense music]
[snorting]
[screams]
♪♪
Bad rhino!
You bring that back!
[grunts in confusion]
♪♪
[barking]
[chattering in confusion]
[chattering happily]
[barks]
[screaming]
[gasping]
George!
Are you all right?
[coos]
[chattering nervously]
[grunting angrily]
[cawing]
You saw that rhino
and a flying dog?
[chattering nervously]
Oh, it sounds
like a nightmare.
[coos in confusion]
It's a scary dream.
Dreams are stories in your head
and we call the scary dreams
nightmares.
But they aren't real.
[whimpering]
[narrator]
It sure seemed real to George.
[playful marimba music]
But the Man
didn't have a horn now.
Were you dreaming of me too?
[whimpers]
Well when you wake up,
and see your bed and your room,
you know you're safe
and everything is okay.
See?
[soft marimba music]
♪♪
Hey, there's Hundley.
[quacking]
[chattering nervously]
[barking]
Ahh, so it was Hundley who
was flying in your dream.
George had a nightmare
last night.
Oh, I once had one
where the mailman
delivered a box of mice!
And they ran all over my lobby!
♪♪
[rustling]
[narrator]
Was that the rhinoceros?
[chattering nervously]
[suspenseful music]
[barking]
[giggles]
[sighs]
[narrator] Maybe what
George saw the night before
really was just a nightmare.
[cheerful marimba music]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] That night, George
wasn't going to take any chances.
♪♪
So he had a plan.
He couldn't have a nightmare
if he couldn't fall asleep.
♪♪
But a tired little monkey
can't stay awake forever.
♪♪
[musical grunting]
That did not
sound like the Man.
[suspenseful music]
[musical grunting continues]
[screaming]
[water rushing]
♪♪
[shouting, whimpering]
-George?
-[chattering nervously]
[grunting]
The rhino
was taking a shower?
[chattering earnestly]
Uh-huh,
and then the tub overflowed?
[chattering excitedly]
Aww, it sounds like you had
another nightmare, George.
It's over now.
[whines]
[chattering excitedly]
That rhino really gave you
a nightmare.
I had one like that once.
It was about a unicorn.
[carousel music]
I was riding on a carousel,
and suddenly, the unicorn
I was on took off!
I tried to hang on.
[screaming]
[splashing]
But I couldn't.
And I landed
in a big puddle of mud.
[chattering encouragingly]
Thanks. Every night
for a week afterwards,
I made a wall around my bed
to keep that unicorn away.
[grunts thoughtfully]
[playful music]
[narrator]
That night, George decided
to rhino-proof his room.
Surely these critters
would protect him.
♪♪
A tent would make
him feel cozy and safe.
♪♪
No dream rhino
could get past all that.
[soft music]
[sighs]
♪♪
[snoring]
[screaming]
George!
Are you okay?
[chattering nervously]
That rhino again, huh?
[whimpering]
I think it's time
we consult the experts.
They'll know what
to do about nightmares.
Nightmares?
No, we don't know
what to do about those.
[chatters in disbelief]
[narrator] George thought
scientists knew everything.
There's actually a lot
we don't know about sleep.
But we do know
that your brain stays active
during sleep.
Yes, your brain uses
sleep time to repair
and grow muscles,
and fight sickness.
And it makes up stories.
Some of them can be scary.
[calm piano music]
It's time
for my afternoon nap!
Want to see what my brain
looks like when I'm dreaming?
[chattering happily]
[snoring]
♪♪
He's dreaming now.
[coos]
Hey!
[snorting]
Stop eating my prize!
He has that nightmare a lot.
He wins a big science prize,
but it's made of butterscotch
and the other scientists
eat it!
♪♪
Ah, oh my!
That was a doozy.
[breathing deeply]
[chattering in curiosity]
Well, I don't know how
to stop nightmares, George.
But when I wake up from one,
I hug my pillow
and take two deep breaths.
[breathing deeply]
Yes, just like that.
It always makes me feel better.
[chattering happily]
I like to draw my nightmares
in a dream journal
to remind myself
how silly they are.
You see?
[giggling]
[chattering happily]
You want to draw
your dreams too?
[chattering happily]
Okay. We'll try that tonight.
[cheerful music]
[giggling]
[narrator] That rhino
didn't look so scary now.
Bedtime, George.
[chattering happily]
Is that the rhinoceros
in your nightmare?
[chattering proudly]
♪♪
You want to make him
your pet?
[chattering happily]
Well, good thing
it's just a dream pet rhino.
We don't have the space
for a real one.
[giggling]
Nighty-night, George.
[sighs]
♪♪
[snorting]
[bombastic music]
♪♪
[shouts]
Everything okay, George?
[chattering nervously]
The rhino again, huh?
You want me to sit with you?
[grunts]
[narrator]
George was a little afraid.
But he decided to do
what Professor Pizza did.
[breathing deeply]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] It worked!
He did feel a little better.
[sighs contentedly]
[chattering happily]
Okay.
I'm right in my room
if you need me.
♪♪
[sighs]
[rhino grunting musically]
♪♪
[snoring]
[fast swing music]
♪♪