[upbeat music]
[man]♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man]♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man]♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man]♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
♪ You just can't miss ♪
[all] Whoa!
[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
[all] ♪ Curious ♪
[man]♪ And that's marvelous ♪
[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[whimsical music]
♪ ♪
I, Marco-riffic the Magician,
am here to amaze you.
[dramatic musical flourish]
-Wow.
-Ooh.
[male narrator] George had seen
magicians before,
but he didn't know
he actually knew one.
And now I shall end my show
with my most stupendous trick,
the reappearing rabbit.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪ ♪
Abra-ca-rabbitah!
[dramatic musical flourish]
[excited chatter]
[narrator] The rabbit was gone?
How was that possible?
♪ ♪
Rabbitus, return to us.
[victorious music]
[excited chatter]
Thank you, thank you.
[applause]
Come back for my next show
this afternoon.
[narrator] George had
to learn that trick.
Ah.
Hmm.
[chattering happily]
You want to be a magician?
[grunting excitedly]
Well, first you have
to learn a trick.
[chattering happily]
The reappearing rabbit trick?
That one's kind of hard.
[chattering happily]
Okay, you better take notes.
There are a lot of steps.
[chattering excitedly]
[upbeat music]
Step one. See this
little compartment here?
[grunts affirmatively]
This is where
your bunny hides
when he "disappears."
Make sure this door's closed
before you start.
[grunts excitedly]
Step two.
Put your bunny on the table
and your hat on the bunny.
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
Step three.
Press the hidden foot pedal.
This pedal opens that trap door
beneath the bunny.
And he goes into
the compartment.
See?
[chuckles]
[chatters curiously]
♪ ♪
Step four.
While you show everyone
the rabbit is gone,
put some food on the table.
Sniffles likes radishes.
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
Step five.
Press the pedal again.
And the rabbit comes back
for the food.
Raise the hat,
and ta-da!
[chatters excitedly]
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
[chatters worriedly]
[chuckles] I told you there
were a lot of steps.
[counting steps]
♪ ♪
Whoa.
You'll want to keep those cards
in the right order.
Here, let me arrange them
for you.
[chatters appreciatively]
There.
Now step one is on top.
You can borrow my table
for a few hours to practice.
I'll pick it up before my show.
-Ah.
-Oh.
You can't borrow Sniffles.
He only works for me.
But I'm sure you could find
some other little critter.
♪ ♪
[narrator] George wondered
what animal he could get
to help him with the trick.
[coos]
'Ey.
[chatters excitedly]
[coos]
[whimsical music]
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] How about Compass?
At least he was good
at disappearing.
[blows]
[chatters inquisitively]
[narrator] And reappearing.
[chuckles]
[coos]
[door knocks]
Thanks for coming over.
Apparently just me isn't
a big enough audience.
[chattering excitedly]
Uh, I mean, welcome to Monkey
the Magnificent's Magic Show.
[chatters happily]
-[chuckles] I love magic.
-Oh, me too.
In eighth grade I was actually
known as the Wizard in Yellow.
Oh, you don't say.
[playful music]
[chattering happily]
[coos]
♪ ♪
[chattering excitedly]
Whoa.
♪ ♪
[chattering excitedly]
[chatters worriedly]
-[chattering happily]
-[cooing]
[victorious music]
-[whistles]
-Great job, George.
-Encore, George, encore.
-Encore, encore.
Encore.
[doorbell rings]
Hi, Marco. You're just in time
for George's magic show.
He just made Compass disappear.
-[coos]
-And reappear.
-Wow.
-[chattering excitedly]
Hey, want to do that trick
in my show this afternoon?
Who's seen a disappearing
pigeon before?
[gasps]
[chattering happily]
[cooing]
[narrator] George and Compass
were ready for the big time.
-Huh?
-[narrator] Or were they?
The crowd was even
bigger than before.
[chattering nervously]
Yeah, it is a big crowd.
But don't worry,
if you forget a step,
just take a peek at your cards.
Well, it's show time.
[dramatic musical flourish]
Huh?
[whimsical music]
[blows]
[excited chatter]
♪ ♪
And for our final trick,
allow me to introduce
our guest magician,
Monkey the Magnificent.
[cheers and applause]
[excited chatter]
[chuckles]
[cooing nervously]
Ooh!
[narrator] The cards
were out of order.
[chatters worriedly]
[narrator] But the audience
was waiting.
He'd just have
to remember the steps.
[playful music]
♪ ♪
[chattering excitedly]
[chatters happily]
[sighs]
[cheers and applause]
[cooing]
♪ ♪
[coos]
[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
[chatters excitedly]
Huh?
♪ ♪
[chattering nervously]
Uh-oh. Looks like George
could use some help.
[heroic music]
He brought a cape.
♪ ♪
Good afternoon,
everybody.
[playful music]
Ooh, oh, where's the thumb?
[humming]
[applause]
♪ ♪
Huh?
[chatters worriedly]
Maybe Compass is backstage.
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
-[coos]
-[chattering excitedly]
[victorious music]
[playful music]
[chatters happily]
[narrator]
So that's what happened.
George had forgotten step one.
Close door.
[whimsical music]
♪ ♪
George had completed
part of the trick,
but what came next?
[chattering worriedly]
♪ ♪
Ah.
[narrator] They were
in the right order,
but what if they fell again?
Huh?
Follow the oranges.
There's one.
There's two.
There's three.
[narrator] Maybe he could
number the steps.
♪ ♪
[counting]
[narrator] One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
[chattering excitedly]
Thank you all.
Now back to
your scheduled magician.
[chattering thoughtfully]
♪ ♪
[narrator]
Compass was in the compartment,
and birdseed was on the table.
So he was at step five.
[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
[chattering happily]
[victorious music]
[cheers and applause]
Wonderful, wonderful.
♪ ♪
[cooing]
Great show, George.
Hey, maybe you could be
a permanent part of the act.
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator]
George loved that idea.
Now, if only
he could find his pigeon.
[calling out]
[playful music]
[cooing]
[laughs]
♪ ♪
[male narrator] Nothing made
George happier
on a summer sunny day
than a surprise
visit to a friend.
♪ ♪
[barking]
[narrator] Especially when
that friend was Charkie.
[chatters excitedly, grunts]
-[narrator] That wasn't Charkie.
-[giggling]
♪ ♪
[dogs panting]
-Huh?
-Sorry, George.
You came at snack time.
-[chattering curiously]
-[chuckles]
These are the first customers
of our new dog-sitting service.
We take care of people's dogs
and make sure each one
gets a snack,
a bath, and a walk.
-[chatters happily]
-They just ate.
So next it's bath time.
You look like
you could use a bath too.
Huh?
[giggles]
[giggling]
-[chattering excitedly]
-[barking]
♪ ♪
Okay. We fed the dogs
and gave them baths.
Next, we take 'em
for a walk in the park.
[upbeat jazz music]
[dogs barking]
[narrator] George wondered
why they call it a walk.
[chatters exhaustedly]
Fetch it.
[dogs barking]
Get the stick.
-[chattering happily]
-[barking cheerfully]
[playful music]
[grunts]
[groaning]
[grunts, giggles]
[calm music]
♪ ♪
[yawns]
Are you worn out
from your walk, girl?
That's the real reason
we take the dogs
for a walk in the park.
It tires 'em out.
[chatters exhaustedly]
[all] [snoring]
♪ ♪
Oh, no, not again.
Gnocchi!
Huh?
[meowing]
[chattering inquisitively]
Cheffy spent all morning
making a spaghetti mammoth
for the Professor's
Paleontology Pasta Party.
But Gnocchi won't stop
playing with the noodles.
It's a cat-astrophe.
I'm calling Professor Wiseman.
Gnocchi won't stop so
we have to cancel the party.
Hello, Professor Wiseman?
I have some bad news.
[narrator] Maybe the chef just
needed a dog-sitting service.
-For cats.
-[meowing excitedly]
Ah.
[grunting excitedly]
You want to look after
Gnocchi for me
during the pasta party?
[chattering happily]
The party is back on,
Professor.
Giorgio is going
to look after Gnocchi.
[Wisman muttering]
What's that?
Hold on, I will ask him.
Could you look after Professor
Wiseman's cat, Lucky, too?
She doesn't like to be alone.
[chatters affirmatively]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
[cats purring]
[grunts excitedly]
Ooh, would you mind
keeping an eye on Ellcee
while I run some errands?
I'd love to help, Lydia.
But poor Hundley
is so allergic to cats.
[sneezes]
[groans]
[chattering excitedly]
Oh, you'll watch Ellcee?
But you already have two cats.
Ellcee would make three.
Won't you have your hands full?
[chattering confidently]
♪ ♪
[narrator] It would take more
than three cats
-to fill George's hands.
-[chattering happily]
[groaning worriedly]
♪ ♪
[both meowing]
[narrator] Steve and Betsy
had a dog-sitting list,
so George decided
to make a cat-sitting list.
[chattering happily]
[narrator] George had helped
take care of five dogs.
How hard could it be
to take care of three cats?
Hmm.
[narrator] If only
he knew where they went.
[cooing]
-[grunting excitedly]
-[meowing]
[playful music]
[narrator] Compass was surprised
to see George playing chase
-with cats.
-[cooing]
[narrator] Maybe George had been
a cat this whole time.
♪ ♪
Nope. George definitely
was not a cat.
♪ ♪
Hmm.
[meowing playfully]
A-ha!
[yelps, thumps]
♪ ♪
-[purring]
-[meows]
♪ ♪
-[chattering nervously]
[chatters happily]
[narrator] First, George needed
to feed the kitties.
But what did they eat?
Hmm…
A-ha!
♪ ♪
[narrator] Luckily,
George had some biscuits
he kept for Hundley.
The cats would like those.
[all] [repulsed meowing,
hissing]
[chattering disappointedly]
Hmm…
[narrator]
Dogs liked dog biscuits.
-But cats did not.
-[gasps]
-[cooing worriedly]
-[both] [meowing]
[suspenseful music]
[grunting]
[cooing]
[narrator] Those cats were way
too interested in Compass.
[yelps]
[chatters]
[narrator] George
wondered how he could keep
three different cats out
of three kinds of trouble.
Uh, a-ha!
[playful music]
♪ ♪
[narrator] They couldn't
cause too much trouble
in the bath tub.
And it was time for
their bath.
[all] [yowling]
[upbeat music]
[confused chatter]
[narrator] Unlike dogs,
cats did not like bath time.
A-ha!
[narrator] It's good that
the next thing on his list
was a walk.
That would tire the cats out.
George just needed to borrow
some of Hundley's leashes.
[chattering happily]
[playful music]
[all] [meowing excitedly]
♪ ♪
'Ey!
[grunting worriedly]
♪ ♪
[elevator bell rings]
[marching music]
[narrator] Why were the cats
following the lady
but not him?
[chattering excitedly]
[elevator bell rings]
Oh, no.
Not my boa.
[playful music]
[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
Huh?
[narrator] Give the leashes
to George for the cats?
-[barks negatively]
-[narrator] No.
[grunts, sneezing]
[meowing playfully]
[grunting worriedly]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Then Hundley
had a change of heart.
[sneezing]
[chatters happily]
♪ ♪
[sneezes, groans]
[grunting excitedly]
♪ ♪
[groans]
[narrator] But cats
did not walk like dogs.
[birds chirping]
♪ ♪
[sighs]
[grunting worriedly]
♪ ♪
-[yearnful meowing]
-[grunts]
♪ ♪
[groaning]
[grunts]
[playful meowing]
[meows]
Hmm. Ah.
[ingenuous giggling]
[meows]
[playful meowing]
[defeated grunting, sighs]
[narrator] Cat-sitting wasn't
anything like dog-sitting.
♪ ♪
[gasps] Ooh.
[coos]
[chattering happily]
[cooing happily]
[chattering excitedly]
Hmm…
[narrator] George remembered how
interested the cats had been
in the lady
with the feather boa.
And in Compass.
A-ha!
[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
[cooing]
[whimsical music]
[narrator] George couldn't get
the cats to behave like dogs…
♪ ♪
But maybe he could get them
to behave like cats.
♪ ♪
[chattering happily]
[meows excitedly]
[meows happily]
[giggles]
♪ ♪
[narrator] It worked.
George was a cat-sitter
extraordinaire.
♪ ♪
Ooh, I hope Ellcee
wasn't too much trouble.
[shushes]
[all] [snoring, purring]
[gentle piano music]
[sneezes]
[grunts happily]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪