[upbeat music]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing.
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa.
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
[grunting happily]
[male narrator] George had had
sleepovers before…
Whew.
[narrator] But never one at
Professor Wiseman's.
[chattering happily]
[laughs] That's great,
George.
Hi, there.
Thank you so much
for looking after George
while I'm
at the Dinosaur convention.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
We're going to have a super
time.
First, we'll order from
Pisghettis…
Then we're going to play some
games,
like Twisty-Turny-Tumble.
Ooh, I haven't seen that one
in years.
Finally, we're going to make
edible toothpick sculptures.
[chattering excitedly]
[laughs]
It's not for another
eight hours, buddy.
Aww.
I'll check in with
you tonight
and pick you up tomorrow
morning, okay?
Uh-uh.
[grunting happily]
Hmm.
[chattering excitedly]
Lucky's been looking
forward to seeing you.
Meow.
[gasps]
[chattering curiously]
That's my tablet.
It controls many things
in the apartment.
Here, I'll show you.
I can change the lights…
Ohh, ahh.
Put on music…
[classical music]
Ahh, ahh, mm.
You want to try it?
Okay.
[upbeat music]
Ahh.
[music stops]
[chattering excitedly]
Ah, you've discovered Shwoop,
my robotic floor cleaner.
[giggles]
[chattering curiously]
[laughs]
It stopped because it has
sensors
so it won't run into walls
or chairs…
or monkeys.
Whoo.
You can also turn
everything on and off by hand,
but it's a lot more fun to use
this.
Uh-huh.
Now, how about we get
this sleepover started?
[chattering excitedly]
[giggles]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
Meow. Meow.
Meow.
[laughter]
♪ ♪
Ahh.
[laughter]
And then the baby
elephant and the brave
little mouse curled up together
and fell asleep.
[yawns]
[chattering sleepily]
Good night, George.
Sleep well.
Mm.
Ohh.
Good night, George.
[babbling sleepily]
[narrator] George had no trouble
at all
sleeping in a new place…
[clanging noise]
Huh?
[chattering nervously]
[narrator] Until the middle of
the night.
[chattering nervously]
[narrator] Did Professor Wiseman
have a snake…
[upbeat music]
[narrator] Wearing a suit of
armor?
Ehh, uh-uh.
[gasps]
[suspenseful music]
[chattering curiously]
[laughs]
-Meow.
-[clanging noise]
Meow.
Ahh.
[narrator] Those strange sounds
were coming
from the radiator.
[rattling noise]
[chattering curiously]
[narrator] Was it a monster
eating a midnight snack?
[chattering curiously]
[rattling noise]
[narrator] The sound was coming
from the freezer.
[grunting]
[ice rattling]
[narrator] It was just the ice
maker.
Mysteries solved.
-[yawns]
-[narrator] Now back to bed.
Meow.
[yawns]
Huh?
[narrator] That is, if he had a
bed.
[grunting]
[narrator] Did it fold up
because George
wasn't sleeping in it?
[chattering curiously]
[chattering excitedly]
Huh?
[chattering confusingly]
[narrator] But which button was
the one that opened the bed?
Uh-oh.
[upbeat music]
Augh!
Uh-uh.
[chittering]
[blender whirring]
Augh!
[toaster popping and buzzing]
[water rushing]
Yes. Anyone can learn the
tuba.
Let's start off with
the basics.
[tuba tooting]
That is C-Sharp.
[chattering nervously]
[tuba tooting]
Augh.
[narrator] Now the tablet wasn't
working.
Ohh.
[narrator] What if all the noise
woke Professor Wiseman?
[snoring]
[groans]
[narrator] How could George turn
off all these devices
without that tablet?
[tuba tooting
and blender whirring]
[blender stop whirring]
Meow.
Ahh.
[narrator] George could turn
off the devices by hand…
Or foot.
And he could find what else was
on by listening.
[tuba tooting]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
[music stops]
And that was an E.
Ahh.
[window shade whirring]
Meow.
Ohh.
Ahh.
[narrator] Finally, everything
was quiet…
[robotic vacuum whirring]
Oh, augh!
[narrator] Almost everything.
[chattering excitedly]
[chattering worriedly]
Meow.
[sighs]
[narrator] Shwoop ran away from
George…
Aha.
[narrator] But toward the grape
that fell on the floor.
[chattering excitedly]
[giggling]
[robotic vacuum whirring]
[chattering excitedly]
[whirring stops]
Ahh.
[Proffessor Wiseman] Ahem.
Wow.
Guess you felt like doing a
little midnight cleaning.
[chattering guiltily]
Heh-heh. It's okay.
Actually, I saw how you managed
to turn off Shwoop.
That was great problem solving.
[chattering modestly]
Now, let's clean all this up.
[chattering happily]
Oh, the battery on my tablet
must have run out.
[chattering curiously]
You want to clean up the
mess?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Press this button.
[chattering excitedly]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
Thanks so much for
looking after George.
Oh, it's my pleasure.
Did you have a good time?
Oh…[giggles]…
Uh-uh.
He helped me clean the whole
apartment.
Uh-huh.
[giggles]
Oops. Butterfingers.
[chattering excitedly]
[robotic vacuum whirring]
[giggling]
♪ ♪
[gentle piano music]
[narrator] Bill's mom was
getting married,
and George was asked to be the
ring bearer.
So naturally, he said….
[whimpering]
Hold still, George.
Ahh. [laughs]
All done.
Whoo-hoo-hoo! Ha-ha!
You looking forward
to being ring bearer, George?
[chattering excitedly]
[upbeat music]
George, don't mess
up your suit.
[remote car lock beeps]
Hiya, George.
[chattering excitedly]
Are you ready to be the ring
bearer?
Uh-huh.
Here's the ring pillow.
And here are the rings for the
bride and groom.
Oooh, ahh-ahh.
You remember what to do,
right?
You'll carry the rings down the
aisle and hand them to me.
[chattering knowingly]
Hi, Bill.
So today's the big day.
Sure is.
Hey, did you know I'm the
Best Man at the wedding?
Yes. You mentioned it at the
wedding rehearsal yesterday.
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Well. follow me.
I'll take you back to where the
guests are.
Hey, did you know
that the Best Man
gives a toast at the wedding?
You mentioned that too.
[chattering knowingly]
Five times, huh?
Oh, yeah. Right.
Well, did I tell you I've
been working on it all week?
Uh, you mentioned that when
you called us
this morning at 6:00 a.m..
Uh-uh.
[yawns]
Oh, yeah. Right.
Ahh. Ahhh.
[narrator] George thought the
backyard looked magical.
[gasps]
Ohh, wow.
Hi ya, George.
Lookit my pretty flower girl
dress.
Lookit my pretty flower petals.
-Smell 'em.
-Ohh.
[sniffs]
Ahh.
[chattering excitedly]
Hey, wanna see the
new fish pond we put in
for the wedding?
[chattering excitedly]
Come on.
Ta-da.
Whaaa!
[gentle piano music]
Aww.
[chattering gently]
Ohh.
-Augh, the rings.
-Ahh!
[chattering nervously]
[whimpering]
I can't see them. Can you?
Ohh.
[whimpering]
[narrator] If George could get
the water out of the pond,
maybe he could find the rings.
[chattering knowingly]
[narrator] The pillow was
squishy like a sponge.
He could use it to sop up
the water.
Ahh.
[upbeat piano music]
You're going to soak
up the water?
That might work.
Huh? [grumbles]
Looks like we need a
humongous sponge, George.
And we don't have one.
Ohh.
[chattering excitedly]
My basket?
That's a great idea.
Ohh.
[groans]
I guess we need something
that isn't full of holes.
Ohh, aww.
[gasps]
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] Maybe Bill would have
an idea.
Bill, Bill….
Sorry, guy, can't talk now.
I'm rewriting my toast.
It has to be more dramatic.
Aha.
[chattering excitedly]
Scoop with an ice bucket.
That's a great idea.
I'll find another one.
Mozzarella ball?
Oh, yes. Thank you.
[narrator] The ice bucket wasn't
full of holes like the basket.
But it was full of ice.
Huh.
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] Little monkeys don't
understand fashion.
Ooh.
[chattering excitedly]
You got 'em, George.
Ahh.
[water splashing]
-Huh?
-What's that sound?
Huh?
[narrator] They forgot about the
fish.
That's not enough water for
them.
We better put them in something
else.
[chattering excitedly]
Water glasses.
-Ahh.
-Perfect.
[chattering excitedly]
Two fish saved.
Let's get the rest.
[chattering excitedly]
I need more mozzarella balls.
Be right there.
I'm adding a little mint to
the water.
One, two, three, four,
plus those other two.
That makes six.
All the fish are safe.
Ahh, whew.
We better get my flower
petals back in my basket.
Uh-huh.
[chattering excitedly]
[violin music]
♪ ♪
[upbeat piano music]
[gasps]
The fish are gone.
[whimpering]
Ahem, may I have your
attention please?
Oh, it looks like Bill is
almost ready to speak.
[chattering worriedly]
It is with great pride
that I present my toast
to the bride and groom.
Bill, your toast is given
after the wedding, remember?
Oh. Yeah. Right.
It is with great pride that I
practice my toast.
[laughter]
You know what happens
after the toast, George?
[chattering confusedly]
Everyone drinks the water.
Ohh.
Huh?
My Mom has always
kept me warm
and loved and happy.
And she really likes my rabbits
too, every single one of them.
She takes me fishing
and makes the best
zucchini and cheese ever.
She is by far the
best mom in the world,
and I've asked around.
One, two, three, four, five.
Wait a sec.
There were six fish to
begin with,
but we only have five.
[chattering confusedly]
So let's drink to the happy
couple.
Augh.
Oh, well,
I left my water right here.
I don't know where that would
be.
[slurping]
Huh?
Ew.
[stammering]
Whew.
Ohh.
[chattering knowingly]
[narrator] That garden hose was
just the thing George needed.
[chattering excitedly]
Ahh.
Ohh, whew.
[chattering gently]
[narrator] George was glad the
six little fish were safe.
George, where are the rings?
[gasps]
[chattering nervously]
[narrator] George left them at
the pond.
Whoa! Whoa!
[chattering worriedly]
Oopsie, I forgot the cake
cutter.
[chattering nervously]
Ahh!
Ow.
Ohh.
[chattering worriedly]
[gasps]
Oh, my beautiful cake,
she is
she's ruined.
I'm finished.
I'm all done.
I'm ruined.
Fantastico.
Netti,
you are a genius.
[chuckles]
That is why you married me.
[violin music]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George thought the
wedding was sweet.
Nom-nom-nom, ooh.
[narrator] But not nearly as
sweet as the wedding cake.
Here she comes.
[violin music]
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]