[upbeat music]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
-[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[suspenseful piano music]
♪ ♪
[birds chirping]
[pleasant piano music]
♪ ♪
[male narrator] George loved
playing hide n' seek…
And playing with Charkie was
a special challenge.
George couldn't outsmart
Charkie's super sense of smell!
[grunting in defeat]
[chatters excitedly]
[barking]
[chattering happily]
[grunting, counting]
[whimpering]
[thunder rumbling]
[grunting excitedly]
[chattering curiously]
-[grunting excitedly]
-[thunder rumbles]
[narrator] George loved watching
a good storm,
but first, he needed to
find Charkie.
-[whimpering]
-[chatters]
[narrator] That wasn't a very
good place to hide.
[chattering triumphantly]
[whimpering]
Time for lunch.
It's my famous Pesto Pasta
with Parsley &amp; Peas.
[chatters excitedly]
And for our guest,
my famous
uh…kibble.
[panting, barking]
[panting]
[thunder booming]
[barks in fright]
-Whoa!
-[yelping]
[sighs]
Maybe instead we'll have
my famous…
something else.
[narrator]
Where was Charkie going?
It was George's turn to hide.
-[whimpering]
-[chatters curiously]
[narrator] This was also not
a very good place to hide.
[chatters excitedly]
-[whimpering]
-[grunts curiously]
[whimpering]
[narrator] Why was Charkie
so afraid all of a sudden?
[piano chords]
[howls]
Huh, it's a miracle I didn't
get any on my shirt.
-[barking]
-Ooh!
Spoke too soon.
-[thunder rumbling]
-[howling]
[whimpering]
[chatters inquisitively]
Hm.
She must be afraid of storms.
Lots of dogs are.
Aw.
Poor Charkie.
We're here with you.
[chatters encouragingly]
[narrator] George wondered why
Charkie was scared of storms.
[chatters contemplatively]
[narrator] He thought they were
kind of exciting.
[thunder rumbles]
[chatters happily]
[narrator] Maybe Charkie just
didn't like all that rain?
[barking excitedly]
[water splatters]
[narrator] No.
Charkie loved any excuse
to get wet.
It had to be something else.
[thunder rumbles]
[chatters curiously]
[narrator]
Could it be the loud noise
the thunder made?
There was only one way
to find out…
[grunting excitedly]
A little dish soap
should get this out…
[banging loudly]
[gasps]
Oh!
[banging continues]
-[chatters curiously]
-[barks]
[giggles]
[narrator] Nope.
It wasn't the loud noise,
either.
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] What else
happened during a storm?
[piano chords]
[chatters triumphantly]
[narrator] Lightning!
-[thunder rumbles]
-[howling]
[barking]
[barking happily]
[toy squeaks]
[narrator] Nope.
Charkie wasn't afraid
of flashes of light.
[howls]
-[thunder booms]
-[narrator] Except that kind.
Okay.
More kibble for Charkie.
And peanut butter and banana
sandwiches for us!
-[barking]
-Ow!
[grunts]
Oh.
[chatters happily]
[grunting excitedly]
[whining]
[thunder rumbles]
Seems like the storm
is getting closer.
-[chatters curiously]
-Yeah.
You can tell how close
or far a storm is
by counting the seconds between
the lightning and thunder.
[chatters inquisitively]
Quick, start counting.
One, two, three,
four, five--
[thunder rumbles]
The last time I counted,
it was six seconds,
so it's getting closer.
But don't worry.
We're safe in here.
[electricity crackles]
[all gasp]
It's okay.
The storm just knocked
out the power.
I'll get some flashlights.
[barks, whines]
[chatters]
-[whimpers]
-Well.
I'll get there eventually.
[grunts triumphantly]
Aw. Hm.
[clicking]
Huh?
[chatters in confusion]
[clicking]
Huh.
George, did you use up
the batteries
playing with
the flashlights again?
[jaunty music]
♪ ♪
[chatters sheepishly]
[sighs] I'll go ask
the Doorman for some batteries.
[whining]
[grunting excitedly]
Good idea.
Oh, it's his lunch hour,
so he might be
in his apartment.
[chatters]
[grunts excitedly]
[whines]
[gasps]
[grunting, counting "1, 2"]
[thunder rumbles]
[narrator]
There were only 2 seconds
between the lightning
and thunder.
The storm was getting closer!
[chattering happily]
[door creaks]
[door creaking]
[chattering loudly]
[music playing softly]
[narrator] The Doorman's
apartment seemed to be empty.
But where was that music
coming from?
[soft music playing]
♪ ♪
[grunting softly]
[narrator] Hundley wasn't scared
of this storm at all.
[thunder rumbles]
[yawns]
[narrator] In fact, he didn't
even notice it!
Maybe Hundley could tell George
how to keep Charkie
calm during the storm.
[chattering inquisitively]
[barking]
[thunder booms]
[whines]
[whimpering]
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] So Hundley  was
afraid of the storm.
Oh, hi, George.
Is the Doorman home?
[chatters happily]
[grunts negatively]
Oh, then he must be
in the lobby.
I need batteries
for my flashlight.
[chatters affirmatively]
Batteries?
Sure!
Help yourself.
[thunder booming]
Thanks again for the tip
about the safe space.
My dog has never been so calm
during a storm.
[chattering questioningly]
A safe space is a place dogs
can go during a storm.
[grunts excitedly]
They relax there
because they can't hear
or see the storm.
[chatters comprehensively]
[narrator] That's why Hundley
could sleep through the storm!
The music distracted him
from the thunder.
And he couldn't see
the lightning from the closet.
It was exactly
what Charkie needed!
[chatters in question]
Take as many as you like.
I've got tons of 'em.
[chatters appreciatively]
[grunting excitedly]
-[panting, whining]
-[strains]
Ooh. Hey, Charkie.
[thunder rumbles]
[whines]
How about I just stretch
my legs a little?
[sighs]
[grunting excitedly]
[chatters triumphantly]
Boy, am I glad to see you,
George.
-[grunting]
-Wait, I--
[sighs]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] A safe space needed
a comfy bed…
Um. George?
[narrator] Nice lighting…
[grunts]
[narrator] Soothing music…
[radio static,
soft music plays]
And snacks!
Now all Charkie's safe space
needed was Charkie!
[toy squeaking]
[chattering encouragingly]
[barking]
[chattering happily]
[sighs]
[bones crack]
Oh.
[chatters happily]
[barking]
[narrator] Finally!
Charkie was calm.
[barking happily]
[toy squeaking]
[gasps]
[grunting, counting
"1, 2, 3, 4"]
[thunder rumbling]
[narrator] The time between
the lightning and thunder
was getting longer again!
That meant the storm
was moving away.
And Charkie was happy.
The safe space had worked.
What's going on in here?
[chatters excitedly]
Wow. This is pretty cozy.
[piano chords]
[man in the yellow hat]
One, two,
three, four, five,
six--
[thunder booms]
[upbeat piano music]
♪ ♪
[narrator] It was spring
in the city…
And things were hopping
at Patty's Posh Pet Parlor.
Including Charkie!
-[barks]
-[grunts happily]
[barks]
Sorry.
I'm just getting to Charkie.
With the Dogs of N Avenue
calendar photo shoot today,
it's been a busy one!
[dogs barking]
[chuckles]
I guess everyone wants to be
in the new
Dogs of N Avenue Calendar!
Yes!
Sorry, Steve.
The calendar is just for dogs.
[chatters curiously]
The money
from the calendar sales
goes to
our local animal shelter.
-[chatters comprehensively]
-Well,
Charkie should be done
in about an hour
if you want to wait for her.
Hm. I have to get
to my xylophone lesson.
[defeated sound effect]
Aw!
But Steve isn't doing
anything.
Nothing but saving
the galaxy.
Steve, this is important.
We need you to wait for Charkie
and get her to the photoshoot.
Clean.
Sure. Clean.
Uh, photo…
-[defeated sound effect]
-Shoot!
[sighs]
[chatters happily]
Great!
Thanks, George!
[chatters]
[video game sound effects]
Want to help me bathe
Charkie?
[grunts excitedly]
[narrator] George had never
washed a dog before,
professionally.
[chatters curiously]
We use this to keep them
in place.
[cheerful music]
[narrator] George was eager
to learn every step.
Charkie had to be brushed
to remove tangles.
Then she went in a big tub.
[barking]
[narrator] Where she got
rinsed…
Shampooed…
Rinsed again…
Then towel dried.
After that came
the detangler…
and combing.
And finally there was
a warm fan.
[giggles]
And while one dog
is drying,
I brush out the dog
I bathed before.
[grunting, panting]
-Want to take a ride?
-[chatters in question]
[table whirs]
[grunts excitedly]
[chattering happily]
Once the dogs are dry,
they get sprayed
so they smell good.
[sneezes]
And then
they get brushed again.
[narrator] And last of all,
Charkie got a bandana!
Ha-ha!
Here I come, Level 4!
[chatters assertively]
Uh, okay.
I can take Charkie
from here, George.
[chatters in concern]
[barking]
[grunts in dismay]
Wow, looks like you had
quite the adventure
since you left.
Uh. Think maybe you could
groom her again
before the photoshoot today?
Well, there are a few dogs
ahead of her.
But I can squeeze her in.
[chatters in relief]
[beeping]
It's never made
that sound before.
No, no, no, that's me.
Time to put more money
in the parking meter.
Wee. City life!
I'll be back in a few minutes.
Maybe put Charkie in one
of those crates for me, okay?
Now, where did I park my car?
[panting, barks]
[chatters happily]
[gasps]
[narrator] George didn't
know that Hundley got groomed!
[grunts happily]
[growling]
Aw, that photoshoot is
in less than two hours.
It took Patty an hour to
groom Charkie the first time.
But now she has to groom
all these other dogs
before she can do Charkie.
[narrator] Charkie would
never be done in time.
Unless…somebody helped.
[grunts happily]
[chatters]
[imitates water spraying]
You think we should
wash the dogs?
[chatters affirmatively]
[grunts curiously]
[narrator] George had
only helped Patty once,
but monkeys
were experts at baths.
[chatters worriedly]
[growls]
[narrator] Hundley wasn't
sure what George was up to,
but whatever it was,
he didn't approve.
[grumbling]
[chatters encouragingly]
[barks]
[yawns]
We'll just have to
put him in.
[both grunting]
Patty must be super strong
to handle these big dogs!
[narrator] George
was already messing up.
[both straining]
Hey, we can wash them
from out here.
Aunt Margaret's got one
of these.
They stretch.
Patty probably washes
the big dogs on the floor.
[muffled barking]
[chatters worriedly]
[narrator] George didn't
remember this happening
with Charkie!
Next came the shampoo.
Then the rinse.
[barking]
Patty must do nothing
but change clothes all day.
She's always dry
when I see her.
[grunts happily]
[sniffs]
[grunts in disgust]
[narrator]
Goliath was clean now.
But he sure didn't smell
like it.
And then George remembered…
He'd forgotten the spray.
[grunts happily]
-[sneezes]
We're short on time.
We have to hurry!
[chatters]
[grunting excitedly]
At least it will be easy
to put this one in the sink.
Ah!
-[grunting]
-[barking]
[chatters triumphantly]
[pleasant piano music]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Now what was
he supposed to do?
[chatters in thought]
[gasps]
[chatters happily]
Hey! Good thinking.
[chatters]
[barks, panting]
[chattering happily]
[barks softly]
Hey… George, look!
I think I broke her fur.
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] George
couldn't remember what to do.
Yeah. Let's quit
while we're ahe--
Huh?
Oh, this must be how Patty
dries the dogs!
[chatters comprehensively]
[narrator] If only George had
a way to remember the steps.
[grunts excitedly]
[narrator] Patty's basket!
That could tell him
about the order!
First, was a brush,
second, the shampoo,
third, the towel.
That seemed
like the right order.
[barks in concern]
[narrator] There was only one
way to find out!
[growls]
[narrator] Hundley wondered how
George would make him look bad.
[barks in concern]
[narrator] First the brush.
[grunts happily]
[panting happily]
[chattering]
[narrator] Second the shampoo.
[barks happily]
[narrator] Third the towel.
[grunts]
[narrator] Fourth,
the detangler, and the comb.
While Hundley was drying,
George and Steve
groomed the other dogs..
Two at a time.
[table whirs]
Once the dogs were dry,
the fifth and sixth steps
were spraying and brushing.
[sneezes]
[narrator] And finally, they
were all groomed to perfection.
In plenty of time
for their close up.
[chatters happily]
[shutter clicks]
I'm back!
Huh.
Where'd everybody go?
[fast swing music]
♪ ♪