[upbeat music]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
♪ Like Curious George ♪
[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[goofy music]
♪ ♪
[mimicking engine rumbling]
[meowing]
[male narrator]
George was excited
to go visit outer space.
At the new solar system exhibit
in the museum.
Hi, George!
Like my new space helmet?
[cooing happily]
-[mimics engine]
-Right behind you!
[cooing happily]
♪ ♪
[both] Whoa!
Marco, George, welcome!
[meowing]
Oh, I'm sorry, but the museum
has recently adopted
a no-Gnocchi policy.
[meowing sadly]
Aww.
Here.
[meowing]
♪ ♪
I'll show you around.
We have a minute before
the space show begins.
♪ ♪
[gasping]
I know what that is.
It's an orrery.
[confused cooing]
That's right.
It's a model of the planets
and our sun in space,
and here's our planet,
Earth, and our moon.
[cooing excitedly]
Ah.
This is a model of a comet,
a huge chunk of ice,
dust, and rock
that flies through space.
[cooing curiously]
[beeping]
Comets swoop in close
to the sun,
then slingshot back,
past all the planets,
into deep space.
-Cool!
-Wow!
[chiming]
Oh, the presentation
is about to start!
[playful music]
♪ ♪
[meows]
[creaking]
[mysterious music]
[meows]
[male narrator] The Sun is the
center of our solar system,
and our Earth revolves
around it in an orbit…
And so do seven other planets.
Ah!
[narrator] Other objects
orbit the sun too,
like comets
and the asteroids found mostly
in the Asteroid Belt
between Mars and Jupiter.
[whooshing]
[all] [gasp]
[narrator]
There's much we don't know
about the other planets,
but in this space show,
we'll explore what we do know
about small and hot Mercury…
Venus with
it's active volcanoes,
and on the other side of Earth,
the dry and dusty
red planet Mars…
The gas giants Jupiter
and Saturn,
and the cold distant planets
Uranus and Neptune.
[meowing]
What?
There's a giant cat planet too!
[cooing happily]
[meowing]
Oh, dear!
Gnocchi, not on the projector!
-[crashing]
-[meows]
[confused meow]
[clearing throat]
[meows]
[sighs] This is why we have
a no Gnocchi policy.
Um.
I'm afraid we're going
to have to cancel
the presentation today,
but you're all invited
to see it tomorrow.
[all groaning]
-[sigh]
-[purring]
[cooing sadly]
Come on, George.
They have a lot of cool books
and other stuff about space
in the gift shop.
[cooing happily]
[upbeat music]
[narrator] At the gift shop,
George got an orrery.
His very own solar system.
[sighs]
[narrator]
He wondered what it was like
on those other planets.
♪ ♪
Mostly, he wondered if there
were any little monkeys on them.
[goofy mysterious music]
♪ ♪
[yawns]
[soft thrumming]
[surprised cooing]
♪ ♪
[confused cooing]
Hi, George!
[cooing happily]
We're gonna explore
the solar system.
Wanna come?
[cooing excitedly]
[narrator] George was going
to get a chance
to look for monkeys
in outer space!
[cooing excitedly]
[meows]
♪ ♪
[cooing happily]
[clicking, whirring]
[cheerily cooing]
[triumphant music]
♪ ♪
There's Earth, our home.
[cooing happily]
[giggles]
Hey, George,
can I borrow your orrery?
[chatters]
The planets
don't line up in a row,
but it's still helpful
because we can see
their order from the sun.
We're right near Earth now,
so which way do you want to go?
Towards the sun,
to Mercury and Venus,
or away from the sun
towards the other planets?
[contemplative cooing]
[narrator] If George was going
to find space monkeys,
he'd better look where
the weather was sunny.
[gasps, chatters excitedly]
[cranking]
[whirring]
[upbeat mysterious music]
That was Venus back there,
but Mercury is even closer
to the sun.
[cooing excitedly]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Mercury was small.
[giggles]
[narrator] But so were monkeys.
[coos excitedly]
[funny music]
♪ ♪
-Okay, space helmets on!
-[meows]
[hisses]
Hey, watch this!
♪ ♪
[chuckling] I feel
so much lighter on Mercury!
[laughing]
[coos excitedly]
We can jump a lot higher here
because little planets
have less gravity.
[chuckles]
[giggles]
[narrator] George thought
monkeys could have lots of fun
on Mercury.
[sighs]
Whew.
[panting]
[narrator] If it wasn't so hot!
[tiredly cooing]
[pants]
I bet it's so hot because
we're so close to the sun.
[playful music]
♪ ♪
[sizzling]
[gasping]
[both] [yelling]
[whirring]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Fortunately,
Gnocchi's ship had great
air conditioning.
[both] [sigh]
[meows]
[whirring]
[adventurous music]
[narrator] Mercury was definitely
too hot for monkeys!
♪ ♪
Venus is the second planet
from the sun.
I bet it's a lot cooler there.
[cooing excitedly]
♪ ♪
[cooing in amazement]
[narrator] From space,
Venus didn't look so hot,
just cloudy.
♪ ♪
[suspenseful music]
[concerned meowing]
[whirring]
[cooing happily]
[narrator] Venus had volcanoes,
just like back home on Earth.
Yeah, I read that Venus
has more volcanoes
than any other planet
in the solar system.
[fizzing]
Look out!
[concerned cooing]
[narrator]
George knew this would not work
for little monkeys.
[triumphant music]
♪ ♪
[gasps] Shall we see
if there's any life on Mars?
[cooing in agreement]
[meows]
[narrator] Gnocchi didn't know
which way Mars was.
[coos]
We just left Venus.
Earth is the 3rd planet,
so we go past it
to get to Mars,
the 4th planet.
[affirmative meowing]
No, Gnocchi,
we're not going to Saturn yet.
Hey, why don't I drive us
to Mars?
[meows]
Okay, to Mars!
[whirring,
thunderous roar]
[George and Gnocchi yelling]
♪ ♪
[whirring powers down]
Okay, I'm getting
the hang of it now.
[cooing excitedly]
[narrator]
George recognized
the third planet from the sun,
Earth.
Yep, that's Earth!
[cooing happily]
[whirring powers down]
[narrator] And that meant
the next planet…
[trumpets sound]
was Mars.
[soft dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[thudding]
[annoyed meowing]
Sorry, it's my first time
landing a spaceship.
[understanding cooing]
[mysterious music]
♪ ♪
[cooing in awe]
[narrator] Mars had mountains
and valleys.
Lots of places
for monkeys to hide.
[chattering]
[chattering echoing]
[narrator] But there wasn't
a tree in sight!
How could a monkey survive
without a single tree to climb?
♪ ♪
It was also very dry and dusty.
[meowing]
[narrator]
Mars appealed to Gnocchi.
Cats didn't like water anyway.
Woo-hoo!
I always wanted to be
the first kid on Mars!
[groans, chatters sadly]
Hey! Huh?
Where you going?
[disappointed cooing]
[narrator] George wanted
to go find monkeys!
Yeah, it's too dry here.
Just looking at it
makes me thirsty.
♪ ♪
[meows]
Okay, okay.
I guess you are
the better pilot.
♪ ♪
[whirring, popping]
[cooing excitedly]
Onto the 5th planet
from the sun,
Jupiter!
Thataway, my good cat!
-[whirring]
-[meows excitedly]
[upbeat music]
[Marco] Cool.
♪ ♪
[whirring]
[cooing excitedly]
-[clanging]
-[confused cooing]
[gasps]
[annoyed cooing]
We must be
in the Asteroid Belt!
It's between Mars and Jupiter.
-[confused cooing]
-Remember?
The asteroid belt
is a whole bunch of rocks
orbiting the sun.
-[concerned meow]
-[panicking cooing]
[whirring]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]
[narrator] Jupiter looked big
on the orrery,
but in real life, it was…
[cooing excitedly]
[narrator] Gigahugamongous!
With all that room,
George was sure he'd find
some monkeys down there.
[cooing in awe]
[cooing excitedly]
[whirring, wind whistling]
I don't know where
the ground is!
It seems like
it's just all gas!
[cooing sadly]
[narrator] If they couldn't
find the ground,
then they probably wouldn't be
able to find monkeys either.
[gasps, eureka cooing]
[narrator] Unless…
♪ ♪
There were flying monkeys!
[cooing excitedly]
[cord strains]
Careful, George,
the wind is pretty strong!
[panicked cooing]
Hold on, buddy!
We've got you!
[grunting]
[groaning]
-[sighs]
-[thumps]
[dramatic music]
Wait! Don't head
for that big red spot!
-[panicked cooing]
-Oh, oh!
It's a giant storm!
[meows]
[whirring]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
[contemplative cooing]
[narrator] There were still
three planets left to visit
and the next one had rings!
[cooing excitedly]
You want to go to Saturn?
[cooing in agreement]
Okay.
Straight ahead, Gnocchi!
[meows]
[whirring]
Amazing!
[George and Gnocchi exclaim]
[narrator] Up close,
Saturn's rings sparkled.
George wanted to get
a closer look.
[clanging]
[cooing happily]
[crunching]
It looks like Saturn's rings
are mostly
bits of ice and dust.
[laughing]
[cooing excitedly]
[narrator] What was the Moon
doing way out here?
[cooing in wonderment]
Oh, yeah!
Saturn has a lot of moons!
[cooing in amazement]
[soft music]
♪ ♪
[cooing excitedly]
[narrator] Now it was time
to explore Saturn.
♪ ♪
[confused cooing]
[gasps] Wait!
This one's all gas too?
[confused cooing]
Yeah, it doesn't seem like
there are any monkeys here.
[cooing disappointedly]
[cooing excitedly]
Okay, you heard the monkey.
[meows]
[Marco] To the blue planets,
Uranus and Neptune!
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
Uranus is kind of cold.
[teeth chattering]
[narrator] It was cold,
but some monkeys,
like Japanese snow monkeys,
liked the cold.
Maybe George
would find them here.
♪ ♪
We've been going down
and down for a while now.
It seems like this
one is gas too!
[disappointed cooing]
[cooing excitedly]
[meows]
♪ ♪
[whirring]
Here we are!
Neptune!
[cooing in awe]
[narrator] They'd finally
reached the last planet
in the solar system
and George's last chance
to find monkeys in space.
[cooing in anticipation]
♪ ♪
[narrator] It was so blue,
George's favorite color!
Things were looking up.
♪ ♪
Can you turn the heat up,
Gnocchi?
[meowing desperately]
[all] shivering]
[shivering cooing]
[shivering]
It's super cold
because we're so far
from the sun.
[concerned cooing]
Yep, that's the same sun
we see on Earth.
It looks tiny
from so far away!
[shivering cooing]
[narrator] George could tell
there would be no monkeys
on Neptune.
Even if the planet was
the most beautiful blue,
it was way too cold.
[contemplative cooing]
[whirring]
♪ ♪
[narrator] There weren't monkeys
on the planets he had visited
but maybe there were monkeys
out there
beyond the solar system.
[cooing excitedly]
[narrator] But now,
it was time to go home.
[meows]
-[cranking]
-[beeping]
[concerned meow]
[gasps]
Uh-oh!
Looks like
we're almost out of fuel!
[concerned cooing]
[concerned meowing]
[narrator] George wondered
how they'd get home.
Look!
A comet!
♪ ♪
[cooing in awe]
[narrator] George remembered
from the show at the museum
that some comets swooped
past all the planets.
[cooing excitedly]
Great idea, George,
if we can just make it
to that comet,
it might take us
all the way back to Earth!
[cooing in agreement]
[dramatic music]
[whirring]
♪ ♪
[all] [yelling]
[dreamy music]
[sighs]
[confused coo]
[narrator] George knew that
he'd been dreaming,
but he had also figured
out which planets had monkeys.
♪ ♪
Not super hot Mercury…
Nor volcano-ey Venus…
Nor dry, dusty Mars…
Nor gassy, windy Jupiter…
Nor ringed Saturn…
Nor gassy, cold Uranus…
And definitely not
freezing cold Neptune,
even if it was
a beautiful blue.
That left Earth,
the one planet
that did have monkeys.
[sighs]
[contemplative cooing]
[soft piano music]
♪ ♪
[upbeat music]