[upbeat music]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
♪ Like Curious George ♪
[all] Swing!
[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
[all] ♪ Every day ♪
[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat jazz music]
♪ ♪
[male narrator] There wasn't
a cloud in the sky.
A perfect day
for watching planes fly.
More than anything,
George wished
he could fly, too.
[bright brass march]
[wistful grunting]
[narrator] But he
was stuck on the ground.
[inspired chattering]
[narrator] At least
he could pretend to fly.
[excited cry]
[wind howling]
[alarmed cry]
Oh, dear.
Are you all right?
[upbeat chattering]
Here, why don't you make
a paper airplane out of this?
It's safer
than flying on your own.
[gentle piano music]
[narrator] George
could make an airplane
out of a newspaper?
[comprehending chattering]
[upbeat music]
[industrious chattering]
♪ ♪
[whimsical music]
[excited chattering]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George had to show
someone what he had made.
♪ ♪
You made that plane?
-Cool!
-Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Ha!
[gasps]
Huh?
[disappointed groan]
[explanatory chattering]
Did the plane
blow around outside?
Uh-huh.
Mm, that's not really flying.
The wind was just
pushing it around,
and there's no wind in here.
[disappointed groan]
But we could make a plane
that actually flies.
[incredulous cry]
Hm, let's make a plane
with flat wings
that are the same size.
Uh-huh.
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
Here, try this one.
[chattering happily]
Hm…
I wonder if it would fly
even straighter
if we gave it
a pointy nose.
♪ ♪
[chattering excitedly]
Go, go, go!
♪ ♪
I bet it would fly even farther
if we had more room.
Hm…
[narrator] George wondered
where they could find
a big enough space to test out
their plane.
Pisghetti's?
No, too many bowls of pasta.
The museum?
[whimsical music]
No, too many dinosaurs.
[disappointed chattering]
[narrator] They needed
a huge room
that was empty.
Hm…
[gasps]
[excited chattering]
[demonstrative grunt]
[fanfare]
The Glass Building?
Are you sure
this is okay?
[reassuring chattering]
[upbeat music]
[happy grunt]
[Mr. Glass] No, it's not
tall enough!
Look, when you're on
the top floor,
I want it to feel
like you're flying.
Hey.
Is that an airplane
in my lobby?
[whimsical music]
[chattering happily]
-Let's go again!
-Zoom!
[Mr. Glass] Ahem.
Did you make
that paper airplane?
-[swallows]
-Um, yes, Mr. Glass.
[grunting meekly]
Well, it'll fly better
if you use a triangular design,
and if you make
the wings bigger,
it'll stay in the air longer.
Wow.
You sure know a lot
about paper airplanes.
You bet I do.
Come with me.
♪ ♪
Take this.
[excited grunt]
[Mr. Glass] "Glass' Big Book
of Paper Airplanes."
[curious grunting]
Yep, I wrote it.
I always loved
making paper airplanes,
so I did what I always do:
I became an expert.
Wow.
Ooh.
[narrator] Now that George
and Betsy had expert help,
they could make a plane
that flew even better.
Thank you, Mr. Glass.
Don't mention it.
And here, you'll need this.
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
Oh, and give me a call
when you have a design
you really like.
♪ ♪
-Okay.
-[grunts happily]
♪ ♪
Hm…
[inquiring grunts]
♪ ♪
Ooh, I like it.
We'll try that one first.
♪ ♪
Ah!
I think the one
we had earlier flew farther.
Uh…
♪ ♪
[upbeat rock music]
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
I think we have our plane.
[chattering excitedly]
Hello?
Mr. Glass?
We made the Glass 500,
and it flew and flew and flew!
[Glass speaking indistinctly]
-Uh-huh.
-[Glass speaking indistinctly]
He wants us to come
to the building tomorrow
at 11:00 a.m. sharp,
with our plane.
He has a surprise!
[excited chattering]
Okay.
We'll be there.
Hm.
I wonder what it is.
[narrator] George didn't know,
but he couldn't wait
to see their new plane
soaring across the Glass lobby.
[tranquil music]
The next day
was even windier.
[chattering quietly]
[worried chattering]
[narrator] But George
wouldn't let anything
pry that plane
from his hands.
[minor piano music]
[balloon pops]
Ah!
[narrator] Except maybe
a balloon man.
[worried cry]
[Betsy] Oh, no!
[frantic music]
♪ ♪
[chattering pleadingly]
[downbeat music]
♪ ♪
You-- you lost your plane?
[imitates swallowing]
[imitating engine]
It was eaten
by a garbage truck.
It w-- but what
about our citywide record?
You said the Glass 500
flew so well,
I thought we might have a shot
breaking the distance record.
I invited all my employees
to watch this historic event.
♪ ♪
This is Jinny Stottlemeyer.
She judges city records
for a living.
-[wondering grunt]
-[narrator] George had no idea
their plane could've broken
a record.
That was almost as good
as flying.
Are we ready?
I have to weigh a giant hamster
in 20 minutes.
Well, unfortunately…
[George grunts optimistically]
[optimistic chattering]
You think we can make
another plane?
Mm-hm.
But I didn't bring the book.
[chattering reassuringly]
I like you, kid.
You've got moxie.
You know, you're gonna need
a big private space
to test your designs.
Follow me.
[jazz music]
Ah, perfect.
The wind has died down.
Here's some paper.
Good luck.
♪ ♪
Ah.
Not quite.
Let's adjust the wings
a little bit more.
♪ ♪
Oh.
[frustrated grunt]
[upbeat rock music]
[excited chattering]
♪ ♪
-Aha.
-Yep.
This is our best shot.
-Come on.
-[excited chattering]
[woman] I think it might…
[man] So excited…
[Mr. Glass]
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you.
The current record
for the longest distance
traveled by a paper airplane
goes from
the starting line here
to that line
where Jinny is standing.
Now, the plane gets three tries
to land beyond that line
to break the record.
George and Betsy,
prepare to launch!
Aha.
[narrator] This was it:
George's chance
to break
a citywide record.
Ah… whoo!
♪ ♪
[all exclaim]
[grunts absently]
Ten inches short.
[excited grunt]
Hm.
Four inches short.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
2.1 inches short.
[disappointed murmuring]
Aww.
Can't we try again?
No, sorry.
That's it, everyone.
I'm off!
[jaunty music]
[chattering excitedly]
[whimsical music]
Miss Stottlemeyer,
don't leave yet!
Quick, everyone,
gather the planes!
[all cheering]
[triumphant music]
124, 125…
126 paper airplanes!
[all cheering]
Well, Stottlemeyer?
Did we do it?
It is a new category,
but yes,
I think you've broken
the record
for the most paper airplanes
made by a girl
and a monkey
which flew off the roof
of an office building.
[all cheering]
Ha, ha!
Congratulations!
It might not be the record
you two wanted,
but it's still a big one!
We did it!
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] Monkeys can't fly…
Ah…
Zoom!
[narrator] But they can be part
of a great record-breaking
flying team.
[upbeat jazz music]
♪ ♪
[narrator] It was the very first
snow of the year,
and the only thing better
than catching a snowflake
was teaching Hamilton
how to catch one.
[jaunty music]
[giggles]
We'll be back
from my sister's tomorrow.
Uh, don't worry
about a thing.
George and I
will look after the place.
♪ ♪
I'm gonna go make a sandwich.
-Why don't you…
-[chattering helpfully]
Right.
Feed the chickens.
[jazz music]
[narrator] The only hard part
about feeding the chickens…
[energetic musical cue]
[crowing loudly]
[narrator] Was getting
past Jagger.
[clucks excitedly]
[George] [grunts temptingly]
[upbeat jazz music]
♪ ♪
Ah.
[giggles]
[hens clucking]
[car horn honks]
Hm?
[curious chattering]
[tranquil music]
Huh?
Well, that's
a strange-looking chicken.
[upbeat music]
[grunts merrily]
Well, hello, there.
I'm Rosa.
[chatters happily]
♪ ♪
Ooh.
[curious chattering]
♪ ♪
I'm here to fix
the rain gutters.
I was scheduled to come
on Tuesday,
but I had a cancellation.
[understanding grunts]
That's George.
Ha.
He's… curious.
You like tools, George?
Uh-huh.
Well, that's
a spanner wrench,
-Huh.
-That's a socket wrench.
-Ooh.
-And this is actually called
a monkey wrench!
[appreciative grunting]
Yeah, like you.
But here are
your most important tools.
Something to measure with
and safety goggles.
Ah!
[whistles]
Ah.
Yep, that is one nice
tool belt.
Hm…
Ah.
[industrious grunting]
Ah!
[jaunty music]
[excited chattering]
♪ ♪
[chattering excitedly]
[satisfied chattering]
[narrator] George had done it.
He'd made his very own
tool belt.
[satisfied chattering]
[narrator] George wanted
to fix something
for the animals
with his new tools,
but the Renkins took
very good care of the place.
[disappointed sigh]
[pig grunting]
Huh?
[minor piano music]
[curious hooting]
♪ ♪
Aha!
[narrator] If that hole
wasn't fixed soon,
lots of snow
would get into the barn.
[contemporary music]
[pig squealing]
[cow lowing]
♪ ♪
Good thing
George had his tool belt.
[industrious music]
♪ ♪
Huh?
[excited chattering]
Hm…
♪ ♪
[triumphant chattering]
[chattering]
Huh?
[contemporary music]
♪ ♪
Oh.
[determined grunt]
[gasps]
[squeals]
[grunts ]
♪ ♪
[grunts irritatedly]
Oh.
[narrator] This roof piece
was crumbly.
Maybe he should patch
the hole with something else.
♪ ♪
Aha.
[negative grunts]
[disappointed chattering]
[downbeat music]
Hm.
No mustard?
[contemporary music]
[mischievous music]
♪ ♪
Oh.
[narrator] The bread was
square-shaped
like the shingles,
and it was bendy,
so it wouldn't break.
[satisfied chattering]
[excited chattering]
♪ ♪
Huh?
Could've sworn I had
some bread and a tomato.
[upbeat music]
Ah.
[concerned grunt]
[disappointed chattering]
[narrator] George
needed more bread,
but how much more?
[upbeat chattering]
[narrator] Rosa had told him
the most important tool
was something to measure with.
Well, two slices of bread
covered the top of the hole.
Another two slices
would cover the rest.
Mm-hm.
[chuckles]
[phone rings]
Huh?
[dejected music]
♪ ♪
[door opens]
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George decided
he'd better take
a lot of bread,
just to be on the safe side.
♪ ♪
[mischievous music]
[sighs]
Maybe I should just have
a salad.
[sprightly music]
[outraged grunt]
[excited chattering]
Oh!
[worried chattering]
[narrator] George needed a patch
that birds wouldn't eat.
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
Hm…
[narrator] One, two,
three, four, five.
One, two.
[comprehending grunts]
♪ ♪
Hm…
Ah.
[narrator] Cardboard!
Birds wouldn't want
to eat that.
♪ ♪
George determined
the hole was five breads long
and two wide.
[satisfied chattering]
♪ ♪
[satisfied grunt]
[cheerful snuffling]
[narrator] All that work
had made George hungry,
and watching George
do all that work
had made Hamilton hungry, too.
[easygoing music]
♪ ♪
[grunting happily]
[congenial grunt]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
[sighs]
Who keeps taking my lunch?
[downbeat music]
♪ ♪
[alarmed cries]
Ah!
[worried chattering]
[contemplative chattering]
[narrator] George's patch
was the right size…
but the soggy cardboard
let the water drip through.
♪ ♪
He needed something
that would keep the water out.
[quiet chattering]
♪ ♪
[narrator] The foil kept
the water out…
[chattering happily]
[narrator] But he would need
a lot more to cover the hole.
[chattering excitedly]
[jaunty music]
♪ ♪
Aha.
[squawking angrily]
[casual grunting]
[clucking angrily]
[chattering questioningly]
[clucks]
♪ ♪
-Ah!
-[clucking resolutely]
Uh…
♪ ♪
[chattering questioningly]
[upbeat music]
[narrator] So Jagger likes
some shiny things
and stuffed penguins.
♪ ♪
George waited,
but not a single drop
of water
dripped into the barn.
[triumphant cry]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
Well, I'll be!
I've been meaning
to fix that hole for weeks now.
You really did that, George?
Uh-huh.
[explanatory chattering]
You and your tools
did a nice job.
♪ ♪
[gasps]
In fact, I think you might
have stumbled
onto a great idea, George.
[grunts questioningly]
These are solar panels.
They use the energy
from the Sun
to heat up the barn
and keep the animals warm.
[comprehending grunts]
Ready for the next one.
[jaunty music]
[narrator] George liked
having his own tool belt,
but he liked being
Rosa's assistant even more.
♪ ♪
And, of course,
having his very own assistant.
[giggles]
[upbeat swing music]
♪ ♪