[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[cheerful music plays]
♪ ♪
[male narrator]
George loved sorting things.
[gasps, chatters happily]
[the man in the yellow hat]
You ready to go, George?
[curious exclamation,
chatters happily]
[babbling]
♪ ♪
I think that does it.
Wait.
George, what about Socky?
[grumbles]
[babbles]
♪ ♪
Okay, all ready.
-You want to push the button?
-[excited chattering]
[narrator]
George didn't know much
about laundry, but he loved
pushing the start button.
[loud bang]
[curious exclamation, yelps]
Oh!
[defeated groan]
-[exasperated chatter]
-[sighs]
Sounds like our washing machine
is broken.
I better call the repairman.
[phone dialing]
[phone line ringing]
[phone line beeps]
[whispering]
I have to leave a message.
Hey, Louis, it's me and George.
Our washer's broken again.
Can you call me?
Thanks, Louis.
[sighs]
Well, we'll just have to wash
our clothes at the laundromat.
[curious chattering]
It's for folks who don't have
washers at home.
They have big
washing machines there.
-You'll love it.
-Ooh!
[laughing]
[cheerful music plays]
♪ ♪
[sighs]
Welcome
to the Soap N' Suds, George.
Ooh!
Ahh!
[coins clinking]
[machine whirring]
[curious exclamation]
[curious music]
Ooh!
[chattering excitedly]
George, want to push
the start button?
[excited babbling]
It's right here.
[curious chattering]
[giggles]
[cheering]
[phone ringing]
Hi, Louis.
You can come now?
But…
Now or two weeks?
Okay, see you in ten minutes.
George, I have to go home
and meet Louis.
[sad groan]
[cheerful chattering]
Okay, you stay
and watch the laundry.
-I'll be back in a little bit.
-[cheerful chattering]
♪ ♪
[mischievous giggling]
[cheerful exclamations]
♪ ♪
[repeated
cheerful exclamations]
♪ ♪
[increasingly weary
exclamations]
♪ ♪
[door opens]
[curious exclamation]
♪ ♪
[excited chattering]
You want to help?
Be my guest.
-[excited babbling]
-Thanks, laundry monkey.
[cheerful babbling]
[baby babbling]
♪ ♪
-[inquisitive chattering]
-Putting in the soap.
It cleans the laundry.
[excited chattering]
Sure, go ahead.
♪ ♪
[excited chatter]
Thanks, buddy.
♪ ♪
[baby babbling]
[narrator]
Now what could he do?
-Laundry.
-[gasps]
Ah!
♪ ♪
[grunts]
Uh…
[cheerful exclamation]
[narrator] George wanted
to make sure the man's clothes
got really clean.
♪ ♪
Huh?
[clattering]
[machine whirring, clattering]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Maybe he needed
to put coins in the washer,
just like the snack machine.
♪ ♪
[grunts]
Hmm.
[frazzled chattering]
♪ ♪
[exasperated groan]
[babbling]
Ah!
[cheers]
♪ ♪
[babbles]
[curious chattering]
♪ ♪
[excited babbling]
[excited exclamations]
♪ ♪
[buzzer sounds]
Huh?
♪ ♪
[sniffs]
Ah…
[narrator] Socky smelled
nice and clean,
but he was still wet.
[buzzer sounds]
♪ ♪
Hey, laundry monkey!
[excited exclamation]
Don't you just love
the feel of warm clothes
fresh out of the dryer?
[curious exclamation]
[narrator] This place had
machines to dry clothes, too?
[excited chatter]
♪ ♪
Whoo-hoo!
[babbling]
♪ ♪
Hmm.
[narrator] Had George
forgotten something?
♪ ♪
[excited exclamation]
[excited chattering]
♪ ♪
[cheering]
[sucking]
-[crying]
-Oh…
[fussing, crying]
-[cheerful exclamation]
-Thanks, buddy.
I'll take that.
[sighs] I'd better go get
another bottle.
Hey, uh, would you mind
keeping an eye on my laundry
for a little bit?
[excited chattering]
Thanks.
♪ ♪
[inquisitive chatter]
Bonjour.
[French accent]
This?
It is a tutu.
It is my ballet costume.
[giggles]
♪ ♪
[curious chatter]
[gasps]
I will be right back.
I have to put some money
in the parking meter.
[cheerful chattering]
Oh, you will watch
my laundry?
Why, thank you.
♪ ♪
[narrator] Not only was George
doing his own laundry,
he was doing
everyone else's, too.
[gasps, frantic babbling]
[yells]
[gasps, nervous chatter]
[narrator] The bag of clothes
was still sudsy.
[frantic chatter]
[narrator]
He'd wash it some more.
[grunts]
[excited chatter]
♪ ♪
[weary sigh,
exasperated chatter]
[narrator]
George needed something
to sop up this mess.
Ah!
♪ ♪
[narrator] Dry clothes.
That would work.
[cart squeaking]
♪ ♪
[cheerful chatter]
[buzzer sounds]
[narrator] George saw
the dad's clothes were clean.
Time to dry them.
♪ ♪
[cart squeaking]
[grunts]
[buzzer sounds]
[narrator] Now the nice girl's
clothes were done.
[excited chattering]
[cart squeaking]
[narrator] Might as well
dry them, too.
♪ ♪
[machine rattling]
[alarmed chatter]
[dramatic music]
[screams,
terrified chattering]
♪ ♪
[hollers, panicked chattering]
[water gurgling]
Aha!
[cheerful music plays]
♪ ♪
[cheers]
Uh-huh.
♪ ♪
[cheerful babbling]
[cheerful chatter]
[triumphant exclamation]
[cart squeaking]
[narrator] Folding time.
[laughs, cheerful chattering]
♪ ♪
Hmm.
[narrator] But which clothes
belonged to which person?
[chattering]
[narrator] These belonged
to the man
because they were yellow.
Now George just had to sort out
the rest of the clothes.
♪ ♪
[triumphant cheer]
Sorry I took so long.
Hey, you washed and sorted
these all by yourself?
[chattering]
♪ ♪
-You dried my stuff?
-Merci.
Thank you.
You are the best.
-[cheerful chattering]
-Wow, George!
You did a great job.
[all exclaiming]
[machine clattering]
[all chattering, laughing]
[cheerful music plays]
♪ ♪
[male narrator] Big things
were happening in the city,
and George was right
in the middle of it all.
-Bow tie.
-[cheerful chattering]
Jacket.
[cheerful chatter]
So… pretty nice, huh?
[button clatters]
Cheffy, maybe it's time
for a new suit.
But, Netti,
I wore this to our wedding.
[sighs]
Professor, you are the head
of the award committee.
You tell him.
Maybe it is time
for a new suit.
After all, this is
the Golden Garlic Award.
Which reminds me--
we still need someone
to present the award to you.
Hey, I know!
I know who's perfect!
Georgio!
[cheerful exclamation]
[laughs]
Wonderful!
What a good idea.
Can you do it, George?
[cheerful exclamation]
You're going to need
some dress-up clothes.
[inquisitive chatter]
You're both going to need
some dress-up clothes.
-New ones.
-[sighs]
If you say so, Netti.
-Come on, Georgio!
-[laughing]
-Let's go shopping.
-[excited chatter]
♪ ♪
Voilà.
[awed exclamations]
Oh, nice.
♪ ♪
I'll help you
put that on, George.
-Uh-uh.
-[excited chatter]
[narrator] After all,
George had helped the chef
put on his tuxedo.
How hard could it be?
-Hmm.
-[frustrated grunting]
♪ ♪
-[loud thud]
-[grunts]
Everything okay
in there, George?
Uh-huh.
[sighs, grunts]
[groans]
Huh?
[curious exclamation]
[grunts]
[triumphant cheer]
[narrator] George had shown
those pants who was boss.
Well, almost.
♪ ♪
Ta-da!
[proud chattering]
[exasperated music]
Nice job, George.
The bow tie
is the hardest part.
[cheerful music plays]
[narrator] The tailor measured
and marked.
[cheerful exclamation]
[narrator]
And before he knew it…
George and the Chef
both looked…
Magnifico!
[cheerful chattering]
[chuckles]
Would you like me
to wrap it, sir?
[excited exclamation]
[cheerful chattering]
I think he wants
to keep it on.
[cheerful jazzy music]
♪ ♪
[man] ♪ Hey, now,
there's one snappy guy ♪
♪ A classy jacket, spiffy tie ♪
♪ Feeling great
down to his toes ♪
♪ In those fancy
dress-up clothes ♪
♪ Mister jazzy looking clean ♪
♪ No ifs or buts
or in-between ♪
♪ Watch him stroll,
he's cool as ice ♪
♪ That monkey cleans up nice ♪
♪ Satin pants-y ♪
♪ Dress-up clothes ♪
♪ Classy ♪
♪ ♪
[triumphant cheer]
[laughs]
[mellow music plays]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George didn't even
want to take his suit off
at bedtime,
so a compromise was reached.
♪ ♪
[gasps, excited chatter]
[grunts, excited chattering]
[excited exclamation]
Morning, George.
I have to run and pick up
my tuxedo at the dry cleaner's.
I'll be back,
and then we'll get you dressed
for the ceremony.
In the meantime,
breakfast is on the table.
See you soon.
Bye.
[cheerful chatter]
[door closes]
♪ ♪
[impatient music plays]
[narrator] George wasn't sure
how long soon was,
but it was starting
to feel like forever.
[whines]
[mellow music plays]
[narrator] Maybe he could put on
just the pants…
for practice.
[excited exclamation]
[babbling]
[narrator] George wondered
if he should practice
with the shirt, too.
[grunting]
♪ ♪
[triumphant exclamation]
-[narrator] And…
-[excited chattering]
[narrator] The jacket.
[triumphant exclamation]
[phone ringing]
-[cheerful exclamation]
-Oh, George.
The dry cleaner sent my tux
to the wrong shop.
Carry your suit
to the ceremony.
I'll meet you at the ballroom,
and I'll help you put it on.
If I'm late, get someone else
to help, okay?
-[affirmative chatter]
-Huh?
[impish giggle]
[narrator] George didn't need
to carry his suit.
He was already dressed.
♪ ♪
Now George needed
to get across town.
[both slurping]
[gasps]
[dramatic music]
[grunts, yelps]
[cheerful music plays]
♪ ♪
[relieved chatter]
[hollers, gasps]
Whoa, whoa!
-My paint!
-[gasps]
-[relieved chatter]
-Whew!
-Thanks, George!
-[cheerful babbling]
[relieved exclamation]
[sighs]
Ooh.
[narrator]
George made it to the hotel…
and without a spot.
[gasps, exclaims]
-[groans]
-[narrator] Almost.
[groans]
♪ ♪
[sign beeps]
[cheerful chattering]
♪ ♪
[cheerful exclamation]
[alarmed exclamation]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
[hollers]
[bicycle bell ringing]
[alarmed babbling]
♪ ♪
[horn blares]
[hollers]
[nervous chatter]
[whimpers]
[narrator] George's pants
weren't pants anymore.
[indistinct chatter]
Where is Georgio?
We have to start soon.
I-- I'm sure
he'll be here any minute.
[narrator] George couldn't
present the award half-dressed,
but where was he going to get
a new pair of pants?
Now, these drawings need
to be at the home office ASAP.
You got something
I can mail them in?
Will this do?
[gasps,
inquisitive exclamation]
[narrator] That was it!
After all, what were pants?
Just two tubes for your legs.
♪ ♪
[excited chattering]
-You want a tube, too?
-[affirmative chatter]
-[excited babbling]
-Ah, two tubes!
-No problem.
-[cheerful exclamation]
[grunts]
[narrator]
George had his pants.
[excited exclamation]
-[narrator] Or did he?
-[babbling]
[groans]
[narrator] It turned out,
pant legs were more
than just tubes.
♪ ♪
[curious exclamation]
[narrator] They had to bend
in the middle.
[cheerful exclamation]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
[curious exclamation]
♪ ♪
[inspired exclamation]
-[cheerful babble]
-Huh?
-Well, hello, there.
-[cheerful babbling]
♪ ♪
I'll cut 'em,
but I'm not cooking 'em.
Excuse me.
Any need for these sacks?
You can put those
with the recyclables.
♪ ♪
[inspired exclamation]
Of course you can have
a name tag.
[repetitive chatter]
-[cheerful exclamation]
-Eight tags?
Why not.
[silverware tapping glass]
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome to the 12th Annual
Golden Garlic Award Ceremony.
[narrator] George had
to work quickly.
♪ ♪
[Netti] Georgio?
-Georgio?
-[cheerful greeting]
-Hurry to the stage!
-[affirmative exclamation]
♪ ♪
And now, to present
the Golden Garlic Award…
[drum roll]
[triumphant music]
George, what happened
to your--
What are you wearing?
[cheerful music plays]
[gasps, giggles]
[cheers and applause]
Wow, nice pants.
[giggles, cheerful babbling]
-Thank you, Georgio.
-[grunts]
Next time, when I need
my suit tailored,
I'm gonna come to you.
[cheerful giggling, chatter]
♪ ♪