[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[playful music plays]
♪ ♪
-[barking]
-Huh?
[male narrator]
It wasn't every day
George saw a wizard
and an alien
walking down the street.
It should be a movie
about magic.
No way, science fiction
movies are the best.
Huh?
[narrator] But they did
look a little familiar.
Ah.
[grunting happily]
Ah, hi, George.
[chattering inquisitively]
-We're making a movie.
-Oh.
It's for a film festival
just for kids.
Ah.
But we have to turn in
our movie tomorrow
and we haven't even
started filming yet.
Well, we could start,
if you just let the film
be about aliens.
I'm telling you,
it's about wizards.
-Aliens.
-Wizards.
-[Steve] Aliens.
-[Betsy] Wizards.
[chattering diplomatically]
♪ ♪
You think we
should combine them?
You mean do a story
about aliens and wizards?
[chattering excitedly]
Hmm, that could be
kind of cool.
Great idea, George.
Hey, do you wanna help us?
[chattering excitedly]
Good. We could really use
an extra set of hands.
[grunting happily]
[chuckles]
And feet.
♪ ♪
Okay, I think we finally
have our story.
[chattering excitedly]
Once there was a girl
who was cursed
-and turned into a dog.
-[pants]
Huh?
Then one day an Alien
and Wizard team up,
eventually break the spell,
and turn her back into a girl.
-It's called…
-[both] "A Doggy Adventure."
-[chattering excitedly]
-[barking excitedly]
Hmm.
In the first scene,
the Alien finds the Dog
and learns
she's actually a person.
That's 'cause the Alien
can read minds.
Then they meet the Wizard
and ask her for help.
[chattering happily]
Betsy and I are both
in the scene, George,
so would you operate
the camera?
I'll show you how.
Uh?
Oh.
A-ha.
See this button?
Just press it
to start recording.
-Mm.
-[tablet beeps]
-Oh.
-[chattering happily]
Next, you have
to frame the shot.
That means you keep the actors
in the middle of the picture.
-[slurps]
-Hey.
And try to make sure the actors
don't lick the lens.
[giggles]
[grunting happily]
One more thing.
This button lets you
zoom in and out.
That makes the picture look
closer or farther away.
-Ah.
-[grunting happily]
Think you can remember
all of that?
[chattering happily]
Okay, George.
Start filming.
[tablet beeps]
-Action.
-What?
You are a person who has been
turned into a dog?
[barking happily]
Alas, I can read minds, but
freeing you from this curse
is beyond my powers.
[grunting inquisitively]
-Fear not, I, the Wizard--
-Huh?
Can help you.
George, what're you doing?
Huh?
You need to stay
behind the camera.
[playful music plays]
-Oh.
-[giggles]
[chuckles]
It's okay.
I'm sure you only
did it at the end.
We don't have much time,
so let's move on to scene two.
[jazz music plays]
♪ ♪
Okay, in this scene,
the Wizard, that's me,
realizes that she has
lost her magic wand.
[chattering worriedly]
I know.
Terrible, huh?
-Okay, let's film from here.
-[chattering happily]
[Betsy] And action.
♪ ♪
Oh, no, I have lost
my magic wand.
Without it, I can't
reverse the spell.
-Huh. We must find it, Wizard.
-[barking excitedly]
Where did you last see it?
[chatters happily]
[Betsy] Well, I had it
when I was making
that magic potion earlier.
[Steve] Did you check
your pockets?
-[Betsy] It's a magic wand…
-[sniffing, barking]
[playful music plays]
[chewing, munching]
Hey, get away from those.
[Betsy] I have a backup one, but
it's with my fairy godmother.
-Ooh.
-[chattering curiously]
[Betsy] And cut.
-How was that, George?
-[chattering happily]
Great. We can move on
to scene three.
♪ ♪
-[burps]
-[giggles]
♪ ♪
Okay, scene three.
While they look for the wand,
a dog catcher comes
and chases the dog away.
[both gasp]
This time I'll film,
because I need you
to lead Charkie
through the park.
-I'll follow.
-Okay.
Okay?
Action.
[chattering happily]
[upbeat music plays]
[Charkie barking excitedly]
♪ ♪
-Whoa.
Slow down, guys.
[barking excitedly]
Charkie, no.
Huh.
[grunting excitedly]
Slow down.
[grunts]
[playful music plays]
Steve, look out.
[grunts]
Oh, no.
[Steve] The tablet.
♪ ♪
-Phew.
-[chattering happily]
No, we didn't get the shot.
But we'll come back to it.
At least we got
plenty of sunshine.
[thunder roars]
[ominous music plays]
[both] Aw.
♪ ♪
Oh.
We still got this
last scene to film.
They find the wand and the dog
and then turn the dog
back into a girl.
[solemn jazz music plays]
But I don't think we're gonna
be able to finish, Steve.
Ah.
♪ ♪
Ooh, ah.
Ah, making a movie
is a lot harder
than I thought
it would be.
[chattering happily]
[playful music plays]
♪ ♪
Hmm.
Wow.
I don't think
it's gonna stop.
Let's just go home and see if
we filmed anything we can use.
♪ ♪
Huh?
[Steve] What?
You are a person who has been
turned into a dog?
Alas, I can read minds, but
freeing you from this curse
is beyond my powers.
[Betsy] Fear not.
I, the Wizard, can help you.
-Ah.
-[giggles]
[chuckles]
Yeah, it is pretty funny.
Too bad we're not
making a comedy.
Yeah, let's just skip
to scene two.
[clicks mouse]
We must find it, Wizard.
Where did you--
[Betsy] Well, I had it
when I was making
that magic potion earlier.
[Steve] Did you check
your pockets?
[Betsy] It's a magic wand.
It's not gonna fit…
[sniffs, barks]
-Huh?
-What?
[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
Get away from those.
[Betsy] I have a backup wand,
but it's with
my fairy godmother.
[chattering proudly]
Well, I don't think we filmed
anything we wanted to.
Oh, we got nothin'.
[chattering happily]
Hey, George has a point.
There  is a lot here.
Maybe we can use it.
Huh?
How?
It doesn't fit with our story.
No, but we could use
the shots differently
and change the story a little.
Like… that smoke could be
where the Wizard
changes the dog
back into a girl.
Yeah, we could start
with a shot of Charkie,
then put in the smoke.
[whimsical music plays]
♪ ♪
Okay.
Alakazam.
You are now a girl again.
[yelps]
[grunts excitedly]
[giggles]
Hah!
Okay.
Let's see if we can turn this
into a movie.
[munching, chewing]
Ooh, I got a great idea.
Play it backwards.
[playful music plays]
[laughter]
♪ ♪
Hey, let's add
a narrator too.
Oh, oh, and what if
that Frisbee
wasn't a Frisbee at all but…
-Ooh.
-[chattering excitedly]
[gasps]
A flying saucer.
That's perfect.
[eerie music plays]
[Betsy] After landing,
the alien realized
he could communicate
with this four-legged
creature.
[barking happily]
[Steve] Help, I have been
turned into a dog.
I think it happened
when I tried to eat a plate
of magic hot dogs.
But that wasn't a good idea.
[laughter]
[Betsy] To help, the Dog,
the Alien, and the Wizard
voyaged across the stormy sea.
[all gasp]
[Betsy] Then the Wizard
found her wand
and reversed the spell.
And when the smoke cleared,
the dog had been changed
back into…
a monkey.
The end.
[cheers and applause]
[upbeat music plays]
Bravo.
[narrator] It wasn't the movie
they set out to make.
It was even better.
♪ ♪
[upbeat music plays]
[barking excitedly]
[male narrator] After a fun
weekend in the country,
it was time for George
and his city friends
to say goodbye.
-[chattering happily]
-[barking]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Even Charkie
wanted to say goodbye
to her new friend.
[barking excitedly]
Come on, Charkie, time to go.
Get in the car.
[chattering happily]
[grunts]
♪ ♪
-Thanks, George.
-[engine starts]
-Bye.
-Safe trip.
-See ya.
-Bye.
[narrator]
Charkie left her ball.
Uh-oh.
-Hey.
-Oh, hi, George.
Hey, you found Charkie's ball.
[upbeat jazz music plays]
[barking excitedly]
-[chuckles]
-[groans]
[chattering inquisitively]
I'm writing a letter to Bill
to tell him all about
life in the city.
Ah.
Are you going back
to the country soon?
-Uh-huh.
-Great.
Can you give this to Bill?
I don't have his address.
[chattering happily]
[playful jazz music plays]
[narrator] Maybe Charkie would
like to write a letter
to her new friend too.
♪ ♪
She'd tell Jumpy that she got
her favorite ball back.
Ah.
[barks]
"Sincerely, Betsy.
From the city."
♪ ♪
Oh.
[giggles]
-[slurps]
-[giggles]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George had letters
for Bill and Jumpy.
[chattering excitedly]
A letter?
For me?
[gentle jazz music plays]
♪ ♪
[chuckles]
That Betsy's quite a character.
[chatters happily]
♪ ♪
[chattering excitedly]
[chirps]
[playful jazz music plays]
-Hmm?
-[chattering happily]
[giggles]
[sniffs]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George was happy that
both letter were well-received.
[chuckles]
Hey, George,
would you give this to Betsy
-when you go to the city?
-Uh-huh.
I wanna send her all
different kinds
of country leaves.
[grunting happily]
[narrator] Jumpy probably wanted
to send something
to Charkie as well.
-Oh, ah.
-[chattering happily]
[narrator] Country dirt
was the perfect gift
for a dog who liked to dig.
And the Renkins
had the best dirt.
[chickens clucking]
♪ ♪
Hi.
[narrator] Maybe the chickens
wanted to send something
to a city bird.
And George knew just that bird.
Compass.
-Oh.
-[giggles]
[narrator] But what would
a chicken send to a pigeon?
♪ ♪
-Ah.
-[chickens clucking]
[narrator] Chicken snacks.
George, time to go
back to the city.
[chatters happily]
[grunts]
[gasps]
Whoa, there.
Hey, who are these
packages for?
-[chattering happily]
-[cooing]
-Compass?
-Uh-huh.
[barking]
-And Charkie?
-Uh-huh.
[chattering happily]
-Betsy.
-Yeah, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Well, okay, but how're you
gonna tell them apart?
They all look the same.
Huh?
Uh-oh.
[narrator] His friend was right.
Betsy might get the chicken
snacks by mistake.
♪ ♪
[giggles]
Hmm…
[narrator] George didn't want
to open the envelopes.
-They looked so nice.
-[rustling]
This one was pretty light
and made leafy sounds.
It must be for Betsy.
[chattering happily]
[rustling]
Ah.
[narrator]
The second package definitely
sounded like chicken snacks.
[chattering happily]
[narrator] That left the dirt
for Charkie.
♪ ♪
Now, each envelope would
go to the right person.
Or dog.
Or pigeon.
Mm.
Huh? Huh.
♪ ♪
[chattering excitedly]
[cooing]
♪ ♪
[narrator]
Compass was speechless.
[chattering excitedly]
Oh, hi, George.
Is this from Bill?
[giggles]
Thanks,
George.
-[barking excitedly]
-[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
Oh, no.
[chattering worriedly]
Hey, do you think
Bill would like it
if I made him
some cookies?
[chattering happily]
[light jazz music plays]
[cooing]
Hmm, which is better,
granola-banana
or oatmeal-raisin?
Uh…
-Oh.
-[chattering happily]
Both? Okay, why not?
♪ ♪
Ah.
[narrator]
George could help Charkie
send nut snacks to Jumpy.
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
[cooing]
[narrator] And Compass had found
the perfect city food
-to send to the chickens.
-Ah.
[giggles]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Betsy's cookies
wouldn't fit into an envelope.
Uh-oh.
♪ ♪
[narrator] And it didn't
look like the nuts
and popcorn would either.
-[sighs]
-[grunts]
Be right back.
Ah.
[grunting excitedly]
-You want these recyclables?
-Uh-huh.
Okay.
[upbeat music plays]
Hmm.
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
Ah.
-[gasps]
-[chuckles]
[narrator] Bill loved
Betsy's cookies.
[chimes ring]
[chirping]
Ah.
[playful music plays]
[narrator] Jumpy was speechless.
♪ ♪
Same for the chickens.
Hey, George,
take my picture.
[light jazz music plays]
♪ ♪
[camera shutter snaps]
[narrator]
Bill gave George the idea
to send pictures of his country
friends to his city friends.
[cooing]
♪ ♪
[barking happily]
[chatters happily]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Then there were more
and bigger deliveries to take
back to the country.
♪ ♪
Sorry, George,
but we've got car trouble.
Looks like we're not going
to the country this weekend.
Aw.
[chattering worriedly]
[narrator] How would George
deliver all the packages?
His country friends
would be expecting them.
[all sobbing]
[solemn music plays]
♪ ♪
Aw.
Well, you could
mail the packages.
[light jazz music plays]
[narrator] The mail carrier
probably wouldn't deliver
to squirrels and chickens.
But they would deliver to Bill.
Hey.
[chattering excitedly]
♪ ♪
Okay, "Dear, Bill…"
[chattering eagerly]
[narrator] George and his friend
worked on the letter.
And they took everything
to the post office.
♪ ♪
-A few days later…
-[bell ringing]
Um, excuse me,
Mr. Jumpy Squirrel?
I've got a delivery for you
from a Ms. Charkie the dog.
[playful music plays]
[grunts, sniffs]
[squeaking]
Courtesy of George's
Delivery Service.
Have a nice day, sir.
[chirping]
[squeaking]
♪ ♪
[both clucking]
[clucking excitedly]
♪ ♪
[giggles]
[narrator] George wished he
could've been there to see
the chickens enjoy
their new bath.
And with the photos
Bill sent him,
he kind of was.
[upbeat music plays]
♪ ♪