[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[bright music plays]
♪ ♪
[male narrator]
On hot summer days,
George had two favorite ways
to cool off.
[laughing]
[narrator] The first was zipping
down the water slide.
The second was sipping
a fresh glass of juice.
[phone rings]
-[beep]
-Yello?
Howdy, cuz!
We've got a huge
crop of oranges,
hundreds of crates
more than we can sell.
I know how you and George
love our oranges,
so I wanted to send you some.
[chatters]
Eustace, how generous!
We'd love a dozen or two.
Hoo-wee!
Okay.
Two dozen it is!
Two dozen crates of oranges?
[bike bell rings]
Boy, you guys must
really like oranges.
What're you gonna do
with so many?
Ah…
[gulping]
[giggles]
That's a lot of orange juice
for one man and one city kid.
Uh-huh.
Hey, there's a construction
crew down the road.
We could set up
an orange juice stand.
[chattering excitedly]
[engine turns over]
I have some errands
to run, George.
I'll be back in a few hours.
Good luck with the juice stand.
-Bye!
-[chatters]
[mellow music plays]
♪ ♪
[chatters]
Whew.
♪ ♪
Yep, with this heat,
they're gonna be thirsty.
Better start squeezing.
[chatters]
[bright music plays]
Hi, fellas.
One cup, please.
[truck hisses]
[machine whirs]
Ah!
[chatters curiously]
We're replacing
a leaky water pipe.
Fred's digging out a trench
for it with his backhoe.
Ah.
One fresh-squeezed OJ.
[gulps]
[sighs]
Mmm.
Delightful.
Thanks.
[coin clatters]
[machine whirrs]
Here.
With more hands,
we can double our output.
Ah.
♪ ♪
[gulps, sighs]
You see Kieren?
She can lift over three tons!
[chuckles]
Well, not her--  her crane.
[punchy music plays]
♪ ♪
Ah.
-I'll take another.
-[coin clatters]
[bright music plays]
♪ ♪
[truck hisses]
[gulping]
Mmm.
[chatters]
Bang, bang, bang,
bang, bang, bang?
Good point, George.
Isn't the road
gonna be all bumpy?
Oh, not after
Lucy's done with it.
[chatters curiously]
Aw, Lucy is what Phillippe
calls his steamroller.
[fanfare plays]
That steamroller is so heavy,
she'll squeeze all that
flat as a pancake.
[punchy music plays]
♪ ♪
-Cool.
-Ah.
I'll take another.
Actually, make it two.
And I bet Phillippe
will want some more as well.
[coins clatter]
Hmm…
Ah.
[bright music plays]
[grunting happily]
♪ ♪
Whew, juicing oranges
is thirsty work.
Luckily, we have two cups left.
-[gasps]
-Thanks, guys.
[coin clatters]
Ah.
You guys sure work fast.
It's the machines.
They make our job
so much easier.
See you guys after lunch.
[sighs tiredly]
They're gonna want more juice
when they get back.
I wish we had machines
to help us.
[gasps]
Oh?
[piano trilling]
Hmm…
I'll see if there's anything
in my house that might help us.
You better start squeezing.
[truck whirring]
Ah.
[oranges squelch]
[narrator] Maybe the perfect
orange-juicing machine
was right in front of him.
Ah!
[uneasy music plays]
[narrator] George just
needed to figure out
how to move this thing.
No squeezing machines,
but I got these.
Wow, you can drive
a steamroller?
Uh, uh-uh…
[chatters]
I'm pretty sure you need
a steamroller's license.
Aww.
[chitters]
[narrator]
Jumpy couldn't believe it.
That was the biggest acorn
he'd ever seen.
[lever clicks]
-[surprised chatter]
-[gasps]
[punchy music plays]
♪ ♪
George, stop the machine!
You don't have a license.
[chatters in confusion]
♪ ♪
[chitters]
Watch out for
the fire hydrant!
[screams]
♪ ♪
Whew.
And now the fence!
[screams]
[chitters]
[chatters in panic]
[screams]
George!
Huh?
Maybe steamrollers
have brake pedals.
Look down and see!
[chatters]
[music quickens]
[panting]
George!
[ducks quacking]
♪ ♪
[chatters in panic]
-[gasps]
-[chattering]
[narrator] George wanted
the mailbox to move…
But it didn't listen.
[whimpers]
[moos]
[panting]
George, is that a key?
[chatters]
Quick!
Turn the key!
[key clicks]
[steamroller hisses]
[relieved sigh]
Kind of a mess,
but it did
squeeze those oranges,
Oh, well.
Too bad we don't have
our own steamroller.
Ah.
Hmm…
Ah!
[narrator]
But maybe they could get one.
Ah.
[narrator]
They could get a big roller,
something to attach it to,
and something to push it,
and make their own steamroller.
Huh?
[chatters]
Aww.
[narrator]
It looked like a steamroller,
so why wasn't it
squeezing the orange?
-[orange squelches]
-[gasps]
Huh?
[grunts]
Aha!
[narrator] They needed
to make the barrel heavier.
Just a little water
would do it.
Crush away, George!
[chatters excitedly]
[slow punchy music plays]
♪ ♪
We have orange juice,
George!
-Keep peddling!
-[grunts]
[panting]
[victorious music plays]
There's almost
a pitcher's worth.
And just in time.
Here come our customers.
Ah.
[gasps]
Lucy?
What are you doing over here?
And how did you get so dirty?
Do you two know who drove Lucy?
[chuckles]
George did.
-[chatters]
-Really?
Well, I'm surprised a monkey
can get a steamroller license.
He's a hero.
A squirrel jumped into it
and it started moving.
George steered it
and stopped it.
Uh-huh…
[chatters excitedly]
Phillippe,
did you leave
Lucy's key on again?
Maybe.
So, George,
it was you who flattened
part of my backfield.
Uh…
[whimpers]
Oh, I needed it flattened.
I'm putting
a strawberry patch there.
How can I repay you
for saving my Lucy?
Hmm…
[narrator] So, Phillippe
shined up his steamroller.
[chatters excitedly]
[punchy music plays]
♪ ♪
Thank you, George.
Hey, George.
I got something for you.
[chatters excitedly]
It's an electric juicer.
It makes getting
orange juice easy.
Ah!
[chattering excitedly]
Um, have I missed something?
Uh…
[giggles]
[playful music plays]
♪ ♪
-Why, hello there, sir.
-Ah.
Uh, what's fresh today?
[chatters happily]
Hmm, okay.
I'll take two, uh, carrots.
Are-- are the rulers
the carrots?
Uh-huh.
Oh, great.
And one bunch of, uh, celery.
Uh-huh!
[chatters]
And, uh, hmm.
Looks like you've got
two things mixed together here.
Huh?
Well, they're both round,
but they're different
colors and sizes.
They don't really go together.
Ah.
♪ ♪
[chatters excitedly]
[shouts happily]
Great!
I'll have two apples
and two oranges.
[chatters]
[chatters excitedly]
Thanks.
I can't wait
to take these veggies home
to make a delicious dinner
for my…
monkey?
George?
Where'd you go?
[chatters]
-Oh, you're in bed already?
-[chatters]
Are you feeling okay?
[chatters]
[imitates snoring]
Oh, right.
You need to get your sleep before
the farmer's market tomorrow.
Well, I'm sure you'll do a
great job helping the Renkins.
[yawns]
[chatters pleasantly]
Nighty-night, George.
I'll see you in the morning.
[snores softly]
[grunts]
Ah!
I'm ready for my first
farmers' market in the city.
How about you, George?
Uh-huh!
Perfect timing, George.
We're just about packed up.
♪ ♪
[gasps]
Oh, no, no, Blanche!
Ah, sorry, ol' girl.
These aren't for you.
George,
could you take Blanche
somewhere away
from the market food?
Uh-huh.
Ah…
[chatters]
[bleating]
♪ ♪
Come on, George.
Time to go.
♪ ♪
Hop in.
[grunts]
[seatbelt clicks]
-[bleating]
-[engine revs]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George couldn't wait
to sell things at the market.
[laughs]
Isn't it exciting, George?
[chatters]
Wow.
[cars honking]
There's so much going on.
[gasps]
♪ ♪
Here we are.
[both gasp]
What happened?
[chatters]
[bleats]
Looks like
we have a stowaway.
You stay in there
while we set up, girl.
Then we'll figure out
where to put you.
Ooh.
[laughs]
Oh.
This is the most amazing-est
thing I've ever seen!
[chatters]
Okay, everybody, let's hurry
up and get everything sorted.
-Okay.
-[chatters]
[narrator] Luckily, George was
a one-monkey sorting machine.
Carrots with carrots,
apples with apples.
[gasps, whimpers]
[narrator] And mushy with mushy.
Ick.
♪ ♪
Hmm…
[narrator] There was something
funny about that apple.
Hmm…
[chatters contemplatively]
Ah.
[narrator]
Because it wasn't an apple.
It was a pepper.
[chatters]
[laughing]
Why, look at you go, George.
Uh-huh.
Looks like we're ready
to open for business.
[mischievous music plays]
-You ready to start, George?
-Uh-huh.
Let's go!
[playful music plays]
Huh?
George, come on.
I want you to show me the city.
[chatters]
You wanna sell stuff?
Uh-huh…
[chatters]
Mm, well,
what if first we-- uh-oh.
-Blanche!
-[chatters]
♪ ♪
She must have climbed out
the truck window, Grandma.
Well, we can't roll them up,
not on a hot day like today.
Oh, it's okay.
George and I will find the
bestest place to tie her up.
That must be some kind of
super duper,
double-double knot, George.
It'll never come untied.
Uh-huh.
Hey, George.
That's your building, right?
Uh…
[chatters sheepishly]
Well, since we're right here,
could I at least
have a peek inside?
Please, please, please?
Pretty please?
Uh…
-[chatters]
-[laughs]
Then you can do
all the selling you want.
[laughs]
Wow.
This is the most amazing-est
house in the world, George.
Look at all the mailboxes!
Are they all yours?
[chatters]
And all those stairs--
do they go up to your room?
[chatters]
And that dog!
[gasps]
-[grunts curiously]
-He's so handsome.
[narrator] Hundley didn't realize the
monkey had such intelligent friends.
[gasps]
And look at the flowers!
And look at the… goat?
Huh?
-Blanche!
-[shouts]
[grunts, barks]
[narrator] Hundley knew
it was too good to be true.
-[barking]
-[bleating]
[shouting]
[frantic music plays]
Blanche!
Come back!
-[grunts]
-[George shouts]
[bleating]
[chattering]
♪ ♪
Aha!
[elevator dings]
Oh, this is the
glossiest building
I've ever seen.
[elevator dings]
-[shouts]
-Oh, oh.
[elevator dings]
A goat?
How unique!
I like things that are unique.
Keep it up!
[elevator dings]
George?
What are you doing here?
[chatters]
We're looking for our goat.
Ah.
He just went down.
[chatters happily]
So, that goat
doesn't work for us?
Ah, I knew it was
too good to be true.
Get me a goat!
[chatters]
♪ ♪
[bleating]
[laughs]
What a big park!
♪ ♪
[panting]
A fountain?
-[chatters]
-Oh, this city has everything.
[laughs, pants]
Where'd she go now--
oh, wow.
Look at that fancy trash can.
[narrator]
George didn't see Blanche,
but he saw where she'd been.
-[woman] Taxi.
-[tires screech]
[gasps]
[chatters, grunts]
♪ ♪
Market Square, please.
Ah, I guess
you were here first.
-[shouts]
-Stop!
Goat!
Taxi!
Here you go.
Market Square.
[bleats]
-[shouts]
-Stop!
-[bleats]
-[both gasp]
Blanche took a cab
back to the market?
Huh.
I always knew
she was independent.
There you are, George.
Mr. and Mrs. Renkins
went looking for youse.
Oh, no!
Now they'll never
sell anything.
[gasps]
[chatters]
[upbeat music plays]
Look at you go, Georgie…
[laughs]
Now, I also need
two garlic bulbs,
three onions,
four green peppers.
And there was
a great big fountain.
It's right over there!
This is the most
amazing city ever!
[narrator] George, Allie,
and the Renkins' vegetables
were the hit of the market,
and the mushy food kept Blanche
too busy eating to run away.
[upbeat music plays]
♪ ♪