[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
Wow.
[male narrator]
George couldn't wait
for the Founder's Day
celebration.
[grunts happily]
[narrator] And it was
just a day away.
I'm ready, George,
if you want to help.
[chatters excitedly]
Let's be careful with
this antique rocking horse.
Whoever wins it
will sure be lucky.
[chatters]
Hey, yeah,
you could win the raffle.
Well, George, are you excited
to eat and play
just like our founders did
200 years ago?
[chatters, chuckles]
How's the cooking
for the feast going?
Oh, I still have tons to do.
Making everything
from scratch is hard work.
I don't know how
our ancestors managed.
Well, as my
great-great-grandfather
Zebediah Renkins used to say,
"Good things take time."
I could use a taste tester
to see if everything
is turning out okay.
[knowingly]
Know of anyone?
[babbles excitedly]
Ah!
[pigs snorting]
[all chewing]
[rustic music plays]
[narrator] George thought
there was nothing better
than toast with butter.
Mmm.
I made it just like
they would've in the 1800s
in this old butter churn.
Ah! [chatters curiously]
-This is the churning stick.
-Huh?
You put this wide,
flat end in the churn
and move it up and down,
like this.
Oh!
And all that stirring
turns cream into butter.
[clattering, pig snorts]
[gasps]
-[Mr. Renkins] Oh, dear.
-[squealing wildly]
Hamilton, no!
[lively music plays]
Well, I'll be.
Hamilton just polished off
the whole crock of butter.
[gasps]
That was all the butter
for tomorrow's feast.
[George gasps]
You could get more
at the store.
Serve butter that wasn't made
the old-fashioned way?
Old Zebediah Renkins
would not approve!
Well, looks like, tomorrow,
we'll all be eating dry toast.
[bread crunching noisily]
Hmm.
[all sigh]
[chatters confidently]
[chatters]
You want to make the butter?
It's not a quick job.
Before you start churning,
you have to get fresh cream.
Ah!
[babbles happily]
I guess we better
pay Leslie a visit.
[chuckles excitedly]
[cow moos]
[chitters questioningly]
Butter is made from cream.
That's the fatty part
of the milk.
Oh!
Now, you have to store
the jar someplace cool.
Then it takes a whole day
for the cream
to rise to the top.
[babbles keenly]
You skim the cream
off the top,
and finally, you put the cream
in the churn and churn it,
just like I showed you before.
Do you think you can
handle all that, George?
[chatters confidently]
♪ ♪
[grunts happily]
[babbles in thanks]
Good-bye, George.
Good luck!
[narrator] George figured
he would store the milk
in the refrigerator back home.
[gasps]
[chatters uncertainly]
[narrator] But were there
refrigerators
way back in Zebediah's time?
Uh-uh.
Hmm.
[narrator] How could George keep
his milk cool overnight
without using a modern machine?
Huh?
[shouts]
[pig squeals]
[lively music plays]
[chattering in alarm]
Whew.
[shivers]
Ah!
[narrator] If the stream
was too cold for monkeys,
George figured it might
be just right for milk.
Aha.
[grunts cheerfully]
[grunting]
[narrator] With the jars secure,
George could leave them
overnight…
[pleasant music plays]
-[yawns]
-[narrator] …and collect them
in the morning.
[shouts in shock]
[chattering anxiously]
[narrator] George was sure
this was where he left
the jars yesterday.
Ah!
[straining]
Oh!
[sighs happily]
[grunting]
[groans]
[narrator] He needed
a long, sturdy stick
to dislodge those jars.
Ah!
[chatters happily]
[grunting]
[snorts, squeals]
[shouts]
Uh…
[sighs sadly]
[narrator] At least George
still had the milk.
[colonial flute music plays]
Aha!
[narrator] And the cream
had risen
to the top of the milk,
just like in the old picture.
♪ ♪
So George skimmed off the cream
from the first jar.
Hmm.
[babbles thoughtfully]
[narrator] But without
the churning stick,
what could he use
to make the butter?
[gasps]
[chattering excitedly]
[grunting]
[babbles in frustration]
Ha!
[grunting]
[dejected babble]
[narrator] The broom handle
didn't move
the cream around much.
It wasn't the right shape.
Hmm?
Ah!
[cheerful music plays]
[grunting]
Phew.
Hmm.
[gasps] Ah!
[grunting]
Oof!
[snorting happily]
[groans]
[intriguing music plays]
♪ ♪
George, all set
for Founder's Day today?
[gasps] Oops.
What happened here?
[chattering sadly]
Oh, you were trying
to make old-fashioned butter?
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
We made butter at school,
but we didn't use a churn.
We just shook it
in a jar, like this.
[grunts]
After a while,
you get whipped cream.
[chatters in disbelief]
♪ ♪
[babbles questioningly]
But if you keep shaking,
you'll get butter.
I'd help, but it's almost
time for the sack race.
I'm a judge.
See you there!
Hmm.
[grunting]
[grunts in frustration]
[narrator] This was too hard.
George would have to break
the news to Mrs. Renkins
that there'd be no butter
for Founder's Day.
-[chitters insightfully]
-[narrator] Maybe the raffle drum
could shake the cream.
Hmm.
[grunting]
[narrator] It had
an easy-to-turn crank.
[giggles triumphantly]
[grunting excitedly]
[cheerful music plays]
♪ ♪
[grunting]
[narrator] After a few minutes,
George couldn't wait
to see what was inside.
Hmm.
[shimmering tones]
[slurps]
[chatters approvingly]
[narrator] The cream had
turned into whipped cream,
just like Allie said.
Ah!
[narrator] Now George was sure
he'd get butter.
[panting]
[groans]
[narrator] If only his arm
wasn't so tired.
[chatters insightfully]
[jaunty music plays]
[babbles contentedly]
♪ ♪
[grunting eagerly]
[chatters]
♪ ♪
[giggles triumphantly]
[whoops loudly]
[horse whinnies]
[grunts]
[chittering frantically]
[rambunctious music plays]
[chittering]
[crowd cheering]
[George chittering]
-[gasps] Oh, golly!
-Oh, dear.
♪ ♪
Whoa, girl, whoa!
[horse chuffs]
Everything okay, George?
[panting] Uh-huh.
Well, it looks like
the rocking horse is okay.
Hey, what's this?
[chatters happily]
George! You made butter!
[gasps]
Uh-uh.
[babbles admiringly]
Oh, right.
The horse made it.
Never thought
of using a horse
to make old-fashioned butter,
but…
eh, I'm sure
Zebediah would approve.
♪ ♪
Ah!
Yum-yum-yum-yum!
[bell rings]
Come and get it!
[chuckles]
Well, what are we waiting for?
Let's join the feast.
[narrator] So there was butter
for bread at the feast
after all.
[pleasant woodwind music plays]
♪ ♪
Mr. Renkins wasn't
quite sure
how whipped cream got
in the raffle drum…
but Mrs. Renkins
put it to good use.
♪ ♪
Mmm-mmm!
Delicious, Mrs. Renkins.
Well, as old Zebediah
would say,
"Good things take time."
[chuckles] Yep.
And other times,
good things take a monkey.
[all laughing]
[male narrator] There was
nothing like a summer nap
in the hammock.
The sun was shining,
the breeze was blowing…
-[chatters in surprise]
-[narrator] And the Jumpys
were jumping.
[grunts]
[trills lips, gasps]
[laughs]
[playful music plays]
[babbles curiously]
Ah! [giggles]
Hmm.
♪ ♪
[narrator] George had seen
Jumpy collect acorns,
but a red ribbon?
[chatters inquisitively]
[narrator] Was he planting
a ribbon tree?
[chatters thoughtfully]
[narrator] George was pretty
sure those didn't exist.
[bird chirps]
Ooh.
[narrator] What
a beautiful bird.
[squeaking indignantly]
[both chittering angrily]
Yay!
[narrator] Jumpy and the bird
were playing tug-of-war.
[rambunctious music plays]
[babbles in wonder]
♪ ♪
Huh?
-Aww.
-[squeaks sadly]
[narrator] Jumpy seemed upset.
He probably still wanted
to play tug-of-war.
[chatters encouragingly]
[grunts huffily]
♪ ♪
Huh?
[chitters insightfully]
[narrator] Maybe Jumpy was tired
of playing tug-of-war
and wanted to play
follow-the-squirrel instead.
[imitating squirrel chatter]
[mysterious music plays]
[sniffs]
♪ ♪
[playful music plays]
[chatters happily]
[sniffs, chatters]
[grunts excitedly]
[imitates squirrel chatter]
♪ ♪
[intriguing music plays]
Ooh.
[chitters happily]
[grunting excitedly]
[grunts cheerfully]
[chatters]
♪ ♪
[chatters amazedly]
-[chatters amazedly]
-[squeaks]
[chatters]
-Huh?
-[chatters frantically]
-[shouts]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George had
never noticed
that squirrels climbed
down trees headfirst.
Well, a game was a game.
[chatters nervously]
[narrator] Follow-the-squirrel
was harder than he thought.
[groans]
[narrator] Maybe it was better
to go down the monkey way.
[chatters playfully]
[imitates squirrel chatter]
[chittering irritably]
♪ ♪
[imitating squirrel chatter]
[babbles happily]
♪ ♪
[chatters curiously]
[narrator] George wondered
what this game was.
Pretending to be a statue?
[gasps] Ah?
[deer chuffs]
[narrator] Maybe the deer
was playing too.
[wary music plays]
♪ ♪
[sniffs, chuffs]
[narrator] Or not.
[sneezes loudly]
[snorts angrily]
[squeals]
[grunting nervously]
[warbles fearfully]
[frenzied music plays]
♪ ♪
[babbles]
[shouts]
[Jumpy splutters]
[pants]
[wary music plays]
[chuffing]
[sighs in relief]
[chatters admiringly]
[narrator] George had no idea
squirrels were such good
swimmers.
[giggles]
[narrator] That Jumpy was
full of surprises.
[growls, sighs]
[chitters sadly]
Ah!
[chatters excitedly]
♪ ♪
[cheers, laughs]
Huh?
Huh.
[chattering questioningly]
[calling in gibberish]
Ah!
[playful music plays]
-[snoring]
-Oh.
[narrator] There were so many
things in Jumpy's nest.
[lullaby music plays]
♪ ♪
[sighs contentedly]
[yawns]
[sighs]
-[loud chittering]
-[both shouts]
-[chatters curiously]
-[chittering continues]
-George?
-[chatters]
[both chittering angrily]
[narrator] That bird wasn't
playing with Jumpy.
She was stealing from him!
Ah!
[chattering]
Ah.
[gasps]
[narrator] These things
belonged to Jumpy!
Uh, George?
Watch out.
Don't get too near
that Jay's nest, or…
[squawking]
[warbles dizzily, shouts]
George!
[both sigh in relief]
[squawking in frustration]
[sighs] That's what
I was trying to avoid.
That Jay was building a nest.
[chatters questioningly]
Well, she's probably
going to lay her eggs soon
and needs a place
to raise her chicks.
[squawks sadly]
[babbles regretfully]
[grunting]
Huh?
[babbles anxiously]
I don't know if
you can repair that nest.
They're very delicate.
They take a long time to build.
[sighs]
Ah…
aha! [chatters excitedly]
[chattering joyfully]
[jazzy upbeat music plays]
♪ ♪
[chatters triumphantly]
Um… I guess
it's worth a shot.
♪ ♪
[calls in gibberish]
[chittering excitedly]
[tweets disapprovingly]
[giggles]
[sighs]
Maybe we should just
leave the Jay alone.
She'll build another one.
[twitters]
[glum piano music plays]
Hmm.
[chatters keenly]
[narrator] George wanted
to make it easier
for the Jay to build
another nest.
[upbeat music plays]
♪ ♪
[Jay tweets]
[chatters victoriously]
[chattering happily]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Maybe the Jay wanted
bits of cloth
and ribbons too.
-[angry chittering]
-Huh?
[both chittering angrily]
[babbles pleadingly]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Now Jumpy was taking
things from the Jay's nest.
Hmm.
Ah!
[narrator] Maybe Jumpy
and the Jay each needed
their own things
for their nests.
♪ ♪
And a guard to make sure
they each took
from their own pile.
[authoritative drum music plays]
[cheery music plays]
[chittering excitedly]
[gasps, shouts]
[babbling]
[squeaks]
[chittering happily]
[chuckles]
[laughs] Amazing.
[chatters impatiently]
[narrator] Two-and-a-half weeks later,
the nest had some new tenants.
The Jay and her little chicks
had everything they needed.
Aww.
[babbles cheerfully]
[lullaby music plays]
[snoring]
[narrator] And so did Jumpy.
♪ ♪
[giggles, chatters happily]