[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
♪ ♪
[chatters sadly]
[male narrator] Sometimes,
winter could be tough
for a little monkey,
and altogether, too wintry.
[birds chirping]
[bright music plays]
♪ ♪
[chattering happily]
[chattering excitedly]
[narrator] So when spring
finally arrived…
-[chatters excitedly]
-Whoa!
[narrator] …a monkey was
ready to go outside.
[elevator dings]
[chuckles] Can I at least
finish my breakfast?
Hey, George.
[chatters]
George can't wait
to go to the park.
He's been feeling cooped up.
Actually, I was just
on my way there.
It's Plantapalooza today.
[chatters questioningly]
It's when the park gardeners
plant all the flowers.
Anyone can help,
and you can make
whatever designs you want.
Ooh…
[chatters]
I was coming by to see
if anyone wanted to join me.
[excited chatter]
How about you, Hundley?
You love flowers.
Hmm…
[sniffs, grunts]
[narrator] It was true.
Hundley did love flowers.
[annoyed grunt]
[narrator]
But Hundley hated dirt.
-[sputters]
-[grunts uneasily]
Come on, Hundley.
I bet Marco and George
could use a dog
with your refined taste.
[grunts]
-Oh.
-[both laugh]
[narrator] Yup,
Hundley had better go
to make sure George
didn't make a mess of things.
[giggles]
That's the spirit.
We'll bring a picnic and
join you for lunch around 1:30.
Great idea.
I can't wait to see
those flowers.
[chattering]
You can arrange them
however you like.
There's an empty plot
right over there.
Happy planting!
Thanks!
[grunting]
Let's put some blue ones here
and red ones there.
[chatters in agreement]
It'll look like
a big splatter of paint!
[chatters excitedly]
[unsure grunt]
[narrator] Hundley didn't
like the sound of that.
What were other people doing?
-Hm?
-[narrator] Ah.
Nice and orderly.
[barks in approval]
♪ ♪
-Hm…
-[barks in approval]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
[fantastical music plays]
[narrator] Now, that was how
a flower garden should look--
full of tidy, beautiful shapes.
[grunts in approval]
[chattering excitedly]
[shocked grunt]
[chattering]
Looking good, George.
Let's start digging.
[barks furiously]
[grunts]
[chatters]
You wanna put
some flowers out?
Here you go.
[grunting]
Huh?
-[barks]
-Ah!
[chatters excitedly]
Wow, that makes our design
seem really random.
Hi, there.
Like our little
flower experiment?
It's a molecular structure
of carbon…
Because all life
is based on carbon.
-Get it?
-[both laugh]
It sure is.
[playful music plays]
[chatters]
I think he wants to know
how you got everything to look
so neat and orderly.
Oh, well, we precisely
measured everything
before we started.
-Are you three planting?
-[Marco] Yeah.
[chatters]
And I think you just
gave us an idea.
Uh-huh!
[barks]
Okay, so what should we do?
I really liked how they made
the shapes with the flowers.
[chatters in agreement]
[chatters]
Rectangles?
Yeah.
And we could make them
in different colors.
[chatters excitedly]
[barks]
[mellow music plays]
Hmm…
[barks]
[narrator] Hundley was right.
That line was crooked.
If only he had something
long and straight,
like Professor Pizza's ruler.
[grunts]
Ah…
[chatters]
[narrator]
Hundley was long and straight.
[chattering]
[disgusted grunt]
[sighs, chatters]
♪ ♪
[grimaces]
[chatters]
[surprised grunt]
♪ ♪
[uncomfortable grunt]
[narrator]
Hundley hated getting dirty…
-[barks]
-Huh?
[narrator] But he hated those
crooked lines even more.
[chattering excitedly]
[grunts uneasily]
[chatters]
Well, what do you think?
[chatters in approval]
How about you, Hundley?
[sputters, grunts]
-[clock tower dings]
-[all gasp]
It's 1:00.
We only have a half an hour
before our picnic.
Let's finish it
before they get here.
[grunts]
[narrator]
That wasn't much time.
And Hundley wanted everything
to look perfect
for the Doorman.
Good idea, Hundley.
We better start planting
right away.
[chatters]
Ooh?
Huh.
[narrator]
That gave George an idea.
[chatters excitedly]
[narrator] He had something
that would help the digging.
Huh?
[grunts]
[barks]
♪ ♪
[narrator] Getting dirty
wasn't so bad
when the results
were so beautiful.
[happy grunt]
Huh?
[gasps]
[chatters excitedly]
[laughs, chatters]
[barks in panic]
-Ah…
-[panicked chatter]
[lively music plays]
[barks]
♪ ♪
[gasps, chatters sadly]
Huh.
That would be good to dig with,
if Hundley hadn't already
planted that rectangle.
[chatters pleadingly]
[huffs]
[chatters sadly]
[truck whirrs]
[narrator] No doubt about it--
that rectangle was ruined.
Ah.
[narrator]
But maybe George had made
a different shape by accident.
[chatters]
[playful music plays]
-Huh?
-[grunts questioningly]
Ah…
[chatters]
A triangle!
I like it.
Hey, we could make all
different kinds of shapes.
How about…
a shape like that roof?
I think that's
called a trapezoid.
[chatters]
[grunts]
[huffs]
[dejected whimper]
[Marco laughs]
That's a great shape, George.
[George chatters excitedly]
[grunts tiredly]
[narrator] Being angry
was getting boring.
Hundley decided
to go see how badly
George had messed things up.
[panting, grunts]
[narrator]
Hundley had to admit--
it did look orderly.
[grunts in approval]
We have enough for one more.
Maybe we should just
leave this one as a rectangle.
[chatters]
[grunts, barks softly]
[bright music plays]
Hm.
♪ ♪
-[surprised chatter]
-[barks]
♪ ♪
[gasps]
That shape is a parallelogram.
Oh.
How on Earth
did you think that up?
[barks]
Wow!
I'm really impressed.
I'll say.
I knew it would turn out
beautiful with you on the job.
[grunts]
Hey, I made a shape…
Sandwich-shape.
-Yeah!
-[barks]
♪ ♪
[chomps]
[narrator] And that's how
the first day of spring
turned into
the best picnic ever.
[upbeat music plays]
♪ ♪
Welcome to the day before
the Great Golden Egg Hunt.
[both cheer]
And now we will pick
a name out of the hat
to see who hides the eggs.
[drum roll]
This year's egg hider is…
George!
[cheers wildly]
George, tonight you must hard
boil and color all the eggs.
Tomorrow, you'll hide them.
Hee.
But most importantly,
you will need to hide
The Great Golden Egg.
[gasps]
Oh.
-[chatters]
-[egg rattles]
It's filled with bird seeds
so it won't blow away.
Whoever gets the most points
wins this trophy
and gets to keep it all year.
The egg hunt begins
at 10:00 a.m. sharp,
so get some sleep tonight,
people!
[mellow music plays]
[narrator] George had colored
all 12 of the hard boiled eggs.
[chatters]
[narrator]
He had three red eggs…
-[chatters]
-[narrator] Three blue eggs…
-[narrator] Three yellow eggs…
-[chatters]
-[narrator] And three green eggs.
Ah!
[dejected sound]
Ah.
♪ ♪
-[chomps]
-[knocking]
Ah…
[chatters]
-Hi, George!
-Ah!
I was telling Vicki
and Vinnie all about
the Great Golden Egg Hunt
and they wanna be a part of it
and I said, "Okay, sure."
[chatters]
We brought some
hard boiled eggs.
But we didn't dye them yet.
'Cause you're
the official egg hider.
And dyer.
Any who,
we'll see you tomorrow.
And remember,
hide those eggs really good!
I want a challenge.
Ah.
Uh-huh.
[chatters]
-Bye!
-See ya!
[narrator] George had
12 more eggs to color.
Now he had six red eggs,
six blue eggs…
[chatters]
Ah?
[narrator] But only five yellow
eggs and five green eggs.
Aww.
[narrator] George wanted
to make the same number
of eggs for each color.
Huh?
Ah!
♪ ♪
Hee!
[narrator] 23 eggs all ready
to hide tomorrow morning.
[sneaky music plays]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George was
determined to hide the eggs
in hard-to-find places.
Uh, hmm…
Aha!
Hope you're not gonna
hide one in the mailbox.
Allie always looks there first.
Huh?
Ah.
[giggles softly]
See ya.
Hmm…
-[chatters victoriously]
-[bike bell rings]
The mulch is the
second place she looks.
-[chatters]
-Yup!
I always find one there.
[sighs]
♪ ♪
[narrator] George hadn't found
a good hiding place
for one single egg.
[chatters]
♪ ♪
-[watering can rattles]
-[panicked chattering]
[giggles, chatters]
Ah.
♪ ♪
Shh…
[chatters]
[gasps]
[narrator]
The yellow egg was almost
the same color
as the yellow hay.
Hmm…
ah.
[narrator]
You could hardly see it.
[pleased chatter]
[narrator] Camouflaging was
a great egg-hiding strategy.
Aha.
-[chickens squawk]
-[screams]
[chickens cluck]
Ah.
[chickens cluck curiously]
[giggles mischievously]
Hmm…
Aha!
[chatters victoriously]
[giggles]
[chatters]
[egg rattles]
[narrator] This one needed
a really good hiding place.
[gasps]
Ah!
[chatters]
[narrator] No one would
look for the Golden Egg
in the actual prize.
Hiya, George.
Want some pancakes
before your egg hunt?
Ah!
Uh-huh!
[chatters]
[chitters]
[sniffing]
[narrator] Jumpy thought
it smelled like food.
Maybe it was
a giant golden nut.
[chitters]
All right,
is everybody ready?
-I'm ready.
-Ready!
-Yeah!
-Me too!
[chatters]
[cow bell jingles]
-[laughs]
-I'm gonna get the most!
-Yeah, go, go, go!
-[laughter]
[bright music plays]
Hmm…
[pigs scoffing, grunting]
[mellow music plays]
♪ ♪
I found one!
[laughs]
[sighs]
Hmm…
Oh, wow.
[giggles]
Wow, you're a good
egg hider, George.
[giggles, chatters]
[grunts]
[groans]
This could take forever!
[chatters worriedly]
[clock ticking]
[narrator] What if it
really did take forever?
[somber music plays]
♪ ♪
[chatters worriedly]
Ah!
[laughs]
[narrator] George needed
to move things along.
[whistling nonchalantly]
I found one!
[giggles]
[chatters]
[grunts]
[wind chime jingles]
[chatters]
[gasps]
[laughs]
Gotcha.
[pleased hum]
Okay,
time to tally the score.
I got six points.
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
I've got six points too.
Well, I got seven points…
[satisfied laugh]
One, two, three, four.
I've only got four points.
Okay, let's see.
That makes… 23 eggs in total.
You found them all.
Ah-ah-ah.
[chatters]
Yeah, we still haven't
found the Golden Egg,
and that one counts
as five points.
So, anyone can still win.
[laughter]
[narrator] George may have
given a few hints before,
but no way was he going to hint
where he hid the Golden Egg.
Are you sure you hid
the Golden Egg?
We've been looking
for almost half an hour.
Uh-huh.
Nope.
Huh?
[gasps]
[narrator] George was sure
he'd hidden the egg in there.
Where did it go?
-[gasps]
-[chitters]
[grunting]
[sighs, grunts]
[chatters]
[chitters]
[chatters, yelps]
[giggles]
[chitters]
Jumpy's got the Golden Egg!
Gah!
[panicked chatter]
[chitters]
[panicked squeak]
-I got it.
-[egg rattling]
[victorious music plays]
Yay!
And the final score--
Vicki has nine.
Vicki is the winner!
[all laugh and cheer]
♪ ♪
Wow!
It's beautiful.
[laughs]
[narrator] George felt good.
[chitters softly]
[narrator] So good…
he decided to share the joy
with Jumpy.
[upbeat music plays]
♪ ♪