[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
[male narrator]
A nature hike with friends
was a great way
to spend a summer day.
Thanks for inviting
me and Hundley.
As soon as I got
the fossil permit,
I thought of you two.
On a fossil hunt,
the more eyes, the better.
Huh?
[soft woofs]
What do we have here?
Look, George.
A fossil!
[chattering]
Huh.
Ehh.
-Oh--
-[both] No!
Eh? Huh?
Turn it over
and take a look.
Ah!
That's called
an imprint fossil.
A plant made that impression
a long, long time ago.
Ah!
Hmm. The museum's
gonna love that.
Let's put it in here
where it'll be safe.
Ooh. Ooh-ah.
Ah…
[barking]
No snacking yet, George.
We have a lunch spot planned.
Vista Point.
But first, we should try
to find some more fossils.
[chatters]
[mellow music plays]
♪♪
[both gasp]
It took millions of years
for the river to carve
this canyon.
Ooh!
[chattering]
Yep. That is a really
long time.
Hmm.
Ehh.
[narrator] Finding fossils
was hard work.
[sniffing]
George was surprised
Hundley hadn't found any yet.
He was so much closer to them.
[Hundley sniffing]
Huh?
Ooh ooh ah!
It's a pull ferry.
It's how we'll get
across the river.
-Jump on, George.
-Oh!
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
Mm-hmm.
There ya go.
♪♪
-Ooh!
-Ha.
The rope loops around
that wheel.
It's called a pulley.
See?
When I pull…
the rafts moves forward.
♪♪
Is that an ammonite fossil?
Ooh, let's see!
Oh, no!
[chattering]
Ooh!
Ooh-ooh-ooh-ah-ah-ah!
-[chattering]
-Wha--
[groans] Err…
[narrator] Hundley thought
he'd better stay with George
to make sure he didn't
eat their lunch.
[chattering]
That pulley sure made
pulling easy.
♪♪
Ah!
Mmm.
[narrator] That knot
looked a little loose.
Luckily, Hundley was on duty
to tighten it.
[soft woof]
♪♪
Oh--Ah!
[narrator] Maybe George
could pull them back
to the other side.
[whimpers]
[Hundley barks]
[George and Hundley
making sounds]
[gasps]
George?
Come back here!
I don't think he can.
Stay calm, George.
We'll meet you downriver!
[energetic music plays]
♪♪
[Hundley groans]
Eh.
[chattering]
[panting] This way!
If we hurry,
we can catch up to them.
Ah… ooh!
[panting]
[narrator]
Rafting in the hot sun
sure made a dog thirsty.
[whimpers]
Ah! Ooh ah…
[narrator] Hundley had never
drunk water
from a monkey's feet before.
But it wasn't bad.
[George laughs]
♪♪
Ah!
Whoo hah!
[laughing]
Oh! Oh! Oh!
[narrator] The lunch!
Someone had to save it!
And that someone
was a wiener dog.
[happy chattering]
Ooh ooh ooh.
I don't see them.
They must be moving
faster than we thought.
I'm not sure what else
to do.
I'd better call
the park rangers.
[numbers beeping]
Yes. I'd like to report
a monkey
rafting through the gorge
with a dachshund.
[click, dial tone]
Hello?
Did they hang up?
It often takes
more than one call.
We should keep moving.
Maybe we can catch 'em
at the next bend.
[mellow music plays]
♪♪
Hmm…
[narrator] Was that a fossil?
-Ah!
-[chattering]
[narrator] George needed
a closer look.
[energetic music plays]
♪♪
Ohh…
[triumphant chords]
[sniffing]
[excited chatter]
Mmm?
[barking]
[narrator] They had to
protect the fossil,
and Hundley knew only
one way to do it.
Aah!
[chattering]
[Hundley whimpers]
Huh?
[narrator] George could see
Hundley's little legs
could never climb
a canyon wall without help.
-[woof, woof]
-Huh?
Ehh!
Hmm…
[narrator] Maybe that pulley
could help.
A pulley made
pulling across easy.
Maybe it could make
pulling up easy too.
Ooh!
[upbeat music plays]
[chattering]
[woof, woof]
[woof]
[jazzy upbeat music plays]
♪♪
Ah!
[chattering]
♪♪
[narrator] George's pulley
idea worked.
-When he went down…
-Hello!
[narrator] Hundley went up.
Hundley had his own
monkey-powered elevator.
[chattering]
[grunting]
♪♪
Whew!
Ta-da!
[narrator]
Hundley was so happy,
he decided George
had earned a snack.
[woof, woof, woof]
[narrator]
And George agreed.
George?
[light music plays]
Huh?
Ah!
Hundley, you're okay!
[woof, woof]
Well, I guess we can
collect fossils
and eat at Vista Point
some other day.
That view!
This is Vista Point!
[stirring music plays]
By golly, it is!
[Hundley barks]
Ah!
The basket is full of fossils!
Really nice ones.
But how did George
and Hundley find them
and get them
all the way up here?
If there's one thing
I've learned,
it's that anything is possible
with a monkey.
Uh-huh!
[uplifting music plays]
♪♪
[jazzy music plays]
[narrator] George was a very
good audience member…
which was why Betsy
invited him over
to hear her new story.
[whispers]
Pass the blueberries.
Okay, here goes.
"Greta Gibbons:
the Goose Girl."
Oh, wait.
Let me start again.
"Greta Gibbons:
the Goose Girl"!
Ehh. That one sounded weird.
I'll try another.
Betsy, relax,
It's just the title.
Yeah! To a story
I'm reading on the radio!
Live!
Millions of people
will be listening!
[chattering]
That's right, George.
We'll all certainly
be listening.
And I'm sure it will be
wonderful.
-Mm-hmm.
-But what if it isn't?
What if my reading
doesn't have any…
pizzazz?
[chatters]
How could it not?
Your story won the contest.
Read that first sentence.
"The train chugged steadily
through the mountains,
"its whistle getting
louder and louder,
piercing the night sky."
[both gasp]
[shrill whistling]
Ooh… ah!
Oops! Sorry.
That's the tea.
[whistling, bubbling]
[chattering]
[imitating whistling]
Ha ha. Yeah.
It did sound like
that was the train's
whistle.
Wait a minute--what if you
added sounds to your story?
Now, that would really
give it pizzazz.
You're right!
But there's no time.
And I have to rehearse.
Don't worry--George and I
will help you out.
Won't we, George?
[chattering]
Just tell us
what sounds you'd like.
We'll gather the materials to
make them at the reading.
Okay. Done.
Eight sounds that would
really bring the story to life.
Wait--an alligator?
Yeah. Remember when Greta
flies over
a snapping alligator
on her magic goose?
Oh, right.
We should split up.
It'll go quicker.
You take the first four sounds.
I'll take the second.
[narrator]
George had to find sounds
for a chugging train…
-Mmm.
-[narrator] A sword fight…
a snapping alligator…
-Hmm?
-[narrator] And a witch's pot
of bubbling magic potion.
Eh…
[narrator] George had no idea
where he could find a train
-or swords.
-Ah!
[narrator] But he knew where
he could find an alligator.
-Hmm…
-[narrator] Now, how was George
going to fit that alligator
in his wagon?
[parts clattering]
Huh?
[snap]
Oh!
[narrator] Maybe it wasn't
such a good idea
to bring an alligator
to the show.
Ohh…
Ah!
[narrator] George didn't know
any witches,
but he did know someone
with lots of pots.
What, what--You want
a pot like this-a?
[huffs] That looks like
something a witch would use-a!
Uh-huh, uh-huh!
Ah, well, uh…
people do say
my cooking is magi-cal!
Ha ha ha!
But I'm sorry, Georgio.
I don't have
a witch's cauldron.
Oh…
[snap]
Eh!
[narrator] That snap sounded
awfully familiar.
Oh!
-Aah!
-Whatsa matter?
[excited chattering]
[imitating snapping]
An… an alligator?
Here? Ha ha ha!
No, no, no.
Pisghetti does not allow
alligators in his kitchen!
[snap]
-Aah!
-Oh, that's just Netti
putting up the new orders
as they come in.
[snap]
Three minestrones
and-a one fruit smoothie!
Comin' right up-a,
amore mio!
[blender humming]
[snap]
-[snap]
-[triumphant chords]
[narrator] George didn't
need an alligator--
just something
that sounded like one.
[excited chattering]
What, you want to take
the clipboard?
Uh-huh.
[laughs] Sure!
But why?
You opening up your own
restaurant, Georgie?
Ah… tee hee hee.
[chattering]
Oh, yes!
Betsy is reading her story
on the radio tonight-a!
[chattering]
[imitating snapping]
Oh, you want to make
an alligator sound
-for the reading.
-Uh-huh, huh-huh!
Ha ha! Great idea!
Let's see that list again.
[chattering]
A train? Ha ha!
I have just the thing!
Okay, close your eyes.
Ohh…
-[chugging sound]
-Oh!
[imitating chugging]
[laughs]
[brushing sounds like
train chugging]
Hee hee hee!
Not bad, eh, Georgio?
Chugga-chugga-chugga-chugga.
It's just-a like the choo-choo!
Now, you try.
[chattering]
Ooh!
[laughs]
Ah, this looks like
a sword fight.
Hmm. What could we use?
-[clinking]
-Huh?
[clinking]
Oh, Gnocchi.
Such a clever gatto, huh?
Ha ha ha!
[clanking]
Well, what do you think,
Georgio?
Ooh! Uh-huh!
[chattering]
[bubbling sound]
Yes. That does sound like
a witch's pot-a.
But I can't give you
my minestrone!
It's today's lunch-a special.
Oh…
Wait, wait.
I have an idea.
[upbeat music plays]
[bubbling sound]
♪♪
Ha ha.
I let the customer know
her fruit smoothie will
take a little longer.
[bubbling]
[both laughing]
[narrator] Finally, George
had everything he needed
to make the sounds
on his list.
Ah. Eeh?
[chattering]
One of my sounds I needed
was boots in mud.
So I filled my shoes
with oatmeal.
Not a good idea.
[chattering]
It's okay. I found
something else that works.
But now I wanna change
before the show.
I'll be back soon and explain
all the stuff I found.
[narrator] Steve had very
different sounds on his list.
There was a galloping horse…
Uh-huh!
-[narrator] Boots walking in mud.
-Uh-huh.
[narrator] A honking goose.
Mm…
[narrator] And thunder.
[chattering]
[narrator] But how were
these things
supposed to make
those sounds?
Coconuts?
A soggy newspaper?
What are we supposed to
do with these things?
Where's Steve?
This one or this one?
Ah, nuts, this is tough!
[mellow music plays]
We'll be going on-air
in just a few minutes.
-Get ready.
-Good luck, dear.
Oh, Steve isn't back yet.
Maybe we just shouldn't
do any sounds.
Hmm.
[clop clop]
-[clopping]
-Hey!
That sounds like a horse!
[chattering]
[honk honk]
-[chattering]
-[imitates horn]
Right, the goose!
Of course!
[squishing sound]
Oh, oh, that's number six!
Boots walking through mud!
So this is number eight,
thunder?
Oh…
And we're live
in ten seconds.
Here we go, George.
Okay. I'll hold up my fingers
for what sound I want.
One, two, three.
Then you make the sound.
Got it?
"The train chugged steadily
through the mountains."
[chugging sound]
Netti, that's our wire
brush and pan!
[chuckles]
Sounds-a nice.
"With silver egg in hand,
Greta jumped onto
her noble steed and raced
from the witch's castle
as fast as she could."
[clopping sound]
[clopping]
"It was the moment of truth.
Had Greta broken
the witch's spell?
She closed her eyes
and listened
to the distant rumble
of thunder."
[whimpering]
[fly buzzing]
Shh!
[rumbles]
[rumbling]
[inaudible]
"Greta opened her eyes,
and there was her beloved
goose, back to normal!
Yes!"
[honk honk]
"She had done it.
The end."
-Bravo!
-Good job!
Bravo!
[chattering]
[giggles]
Yeah. I guess that did
have a lot of pizzazz.
[George giggles]
♪♪
[upbeat jazzy music plays]