[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
[male narrator] George like
everything at Pisghetti's.
Ah…
[narrator]
But his favorite
was Chef Pisghetti's
endless spaghetti.
And for you,
the penne alla pesto.
Oh, wait.
No, you ordered rigatoni.
Or was it bucatini?
Or capellini?
Ay, I forget!
Don't worry about it.
It was the penne, but I'll take
anything you make.
It's so busy today,
and Netti is away.
[slurps, grunts inquisitively]
At a cannoli convention.
I could really use
her help today.
[slurps]
[cell phone ringing]
-[cell phone beeps]
-Uh, Pisghetti's.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Your order is coming.
I'll be there right away.
-[cell phone beeps]
-Oh, what to do.
Sally Tessio,
one of my best customers,
broke her foot,
and I told her
I would deliver her lunch.
Uh…
[clears throat]
Everybody!
[chuckles]
Uh, eat slowly!
[customers murmuring]
[slurps]
[chattering happily]
You want to deliver lunch
to Sally?
[chattering happily]
Really?
[gasps]
Oh, Giorgio,
you are such a good monkey.
Come to the kitchen.
[grunting happily]
[upbeat music plays]
Tortellini alla Tessio--
I make it just for Sally--
and a small salad.
[chatters happily]
Okay, you bring it
to 213 Elm Street,
just across from the park--
apartment 8.
Capisce?
[chattering happily]
Ooh, wait, Giorgio.
You can't carry it like that.
Eh, you have to put it
in something.
Table 6 needs more cheese!
Coming!
♪♪
I'll be right back, Giorgio.
[narrator] Chef was so busy.
[chattering sadly]
[narrator] George could find
something to put the food in.
♪♪
Ah!
[whistling]
-[Marco] Ladies and gentlemen…
-Ah.
Prepare to be amazed.
Ah.
[chattering happily]
I will now perform
my most dangerous trick ever--
sawing a teddy bear in half.
-[children gasp]
-Ah.
Don't worry. My assistant
will be just fine.
♪♪
At least, I hope so.
[gasps]
[saw crunching]
♪♪
[children gasp]
[shouts]
Oh, no, what has happened?
Maybe I can put him together
with the magic words.
♪♪
Abracadabra!
-[children cheering]
-[chattering happily]
-Huh? [grunts]
-[meows]
-Uh-uh.
-[chattering]
[meows]
Uh-uh-uh.
♪♪
[chattering]
Ah!
[chattering happily]
♪♪
Yes!
[chattering happily]
Oh, my lunch
from Pisghetti's.
Thank goodness. Come in.
♪♪
It looks scrumptious.
But it's cold.
[chattering]
Try it yourself.
Oh.
[chatters]
Ah.
[chattering]
Yes, that's cold, too,
but the salad
is supposed to be cold.
The pasta
is supposed to be hot.
[chattering]
Well, I could heat it up, but
Chef is such a perfectionist,
he'd want to know
it arrived cold.
-Let's call him.
-Ah.
-[cell phone ringing]
-[shouts]
Fresh pepper?
Uh, Pisghetti's.
Oh, Sally. What?
No, no, no, no, no.
Tell Giorgio to bring it back.
Pisghetti does not serve
cold tortellini.
♪♪
It's my fault, Giorgio.
You probably got lost, yes?
[chatters happily]
Well, then why
the pasta was cold?
She lives very nearby.
Oh! Did you stop along the way?
Ah… uh-huh.
[chattering happily]
Yeah, that's
all right, Giorgio.
[chuckles] But food loses heat
after a while, eh?
Ah.
So this time
no stopping, okay?
-[chatters]
-Now…
we got to find something to put
the pasta in to keep it warm.
One of the customers
has a fly in his soup.
Che disastro!
♪♪
[chattering]
Ah!
♪♪
[narrator] A hat kept George
warm in the winter.
Maybe it would keep
the food warm, too.
[chatters]
[chatters happily]
Aha.
Oh, it's the delivery monkey.
Ah!
[chattering happily]
Eh?
You're right.
The pasta is hot,
but so is the lettuce.
That was supposed
to stay cold, remember?
Oh.
[chatters sadly]
And when hot things and cold
things are touching each other,
the cold things
tend to get hot.
Huh.
Perhaps I should just order
a pizza.
[chattering wildly]
[chatters]
Oh, all right, then.
[chattering happily]
[Chef and waitress]
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
[narrator] George didn't want
to bother Chef.
He would put Sally's lunch
together himself.
[chatters happily]
Ah!
[gasps]
[giggles]
[chattering happily]
[narrator] Now, how could he
keep the pasta warm
but the salad cold.
Ah.
Ah, ah.
[narrator] The napkin
kept those rolls warm.
Maybe that would work
on the pasta, too.
♪♪
Ah!
[chattering happily]
[steam hissing]
[narrator] If the salad
was right next to the pasta,
it might not be cold
when he brought it to Sally.
Ah!
♪♪
Ah.
[narrator] One section
for the tortellini,
one for the salad.
Nothing was touching.
Ah.
[chatters happily]
[narrator] George was ready
to make his delivery.
♪♪
And now…
I will make
this penguin disappear!
[gasps] Oh.
[chatters]
♪♪
[meows]
Uh-uh!
[chattering]
[kittens meowing]
Oh.
[chattering wildly]
♪♪
[kittens continue meowing]
[chattering happily]
Ah.
[panting]
[chattering happily]
♪♪
[exhales sharply]
The tortellini is hot.
♪♪
And the salad is cold.
Success!
Bravo, George!
Ah.
[exhales deeply]
But there's still
one little problem.
[chattering curiously]
I hate to eat alone.
Ah.
And then my second husband
was a botanist.
That's someone
who studies plants.
[knock at door]
Sally, scusami.
I just want to see
if everything was all right.
Ha ha, Giorgio is here.
-[chatters happily]
-Everything is fine, Chef.
We've just finished
your delicious tortellini.
Perfecto.
And I have brought dessert.
Cannoli, huh?
[laughs]
Netti is back
from the convention.
-[all crunching]
-[chattering happily]
I must say, Chef,
you have the most amazing
delivery service.
Only the best from Pisghetti.
Ah…
Mmm.
♪♪
[chattering happily]
[narrator] George loved
a good puzzle.
Ah!
[narrator]
Especially a pirate puzzle.
[chattering happily]
♪♪
[whimpers]
[grunts]
[whimpers, chatters]
Can I give you a tip, George?
[chattering happily]
Oh, sorry. I forgot.
Can I give you a tip,
Captain Monkeybeard?
[chattering happily]
Sometimes it helps
if you sort the pieces first.
♪♪
See? These all have
straight edges.
Oh.
[chattering happily]
-[car horn honks]
-[gasps] It's here!
Ah.
[chattering]
Thanks.
[chattering curiously]
Oh, just something special
for a little pirate monkey.
[chattering happily]
[chuckles] Easy, now.
It has to assembled first.
Let's…
Oh, here we go.
"How to assemble your new"--
Avast!
Well, if it isn't
Long Yellowpants and, uh…
[grumbling]
[whispering]
Captain Monkeybeard.
[sighs]
Are you ready
for me pirate party tonight?
Argh!
Say, uh, do you have
a spare serving bowl?
I need something
for my spicy sea monster salsa.
Hmm.
Oh, I have just the bowl.
Follow me.
It's shipshape
and sings sea shanties.
You're joking.
♪♪
Ah!
[grunting]
♪♪
[grunting worriedly]
[grunting] Ah!
Aah!
Huh?
[narrator]
A long wooden pole?
What could that be part of?
[carnival music plays]
Ooh!
[chattering happily]
[narrator] A carousel?
[music flattens]
But a horse wouldn't fit
in this box.
Ah.
[narrator]
George wanted more clues.
♪♪
Hmm.
I could've sworn I put it
with my other novelty bowls.
Well, I guess
I could use this one.
It's shaped like Shakespeare.
Wasn't a pirate, though.
Wait! I bet I put it
in my trunk of ocean things!
You have a trunk
of ocean things?
♪♪
[grunting]
Hmm?
Argh!
Ahoy there, matey!
Hey, what's this?
Oh, did a big wave wreck
your pirate ship,
Captain Monkeybeard?
[laughing]
[grunts]
[narrator]
What if Allie was right?
Oh.
Ah.
[chattering happily]
Hey! Where you going?
I wanted to show you my sword.
♪♪
[grunts sadly]
Aha!
[chattering happily]
Wait!
This really is a pirate ship?
Ah…
[chattering happily]
Wow.
Well, what are we waiting for?
Let's put it together.
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
The Man would be so surprised
when he saw it all built.
♪♪
[chattering sadly]
[narrator]
Except George had no idea
how to build a pirate ship.
-Hmm.
-[bell clangs]
Well, butter my barnacles!
It's not in my ocean-things
trunk either.
Ah, well,
don't trouble yourself.
Any old bowl will do.
Ooh! Aha!
I know exactly where it is--
the music closet.
Music closet?
This place is bigger
than it looks.
♪♪
[grunting]
Ah, no tape or glue.
How are we supposed
to put this together?
Ah…
[chattering]
Hmm, you might be right,
George.
♪♪
Oh, not that.
Huh?
[grunts] Or that.
-Hmm.
-Oh!
[narrator] All these pieces
reminded George of his puzzle.
[gasps]
-[chattering happily]
-You have an idea?
[chattering happily]
♪♪
[narrator] And just like he did
with his puzzle,
George began sorting.
[grunts happily]
Oh.
You're sorting
all the pieces first.
Good idea.
[chattering happily]
♪♪
[narrator]
With everything sorted,
building the ship
would be a snap.
Ah!
[chattering happily]
Yeah, that does kind of look
like the deck of the ship.
[gasps] And these
must be the sides!
♪♪
Hmm. I bet this is the front.
But how do we attach it?
Hmm…
[grunts]
Ah!
♪♪
Uh…
[grunts]
♪♪
You did it,
Captain Monkeybeard.
How did you figure it out?
[laughs, chatters]
♪♪
-Ah…
-Yes!
♪♪
Captain Monkeybeard, I think
we're ready to set sail.
Ah!
Huh?
[narrator]
Something was missing.
♪♪
[chatters happily]
Hey!
You're abandoning ship!
-[objects clattering]
-Oh, it's in here somewhere.
It has to be!
Uh, say, why don't I just
take the Shakespeare bowl?
I'll put an eye patch on him.
[George chattering happily]
♪♪
[chattering happily]
♪ Argh, we are pirates… ♪
I really should get going.
That salsa isn't gonna
make itself, you know.
-Shh. Listen.
-[music continues playing]
[chuckles] Follow me.
[music continues playing]
♪♪
-[music stops]
-Of course.
I should've known it was here.
See, George was so excited
for the pirate party,
he played with it all night.
Ah! Well, it was well worth
the wait.
♪♪
What?
H-how did--
[chatters happily]
Well, shiver me timbers!
She's a beauty.
[chattering happily]
Anchors aweigh!
Look, Captain Monkeybeard,
sea giants!
[men laugh]
[chattering happily]
Wow.
That is really impressive.
But it's supposed
to be a new bed for you.
See?
Ooh!
[chattering happily]
[narrator] George liked the bed,
but it was no pirate ship.
[chattering happily]
Oh, you want to leave it
like a pirate ship?
[chattering happily]
[chuckles] Okay.
[shouting happily]
Aye aye, Captain Monkeybeard!
[shouts]
[chuckles] Too bad we can't
haul it to the party.
It'd be perfect.
I've got a better idea.
[indistinct chatter]
[pirate music playing]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
Want some of my briny broiled
beans, Captain Monkeybeard?
[chatters happily, munching]
[narrator] Nothing was
better than living
on your very own pirate ship.
[yawns]
[narrator] And it made
a pretty good bed, too.
♪♪
[upbeat music plays]