[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
[jaunty music on radio]
[male narrator] Monkeys
can't help
but play with their food…
[grunts, hums merrily]
[narrator] Especially
when there's music.
Check it out, George.
The old penguin suit
still fits.
[gasps]
[appreciative grunt]
Excited about
tonight's concert?
[affirmative grunts]
Ooh, here comes my part.
♪♪
[uncertain low note]
[quavers]
Uh-oh.
Oh, that didn't sound
too good.
Guess I should rehearse
a little more.
[chatters sheepishly]
Huh?
How did that happen?
[explanatory chattering]
It's okay, George.
Just hand me that sponge
with some soapy water on it,
okay?
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
No, it's not coming out.
I better take it
to the dry cleaner's.
Maybe Mr. Nettoyez
can do a rush job.
I guess rehearsal
will have to wait.
No!
♪♪
Uh-uh.
Huh?
[narrator] George knew
his friend needed
a bit more practice.
[chattering]
[narrator] He could take care
of this.
[helpful chattering]
You'll take it
to the dry cleaner's for me?
Uh-huh.
Well, thanks, George.
Okay, once more
from the top.
[uncertain low note]
♪♪
[casually chattering]
[shop bell rings]
♪♪
[Mr. Nettoyez] I'm in the back!
[cheerful grunting]
♪♪
Ooh.
Ah.
[curious chattering]
[Mr. Nettoyez] Over here.
♪♪
[curious chattering]
Oh, hi, George.
Something is jamming this rack,
but I just can't see
what it is.
♪♪
[gasps]
[chatters helpfully]
♪♪
[chatters triumphantly]
[chatters merrily]
Oh, hold on.
I-I'll stop the machine.
♪♪
[buzzer sounds]
[chatters merrily]
♪♪
[chatters cheerfully]
Heh.
Way to go!
Thanks for helping me
with that, George.
Now I can get back to work.
[requesting chatter]
♪♪
Sure, I can do this.
Is that mustard?
[sheepish grunts]
Uh-huh.
♪♪
Mustard's tough.
I'll have it for you
by tomorrow.
[chattering objection]
Oh, this is
for tonight's concert.
Your friend is playing
the tuba.
[positive chattering]
Mm, I'll try,
but I have all these clothes
to clean
and no one to help
at the counter.
Mm.
[helpful chattering]
You want to help?
Mm.
I could use
an extra set of hands.
[helpful grunts]
And feet.
Okay.
[triumphant grunts]
If a customer
is picking up clothes,
they'll give you a ticket.
[querying grunts]
Yes, that's right.
Then you match the ticket
to the one on the item.
Oh.
[comprehending chatter]
I'll be in the back,
cleaning these clothes,
if you need anything.
[reassuring grunt]
-[shop bell rings]
-[starts]
♪♪
[greeting grunt]
A dry cleaning monkey?
[laughs]
Now I've seen everything.
Can I get my tuxedo
for tonight?
♪♪
[affirmative grunting]
Aha!
♪♪
Aha.
[narrator] George saw
that the tickets matched,
so this must be Stig's tuxedo.
-[helpful grunting]
-[doorbell rings]
Thanks, George.
George!
I didn't know you worked
at the dry cleaner's.
[chattering happily]
Hey, have you seen
Aunt Margaret's dress
back there?
[chattering happily]
[narrator] George didn't need
a ticket.
He knew exactly
what that looked like.
[shop bell rings]
[Stig] Uh, George?
Uh, this isn't
my tuxedo
[mysterious music plays]
[narrator] Both tickets
were pink…
-Huh?
-[narrator] But that definitely
was not Stig's tuxedo.
[jaunty music plays]
[inquiring grunts]
♪♪
[alarmed cry]
[narrator] All the tickets
were pink!
[chattering]
♪♪
[narrator] If only George
had a faster way
to look through the clothes.
Oh.
[chattering excitedly]
[upbeat music plays]
[chattering triumphantly]
♪♪
[narrator] A tuxedo.
Jackpot.
♪♪
[chattering happily]
Thanks, George.
♪♪
I'm picking up some teeny,
tiny tuxedo ties
for tonight's show.
Oh.
[uncomprehending grunts]
-Oh.
-Uh, George,
close, but a little too small.
Oh.
[disheartened chattering]
Here, I'll help you, George.
[happy grunt]
One tuxedo and a lot
of tiny tuxedo ties
coming right up.
Hey, can this thing
go any faster?
[explanatory chattering]
♪♪
Oh.
Ha.
[frenetic music plays]
Ha, ha!
Yeah, now we're talking!
Ah!
[concerned chattering]
♪♪
[alarmed chattering]
Aw, oops.
Hm.
[satisfied grunt]
[excited chattering]
[querying grunts]
[irritated whine]
-[Steve] I found it!
-Ah.
[narrator] It wasn't Stig's tux,
but at least they found
something.
Ah.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Here's the ticket.
Huh?
Huh.
[grunting softly]
[narrator] Not only
were both tickets pink,
they were also
both number 22.
[comprehending grunt]
Aha!
[narrator] Maybe George
had to match
the numbers as well.
[upbeat music plays]
[chattering happily]
♪♪
[chattering hopefully]
Ooh.
♪♪
Huh?
[chattering happily]
Ah, this is it.
What a beauty!
Thanks, George.
[triumphant cry]
[circus march]
Excuse me.
I'm here to pick up
my clown costume.
Uh…
Don't worry, buddy.
I got this.
One clown costume
coming right up.
[upbeat music plays]
Ha.
♪♪
[circus march]
And your teeny, tiny
tuxedo ties
are coming up next.
[disheartened chattering]
[narrator] George needed
to clean up this mess.
Hm?
Hm.
Ah.
[narrator] George thought
it might be easier
to see all the numbers
if the clothes were hanging
back on the rack.
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
Ah.
Huh?
[narrator] The rack
had numbers on it, too.
Those must show
where the clothes belong.
Oh.
[narrator] There was ten.
[soft grunts]
[narrator] Then 11, 12,
13, 14…
Huh?
[narrator] And here was
the number 15,
just like on the jacket.
[triumphant cry]
[narrator] That was it!
The numbers showed
where the clothes belonged.
The tutu was 25.
♪♪
Aha!
[soft merry grunts]
♪♪
[narrator] Number nine.
Huh.
[narrator] 30, 31, 32--
the numbers were going up.
George needed the rack
to move the other way.
[gasps]
Ah.
[chattering happily]
[narrator] 18, 17, 16, 15…
Ooh.
Ah.
[chattering merrily]
[triumphant cry]
[satisfied grunts]
G'day, George.
See you tonight, George.
I have some news
about the mustard.
[concerned grunts]
It's all gone!
Success!
[sighs]
Huh?
[querulous grunting]
[upbeat music plays]
[affirmative grunts]
[upbeat orchestral music plays]
♪♪
Mm.
[gasps]
[concerned grunts]
♪♪
[nervous quavering]
[clear low note]
[upbeat music plays]
[triumphant cry]
Whoa!
[awkward brass riff]
Come see me tomorrow.
Aha!
[laughs]
♪♪
[chattering happily]
Thank you, George.
Now we can cross the barn
off the spring cleanup list.
[inquiring grunts]
Oh, I made that last fall.
It's a lantern
made from a gourd.
[inquiring grunts]
A gourd is a vegetable.
They don't taste very good,
but you can do all sorts
of fun things with them.
Let's see if the battery
still works.
Whoa.
[interested chattering]
[chattering happily]
I'm also turning some
into birdhouses.
Birds love 'em.
[narrator] George wondered
what he would make
out of a gourd.
Ooh.
Vroom!
Vroom! Vroom!
[laughs]
[chuckles]
Gourds are pretty easy
to grow.
You can plant your own
if you like.
I'll help you get started.
[enthusiastic cry]
[rustic music plays]
Yeah, here's a good spot.
Plenty of sun, and the soil
is soft and rich.
♪♪
[comprehending grunts]
First, we'll plant the seeds
in little mounds.
Four ought to be enough.
[chattering]
[laughs]
Much obliged.
♪♪
Now make three little holes
in each mound, like this.
♪♪
These are gourd seeds.
[gasps]
Ooh.
They grow into vines,
and from the vines
grow those gourds you saw.
Oh.
Put one or two of these
in each hole.
♪♪
They're gonna need
some water.
♪♪
There's a stream
a bit further up the hill.
Oh.
Uh-huh.
♪♪
[gasps]
[frog croaks]
Oh.
[friendly grunt]
[frog croaks]
[upbeat music plays]
[laughs]
[splashing sound]
♪♪
[concerned grunts]
Oh, careful, George.
You want to pour it gently,
and not all in one place.
♪♪
[grunts softly]
That's it.
Let the water soak in
all around.
By the end of summer,
you'll have
big, beautiful gourds.
But you'll have to water them
every day,
or they won't grow.
[understanding grunts]
♪♪
[labored grunts]
[narrator] It was hard work,
but George watered his gourds
every day.
Phew.
[energetic music plays]
[excited chattering]
[disappointed grunts]
[downbeat music plays]
[flighty flute music plays]
[languid rustic music plays]
♪♪
[labored grunts]
Phew.
♪♪
[wind whistling]
[labored grunts]
[gasps]
[upbeat music plays]
[laughs]
[frog croaks]
[chattering happily]
[languid rustic music plays]
♪♪
Whoa!
Oh.
Oh…
[knocking]
Hi, there.
Got your note, George.
I brought you my pickle bucket.
[thankful chattering]
Oh, hi, Bill.
Come on in.
Uh, you buy pickles
by the bucket?
They don't sell them
by the barrel anymore.
Huh?
[sniffs]
Ooh, is that meatloaf?
Hot out of the oven.
You want to pull up a chair?
Oh, really?
Okay.
Thanks.
[upbeat music plays]
Gravy?
Yes, please.
But wait, I don't want
the gravy to touch my carrots.
♪♪
Oh.
[excited chattering]
♪♪
[satisfied grunt]
Okay, well, I'm having dinner
with two expert gravy trappers.
[grunts]
See?
Then I dig a little trench
so the gravy flows
right to the meatloaf.
[comprehending grunts]
[excited chattering]
♪♪
Ah.
[jaunty music plays]
♪♪
Ah, phew.
Ahh!
Ooh.
♪♪
[laughs]
[frog croaks]
♪♪
[chattering happily]
[frog croaks]
♪♪
[suspenseful music plays]
[jaunty music plays]
[cheering triumphantly]
[chattering happily]
♪♪
[triumphant cry]
[concerned cries]
♪♪
[satisfied grunts]
[sedate music plays]
♪♪
[satisfied grunts]
[narrator] There.
No more buckets.
[building music plays]
♪♪
[triumphant musical cue]
[tranquil music plays]
♪♪
[frog croaks]
Mm.
Did you just hear a ribbit?
Uh-huh.
-[frog croaks]
-[gasps]
[frog croaks]
I think it's coming
from the basement.
[frog croaks]
[both gasp]
[upbeat music plays]
[chattering happily]
[jaunty music plays]
♪♪
Why is a frog
in our basement?
[frogs croaking]
[downbeat music plays]
♪♪
Maybe I should have asked
"Why are all those frogs
in our basement?"
♪♪
We caught ten frogs
in the basement.
Frogs like water,
and it is awfully wet out here.
But it hasn't rained
for weeks.
Where did all this water
come from,
and all these yellow flowers?
[narrator] George
had seen them before,
but where?
[cheerful grunt]
[upbeat music plays]
[frog croaks]
[narrator] Then he remembered.
[excited chattering]
♪♪
[explanatory grunt]
-Oh, my goodness.
-Oh, my.
You dug this trench so water
could flow to your gourds?
[affirmative chattering]
Well, that's called
irrigation.
You're a natural farmer, George.
[chattering happily]
Unfortunately, I think
you've also irrigated
the house.
Water has been flowing downhill
all summer long.
Uh-oh.
[gasps]
[cheerful grunt]
[optimistic chattering]
♪♪
[satisfied grunt]
-[triumphant musical cue]
-Ah.
Nice job, George.
When our basement
dries up,
your frog friends will leave
and find somewhere else
to live.
Hm…
Oh, these gourds
are gorgeous.
When they're dry,
their shells will harden.
Then I can show you how to make
the gourd lanterns.
[negative grunts]
Birdhouses?
[frogs croaking]
[narrator] Not birdhouses,
either.
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
[frog croaks]
[imitates croaking]
[laughs]
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪