[upbeat music plays]
[singer] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
[singer]
♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[singer] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[singer] ♪ And everything ♪
-[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[singer] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
-[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[singer]
♪ There's more to explore ♪
♪ When you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[singer] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
[singer]
♪ And that's marvelous ♪
[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[singer]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[bright music plays]
♪♪
[narrator] It was a perfect day
to enjoy the great outdoors.
[boxes dragging]
[sighs]
[narrator] But George was stuck
in the great indoors.
Some of this has been here
since this was
my grandfather's house.
-[grunts curiously]
-Uh…
We should probably donate this.
[gentle piano music plays]
♪♪
[chatters happily]
[grunts curiously]
[chatters excitedly]
Wow.
This looks like one of my
Grandpa's Treasure Clue Maps.
[chattering inquisitively]
[laughs] Yeah, Grandpa
would hide clues
and I'd follow them
to find the treasure.
But I don't remember ever
seeing this one.
[chattering happily]
Okay, let's go.
Let me grab my shovel
and compass!
[chatters excitedly]
[Man in the Yellow Hat] We're here!
Bugaboo Bend.
[grunting happily]
[laughs] Wait for me, George!
Let's see…
according to the map,
we need to dig up
the first clue
here at the wishing well.
X marks where we start.
[grunting]
[chatters inquisitively]
[chatters questioningly]
The X isn't on the ground,
George.
-It's only on the map.
-[chatters curiously]
The X shows that we should
dig by the well,
and the N means
it's on the north side.
[grunts]
[grunting questioningly]
The compass can show us
which side is north.
[chatters]
[Man in the Yellow Hat]
The N stands for north,
and the needle
always points north.
So we just need to line up
the N with the needle
and then we walk north.
[grunts]
[cheerful music plays]
[chatters happily]
Yep, that's the north side.
Let's hope it's here, George.
[grunts]
[chattering]
Ah
[chattering curiously]
[laughs] Don't worry, George.
That's not the treasure.
It's just the first clue.
Open it.
[chattering timidly]
[chatters happily]
"Head to the west
and find the mighty oak.
Dig on its west side,
this is no joke."
[narrator]
But which way was west?
The compass only had a needle
that pointed north.
[Man in the Yellow Hat]
The W stands for west.
Once you line up
the compass with north,
west is always to the left.
Okay.
[grunting excitedly]
[distant train horn blares]
[grunting happily]
Hmm, we're supposed to find
the "mighty oak,"
but oak trees don't have
white bark.
These are birch trees, George.
[grunts disappointingly]
[sighs] There's a big ol' oak
here somewhere.
[chuckles] Grandpa and I used
to climb it.
It had a trunk this big.
[chatters]
[grunting]
Yeah, like tha-- [gasps]
You're right!
[chatters sheepishly]
Ah, gee, I guess
they had to cut it down.
Okay, let's find
the west side of it.
[chatters curiously]
[grunts, giggles]
[chatters triumphantly]
You did it, George!
"Follow the tracks.
When you've reached
the same number of poles
as you have hands,
dig to the south
of where it stands."
[grunts happily]
[grunting excitedly]
Hmm.
That was pole number one.
We need the same number
as you have hands.
[grunting in succession]
Four? [chuckles]
Well, I guess monkeys
do have four hands,
but these clues were written
for a little boy.
[chuckles] Me.
[chattering happily]
[Man in the Yellow Hat] Right.
[grunting happily]
Now we "dig to the south."
[chatters curiously]
[Man in the Yellow Hat] See the S?
That stands for south.
South is the opposite of north.
[grunting excitedly]
[Man in the Yellow Hat grunting]
[chattering happily]
[Man in the Yellow Hat]
Here it goes.
"Go directly east
till you find a cider tree.
The last clue is there
but it's kind of hard to see."
-[gasps]
-[grunts curiously]
Ooh, I'll bet cider tree
means apple, as in apple cider.
[grunts]
[chattering]
[Man in the Yellow Hat]
You see the letter E?
That's east.
East is the opposite of west.
That way!
[chattering excitedly]
Wait, we need to refill
this hole.
Uh, never mind.
You go.
I'll catch up with you, okay?
[chatters]
Just make sure you keep
walking east
until you come
to the first apple tree.
[chatters]
[grunting happily]
[bright music plays]
♪♪
[grunting]
[giggles]
[grunts]
[chatters triumphantly]
Excellent navigating, George.
The clue says that once
we find the apple tree,
"the last clue is hard to see."
[chatters curiously]
Good idea, George.
Maybe Grandpa tied it
to a branch.
[grunting happily]
[chattering curiously]
[grunting]
[chattering happily]
[squirrel chittering]
[shrieks, chitters]
[chatters]
[chittering angrily]
[grunting inquisitively]
[chitters]
[chatters triumphantly]
You found the last clue,
George.
And a key?
"To find the treasure
and open the lock,
walk ten steps
toward Turtle Rock."
Turtle Rock.
[gasps, chatters]
Yes, George?
[grunting happily]
That's it!
Ten steps.
Ready?
[grunts happily]
-[grunting]
-One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten.
Oh, I can't believe we're gonna
find Grandpa's treasure!
[grunting]
[grunting] Where is it?
I mean--it has to be here.
[grunting sadly]
Um…
[sighs] It's not here.
[grunts curiously]
Maybe Grandpa
never buried it.
Or someone else found it.
[grunts sadly]
[sighs] Nothing to do now
but fill in the hole
and go home.
[chatters disappointingly]
[sighs]
Hm? Oh.
I'll slow down, George.
I forget smaller legs
take smaller steps.
[grunting]
[narrator]
His friend was right.
Smaller legs did take
smaller steps.
[grunts triumphantly]
[upbeat piano music plays]
[chatters]
Huh?
[grunting in succession]
[grunting excitedly]
You think I should dig there?
[chatters in agreement]
Right.
I went farther because
a grown-up's steps are longer.
[grunting in agreement]
And the treasure hunt wasn't
made for a grown-up!
[laughs] Stand back!
[grunts]
[thud]
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
[grunts]
[Man in the Yellow Hat]
Here it goes.
Ready to see our treasure,
George?
[grunts in agreement]
[chatters inquisitively]
[laughs] Pingle-tube!
[grunts curiously]
It's this great game
my Grandpa made up!
"You solved the clues.
Your quest is done.
The greatest treasure
is having fun!"
[chuckles] "Love, Grandpa."
[narrator] George felt proud.
He had found the lost treasure
of Bugaboo Bend.
[exciting banjo music plays]
Go!
[blows forcefully]
-[laughs]
-[grunts]
[narrator] And got pretty good
at Pingle-tube too.
[laughing]
[chatters curiously]
[laughter]
[cheerful music plays]
♪♪
[narrator] Lunch at Pisghetti's
was always fun,
especially when there was
something to celebrate.
-[party horn honks]
-[giggles]
Congratulations on winning
that essay contest.
Well, I had a great topic:
George!
[party horn honks]
[gasps]
Hey, a published author
deserves a special dessert!
Chef's famous apple pie!
Oh, apple pie!
My favorite!
This is the last piece,
so you two will have to share.
Tell me, how did you do it?
[Man in the Yellow Hat]
Well, you see, I find
that writing just requires
the right inspiration,
and well, for me,
that inspiration is George.
[chatters questioningly]
Georgio, that piece was
to share with your friend.
[chattering apologetically]
Oh, it's okay.
I'll get some next time.
You know,
I've always wanted to try
-writing poetry.
-Oh?
[narrator]
George thought there must be
more pie in the kitchen.
[mellow music plays]
[grunting curiously]
[grunting inquisitively]
Oh, sorry, Georgio, we're out
of my delizioso pie,
and I'm much too busy
to make more.
[chatters sadly]
[grunting thoughtfully]
[narrator] George wondered
if he could make the pie.
It was just apple goo
and yummy crust.
[chattering]
[chattering excitedly]
Wha--you want to make my pie,
Georgio?
[grunting in agreement]
Well, my famous pie
is very easy to make.
Okay, I'll give you the recipe.
[chatters questioningly]
Well, a recipe tells you how
to make pie or other foods.
For you, I'm gonna write it
in pictures.
[peppy music plays]
These steps are
for the apple filling.
Wash six apples,
then add 1/2 cup of sugar--
that means cup is filled
to the middle, eh--
then a teaspoon of cinnamon.
Next, add a little lemon,
mix it all up.
Voila!
Molto bene!
[grunts affirmatively]
Now the steps for
my fantastico flaky crust.
The oven gets set
to 350 degrees.
But, Georgio,
you got to get an adult
to help you set the oven.
[chatters affirmatively]
Take 1 teaspoon of salt,
2 cups of flour,
a stick of butter,
and 1 cup of water.
Put them in a bowl.
We're going to mix
them all up,
-flatten it out…
-[grunts]
Then lay it in a pie pan,
add the apple filling,
and bake for 45 minutes.
Voila!
[grunting, mimics]
[narrator] George was ready
to make a pie.
Maybe I'll get some dessert.
[grunting]
Oh, you want to get me
dessert?
[chatters affirmatively]
Okay, just, uh,
keep it simple.
I'll be in my room writing…
a poem.
[sighs] I should think
of a rhyme for monkey.
Funky?
Chunky.
[bright music plays]
[narrator] George started
with the apple filling.
First step, wash six apples.
♪♪
[chatters]
[narrator] One, two, three,
four, five, six.
-[grunting]
-[narrator] The dishwasher
got things really clean.
[grunting]
[bottle squirts]
[narrator]
Six apples, six squirts.
[grunting]
[beep]
-[dishwasher whirring]
-[grunts]
[narrator] Now to collect
the other ingredients.
[chatters]
[narrator] He needed sugar…
And cinnamon.
[sniffing, grunts in disgust]
[sniffs, sighs]
[narrator] And lemon.
Living with a monkey
is humbling.
-[rumbling]
-What's that rumbling?
[laughs] That rhymes!
[chattering]
Oh, it's a surprise.
Sorry, George.
[beeping]
[grunting]
[steam hisses]
[grunting happily]
[narrator]
Apples in apple pie
were supposed to be
nice and gooey.
[splattering]
Next, he needed a cup filled
to the middle with sugar.
♪♪
Sugar cubes were fun.
[grunts curiously]
[narrator]
But he had too many.
Just half a cup.
Next a spoonful of lemon.
[chatters happily]
[narrator]
And a spoonful of cinnamon.
[grunting happily]
[triumphant music plays]
[chatters]
[narrator]
Time to make the crust.
[grunts thoughtfully]
[narrator] He needed an adult
to turn on the oven
[grunts enthusiastically]
Mmm, smells like cinnamon
in here.
[shushes]
[softly] Oh, you doing
something secret, George?
[chattering affirmatively]
[whispering]
Your secret's safe with me.
[narrator] It was time
to gather the ingredients
for the crust.
First, a spoonful of salt.
[grunting]
[chatters happily]
[narrator]
Then 2 full cups of flour.
[chatters]
[narrator]
Next, add the butter.
[chattering happily]
[narrator]
And a cup of water.
Mixing time.
George remembered this part.
[grunting excitedly]
[narrator]
Next, make the dough flat.
[musical drum flourish]
[grunting happily]
[narrator]
Now George needed
a round pan to put it in.
[pans clattering]
[chatters triumphantly]
[gentle music plays]
[grunts thoughtfully]
[narrator] Maybe crust would
shrink in the oven.
[chatters curiously]
[grunting]
[chatters triumphantly]
[narrator]
It was baking time.
[dramatic music plays]
Boy, you creative types
sure are messy.
[shushes, chatters]
[chattering happily]
Gee, I guess I just don't get
gourmet cooking.
[narrator] George's recipe
said to bake the pie for 45.
[timer beeping]
[grunts]
[chatters thankfully]
[whispers] Anytime.
George, could--could I get
a glass of water?
-Here you go.
-Thanks!
George, what was the doorman--
[gasps]
Well, you didn't keep it simple.
[timer beeping]
[grunting excitedly]
[chatters triumphantly]
Huh, you made me a…
a-- What is that?
[chattering happily]
[grunting]
You made me an apple pie?
[chatters in agreement]
Oh, my.
[laughs awkwardly]
It's really salty
and cinnamon-y. [chuckles]
[grunting in disgust]
[chattering questioningly]
Well, George, it looks like
things didn't go
quite as planned.
[grunting sadly]
Hey, how about
after we clean this up,
we get more ingredients
and make a pie together?
-[chatters enthusiastically]
-Wait, that's it!
I once tried to rhyme
with a monkey,
and my rhyming was
all very clunky.
Then George made a pie.
He gave it a try.
Together,
we'll make one less…
chunky?
[chattering happily]
[giggling]
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪