[upbeat music plays]
[man] ♪ You never do know
what's around the bend ♪
♪ Big adventure
or a brand-new friend ♪
♪ When you're curious ♪
-♪ Like Curious George ♪
-[all] Swing!
-[man] ♪ Well, now, every day ♪
-[all] ♪ Every day ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so glorious ♪
-[all] ♪ Glorious ♪
-George.
-[man] ♪ And everything ♪
-[all] ♪ Everything ♪
-[man] ♪ Is so wondrous ♪
[all] ♪ Wondrous ♪
[man] ♪ There's more to explore
when you open your door ♪
♪ And meet friends like this ♪
-♪ You just can't miss ♪
-[all] Whoa!
-[man] ♪ I get curious ♪
-[all] ♪ Curious ♪
-[man] ♪ And that's marvelous ♪
-[all] ♪ Marvelous ♪
[man]
♪ And that's your reward ♪
♪ You'll never be bored ♪
♪ If you ask yourself,
"What is this?" ♪
♪ Like Curious ♪
♪ Like Curious,
Curious George ♪
Oh.
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
[male narrator] The first cold
day of fall
is the perfect time to test
out your new coat.
♪♪
[squirrel chitters]
[whimsical music plays]
Or to find the perfect hiding
place for your new acorn.
♪♪
Or best of all,
enjoy your new book
by a cozy fire.
Fearless Freddy never gave up.
[chatters indistinctly]
[narrator] He would stop
at nothing to get back
into the castle
to rescue his beloved cheese.
[chatters excitedly]
[narrator] Even if a cranky
old dragon had taken it.
[chatters, laughs]
♪♪
[chatters, giggles]
[chattering excitedly]
Hmm? Did you say something--
oh, no!
It's… a… stinkbug.
[sniffs, chatters]
It doesn't smell now,
but if it gets scared,
it makes a horrible smell.
That's why it's called
a stinkbug.
[chatters]
Can you find something
to put him in
so we can take him outside?
[chatters]
♪♪
[chattering]
Now… very carefully let
the bug crawl into the jar.
[chatters]
♪♪
[upbeat music plays]
Whew! [sighs]
You want to take him outside?
[chatters]
[narrator] His back was shaped
just like
Fearless Freddy's shield.
So George named him Freddy.
[chattering]
♪♪
[chatters]
[wind howls]
Brrr. Opening that door
let the chill in.
[chatters]
♪♪
[giggles]
Oh, thanks.
[sighs]
[gasps, whispering]
Stinkbug. Stinkbug!
Huh?
♪♪
[chatters]
[whimpers]
♪♪
[yells]
[mysterious music plays]
[chatters]
Ugh!
♪♪
Good thing he didn't spray us,
huh, George?
[chatters]
[narrator] Why did Freddy
come back inside?
Maybe Freddy wanted to live
with them.
♪♪
Pass the peas, George?
-[coughing]
-Yuck!
[coughing]
Yuck!
[narrator] Moving in with them
was out of the question.
[chatters]
[narrator] Maybe Freddy just
needed his own house,
like their house,
only bug-sized.
♪♪
George could build him one!
[chittering]
♪♪
[chatters]
[narrator] Since Freddy seemed
to like their house so much,
George wanted to make
his house just like it.
♪♪
So it needed some cozy rooms.
[chatters]
♪♪
Ooh.
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
[chatters]
[chattering]
♪♪
[chatters]
[jar rattles]
♪♪
[chattering]
Mm…
[narrator] Freddy needed
some furniture.
Otherwise, what would
he sit on?
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪
A comfy chair by a cozy fire.
Nice and soft.
[chatters]
[narrator] A yummy walnut snack
on the dining room table,
in case Freddy was hungry.
[chatters]
♪♪
[narrator] A bathroom mirror
and a big bathtub.
[chatters]
[narrator] Flowers smell good.
And Freddy could use some help
in that department.
[chatters]
[narrator] Voila.
The perfect buggy house.
[chatters]
♪♪
[narrator] Freddy looked very
happy in his new house.
[giggling, chattering]
George, lunch is ready.
[chatters]
♪♪
Mmm. There's nothing better
on a cold day
than a nice, warm
grilled cheese sandwich.
[munching noisily]
♪♪
[gasps]
Stinkbug!
Ugh! He's after me!
[dramatic music plays]
[chattering]
[narrator] Maybe bugs like
different sorts of things
in their houses.
♪♪
[chattering]
[narrator] George decided
to investigate
what sorts of things
bugs like to live in.
♪♪
[chattering]
[narrator] Bugs like to live
in all sorts of things.
[chatters]
[narrator] How could
George decide
what was right for Freddy?
[chatters]
[narrator] Each room
could be different.
♪♪
[chatters]
[chattering]
♪♪
[Man in the Yellow Hat] George!
Come on in.
It's getting dark.
[gasps, chatters]
♪♪
[narrator] George couldn't wait
to see
how Freddy liked sleeping
in his new house.
[wind howling]
[chattering]
♪♪
[chatters]
[narrator] There were
caterpillars
in the living room,
ladybugs in the bedroom,
and beetles in the bathroom.
But there was no Freddy.
[chattering]
[squirrel chittering]
[chittering]
Oh!
[narrator] That was it!
Stinkbugs liked living
under leaves!
[chatters]
[narrator] None of these
stinkbugs
had a freckle on their back.
Where was Freddy?
♪♪
[chatters]
[Man in the Yellow Hat] No!
Not my slippers!
[groans]
I propped my feet up
by the fire, and wham!
He stunk up my slipper!
Ooh.
Mm.
♪♪
[chatters]
[narrator] First,
Freddy came in
and sat on the man
by the warm fire.
Then he went under
the warm blanket.
Then he went onto
the warm sandwich.
And now he was on the slipper
by the warm fire.
[chatters]
[narrator] Freddy just wanted
to get warm.
♪♪
George was happy
all the other bugs
were enjoying his buggy house.
[chatters, giggles]
[chatters]
[narrator] And Freddy was happy
to be warm and cozy
by the fire.
[Man in the Yellow Hat] Tomorrow's
supposed to be warmer,
so we'll find a nice place
for him to live outside,
away from the house, okay?
[narrator] But Freddy was a lot
like Fearless Freddy.
He would never, ever give up
trying to get back
into the castle.
[chattering]
♪♪
[whimsical music plays]
[narrator] George loved
going to the stationery store
with Steve.
[sniffs]
[sighs]
[narrator] There was just
something about the smell
of all those school supplies.
I need a binder, paper,
and number 2 pencils.
[panting]
Whee!
[laughs]
[grunts]
Ha.
Ha! Got it.
♪♪
[chattering]
-[Rachel] Hey, Steve.
-Ah!
Oh! Hi, Rachel.
Ah!
I'm shopping for the art fair
this weekend.
I have the best idea!
Uh, what are you making?
Can't tell you.
It's a secret.
But… I'll give you a hint.
[whispering] I'm building
something
out of school supplies.
Are you doing something
for the fair?
Um, yeah!
Of course.
It's a secret too.
♪♪
Oh. Okay.
Well, good luck!
You too!
Quick! I need ideas
for an art project!
[chatters]
My friend Rachel and I have
been competing since preschool.
If she's making an art project,
I have to make a better one.
Hmm. Maybe I could build
a robot out of pencils.
[rubber band boings]
[chatters, laughs]
[gasps]
That's it!
[chatters]
I'm gonna make the world's
biggest rubber band ball!
George, you're a genius!
♪♪
[chatters]
Ah, here we go.
"Fold a rubber band into a wad,
then wrap another rubber band
around it."
[chatters]
♪♪
Ta-da!
Nice!
Now we just keep wrapping
rubber bands around it
until it's huge!
[chatters]
♪♪
We're gonna need…
-[chatters]
-A lot of rubber bands!
♪♪
-[man] Chair!
-Huh? Oh!
Phew.
Thanks, buddy.
[chatters]
[narrator] Now, where could
George find
lots of rubber bands?
[chatters]
[gasps, chatters]
Rubber bands?
-[chatters]
-Try my desk drawer.
[George vocalizing]
♪♪
Whoa!
Ooh! Ah!
[narrator] George had hit
the rubber band jackpot!
[chatters, laughs]
[chatters]
[narrator] Rubber band
scavenging was thirsty work.
♪♪
[chatters]
[gasps]
Ah!
♪♪
[chatters]
Bye, George.
Be a good little monkey.
[chatters]
[chattering]
Wow! With all these
rubber bands,
this baby's gonna be gigantic!
♪♪
Or… maybe not.
Actually, a lot of these
are pretty small.
Aww…
[barks]
Charkie, no!
[narrator] Charkie thought
the ball was perfect
just the way it was.
That's art, not a toy!
[Charkie panting]
Hmm. Where can we get more
big rubber bands?
Hmm.
[chatters]
♪♪
[narrator] The man had so many
rubber bands,
there were probably some big
ones George hadn't found yet.
Ah!
♪♪
Uh-uh-uh.
You can't have that one.
It's holding down the lid
on my knickknack box.
Aww.
[chatters]
Why are you taking
all our rubber bands anyway?
[chattering]
You're making a ball
out of rubber bands?
[chatters]
Fantastic!
I think I have some more
in the closet.
[chatters]
♪♪
[gasps]
[chatters]
♪♪
-[man] Table!
-[chatters]
Oh, thanks, buddy!
It sure is good to have
a monkey in the neighborhood.
[chattering]
♪♪
[Steve] Finito!
I think this is good, George.
[chattering]
[doorbell ringing]
[barking]
[upbeat music plays]
[gasps]
It's Rachel!
We gotta hide the ball!
[chatters]
She won't show me
her project,
so I'm not gonna show her mine.
[grunts]
[chatters]
♪♪
[doorbell rings]
-[panting]
-[chattering]
♪♪
Hey, Rachel, what's up?
Hi. I was at the store
picking up a few things
for my project
and I thought I'd see
how you're doing.
Uh, my project
is going great.
It's gonna be really big.
[Rachel] So is mine.
Mine's going to be huge.
[Steve] Well, mine's gonna be
ginormous!
-[George chattering]
-[gasps]
[both groaning]
♪♪
[chatters]
What's up with Charkie
and George?
Oh, they're just playing
with a ball.
Uh, I mean, a dog toy.
Well, I gotta get back to work.
Good luck.
See you tomorrow. Bye!
Phew.
"Huge," huh?
George, we gotta make
our ball bigger.
♪♪
[man] I could use a little help
here!
♪♪
[chatters]
[chattering]
[woman grunting]
[man grunting]
-[chatters]
-[woman grunts]
♪♪
Whew! Thanks again.
How can we repay you?
[chatters, giggles]
♪♪
[gasps]
[chatters excitedly]
George, you're amazing!
[giggles]
♪♪
Who knew a bunch of rubber
bands could be so heavy?
I'm glad we have an elevator.
[grunts]
Which is out of order.
Now what?
Uh…
[chatters]
Oh, yeah!
Good idea.
But it is pretty heavy.
-Ah!
-Oh, no!
[dramatic music plays]
♪♪
[chattering]
At least it's going
the right way!
-[chattering]
-[panting]
♪♪
[chattering]
[pole clangs]
♪♪
[chattering]
[whimpering]
Ah!
♪♪
[whimpers]
[chattering]
[grunts]
What? Hey!
Whoa, dude!
-[George yelling, whimpering]
-Hey!
Whoa!
♪♪
Later, skater!
[sighs]
♪♪
[chatters]
-[panting]
-[sighing]
That's your project?
Big, right?
It's impressive.
All those rubber bands.
Thanks. Where's yours?
Right here.
[George chatters]
Is that a miniature Eiffel Tower
made out of paper clips?
-Yep.
-[chatters]
Wow. It really is
your biggest idea yet.
[chatters]
[photographer] All right,
children.
Say cheese.
[grunts]
[whimpers]
[chatters]
[camera shutter clicks]
[all] George!
[George chatters, laughs]
[upbeat music plays]
♪♪